<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xd="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/doc/xsl" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd" version="3.4">
  <identifier type="local">LI09742</identifier>
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Moving library collections :
a management handbook</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name>
    <namePart>Habich, Elizabeth Chamberlain</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="lcnaf">aut</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="text">Westport, Conn.</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <publisher>Greenwood Press</publisher>
    <dateIssued>1998</dateIssued>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <extent>1 Bound Volumes</extent>
  </physicalDescription>
  <relatedItem type="series">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>The Greenwood library management collection,; Variation: Greenwood library management collection.</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <abstract>Abstract: 	"Moving a library is a mammoth task that requires precise, long-range planning. This book is a comprehensive guide to making that move a smooth one. Filled with practical advice culled from reports on more than a hundred moves, it addresses the needs of libraries planning to use a moving company or moving themselves. Habich gives the library move planner the analytical tools and knowledge of procedures necessary for carrying out the move effectively and efficiently."--BOOK JACKET.
Contents: 	Foreword / Lee B. Brawner -- I. Planning Collection Space. 1. Determining the Size of Existing Collections. 2. Planning for Growth. 3. Preparing a Collection Layout Plan -- II. Planning the Collection Move. 4. General Considerations -- III. Using a Moving Company. 5. Library and Mover Responsibilities. Library and Mover Responsibilities from a Mover's Perspective / Michael J. Kent. 6. Preparing a Request for Proposal (RFP). 7. Selecting a Mover. 8. Carrying out the Move: Working with a Mover -- IV. Doing the Move Yourself. 9. Planning Move Logistics. 10. Executing the Move Yourself -- V. Special Topics. 11. Moving Library Collections: Pest Management Control Issues / Agnes Quigg. 12. Cleaning Collections / Joyce Frank Watson.</abstract>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Library moving</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <geographic>United States</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Library materials</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Library administration -- methods</topic>
  </subject>
  <genre>volume</genre>
  <classification>025.8 HAB AS</classification>
</mods>
