<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA1545.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Ford Foundation records, Rights and Social Justice Program, Office Files of June Zeitlin</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Rights and Social Justice Program, Office Files of June Zeitlin <num>FA1545</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-03-25 06:33:12 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Ford Foundation records, Rights and Social Justice Program, Office Files of June Zeitlin</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="naf">Zeitlin, June H.</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" rules="dacs" source="nad">Ford Foundation</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA1545</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.95 Cubic Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">3 Hollinger boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1990/1992" type="inclusive">1990-1992</unitdate>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="cc451b7d85ff84cf33ed05f8e32e21db">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="78c5e3ae10373ed89fc07e17fb358f4c">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Reproduction/duplication of archival items is routinely provided in accordance with "fair use". If the RAC does not hold copyright for an archival collection, or items within a collection, it is the users responsibility to contact the copyright holder, or make a fair effort to do so, prior to publication.</p>  </userestrict>
  <bioghist id="6f9a041bdba652c12ddc526ff1b53de0">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The Ford Foundation was chartered by Henry and Edsel Ford in 1936 "to receive and administer funds for scientific, educational and charitable purposes, all for the public welfare", and initially served the Ford family's charitable interests in the Detroit area. Following the deaths of Edsel Ford (1943) and Henry Ford (1947), the Foundation was propelled to the forefront of philanthropy as the largest American foundation in terms of both endowment and yearly expenditures, and with an international scope to its major program areas. During the Foundation's first twenty years its major programs were in international economic development, primary and higher education, educational and public broadcasting, behavioral sciences, civil liberties, urban development, fine arts and the humanities. The Ford Foundation also partnered with the Rockefeller Foundation in supporting agricultural development in South America, Africa, and Southeast Asia. Since the 1970s, the Foundation has also pioneered programs in women's rights, energy policy, micro-financing in under-developed countries, establishing human rights groups, and improving international HIV/AIDS education.</p>  </bioghist>
  <acqinfo id="fac62a7edfe79ede8f8d2a66c9981202">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Ford Foundation archive was deposited at the RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files, and officers' papers were transferred to and accessioned by the RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.</p><p>This material was transferred to the RAC in 2019 and was ingested by the RAC as Accession 2019:085.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <scopecontent id="14f1ce1d6952a503bf6623e404d4b347">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Collection contains the staff subject files that June Zeitlin created during her tenure as Deputy Director of the Ford Foundation's Rights and Social Justice Program. Records consist solely of Zeitlin's chronological correspondence. In addition to the files Zeitlin created when she served in the Rights and Social Justice Program, there is also some material that originates from Zeitlin's time as a Program Officer in the Human Rights and Governance Program. The responsibilities of the Human Rights and Governance Program transferred to the Rights and Social Justice Program in June 1991.</p><p>
The correspondence in the collection documents Zeitlin's communication to grantees, potential grantees, Ford Foundation staff members, and collaborating institutions and individuals. It regards projects and programs related to the advancement of women's rights and opportunities as well as some Rights and Social Justice program administration and planning activities. During this time, the Foundation sought to provide support for initiatives related to women's legal rights, reproductive rights, women's economic opportunities, the intersection of work and family, the intersection of international human rights and women's rights, and domestic violence prevention.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="f770c92483af769a8fb629b579398126">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection consists of one series of chronological correspondence. Files within the series are arranged chronologically, while documents within the files are arranged alphabetically by correspondent name.</p><p>
Original order was maintained as much as possible.</p><p>
Collection arrangement is as follows:</p><p>
Series 1. Chronological files, 1990-1992</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="e8a8fa21ba1c405dfa4d157d82208bd3">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>  </prefercite>
  <bioghist id="b8d291c944b1f963b701cfc2169dfe38">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Throughout her career, June Zeitlin has worked as a foundation executive, women's rights lawyer, and public policy expert. She held a number of different positions related to human rights, women's rights, public policy, and governance from 1986 to 1999 at the Ford Foundation. The Foundation originally hired her as a Program Officer in the Human Rights and Governance Program. Following a change to the Foundation's program structure for human rights support, she became Deputy Director for the Rights and Social Justice Program. In this position, she was responsible for managing grants for women's rights and opportunities. Then in 1993, she became Director of the Governance and Public Policy Program and retained her Director responsibilities when that program transitioned to become Governance and Civil Society.</p><p>
Zeitlin graduated from the University of Rochester in 1970 with a B.A. in political science. She then earned her law degree from New York University in 1973. Prior to her work at the Ford Foundation, she held a variety of government and legal advocacy jobs in Washington D.C. and New York City. Some of these jobs included Legislative Assistant to Representative Bella Abzurg (1975-1977), Director of the Office on Domestic Violence in the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (1979-1981), Attorney for the National Women's Law Center (1981-1982), and Director of the Office of Legislative Coordination for the New York City Human Resources Administration (1982-1985) among others.</p><p>
After leaving the Ford Foundation in 1999, Zeitlin became Executive Director of the Women's Environment and Development Organization (WEDO). She stayed in that position until 2008 and later served as Director for the Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination Against Women (CEDAW) Education Project at The Leadership Conference on Civil and Human Rights.</p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="76bf89e4266d19d1bcf75c805b336539">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processing Level 3: Standard Processing</p><p>
Processed by Darren Young, September 2019</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="d0dbb9c68f0ceccb8dab5f98477c79cd">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Finding aids concerning June Zeitlin's office files when she served as Director of the Governance and Public Policy Program:</p><p><extref href="../FA543/overview">FA543 Ford Foundation records, Governance and Public Policy (GPP), Office Files of June Zeitlin and William Diaz</extref></p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">Ford Foundation</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Family violence</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Human rights</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Reproductive health</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Reproductive rights</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women's rights</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Work and family</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="e8d09cf70e17bebb3646287fa4557488" level="series"><did><unittitle>Chronological files</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.95 Cubic Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">About 2 LTR size and 1 Half-LTR size Hollinger boxes</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1990/1992" type="inclusive">1990-1992</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="239ff8f3acbc7a0c9de3468f4d8e2013"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Series consists of the chronological correspondence June Zeitlin created and maintained during her tenure as Deputy Director of the Ford Foundation's Rights and Social Justice Program in the early 1990s. Some material created during Zeitlin's time as a Program Officer in the Human Rights and Governance Program is also contained within the series. The responsibilities of the Human Rights and Governance Program transferred to the Rights and Social Justice Program in June 1991.</p><p>
Zeitlin primarily addressed her correspondence to grantees, prospective grantees, Ford Foundation staff members, and collaborating institutions and individuals. It documents the various areas of women's rights and opportunities that the Foundation sought to support. These areas include women's legal rights, reproductive rights, women's economic opportunities, the intersection of work and family, the intersection of international human rights and women's rights, and domestic violence prevention. Significant amounts of material regard the Work/Family Collaborative Research Project and the seminars of the Women's Program Forum. The series also contains correspondence that discusses Rights and Social Justice program administration activities such as program review meetings.</p></scopecontent><c id="ee4a7151a95b2b1c2b412a36d65757fd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chronological file</unittitle><unitdate normal="1990/1990">1990</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="aa84ef50eaa8a894917d4a6c306d62bd" label="mixed materials [A0000000115661]" type="box">1</container><container id="b7637916158ae17d5a6e08b0e842d67c" parent="aa84ef50eaa8a894917d4a6c306d62bd" type="folder">1-4</container></did></c><c id="ec8bdf6018413a901eb23a69907fcd47" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chronological file, A-L</unittitle><unitdate normal="1991/1991">1991</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="e37aec03473d14c524198c5c20073ddc" label="mixed materials [A0000000115661]" type="box">1</container><container id="603ebd04a331d2171da64f320521b758" parent="e37aec03473d14c524198c5c20073ddc" type="folder">5-6</container></did></c><c id="fbeedf7e681a4ec05e11bbdab26f6220" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chronological file, M-Z</unittitle><unitdate normal="1991/1991">1991</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="4eed5d4c4ec09362e55680d67f4e41c0" label="mixed materials [A0000000115662]" type="box">2</container><container id="97c0211e966592eac88d44f8e0f68502" parent="4eed5d4c4ec09362e55680d67f4e41c0" type="folder">7-8</container></did></c><c id="d9c8143969b4ef256d7a739d745ca13f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chronological file, A-L</unittitle><unitdate normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="a28f64fba472e2312efac4e5089e9a0d" label="mixed materials [A0000000115662]" type="box">2</container><container id="6d8366aa42ae00878dda6c8a0d627165" parent="a28f64fba472e2312efac4e5089e9a0d" type="folder">9-11</container></did></c><c id="210fc55659b0ebc78c716ce71b1e45e9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chronological file, M-Z</unittitle><unitdate normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate><container altrender="Half Letter Document Box" id="a12853852ae8f1ca3a196cb1308d9eb4" label="mixed materials [A0000000115663]" type="box">3</container><container id="62fa3091a6b95ecf33b30af2472ebb0c" parent="a12853852ae8f1ca3a196cb1308d9eb4" type="folder">12-13</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
