<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xd="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/doc/xsl" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd" version="3.4">
  <identifier type="local">LI09744</identifier>
  <titleInfo>
    <title>A Modern archives reader :
basic readings on archival theory and practice</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <originInfo>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="text">Washington, D.C.</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <publisher>National Archives and Records Service</publisher>
    <dateIssued>1984</dateIssued>
  </originInfo>
  <abstract>Contents: 	1. The European tradition. Some aspects of archival development since the French Revolution / Ernst Posner -- Reflections of an archivist / Hilary Jenkinson -- 2. Pre-archival functions. Archivists and records managers : variations on a theme / Frank B. Evans -- Records management and the walking archivist / Patricia Bartkowski -- Archival Janus : the records center / Herbert E. Angel -- 3. Records appraisal. The appraisal of modern public records / T.R. Schellenberg -- Appraising machine-readable records / Charles M. Dollar -- No grandfather clause : reappraising accession records / Leonard Rapport -- Intrinsic value in archival materials -- 4. Archival acquisition. Good sense and good judgement : defining collections and collecting / Mary Lynn McCree -- Archival collection development : building a successful acquisitions program / Richard M. Kesner -- A primer on manuscript field work / Virginia R. Stewart -- The gift and the deed / Trudy Huskamp Peterson -- 5. Arrangement. Archival principles of arrangment / T.R. Schellenberg -- Archival arrangement--five different operations at five levels / Oliver W. Holmes -- Organizing photo collections : an introspective approach / Nancy E. Malan -- Aural and graphic archives and manuscripts / Ralph E. Ehrenberg -- 6. Description. Efficient finding aids : developing a system for control of archives and manuscripts / Lydia Lucas -- The preparation of inventories at the National Archives / Edward E. Hill -- The place of the register in the manuscripts division of the Library of Congress / Katharine E. Brand -- Subject guides / Virginia C. Purdy.
7. Reference. Reference / George Chalou -- The illusion of omnisicience : subject access and the reference archivist / Mary Jo Pugh -- 8. Public programs. Education programs : outreach as an administrative function / Elsie Freeman [Freivogel] -- Archival exhibits : considerations and caveats / Joan Rabins -- 9. Establishing priorities. Management concepts and archival administration / James C. Worthy -- When is a collection processed? / Megan Floyd Desnoyers -- The archival edge / F. Gerald Ham -- Appendix. Introduction to archival terminology / Maygene F. Daniels.</abstract>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Archives</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcnaf">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Daniels, Maygene F.</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcnaf">
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>United States. National Archives and Records Service</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcnaf">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Walch, Timothy</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <identifier type="isbn">0911333126</identifier>
  <genre>volume</genre>
  <classification>025.17 DAN AS</classification>
</mods>
