<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xd="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/doc/xsl" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd" version="3.4">
  <identifier type="local">LI09734</identifier>
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Management basics for information professionals</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <originInfo>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="text">New York</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <publisher>Neal-Schuman Publishers</publisher>
    <dateIssued>2007</dateIssued>
    <edition>2nd ed.</edition>
  </originInfo>
  <note>Includes bibliographical references and indexes.</note>
  <abstract>Abstract: 	Completely revised and expanded to reflect the rapidly changing sphere of information services, this comprehensive introduction to the management of libraries builds the basic skills good library managers must exercise. The authors offer an authoritative approach on the fundamental concepts of management while recognizing the diverse needs of different operating environments. This edition features two new chapters - Managing Diversity and Career Development - and is kept up to current by material housed on the Web. Drawing from examples of successful leadership techniques from a variety of services archives, information brokers, libraries, records managements and more, this book demonstrates the most effective ways to plan, delegate, make decisions, communicate, and lead a team. Equal emphasis is placed on personal, fiscal, and technological issues, as well as a look at what the future may hold for incoming managers. A practical, up-to-date introduction to library management, here is a text that will appeal to LIS educators, new and experienced libraries in management positions, students, and anyone wishing to acquire a sound knowledge of both the theory and practice of management within the changing information workforce.Contents: 	Introduction -- Management concepts -- The operating environment -- Managing diversity -- Marketing -- Change and innovation -- Decision making -- The planning process -- Power, authority, and responsibility -- Delegation -- Performance, quality, and control -- Communication -- Motivation -- Leadership -- Managing people -- Managing money -- Managing technology -- Managing and planning physical facilities for information services -- Career development -- Looking forward.</abstract>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <geographic>United States</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Management</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Library administration</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Information services</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcnaf">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Layzell Ward, Patricia</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcnaf">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Evans, G. Edward</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <identifier type="isbn">9781555705862</identifier>
  <genre>volume</genre>
  <classification>025.1 EVA AS</classification>
</mods>
