<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>FA566.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper type="filing">Ford Foundation records, International Division, Office Files of Robert H. Edwards</titleproper>
        <titleproper>A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Office Files of Robert H. Edwards
 <num>FA566</num></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by Brian Bleich and Nancy Ng Tam, The Winthrop Group</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>July 2011</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline>
          <addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline>
          <addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2016-12-03 00:11:25 -0500</date>.</creation>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Ford Foundation records, International Division, Office Files of Robert H. Edwards</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="aut" source="lcnaf">Ford Foundation</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>FA566</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.4 Cubic Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1968/1977" type="inclusive">1968-1977</unitdate>
      <abstract id="c7a0223ef5ed739dac40ff694ce77749">Robert H. (Hazard) Edwards joined the Ford Foundation as a program officer for the International Division in 1965. In 1968, Mr. Edwards served as the Foundation’s Representative in Pakistan and, in 1971, became Head of its Middle East and Africa (MEA) Program. Mr. Edwards left the Foundation in 1977 to accept an appointment as President of Carleton College in Northfield, Minnesota. The Office Files of Robert H. Edwards span from 1968 to 1977 and comprises the files that Mr. Edwards kept as Head of the International Division's Middle East and Africa Program. The collection is organized into three series: program management files, subject files, and chronological files. The program management files primarily consist of memoranda but also correspondence, notes, reports and papers relating to the work of Mr. Edwards’s program officer Lowell S. Hardin. Mr. Edwards’s subject files contain memoranda, correspondence, papers, speeches, reports, meeting materials and background primarily pertaining to the Foundation’s programs in the Middle East and Africa. His chronological files of correspondence and memoranda from April to October of 1968 are also available.</abstract>
      <physdesc id="00814e0ff2729346bea972a671ba3cf2">
        <extent>(4 Hollinger document boxes)</extent>
      </physdesc>
    </did>
    <acqinfo id="ea0a2b2b97c1aba9646eca8bbc469341">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
      <p>Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <accessrestrict id="71c10d1b19c6aeb88ec6fc8d5aeb6459">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
      <p>Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.</p>
      <p>Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="6093fb74b139a9baee40689fdf08274a">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
      <p>Completion of a use agreement is required prior to providing scholarly access. See RAC Head of Reference (or applicable designee) for details. Ford Foundation holds title, copyright and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them. The Rockefeller Archive Center has authority to grant permission to cite and publish material from the collection for scholarly purposes. Permission to publish extensive excerpts, or material in its entirety, will be referred to the Ford Foundation.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="2fdea924ea5e7dc2febc5d556217fdb6">
      <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
      <p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>
    </prefercite>
    <separatedmaterial id="52664124e3cc704baca873f292825cf9">
      <head>Separated Materials Note</head>
      <p>Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.</p>
    </separatedmaterial>
    <bioghist id="c0db22731b1afa06fe5e097889f117cd">
      <head>Organizational History</head>
      <p>The Ford Foundation has been engaged in overseas work since the early 1950s. The Foundation's aspiration to become a national and international philanthropy for the advancement of human welfare was first formally expressed in the seminal 1949 report of the Gaither Study Committee, which was commissioned by the Board of Trustees to chart the future. In 1951, the Foundation established two of its first grant programs, Overseas Development (OD) and Overseas Training and Research (OTR). The granting goals were to increase agricultural production, improve health and living conditions, and advance education. South and Southeast Asia were the initial focus, with India and Pakistan receiving the majority of grants. A more limited number of grants were issued in Indonesia and Burma. A program for smaller regional and national grants also was initiated for the Near East. In 1957, Overseas Development further expanded to include programs in Latin America.</p>
      <p>As part of a Foundation reorganization in 1966, the Overseas Development Program, along with other international programs such as International Training and Research (ITR) and Population, became part of a single International Division (ID). A subsequent restructuring of the International Division occurred in 1980-1981 and led to the creation of the Developing Countries Program (DCP). DCP was again restructured in 1989, resulting in the separating of programs in Africa and the Middle East (AME, formerly MEA), Asia (ASIA), Latin American and the Caribbean (LAC/OLAC), Human Rights and Governance (HRG), Education and Culture (EC), Program-Related Investments (PRI), and International Affairs (IA) as independent program areas.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <bioghist id="495bb38b83db3bb76337720bd6c3e6e1">
      <head>Biographical Note</head>
      <p>Robert H. (Hazard) Edwards was born on May 26, 1935 in London, England and was raised in Middleton, Ohio. In 1957, he received a B.A. in English from Princeton University. He subsequently read law at Cambridge University and received an LL.B. from Harvard Law School in 1961.</p>
      <p>After graduation, Mr. Edwards served under the Queen's Commissioner in the Bechuanaland Protectorate from 1961 to 1963, where he assisted in its transition to independence as the Republic of Botswana. From 1963 to 1965, he worked for the U.S. State Department's Bureau of United Nations Affairs on matters relating to the newly independent African countries before joining the Ford Foundation as a program officer for the International Division in 1965. In 1968, Mr. Edwards served as the Foundation's Representative in Pakistan and, in 1971, became Head of its Middle East and Africa (MEA) Program.</p>
      <p>Mr. Edwards left the Foundation in 1977 to accept an appointment as President of Carleton College in Northfield, Minnesota. In 1986, he left Carleton College to join the Secretariat of His Highness the Aga Khan as Head of the Department of Health, Education and Housing in Karachi, Pakistan. From 1987 to 1990, he also served on the Board of Trustees of Aga Khan University. He returned to the United States in 1990, serving as President of Bowdoin College until his retirement in 2001.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <relatedmaterial id="533107cc9dc8acc76f917df5924f1f81">
      <head>Related Collections</head>
      <p>FA547 Ford Foundation records, International Division, Office Files of Forrest F. Hill, 1952-1966 contain related subject files on agricultural development and the establishment of agricultural research and training centers. Dr. Hill served as Vice President of Overseas Development (later International Division) from 1955 to 1963.</p>
      <p>FA503 Ford Foundation records, Africa and Middle East Programs (AME), Program Staff Files - contain other files of Robert H. Edwards. Also included in the collection are files of Dr. John D. Gerhart, Steven M. Riskin, and Anna Wadia. The bulk of the files are meeting and discussion group records from staff participation at internal Foundation meetings and discussion groups that brought together different philanthropies for common goals.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <processinfo id="7e0f00f2bae5ca8dbe9993dfc997a40e">
      <head>Processing Information Note</head>
      <p>This collection was created by merging files that had been misfiled and stored under incorrect departments or divisions. Mr. Edward's chronological files were originally filed among files belonging to the Higher Education and Research Division.</p>
      <p>Box 4 contains legal-sized subject files. These files are part of <emph render="bold">Series II. Subject Files</emph> and have been physically separated from the other (letter-sized) subject files and placed at the end of the collection to accommodate their size. Within the finding aid, they have been intellectually arranged to appear alphabetically by folder title along with other subject files to facilitate access.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <arrangement id="e68baab6fb770e1bad8c60894563f924">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>Collection is arranged into 3 series.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <scopecontent id="63946b584950b16968949bac2ea7cce5">
      <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
      <p>The Office Files of Robert H. Edwards span from 1968 to 1977 and comprises the files that Mr. Edwards kept as Head of the International Division's Middle East and Africa Program. The collection is organized into three series: program management files, subject files, and chronological files.</p>
      <p>The program management files primarily consist of memoranda but also correspondence, notes, reports and papers relating to the work of Mr. Edwards's program officer Lowell S. Hardin. As is reflected in the subjects covered in his files, Mr. Hardin's work primarily concerned agricultural research and rural development in the Middle East and Africa. His files include information on agricultural research centers, international efforts in aquaculture, the world food crisis, the difficulty in recruiting staff for Africa, the phasing out of advisory support for economic planning in Africa, and the possibility of Saudi support for agricultural research.</p>
      <p>Mr. Edwards's subject files contain memoranda, correspondence, papers, speeches, reports, meeting materials and background primarily pertaining to the Foundation's programs in the Middle East and Africa. There are materials on the Foundation interest in and support for inter-faith dialogues in the Middle East, area studies and social science research in Africa, training for journalists in Africa, and international agricultural research and training centers. In addition, there are discussion and background papers as well as memoranda concerning the agenda and logistics for the Ford Foundation Seminar for OLAC/MEA Program Advisors in Agriculture held in Ibadan, Nigeria (1973). Some of the subject files pertain to the Foundation's work on legal development in Latin America and the International Legal Center (ILC) Research Advisory Committee on Law and Development. These files contain meeting materials for the ILC Research Advisory Committee and memoranda reporting on a series of in-house Foundation meetings on law and social change in Latin America (1972-1973).</p>
      <p>A subject file on Foundation-grantee relations contains memoranda and discussion papers critiquing and reflecting on the how the Foundation interacts with grantees. Memoranda and papers address such issues as defining the limits of Foundation intervention in grantee organizations, the autonomy granted to grantees to execute projects, the responsibilities of program officers, and the status of Foundation employees hired through suballocations. These materials appear to be background for task force discussions addressing a lack of sensitivity toward grantees in Foundation policy formulation (1973).</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <accessrestrict id="613232d587b146b3e8645dd4f1952a11">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <bioghist id="42baf2bf4415358789beeaf00798c4ee">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Segment One: International Activities of the Ford Foundation: An Overview</emph>
      </p>
      <p>The Foundation's aspiration to become a national and international philanthropy for the advancement of human welfare was first formally expressed in the seminal 1949 report of the Gaither Study Committee, <emph render="italic">Report of the Study for the Ford Foundation on Policy and Program</emph> (RAC Library, call letters 361.7 GAI ), which was commissioned by the Board of Trustees to chart the Foundation’s future. Foundation Trustees launched Ford’s international grantmaking activities in 1950 when they approved the committee’s report and its embrace of peace, democracy, and freedom.  Since then, the Foundation has tackled these goals using a variety of strategies and responding to changing contexts, from the Cold War to the 1989 fall of the Berlin Wall and beyond.</p>
      <p>Toward the Foundation’s aspiration‎al goal, "the establishment of peace", its international activities have comprised a wide range of conceptual approaches and focus areas. These include international affairs, international studies, international understanding, arms control and disarmament, international law, international economic concerns, and overseas development in nearly every region of the world. Three distinct periods emerge for the international grantmaking defined by external contextual changes and internal changes in Foundation leadership and structures: the expansion era of 1950-1965; the transition and restructuring years of 1966-1988; and the post-1989 shift away from Cold War dichotomies.  During each of the distinct historical periods the consistent objectives were: 1) to ensure freedom and democracy in developed countries; 2) to foster education and international understanding in all countries; and 3) to contribute to the social, economic, and political development of less developed countries.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <bioghist id="82b16c545b3ff4f51db1ee8cd96bb5d6">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Segment 3. Period Sketch - Transition and Restructuring 1966-1988</emph>
      </p>
      <p>In the 1960s, the Ford Foundation Trustees began to rethink the role of the Foundation in the context of the era’s dramatic political and cultural changes. For instance, the passage of the 1964 Civil Rights Act created a domestic policy context in which the Foundation could more deeply engage with issues of rights and social justice. Events overseas starting in the late 1960s would extend the rights agenda to international affairs and development operations at the Foundation -- all advanced by the leadership of McGeorge Bundy (president, 1966-1979). </p>
      <p>McGeorge Bundy was appointed president in 1966, following a significant career in national security and academic administration. During World War II, he worked with the Army’s intelligence division, and in the early post-war years was a political analyst at the Council on Foreign Relations. Even without a postgraduate degree, at the age of thirty -four he became dean of the Faculty of Arts and Science at Harvard University. In 1961, President Kennedy appointed Bundy to be Special Assistant to the President for National Security - a position he held for five years under both Kennedy and Johnson. Those significant years saw the Bay of Pigs invasion, the Cuban Missile Crisis, and the beginnings of the Vietnam War. </p>
      <p>When Bundy arrived at the Foundation, he initiated a restructuring that modeled government departments rather than the academic ones President Henry Heald had established in the 1950s. At the same time, he had to contend with serious financial constraints due to Ford’s overspending in the prior periods and to economic downturns in the global economy. The Board of Trustees mandated an annual spending of over $100 million. </p>
      <p>These economic constraints meant that Foundation programs had to be more selective across the range of its programs. Nonetheless, international activities remained prominent with the new president and trustees. President Bundy and key trustees such Eugene Black (1960-1968, former head of the World Bank) and Robert S. McNamara (1968-1986, former U.S. Secretary of Defense and then head of the World Bank, 1968-1981) reflected a commitment to the international activities. Bundy also added to the board in 1972 the first trustee from a developing country, the Indonesian activist and scholar, Dr. Soedjakmoto, the former Ambassador to the United States from his country and then Special Adviser on Social and Cultural Affairs to the Chairman of Indonesia’s National Development Planning Agency. </p>
      <p>To create economies of scale, Bundy unified US-based international and overseas activities under one division: the International Division (using the name for the first time). That division comprised Resources for Development (area studies, languages, and exchanges), Population, International Relations, Planning and Evaluation, and the country programs. David Bell, an economist and the first administrator of the US Agency for International Development (1962-1966), was named vice president and served in that capacity until the end of Bundy presidency. </p>
      <p>In 1966, Bundy terminated the long-standing internationally oriented but domestically based International Training and Research Program.   Several large domestic programs -- including support of centers of international studies - were phased out in the 1970s. Instead, Ford launched under its international affairs efforts a focused but robust program in security and arms control. Over Bundy’s tenure, the overseas offices were reduced from twenty in 1966 to twelve in 1979, when he retired. </p>
      <p>The Foundation increasingly turned its attention to different set of international issues including human rights and working in repressive societies, such as South Africa. The military coups in Latin America during the late 1960s and early 1970s led the Foundation to initiate in 1976 a human rights program housed in Vice President Bell’s office. </p>
      <p>In 1979, Franklin Thomas was named president of the Ford Foundation (1979-1996).  In contrast to Bundy’s international and defense policy background, Franklin Thomas brought to the Ford Foundation his experience in law, housing, and community development. Prior to joining the Foundation, Thomas, a lawyer, was a Foundation trustee. He chaired the Rockefeller Foundation-funded Study Commission on U.S. Policy towards South Africa and led the Ford-funded Bedford-Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation in New York from its beginning in 1966 until he left in 1979. Earlier, he had been deputy police commissioner of NYC. </p>
      <p>In the first decade of Thomas’ tenure, the international work was still framed using the post-war East-West dichotomy. Several trustees brought to the board active engagement in international issues: Donald F. McHenry (trustee over the period 1981-1993) had served as ambassador to the U.N. and was active in the anti-apartheid movement; and General Olusegun Obasanjo (trustee over the period 1987-1999) had been Nigerian head of state from 1976-1979, and was then president of the African leadership Forum. Along with McNamara and Soedjakmoto, Rodrigo Botero, an internationally renowned economist from Colombia and former Colombian Minister of Finance and Credit from 1974 to1976, remained on the board over the period 1978-1989. </p>
      <p>During the early years of the Thomas presidency, the scope and strategies of the Foundation’s activities were also influenced by economic and global pressures, leading to reduced assets and further financial stringencies. Thomas’ board-mandated reductions resulted, for example, the firing of twenty senior staff at the same time.  To achieve more effective and efficient programs, Thomas had a vision of Ford as one foundation, linking the domestic and overseas activities under new program themes: Urban Poverty, Rural Poverty and Resources, Human Rights and Social Justice, Governance and Public Policy, Education and Culture, and International Affairs. </p>
      <p>The restructured Foundation comprised two programmatic divisions led by vice presidents: U.S. and International Affairs Programs (USIAP) headed by Susan Berresford; and Developing Countries Program (DCP), headed by William Carmichael. Berresford had been at the Foundation since 1970, coming from the U.S. Manpower Career Development Agency. She served in the National Affairs area, first as program assistant and then program officer (1972-1980), becoming head of women’s programs in 1980. The main international efforts under USIAP were housed in Rural Poverty and Resources, Human Rights and Governance, and International Affairs. The other programs - Urban Poverty, Education and Culture, and Program-Related Investments - also addressed a scattering of international issues related to their main themes. </p>
      <p>Carmichael had joined the Foundation in 1968 as Representative in Brazil. In July 1971, he was named Head of the Office of Latin America and the Caribbean, and in September of 1977, he became Head of the Middle East and Africa Office.  The DCP program was responsible for all the Field Offices: Andean and the Southern Cone, Brazil, Mexico and Central America, Bangladesh, India, Southeast Asia, West Africa, Eastern and Southern Africa, and Middle East and North Africa. </p>
      <p>When the Foundation initiated a Human Rights and Governance program (HR&amp;G) in 1981, it was the first instance of a Ford program explicitly entitled “human rights,” despite the fact that human rights grantmaking that had started officially in 1976. International Affairs remained separate from HR&amp;G. In 1987, however, the Board conceptually linked three programs, creating a Trustee committee called Human Rights, Governance, and International Affairs, which existed until 1992. Operationally, however, the programs relating to these fields did not often work together. </p>
      <p>International governance remained a commitment under Thomas. The Foundation, for example, had a long-established relationship with the United Nations: from 1951 until 1988, the United Nations received ninety grants from the Foundation (it received another 198 over the period 1989-2009). </p>
      <p>In these early years of the Thomas presidency, dramatic changes were occurring in the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe. Under President Mikhail Gorbachev’s leadership since 1985, the USSR was opening up to the international community, the rule of law in society was taking prominence there, and press freedoms were spreading. The foundation developed new programs in the region, drawing on the $60 million already spent to promote human rights and free expression and increase Western understanding of developments there. </p>
      <p>Given the continuing economic constraints facing the Foundation and rising debt in developing countries, the Foundation shifted support under DCP to smaller scale community-based initiatives in the field offices. Thomas was also charged by the Board to increase the diversity of grantees, especially to favor populations “most affected” by the problems of concern to the Ford Foundation. The Foundation built on earlier efforts and sharpened its focus on women’s issues throughout the world, including shifting the focus of the population program to women' reproductive health and child survival. </p>
      <p>In the 1980s, Carmichael and others, with strong support from Thomas and the board, continued the 1970s’ support of South African grantees for training large numbers of black lawyers and litigating sensitive cases in the South African legal system. Recognizing the multifaceted nature of discrimination in South Africa, the Foundation not only advanced the rule of law, but also strengthened civic organizations, women’s groups, and educational institutions. Further, it supported a number of activist organizations in the United States that were energetically advocating US governmental sanctions against South Africa and for private disinvestment. The Foundation also played a role in shaping US policy on apartheid through the role Thomas played from 1985 to 1987 chairing the US Secretary of State’s Advisory Committee on South Africa. </p>
      <p>The Foundation's overseas staff also sought to improve the economic situation in poor, marginalized communities through targeted loan programs particularly to women head of households, beginning with the innovative work in Bangladesh of Professor Mohammed Yunus, the founder of the Grameen Bank. The results led the way to establish the field of microfinance with the aim of empowering women living in poverty conditions, such as through a microfinance network in Latin America starting 1980 and a global lending program for women starting in 1987. </p>
      <p>Thomas encouraged staff to share results at worldwide meetings. During those meetings, Ford staff in the country offices and in New York tried to follow the mandate to work as “one foundation.” The persistent challenge toward meeting that goal, however, was that initiatives emerging from the New York-based programs, or indeed any program developed in one country, were not always adaptable, relevant or acceptable in other countries or regions. It remained a challenge to develop a unified program, despite the commitment at the highest level of foundation leadership. </p>
    </bioghist>
    <bioghist id="af88a3b5e3caffd70da621380d782e9c">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Segment 3. Period Summary - Transition and Restructuring 1966-1988</emph>
      </p>
      <p>During this era, the Foundation’s earlier interest in business and the economy evolved into a commitment to improving conditions for people living on the margins of society. The Ford Foundation promoted advancements in women's rights around the globe and introduced micro-lending into grantmaking. At the same time, the economic issues that were shaping program strategies also affected the Foundation's assets. Severe cuts resulted in a significant restructuring of country programs and reduced budgets across all programs. </p>
      <p>Even with the cuts in country offices, in the 1970s Ford grantees in developing countries received approximately 80% of the International Division budget. The remaining fifth went to Population, Development Studies, and International Affairs. Although representing a much smaller piece, the International Security and Arms Control program from 1973 was the Foundation’s most concerted effort to make meaningful inroads in disarmament and nuclear issues - those challenges most directly linked to the Foundation's historic concern for peace. By 1979, the Ford Foundation was the biggest funder of arms control as a field, both in the U.S. and overseas. </p>
    </bioghist>
    <dsc>
      <c id="ref14_zn1" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Program Management Files</unittitle>
          <unitid>I</unitid>
          <unitdate normal="1973/1976" type="inclusive">1973-1976</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="e47d64ad53e50fe65dc4a5c6fa96a54f">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series consists of files kept by Mr. Edwards about the work of his program officer, Lowell S. Hardin. Arranged chronologically, the files contain memoranda concerning Mr. Hardin's management of grants for agriculture and rural development in the Middle East and Africa. They also report on site visits, meetings with grantees and potential grantees and conferences Mr. Hardin attended.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="ref15_jid" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Hardin, Lowell S. -- Re: Phasing Out Advisory Support for Economic Planning in Africa, Update on World Food Situation, etc.</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">Sep-Nov 1973</unitdate>
            <container id="4564235839a1f920c56ef2e6a9e304b0" label="Documents (509439.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="864d37d22566025deec6353832cd2512" parent="4564235839a1f920c56ef2e6a9e304b0" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref16_5ji" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Hardin, Lowell S. -- Re: FF Agricultural Programs, Recruitment for International Development Work, etc.</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1973/1974" type="inclusive">Nov 1973-Apr 1974</unitdate>
            <container id="fb08dc049d0827eb6c9c417c3dc32d22" label="Documents (509439.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="49d396936fc7f523641153aa9f984dbd" parent="fb08dc049d0827eb6c9c417c3dc32d22" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref17_uup" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Hardin, Lowell S. -- Re: Encouraging Saudi Support for Agricultural Research, International Centers Week, etc.</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">Jun-Sep 1974</unitdate>
            <container id="ef9cf64e5f72c06b16f9469dd7eacdba" label="Documents (509439.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="f517457f8961df62b54b10ad711e521f" parent="ef9cf64e5f72c06b16f9469dd7eacdba" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref18_dpb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Hardin, Lowell S. -- Re: International Agricultural Research Centers, UN World Food Conference, etc.</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1974/1975" type="inclusive">Jun 1974-Jul 1975</unitdate>
            <container id="241af498b044eebb0d3f7139cb8f7e2f" label="Documents (509439.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="be62f4128feee500310c5e7c81780691" parent="241af498b044eebb0d3f7139cb8f7e2f" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref19_9xg" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Hardin, Lowell S. -- Re: Sudan Rural Development, Social Science Research and Competence Building in Africa, etc.</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1975/1976" type="inclusive">Sep 1975-Dec 1976</unitdate>
            <container id="6d11eb92c2fc62e67981d4d887a87460" label="Documents (509439.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="ca61dcc85f198724791cf81aefa50d92" parent="6d11eb92c2fc62e67981d4d887a87460" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="ref20_rzc" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Subject Files</unittitle>
          <unitid>II</unitid>
          <unitdate normal="1969/1977" type="inclusive">1969-1977</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="285653b346904de1b6b7210fc0bb373b">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The files in this series document Mr. Edwards work as Head of the Middle East and Africa Program. His subject files contain information on agricultural and social science research in Africa, inter-faith dialogues in the Middle East, and debates over a Soviet-sponsored declaration introduced at the 1976 UNESCO conference concerning the roles of the state and mass media operating within its borders. There are also files for the Seminar for OLAC/MEA Program Advisors in Agriculture held in Ibadan, Nigeria from February 9-10, 1973.</p>
          <p>A few subject files pertain to the Office of Latin America and the Caribbean (OLAC) and the Foundation's policy making generally. These include files on the Foundation's law and development work in Latin America and efforts to increase sensitivity in the formulation of policies governing Foundation-grantee relationships. The files are arranged alphabetically.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="ref21_9qz" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Area Studies -- Re: MEA Luncheons/Meetings to Review Area Studies and Social Science Research</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1969/1973" type="inclusive">1969-1973</unitdate>
            <container id="67b96949d4fcebbc811041c72dfabe4a" label="Documents (509445.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="29870cc16f9ce42cef5ca7d22d878024" parent="67b96949d4fcebbc811041c72dfabe4a" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref22_qq5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies -- 1974 Program Activities, Summary Report</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1974/1975" type="inclusive">1974-1975</unitdate>
            <container id="5f967cf2f0b7975991fa41f65dfedea7" label="Documents (509445.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="a6f08e93d03bf2efffe98cd6b7478547" parent="5f967cf2f0b7975991fa41f65dfedea7" type="folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref23_g34" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies -- Re: Consultation and Comments on Future of the Peace Corps Study</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1976/1977" type="inclusive">1976-1977</unitdate>
            <container id="40080c20df4c70fc77ced497da88562d" label="Documents (509445.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="9ba9e9fc92da8b46dcfd0f7a55939b13" parent="40080c20df4c70fc77ced497da88562d" type="folder">8</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref24_pb1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bundy, George -- "Towards An Open Foreign Policy" and "Private Institutions in the Public Service" (speeches)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">Oct-Nov 1973</unitdate>
            <container id="d5af8732e150106d41629d2fbc52fe97" label="Documents (509445.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="13c1df89aa5664553561ea89de881691" parent="d5af8732e150106d41629d2fbc52fe97" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref25_0ff" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>FF Seminar for OLAC/MEA Program Advisors in Agriculture -- Agenda, Logistics, Overview of FF Agricultural Programs, Background Articles</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1974/1975" type="inclusive">Feb 1974-May 1975</unitdate>
            <container id="93406efa2fe82c74b74c083f9475056d" label="Documents (509445.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="cb5ee98be642a22982fbd04632ecb18b" parent="93406efa2fe82c74b74c083f9475056d" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref26_1tq" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>FF Seminar for OLAC/MEA Program Advisors in Agriculture -- Discussion and Background Papers (1 of 5)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">1974</unitdate>
            <container id="13986638010d287edafb55b2aad5ba9a" label="Documents (509445.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="cf190e7e3cf13876ed87a305d13c5f88" parent="13986638010d287edafb55b2aad5ba9a" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref27_zcr" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>FF Seminar for OLAC/MEA Program Advisors in Agriculture -- Discussion and Background Papers (2 of 5)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">1974</unitdate>
            <container id="d6fd9980caf3ade112547bb30ec92d29" label="Documents (509445.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="7f8ae3493c69170a487c28fb4f263bbf" parent="d6fd9980caf3ade112547bb30ec92d29" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref28_wko" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>FF Seminar for OLAC/MEA Program Advisors in Agriculture -- Discussion and Background Papers (3 of 5)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">1974</unitdate>
            <container id="db50bc9c5dde64434f162b1b758cee24" label="Documents (509445.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="cfce0cc680ce721476d950522c209b91" parent="db50bc9c5dde64434f162b1b758cee24" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref29_tu9" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>FF Seminar for OLAC/MEA Program Advisors in Agriculture -- Discussion and Background Papers (4 of 5)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">1974</unitdate>
            <container id="fa8578d0888fe8890702d51348b0994c" label="Documents (509445.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="9ac94c1c4eb78f793b0aa974ca425f84" parent="fa8578d0888fe8890702d51348b0994c" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref30_qj0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>FF Seminar for OLAC/MEA Program Advisors in Agriculture -- Discussion and Background Papers (5 of 5)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">1974</unitdate>
            <container id="a08f9d8b8ebe2ca736f67c3d9311b1f3" label="Documents (509445.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="e3b4d5a33397d4dbcbfef05c31db083c" parent="a08f9d8b8ebe2ca736f67c3d9311b1f3" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref31_aby" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>FF Seminar for OLAC/MEA Program Advisors in Agriculture -- Handwritten Notes</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">Apr 29-May 3, 1974</unitdate>
            <container id="09079774a4bed86ae9aacba3bcf2888f" label="Documents (509445.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="0239914a71ee63f004dc7e6e46babd17" parent="09079774a4bed86ae9aacba3bcf2888f" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref32_68p" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Foundation-Grantee Relations -- Staff Memoranda and Papers for Discussion on Policy Formulation</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1970/1973" type="inclusive">1970-1973</unitdate>
            <container id="8678ac49de46a3dee73b62cfde7fc2b3" label="Documents (509445.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="4c9ae9d1e73f89323f4930a39e0e81bb" parent="8678ac49de46a3dee73b62cfde7fc2b3" type="folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref33_852" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Foundations -- "Private Foundations: In Search of a Purpose" (speech by Sen. Vance Hartke)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">Feb 8, 1974</unitdate>
            <container id="b7a8b54bd76011f3d3759225eb0aef9b" label="Documents (509445.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="6f8468fa3249105f04a18feb3b8ad7e1" parent="b7a8b54bd76011f3d3759225eb0aef9b" type="folder">8</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref34_kdp" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Germain, Adrienne -- Re: African Training and Research Center for Women (UN ECA), Final Report for Consultancy on Women in Bangladesh, etc.</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1975/1976" type="inclusive">Dec 1975-Jan 1976</unitdate>
            <container id="d80a252c68ef8dd73065a5523f981a8f" label="Documents (509445.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="c66a5fb1d602854fcc3e7db40bf71159" parent="d80a252c68ef8dd73065a5523f981a8f" type="folder">9</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref35_9tx" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Gremillion, Joseph -- Re: Inter-Religious Colloquium in Bellagio, Italy, Tri-Faith Dialogue Panel in Egypt</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1975/1976" type="inclusive">Jul 1975-Jan 1976</unitdate>
            <container id="fe13f17a42b4efa4f1e6a1752977a2c5" label="Documents (509445.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="250d9678b0434bcf06e5170d26f5d16d" parent="fe13f17a42b4efa4f1e6a1752977a2c5" type="folder">10</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref36_42x" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>International Agricultural Centers -- Report on Discussions of 1975 Programs and Budgets</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">Jun 1974</unitdate>
            <container id="5bdd2f2ecd05c78bf3ce02ff794563b6" label="Documents (509445.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aa7a5b22b7a7799092ac12f4e52a8bca" parent="5bdd2f2ecd05c78bf3ce02ff794563b6" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref37_loi" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>International Legal Center -- Research Advisory Committee on Law and Development -- Draft Report on Next Phase of Activities, Grant Action Report</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">Apr 1973</unitdate>
            <container id="93ffeb1f56e67145b85139e8869b9f11" label="Documents (509445.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="6a853620c36aff44795a9a4d58601e6b" parent="93ffeb1f56e67145b85139e8869b9f11" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref38_5cf" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>International Legal Center -- Research Advisory Committee on Law and Development Meeting, Feb 9-10, 1973 (1 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1972/1974" type="inclusive">Dec 1972-Jan 1974</unitdate>
            <container id="062715b1e3d3dd625c3cf83910ca30ef" label="Documents (509445.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="004c03883a22fdcdc7067b10a8977e42" parent="062715b1e3d3dd625c3cf83910ca30ef" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref39_bx2" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>International Legal Center -- Research Advisory Committee on Law and Development Meeting, Feb 9-10, 1973 (2 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">1973</unitdate>
            <container id="e29d9f44ffe65f3ec1a0698be2a9d50f" label="Documents (509445.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="2424251e645d22d1c7ca734e265b8e9d" parent="e29d9f44ffe65f3ec1a0698be2a9d50f" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref40_cdq" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Law and Development -- Re: Law and Social Change in Latin America, OLAC In-House Foundation Meetings, etc.</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1972/1973" type="inclusive">1972-1973</unitdate>
            <container id="5828185877485a56d05a28467066780e" label="Documents (509445.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="5326ae8cf883b5c19a4cb6363f54a6ad" parent="5828185877485a56d05a28467066780e" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref41_up1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Press in Africa -- Re: Nigerian Institute of Journalism and FF Support for Training of Journalists, Controversy Over Soviet-Sponsored UNESCO Declaration Re: Mass Media and the State</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1976/1976" type="inclusive">1976</unitdate>
            <container id="c177bee358ee070016b978387e9c72dd" label="Documents (509445.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="97a13aead650b7fcc27c8a0999f65e6d" parent="c177bee358ee070016b978387e9c72dd" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref42_kyk" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Television -- Re: Placing FF Staff on Local Interview Shows, Proposal for Research into Impact of Television in South Africa</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1973/1974" type="inclusive">1973-1974</unitdate>
            <container id="62b776b6ce36a47007790fdc189ee66d" label="Documents (509445.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="c2ab9a5cf2e24ea141b785ed8f4f627f" parent="62b776b6ce36a47007790fdc189ee66d" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref43_xpl" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Wells, Oris V. -- Re: Discussion on Improving World Food Situation Report -- Memoranda, Notes, Draft Report</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1973/1974" type="inclusive">1973-1974</unitdate>
            <container id="abdafa26a9eb322d0465b7acce726a41" label="Documents (509445.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="e590dec12164f0c3573529176489a522" parent="abdafa26a9eb322d0465b7acce726a41" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="ref44_bme" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Chronological Files</unittitle>
          <unitid>III</unitid>
          <unitdate normal="1968/1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="52820416247d396419b125cdf31d0d96">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series consists of Mr. Edward's chronological files of correspondence and memoranda date from April to October of 1968. The files contain information about meetings with grantees or potential grantees, correspondence with grantees, grant recommendations, and some budget information.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="ref45_y9w" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chronological File April 1968</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1968/1968" type="inclusive">Apr 1968</unitdate>
            <container id="c01c84adfaa78e2ce5dec6d6344d25e2" label="Documents (509469.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="5ffac4b4d16c6f724597d05c3ffb1fea" parent="c01c84adfaa78e2ce5dec6d6344d25e2" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref46_wou" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chronological File May 1968</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1968/1968" type="inclusive">May 1968</unitdate>
            <container id="0c56b9fb67b29803e5cc9e3b045239e8" label="Documents (509469.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="f928a02a9d629c6274766d872877a515" parent="0c56b9fb67b29803e5cc9e3b045239e8" type="folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref47_b6p" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chronological File June 1968</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1968/1968" type="inclusive">Jun 1968</unitdate>
            <container id="c7985e71c5f2fe809056a0c4f9c51ad7" label="Documents (509469.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="72694036953f2a79a1261a80a123527e" parent="c7985e71c5f2fe809056a0c4f9c51ad7" type="folder">8</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref48_vr5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chronological File July 1968</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1968/1968" type="inclusive">Jul 1968</unitdate>
            <container id="0509c554a94e81b17ff1cc111d1f4b69" label="Documents (509469.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="04905704fd937920abbad0d2be3b108a" parent="0509c554a94e81b17ff1cc111d1f4b69" type="folder">9</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref49_dsx" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chronological File August 1968</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1968/1968" type="inclusive">Aug 1968</unitdate>
            <container id="6171f008883731134f147eca09153fb3" label="Documents (509469.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="359fc7ff91d770581e56b64f4fcf65a0" parent="6171f008883731134f147eca09153fb3" type="folder">10</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref50_4z3" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chronological File September 1968</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1968/1968" type="inclusive">Sep 1968</unitdate>
            <container id="ba72db7bd96f69f53d29b6f613cc5771" label="Documents (509469.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="e6b6ea11ac12f5bf6d28a20c895767d8" parent="ba72db7bd96f69f53d29b6f613cc5771" type="folder">11</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref51_133" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chronological File October 1968</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1968/1968" type="inclusive">Oct 1968</unitdate>
            <container id="3bf59789deae1bf881b67c14acc39a6f" label="Documents (509469.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="d588c18b4248feda9b365bb08afe82b2" parent="3bf59789deae1bf881b67c14acc39a6f" type="folder">12</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
