<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA1452.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Ford Foundation records, Human Rights and Governance Program (HRG), Office Files of Stephen P. Marks</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Human Rights and Governance Program (HRG), Office Files of Stephen P. Marks <num>FA1452</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-08-09 00:02:50 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Ford Foundation records, Human Rights and Governance Program (HRG), Office Files of Stephen P. Marks</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname role="aut" rules="dacs" source="nad">Ford Foundation</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA1452</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.52 Cubic Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">4 LTR size Hollinger boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1983/1988" type="inclusive">1983-1988</unitdate>
    <langmaterial id="e2a88a5253cbdc4723edd8873de3e9ca">Materials predominately in English, but there are many files throughout the collection that have one or a few documents in another language such as French or Spanish. Materials in any language other than English is noted at the file level.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <acqinfo id="7c847bb165b0922362260416d7df500e">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files, and officers' papers were transferred to, and accessioned by the RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.</p><p>
The first set of Stephen P. Marks Office Files was transferred to the RAC in 2018 by the Ford Foundation and was ingested by the RAC as Accession 2018:034. A later set of material was transferred to the RAC in 2019 and ingested as Accession 2019:054.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo id="b2e7fe09bbb99e59bc28e75cc63f2567">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processing Level 3: Standard Processing</p><p>
Accession 2018:034 processed by Darren Young, September 2018</p><p>
Accession 2019:054 processed by Darren Young, June 2019</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="253f894ba64e1ba9a2232e5ff5d547cc">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Collection holds the office files of Ford Foundation Program Officer Stephen P. Marks. The files were created during Marks' time in the Human Rights and Governance Program (HRG) at Ford where he was responsible for grant-making decisions related to international human rights.</p><p>
The collection consists of only two series. The first series contains the chronological files Marks maintained to organize his correspondence and other documents, and the second series contains Marks' subject files.
Common types of material found within the collection include correspondence, memoranda, drafts, notes, reports, newspaper clippings, schedules, agendas, and speech transcripts.</p><p>
The collection is comprised of more than one accession of material. The chronological files in Series 1 originated from the first set of material that was transferred to the Rockefeller Archive Center in 2018 (Accession 2018:034). A later set of material was transferred to the RAC in 2019 (Accession 2019:054). The subject files in Series 2 originate from this accession.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <otherfindaid id="543fa734e9f0c443c36b3e34c48a54ef">
    <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
<p>Finding aids concerning the office files of other Ford Foundation officers in the Human Rights and Governance Program (HRG) include:</p><p>
<extref href="../FA717/overview">FA717 Ford Foundation records, Human Rights and Governance Program, Program Director, Office Files of Shepard Forman</extref></p><p>
<extref href="../FA1443/overview">FA1443 Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice, Human Rights and Governance, Office Files of Sara Rios</extref></p>  </otherfindaid>
  <accessrestrict id="61ba1fc01d030f9fdc19eb8444d6c939">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="7cfa8596157a3894dd6e8f5bbb51b4b8">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>RAC users must abide by all applicable provisions of United States copyright law. Reproduction/duplication of archival items is routinely provided in accordance with "fair use". If the RAC does not hold copyright for an archival collection, or items within a collection, it is the users responsibility to contact the copyright holder, or make a fair effort to do so, prior to publication.</p>  </userestrict>
  <bioghist id="f735f11a2fa3486c6760726a6f7ed1c0">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The Ford Foundation was chartered by Henry and Edsel Ford in 1936 "to receive and administer funds for scientific, educational and charitable purposes, all for the public welfare", and initially served the Ford family's charitable interests in the Detroit area. Following the deaths of Edsel Ford (1943) and Henry Ford (1947), the Foundation was propelled to the forefront of philanthropy as the largest American foundation in terms of both endowment and yearly expenditures, and with an international scope to its major program areas. </p><p>
During the Foundation's first twenty years its major programs were in international economic development, primary and higher education, educational and public broadcasting, behavioral sciences, civil liberties, urban development, fine arts and the humanities. The Ford Foundation also partnered with the Rockefeller Foundation in supporting agricultural development in South America, Africa, and Southeast Asia. Since the 1970s, the Foundation has also pioneered programs in women's rights, energy policy, micro-financing in under-developed countries, establishing human rights groups, and improving international HIV/AIDS education. </p>  </bioghist>
  <bioghist id="482f831f7af0a97e6da4ef6ba2c8736c">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Stephen P. Marks worked as a Program Officer in the Ford Foundation's Human Rights and Governance Program (HRG) between 1984 and 1989. He was responsible for grant-making decisions in the area of international human rights.</p><p>
Marks received his BA from Stanford University in 1964 and a Masters degree from the Institute of Advanced International Studies of the University of Law, Economics, and Social Sciences of Paris in 1971. Prior to joining the Ford Foundation, he worked at the International Institute of Human Rights from between 1969 and 1973 and the United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) from between 1973 and 1984. After he left Ford in 1989, he continued to pursue a career in international human rights philanthropy and research with positions at the United Nations, Princeton University, and Columbia University among other institutions, and then in 2000, he became the Director of the Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health Program on Human Rights in Development </p>  </bioghist>
  <prefercite id="1411c55d5511c6b0a7097aaec02c77d2">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>  </prefercite>
  <arrangement id="c578d7697d11e6c871229b80cca93786">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection consists of two series. The series are based on file type.</p><p>
Original order was maintained during processing.</p><p>
Collection arrangement is as follows:</p><p>
Series 1. Chronological files, 1987</p><p>
Series 2. Subject files, 1983-1988</p>  </arrangement>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Ford Foundation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Human rights</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Human rights -- Africa</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Human rights -- Middle East</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Human rights -- South America</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Human rights -- Asia</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="f48bf685e553d920143dc7c99de28963" level="series"><did><unittitle>Chronological files</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.38 Cubic Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">1 LTR size Hollinger box</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1987/1987">1987</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="ce457b2324d4b5ddbf69c4b275640ac0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Series contains the chronological files Stephen P. Marks maintained when he worked as a Program Officer in the Ford Foundation's Human Rights and Governance Program (HRG). It currently consists of only one file that was created in 1987, but it may expand if the RAC receives more accessions of Marks' Ford records.</p><p>
It is chiefly comprised of correspondence and internal Ford memos that Marks sent to human rights organizations and Ford staff members. However, it also contains some correspondence that was addressed to Marks by the aforementioned entities as well as other kinds of documents such as meeting agendas and project proposals. Marks frequently corresponded with Human Rights and Governance Program Director Shepard Forman as well as with organizations like the International League for Human Rights, the International Human Rights Law Group, and the Lawyers Committee for Human Rights. Correspondence discusses subjects like measures against torture, the rights of minorities, women and indigenous peoples, democracy, and international human rights law.</p><p>
Original order was maintained and files represent how Marks compiled the materials. Researchers will therefore see the majority of correspondence in reverse chronological order of creation date.</p></scopecontent><c id="6f136a328f4119e9db456a416ec7590f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chronological file</unittitle><unitdate normal="1987/1987">1987</unitdate><langmaterial id="c9a7b7c9fe88aa5a25831807b4d88432">Materials predominately in English. File also contains many letters in French and a few in Spanish.</langmaterial><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="f20f252a1337bcafda684880dbcfab78" label="mixed materials [A0000000017427]" type="box">1</container><container id="c524f303eee8ef7dcbb024c8d0067a6c" parent="f20f252a1337bcafda684880dbcfab78" type="folder">1-8</container></did></c></c><c id="9420bfc8da9e9e381f2784e3ab0a9526" level="series"><did><unittitle>Subject files</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.14 Cubic Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">3 LTR size Hollinger boxes</extent></physdesc><unitdate normal="1983/1988" type="inclusive">1983-1988</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="50809aa787b2f9a020f31261bad3ce81"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Series contains the subject files Stephen P. Marks maintained when he worked as a Program Officer in the Ford Foundation's Human Rights and Governance Program (HRG). Files document the Human Rights and Governance Program's collaboration with and grant support to human rights organizations and projects in Africa, the Middle East, Asia, and South America during the 1980s. These organizations and projects focused on issues such as the development of human rights law, protections, education, and resources in countries undergoing development, rights protections for different types of groups such as indigenous peoples and returning exiles, research on human rights issues in different countries, and the role of lawyers and judiciaries in the adoption and application of human rights law. Several of the files regard Marks' trips abroad to countries like Israel, Egypt, Chile, and Uruguay where he met with local and regional human rights organizations and institutions. Documents show that Marks worked with the Ford Foundation Field Offices in Cairo, Lima, and Nairobi to set up these trips as well as on other matters.</p></scopecontent><c id="c453325e66524794c6e6e8ad27e1f303" level="file"><did><unittitle>Africa</unittitle><unitdate normal="1983/1988" type="inclusive">1983-1988</unitdate><langmaterial id="e3bc2625e5817b04eb6bb4d7965ca5c4">Materials predominately in English. File also contains some documents in French.</langmaterial><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="4671626a64d10d44408b70fe397ad3cf" label="mixed materials [A0000000114125]" type="box">2</container><container id="06ca08323b07868a8b59760d9c9a79a1" parent="4671626a64d10d44408b70fe397ad3cf" type="folder">9-10</container></did></c><c id="0fe228d12b913c237a13899e1311ad16" level="file"><did><unittitle>Africa</unittitle><unitdate normal="1983/1984" type="inclusive">1983-1984</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="5d92d18d682f772120b18e02f49dc7b6" label="mixed materials [A0000000114125]" type="box">2</container><container id="5f9c6fcd1e563e7ea48f22e2f190b5e3" parent="5d92d18d682f772120b18e02f49dc7b6" type="folder">11</container></did></c><c id="05ab27c59b6e7aa630dbb324f06b31f8" level="file"><did><unittitle>African Jurists Association (AJA)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1987/1987">1987 December 21</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="b72f885a8ed585752d924cf94e5fa4ef" label="mixed materials [A0000000114125]" type="box">2</container><container id="fb95a3e7da52fdd2c2ff956710aaf91b" parent="b72f885a8ed585752d924cf94e5fa4ef" type="folder">12</container></did></c><c id="ef3a9516fa20c675ea48c4d3478878ff" level="file"><did><unittitle>African Seminar on Law and Human Rights in Development</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="f986d4da72119c1d9bac7079f5e4b548" label="mixed materials [A0000000114125]" type="box">2</container><container id="0d76b09a8136e6af6d9e2271fc8132bb" parent="f986d4da72119c1d9bac7079f5e4b548" type="folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="65cfc9d3c7db8bc6ccd130e48f49f4f4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>File only contains a cross-reference note.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="3820506797c9e7f1d22769183a63b651" level="file"><did><unittitle>Asia</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1986" type="inclusive">1984-1986</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="1170befacfd201cdea7df87b84a46d8c" label="mixed materials [A0000000114125]" type="box">2</container><container id="643625aeedc30caeb5f451fbda14d5d5" parent="1170befacfd201cdea7df87b84a46d8c" type="folder">14</container></did></c><c id="81af151e927dd8dc862a53139b03395e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bangalore, India - Judicial Colloquium on the Domestic Application of International Human Rights</unittitle><unitdate normal="1986/1988" type="inclusive">1986-1988</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="5eb6e744cf2db43d500f52fa41239a8b" label="mixed materials [A0000000114125]" type="box">2</container><container id="a309b9db00cc16295cff90833a1431f9" parent="5eb6e744cf2db43d500f52fa41239a8b" type="folder">15-16</container></did></c><c id="f1a734d7fc210e7241b6714ac9479adf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Barsalou, Judy - Cairo, Egypt Office</unittitle><unitdate normal="1988/1988">1988</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="c3300ef6dabbf53f697db687d56ef1c5" label="mixed materials [A0000000114125]" type="box">2</container><container id="54a987728a335a91fb08edb87e462959" parent="c3300ef6dabbf53f697db687d56ef1c5" type="folder">17</container></did></c><c id="081ad50454cc21812a2fc534ae798436" level="file"><did><unittitle>Barsalou, Judy</unittitle><unitdate normal="1986/1987" type="inclusive">1986-1987</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="722f54569de5fdf666931a4895019c9f" label="mixed materials [A0000000114125]" type="box">2</container><container id="f710626c98b9a92939ad5d5e8a2592e5" parent="722f54569de5fdf666931a4895019c9f" type="folder">18</container></did></c><c id="cfa7dda1796cc0868fca8ab786c9bba4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Environmental Policy Institute (EPI)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1983/1984" type="inclusive">1983-1984</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="6b47a7393ab4c6722c40b84ae63fef86" label="mixed materials [A0000000114125]" type="box">2</container><container id="46fb6665f533bb5b15806c6e1a08f6d1" parent="6b47a7393ab4c6722c40b84ae63fef86" type="folder">19</container></did></c><c id="d7609d2800dc25bdb912a79900e949ba" level="file"><did><unittitle>Frankel, Marvin/Kirschner, Robert incident</unittitle><unitdate normal="1987/1988" type="inclusive">1987-1988</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="31fa26a1d2e62da03f8baf33fa59ff09" label="mixed materials [A0000000114126]" type="box">3</container><container id="63009486f25d61ad8172f449eb4edb72" parent="31fa26a1d2e62da03f8baf33fa59ff09" type="folder">20</container></did></c><c id="1eddae72fb1ab16527b5b63af27a820c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Geneva, Switzerland human rights liaison office</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="382f19cf31ae14eda96ccae9d6bf3255" label="mixed materials [A0000000114126]" type="box">3</container><container id="24347018b094a886977110e6bfa1234a" parent="382f19cf31ae14eda96ccae9d6bf3255" type="folder">21</container></did></c><c id="706ed4d94e0f3fad148cf4a04b84800a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hawk, David - Cambodia Documentation Commission (Khmer Rouge Genocide: Accountability and Response)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1982/1987" type="inclusive">1982-1987</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="c9c7e32a15a98c627c7004651cc24dd2" label="mixed materials [A0000000114126]" type="box">3</container><container id="26f9e175ad72a5bd2f4901997626fbc8" parent="c9c7e32a15a98c627c7004651cc24dd2" type="folder">22-23</container></did></c><c id="604e7e6908fc20d02c157320c70b4748" level="file"><did><unittitle>Harvard University Law School Human Rights Program (HRP)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1985/1987" type="inclusive">1985-1987</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="792a9c26a3cbfe2bba7b6b23092ee4e9" label="mixed materials [A0000000114126]" type="box">3</container><container id="49e8ce3936ff7df0c76de9ea8276a445" parent="792a9c26a3cbfe2bba7b6b23092ee4e9" type="folder">24</container></did></c><c id="7ed14a4538b6052355b96131b992a47f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Human Rights and Governance Program (HRG) Meeting, London, England</unittitle><unitdate normal="1986/1987" type="inclusive">1986-1987</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="b13cadcacfa5cd897e9189f00df7008a" label="mixed materials [A0000000114126]" type="box">3</container><container id="4dd0b062d2591968a61fc867d6b545b9" parent="b13cadcacfa5cd897e9189f00df7008a" type="folder">25</container></did></c><c id="2363f660b39b199ae90ce522d063f219" level="file"><did><unittitle>Human Rights and Governance Program (HRG) Meeting, Lima, Peru</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1985" type="inclusive">1984-1985</unitdate><langmaterial id="c3758d048b7f474de9ed41732b222505">Materials predominately in English. File also includes a document in Spanish.</langmaterial><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="e630b5b1391ef67fe1d70460f508500e" label="mixed materials [A0000000114126]" type="box">3</container><container id="c12f29a1cf5914c6b6b1e90f9f887e8c" parent="e630b5b1391ef67fe1d70460f508500e" type="folder">26</container></did></c><c id="3bf40d5c6b0f2d4ee74d8eb736e736b5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Human rights - Sudan</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><langmaterial id="8ba25c0f6f1dd9208d3b4daecbb20a88">Materials predominately in English. File also contains a memo in Arabic with an English translation.</langmaterial><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="d94be775e4c079426917f3a421979a23" label="mixed materials [A0000000114126]" type="box">3</container><container id="26ecee7ad1611d027836ad898de6d7e5" parent="d94be775e4c079426917f3a421979a23" type="folder">27</container></did></c><c id="2928e14732aa7a392fc4f9221aa5a507" level="file"><did><unittitle>Indigenous peoples</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1987" type="inclusive">1984-1987</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="e49a35887dd099bab2264963a32c9274" label="mixed materials [A0000000114126]" type="box">3</container><container id="cc420534b6ed06dabec6ad8b0f36a27a" parent="e49a35887dd099bab2264963a32c9274" type="folder">28</container></did></c><c id="82bed0afe034a0dde9f82df13489bf71" level="file"><did><unittitle>Inter-African Union of Lawyers (IAUL)</unittitle><unitdate>undated</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="73f84a05865e5f326cdf24f3abad4ea5" label="mixed materials [A0000000114126]" type="box">3</container><container id="2d4ca2cfd0120fd1b23917401b4f591b" parent="73f84a05865e5f326cdf24f3abad4ea5" type="folder">29</container></did></c><c id="859c9da2c7ee98fa0e85afa3426130be" level="file"><did><unittitle>Inter-American foundation (IAF)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1985/1986" type="inclusive">1985-1986</unitdate><langmaterial id="08a1f220ff9e35e332cca664d5266e8f">Materials predominately in English. File also contains some documents in Spanish.</langmaterial><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="debccb32c955aa2b9d04716e62e33de1" label="mixed materials [A0000000114126]" type="box">3</container><container id="48178244ea253f462437943cf2eb62e5" parent="debccb32c955aa2b9d04716e62e33de1" type="folder">30</container></did></c><c id="23880f66496549f586e8b4dcf1385915" level="file"><did><unittitle>University of Koln - Etienne R. Mbaya</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1986" type="inclusive">1984-1986</unitdate><langmaterial id="fe0acfb88b4595255b45ade4d44fff11">Materials predominately in English. File also contains a letter in French.</langmaterial><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="91faa617fc6c50c40268399bf532deb6" label="mixed materials [A0000000114126]" type="box">3</container><container id="782dc5b84192c76bc0db7787ed31a202" parent="91faa617fc6c50c40268399bf532deb6" type="folder">31</container></did></c><c id="8ed56f71811f2be37df2fd4400638eba" level="file"><did><unittitle>Law in the Service of Man/al-Haq (LSM) Conference on the Administration of Occupied Territories</unittitle><unitdate normal="1987/1988" type="inclusive">1987-1988</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="1f216e379da626b6df095684d6094bba" label="mixed materials [A0000000114126]" type="box">3</container><container id="06de2194e0dfd0aeb4bc984c47024e3b" parent="1f216e379da626b6df095684d6094bba" type="folder">32</container></did></c><c id="f3f0f846409bab29b5346abfaa91974d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Livezey, Lowell - Non-Governmental Organizations and the Ideas of Human Rights</unittitle><unitdate normal="1985/1985">1985 November</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="759ccc7f39dd19bac73d87c464256940" label="mixed materials [A0000000114127]" type="box">4</container><container id="dfb6407770f03de9c6a484d4dc2f3bfa" parent="759ccc7f39dd19bac73d87c464256940" type="folder">33</container></did><scopecontent id="80bad0b1c6724ee66e3009ba459d4e63"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>File only contains the title page for this report.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="11a0ed9502698e998bec151a57bb259d" level="file"><did><unittitle>MacGregor, Felipe projects</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1985" type="inclusive">1984-1985</unitdate><langmaterial id="2242fa11add739c77de7f96193010cea">Materials predominately in Spanish. File also contains some materials in English.</langmaterial><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="b4e41505368925467d2f93edaf7d1aaf" label="mixed materials [A0000000114127]" type="box">4</container><container id="e1cc61ba70a42746a2ca5e7bc540e808" parent="b4e41505368925467d2f93edaf7d1aaf" type="folder">34</container></did></c><c id="9e7637bd1649dd2b1065caee88047a51" level="file"><did><unittitle>Middle East trip file</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1986" type="inclusive">1984-1986</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="294f9558808a36ef471007e7b04f21b2" label="mixed materials [A0000000114127]" type="box">4</container><container id="c1509b613e2dc04d3b54991d435e43b3" parent="294f9558808a36ef471007e7b04f21b2" type="folder">35</container></did></c><c id="b25447e48d63f8ab0792b6572b90fc31" level="file"><did><unittitle>Middle East</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1988" type="inclusive">1984-1988</unitdate><langmaterial id="cc2395977d730ec530826f2e2e4cd6bb">Materials predominately in English. File also contains a letter in French.</langmaterial><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="6decbb4c8d9687a5debfb93b407da9c1" label="mixed materials [A0000000114127]" type="box">4</container><container id="55953069fdffacade15a27d5e17aa616" parent="6decbb4c8d9687a5debfb93b407da9c1" type="folder">36-37</container></did></c><c id="5832f34366ca03217dc9154e5a3ec950" level="file"><did><unittitle>Morris, Diana - Nairobi, Kenya Office</unittitle><unitdate normal="1987/1987">1987</unitdate><langmaterial id="133632b17d0276276eea4a9b36decb1b">Materials predominately in English. File also contains a document in French.</langmaterial><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="d8d42da06cd7649a4c47d57f6c6c8de2" label="mixed materials [A0000000114127]" type="box">4</container><container id="c420dae17bc8e9c1f25e1bd5f2a76a2a" parent="d8d42da06cd7649a4c47d57f6c6c8de2" type="folder">38</container></did></c><c id="65a482ac82646c166d32e2834b1897e4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Southern Cone trip file - Notes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><langmaterial id="9cf26c02000bd18a3dc250e53519e952">Materials predominately in English. File also contains some documents in Spanish.</langmaterial><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="66571c2004ddede7b95015ecda3bf564" label="mixed materials [A0000000114127]" type="box">4</container><container id="3c2586c3d0d35f3fc0d750e5055c6273" parent="66571c2004ddede7b95015ecda3bf564" type="folder">39</container></did></c><c id="d492d273fa5cf9752358d92b2a1e1b11" level="file"><did><unittitle>Southern Cone trip file</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="f801d16a8dc08d7d9104a64dba2039f9" label="mixed materials [A0000000114127]" type="box">4</container><container id="4d2e907f3578a2202c6e5b9d17bded4f" parent="f801d16a8dc08d7d9104a64dba2039f9" type="folder">40</container></did></c><c id="3f386d66201dbb5fb6cd317177218f04" level="file"><did><unittitle>Southern Cone trip file</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="7d3b556be4bdb52a493d471890d981a6" label="mixed materials [A0000000114127]" type="box">4</container><container id="a2a5d0c6dfc12b9b00e53ffddff756c6" parent="7d3b556be4bdb52a493d471890d981a6" type="folder">41</container></did></c><c id="60dfcfb731953b387ee977f10e00d5e8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Southern Cone trip file</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><langmaterial id="71e92d767fd2f2e66dd22cc69da23d8a">Materials predominately in Spanish. File also contains some documents in English.</langmaterial><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="37e63c2abac9a38c5234abc42c98bc84" label="mixed materials [A0000000114127]" type="box">4</container><container id="3d43128a38d6992c133a5b105279f1bc" parent="37e63c2abac9a38c5234abc42c98bc84" type="folder">42</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
