<?xml version="1.0"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xd="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/doc/xsl" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd" version="3.4"><identifier type="local">LI01202</identifier><titleInfo><title>Improvement programme for metropolitan Calcutta:
1964-1971.
Vol. 1: A Note on Comprehensiveness Plainning.
Vol. 2a: A Note on Master Plan for Water Supply, Sewerage and Drainage.
Vol. 2b: A Note on the Master Plan for Water Supply, Sewerage and Drainage 
Vol. 3a: A Note on the Interim Water Supply Project
Vol. 3b: A Note on the Interim Water Supply Project
Vol.  4.  A Note on a Multiple and Concerted Attack to eliminate endemic cholera
Vol.  5. A Note on massive bustee improvement programm for Calcutta and Howrah
Vol. 6b A Note on a demonstration of a new technique in housing construction and management
Vol. 6A.  A Note on the subsidised housing needs generated by the improvement programm
Vol. 7:  A note on concentrated improvement programm for Hawrah and Tollyguange.
Vol. 8: A Note on the design for an urban redevelopment programm for the Calcutta Metropolitan City
Vol. 9:: A Note on the Suburban development in Sonapur, Kona and Salt Lake and its relation to the planned growth.
Vol. 10:  A Note on the Modernization of traffic operations in Calcutta.
Vol. 11: A Note on the Interim major street and highway plan for Calcutta.
Vol. 12a:  A Note on the Rapid Transit proposals for the principal passanger traffic corridors in Calcutta.
Vol. 12b:  A Note on Rapid Transit Proposals for the principal passengers traffif corridors in Calcutta.
Vol. 13:  A Note on the Proposed Calcutta-Howrah High-Level Bridges across Hooghly.
Vol. 14:  A Note on Modernization of refuse collection and disposal in Calcutta and Howrah
Vol. 15 A Note on Application of National Goals and Standrads for Education to the Calcutta Met Distirct.
Vol. 16: A Note on a proposed Service Centers fo rthe Calcutta Met District
Vol. 17: A Note on Urban Community Development as a Method of Government-Citizen Parternership for improving Living Conditions.
Vol. 18: A Note on Parks and Recreation needs o fthe Calcutta met Distruct and How they can be met.
Vol. 19: A Note on the Development of Haldia with respect to the Port of Calcutta and the Metropolitan Region.
vol. 20:: A Note on the Relationship of Farakka Barrage to the Planning of the Calcutta Met District
Vol. 21a: A Note on the Regional Planning in Eastern India and its relation to Urbanization in West Bengal.
Vol 21b:  A Note on Regional Planning in Eastern India and its Relation to Urbanization in West Bengal</title></titleInfo><name><namePart>West Bengal. Calcutta Metropolitan Planning Organisation</namePart><role><roleTerm type="text" authority="naf">aut</roleTerm></role></name><originInfo><place><placeTerm type="text">[Calcutta]</placeTerm></place><publisher>Calcutta Metropolitan Planning Organisation, 1964-1971</publisher><dateIssued>1964-1971</dateIssued></originInfo><physicalDescription><extent>21 Bound Volumes</extent></physicalDescription><relatedItem type="series"><titleInfo><title>v. 1. A note on comprehensive planning for the Calcutta metropolitan district and its relation to the improvement programme -- v. 3a. A note on the interim water supply project -- v. 3b. A note on the interim water supply project -- v. 4. A note on a multiple and concerted attack to eliminate endemic cholera -- v. 6a. A note on subsidised housing needs generated by the improvement programme -- v. 6b. A note on a demonstration of new techniques in housing construction and management -- v. 7. A note on concentrated improvement programmes for Howrah and Tollygunge -- v. 8. A note on the design for an urban redevelopment programme for the Calcutta metropolitan district -- v. 9. A note on suburban development in Sonarpur, Kona, and Salt Lake and its relation to the planned growth of the Calcutta metropolitan district -- v. 11. A note on the interim major street and highway plan for the Calcutta metropolitan district -- v. 12a. A note on rapid transit proposals for the principal passenger traffic corridors in Calcutta -- v. 12b. A note on rapid transit proposals for the principal passenger traffic corridors in Calcutta -- v. 13. A note on the proposed Calcutta-Howrah high-level bridge across the Hooghly -- v. 14. A note on modernisation of refuse collection and disposal in Calcutta and Howrah -- v. 15. A note on application of national goals and standards for education to the Calcutta metropolitan district -- v. 16. A note on a proposed network of community service centres for the Calcutta metropolitan district -- v. 17. A note on urban community development as a method of government-citizen partnership for improving living conditions in metropolitan Calcutta -- v. 18. A note on parks and recreation needs of Calcutta metropolitan district and how they can be met -- v. 19. A note on the development of Haldia with respect to the Calcutta metropolitan district -- v. 20. A note on the relationship of Farakka barrage to the planning of Calcutta metropolitan district -- v. 21. A note on regional planning in Eastern India and its relation to urbanization in West Bengal and metropolitan Calcutta.</title></titleInfo></relatedItem><note>"For official use only"./ Include bibliographies.</note><subject authority="lcsh"><geographic>India</geographic></subject><subject authority="lcsh"><topic>Regional planning</topic></subject><subject authority="lcsh"><topic>City planning</topic></subject><subject authority="lcsh"><geographic>Calcutta (India)</geographic></subject><relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Ford Foundation grant # 06100217</title></titleInfo></relatedItem><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 21b</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 7</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 21a</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 6B</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 6A</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 5</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 18</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 17</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 9</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 20</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 19</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 8</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 2</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 1 </classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 10</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 4</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 3B</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 3A</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 2A</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 13</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 14</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 15</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 16</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 11</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 12a</classification><genre>volume</genre><classification>307.154 WES VOLUME 12b</classification></mods>
