<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="under_revision" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>FA293.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper type="filing">Commonwealth Fund records, Institute for Child Guidance, SG 1, Series 21</titleproper>
        <titleproper>A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, Institute for Child Guidance, SG 1, Series 21
 <num>FA293</num></titleproper>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline>
          <addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline>
          <addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2016-08-23 00:44:28 -0400</date>.</creation>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="series">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Commonwealth Fund records, Institute for Child Guidance, SG 1, Series 21</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname source="lcnaf">Harkness, Mary Emma Stillman</persname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname source="lcnaf">Harkness, Edward Stephen</persname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname rules="dacs">Harkness, Charles W.</persname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname source="lcnaf">Harkness, Anna M. Richardson</persname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="aut" source="lcnaf">Commonwealth Fund</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>FA293</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.69 Cubic Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">2 boxes</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1926/1933" type="inclusive">1926-1933</unitdate>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_f3704a8d1577011f6d48d65048fc9548">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
      <p>Open for scholarly research, except where particular restrictions are noted.</p>
      <p>RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_e2cbd4e4ee31f6e40e775ac2923e0d2e">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
      <p>RAC users must abide by all applicable provisions of United States copyright law. Reproduction/duplication of archival items is routinely provided in accordance with "fair use." If the RAC does not hold copyright for an archival collection, or items within a collection, it is the user’s responsibility to contact the copyright holder, or make a fair effort to do so, prior to publication.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <bioghist id="aspace_81913bb5fa751de9a41a3a838782ecba">
      <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
      <p>The Commonwealth Fund was established in 1918 with an endowment of $10 million from Mrs. Stephen V. Harkness for "benevolent, religious, educational and like purposes." The early grants supported a variety of programs while generally promoting welfare, especially child welfare. Several grants were made in the field of medical research, but the Board of Directors decided in 1920 that this field was already sufficiently supported by other philanthropic organizations.</p>
      <p>Despite this decision, by the mid-1920s the chief interest of the Fund had become public health, including mental hygiene, community health, rural hospitals, medical research, and medical education. Other grant areas included war relief, educational and legal research, child welfare, and international medical fellowships.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <fileplan id="aspace_26b1dc4111c57b46d6c03e1321ae6cd4">
      <head>File Plan note</head>
      <p>Former Classification: IX; IV 4B 4;</p>
    </fileplan>
    <phystech id="aspace_ca17ef542f15fd90e08e571405ae0b18">
      <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
      <p>Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment</p>
      <p>Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.</p>
    </phystech>
    <prefercite id="aspace_a4e46d8cd36d66592691a2bdb04b7352">
      <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
      <p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>
    </prefercite>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_645528ba45707615a5d10e74093e3681">
      <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
      <p>The Commonwealth Fund's association with the Institute for Child Guidance stems from a revision in the Fund's Program for the Prevention of Delinquency. The Delinquency Program was drafted during the summer and early fall of 1921, with the CF Board adopting the program in November of that year. Actual wok was not begun until the spring of 1922. The forerunner of the Institute for Child Guidance, The Bureau of Children's Guidance officially opened on February 1, 1922, but was not fully active until autumn of that year.</p>
      <p>The five year period of the Delinquency Program expired in the spring of 1927. Already in early 1926, a revised program had been proposed. The Bureau of Children's Guidance closed June 30, 1927, and The Institute for Child Guidance opened in New York City on July 1, 1927. This new Institute, incorporated December 29, 1926, was affiliated with the New York School of Social Work and the Smith College School for Social Work in regards to the training of psychiatric social workers; and with the National Committee for Mental Hygiene in conjunction with the training of psychiatrists and graduate psychologists in practical child guidance work.</p>
      <p>Both the administration and budget of the Institute were controlled by the Board of Directors of the Commonwealth Fund. The nine member Administrative Board of the Institute was appointed by the CF Board of Directors, which retained the right to terminate any appointment at its discretion. Barry C. Smith, Director of the CF, was named Chairman; Porter R. Lee, Director of the New York School for Social Work became treasurer. Other board members included Everett Kimball, Director of Smith College School for Social Work, Frankwood E. Williams, Medical Director of the National Committee for Mental Hygiene, Mildred C. Scoville, Executive Assistant of the CF, and Barbara S. Quin, also of the Commonwealth Fund.</p>
      <p>Lawson G. Lowrey served as Director of the Institute, with David M. Levy as chief of staff, and Christine C. Robb as chief of social services. The initial yearly budget was approximately $160,000. Although the Institute officially closed its doors on June 30, 1933, the Bank of United States, which underwent liquidation at the same time, owed the organization over $20,000. Consequently, the Institute's certificate of incorporation was kept active. The bank's account with the Institute was fully settled in 1944, but the charter was not dissolved until 1951, when the Secretary of State of New York did so.</p>
      <p>The majority of the Institute's surviving records consist of financial statements, audits and correspondence relating to fiscal or budget matters. The minutes of the Institute detail the activities of the Board of Directors, the incorporators, the annual corporation meetings, and the committee dividing the assets of the Institute. In late 1937 the Commonwealth Fund decided that all case files pertaining to the treatment of children at the Institute should be destroyed. Therefore, in February of 1938 these records, as well as the index to these cases, were burned. Other folders in this series contain sensitive material.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <otherfindaid id="aspace_d1e043f02db307fb3df17bd7303a65b1">
      <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
      <p>Other available finding aids describing the Commonwealth Fund records include:</p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA247/overview">FA247 Commonwealth Fund Harkness House drawings</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA276/overview">FA276 Commonwealth Fund records, Annual Reports, SG 1, Series 4</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA277/overview">FA277 Commonwealth Fund records, Archives/Library, SG 1, Series 5</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA278/overview">FA278 Commonwealth Fund records, Austrian Program, SG 1, Series 6</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA279/overview">FA279 Commonwealth Fund records, Board of Directors, SG 1, Series 7</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA280/overview">FA280 Commonwealth Fund records, Capital Grants, SG 1, Series 8</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA281/overview">FA281 Commonwealth Fund records, Child Health Demonstrations, SG 1, Series 9</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA282/overview">FA282 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Community Clinics, SG 1, Series 10</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA283/overview">FA283 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Health Studies, SG 1, Series 11</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA284/overview">FA284 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Public Health, SG 1, Series 12</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA285/overview">FA285 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Publications, SG 1, Series 13</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA286/overview">FA286 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Rural Hospitals, SG 1, Series 14</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA287/overview">FA287 Commonwealth Fund records, Educational Research, SG 1, Series 15</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA288/overview">FA288 Commonwealth Fund records, English Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 16</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA289/overview">FA289 Commonwealth Fund records, Finance Committee, SG 1, Series 17</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA290/overview">FA290 Commonwealth Fund records, Grants, SG 1, Series 18</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA291/overview">FA291 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Family, SG 1, Series 19</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA292/overview">FA292 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, SG 1, Series 20</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA428/overview">FA428 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, Fellows Reports, SG 1, Series 20A</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA293/overview">FA293 Commonwealth Fund records, Institute for Child Guidance, SG 1, Series 21</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA294/overview">FA294 Commonwealth Fund records, Interface Program, SG 1, Series 22</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA295/overview">FA295 Commonwealth Fund records, Legal Research Program, SG 1, Series 23</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA296/overview">FA296 Commonwealth Fund records, Living at Home Program, SG 1, Series 24</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA297/overview">FA297 Commonwealth Fund records, Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 25</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA298/overview">FA298 Commonwealth Fund records, Miscellaneous - unprocessed</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA299/overview">FA299 Commonwealth Fund records, Personnel - unprocessed</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA300/overview">FA300 Commonwealth Fund records, Pilgrim Trust, SG 1, Series 28</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA301/overview">FA301 Commonwealth Fund records, Program for the Prevention of Delinquency, SG 1, Series 29</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA302/overview">FA302 Commonwealth Fund records, Reference Files, SG 1, Series 30</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA303/overview">FA303 Commonwealth Fund records, Reports of the General Director, SG 1, Series 31</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA304/overview">FA304 Commonwealth Fund records, Treasurer, SG 1, Series 32</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA305/overview">FA305 Commonwealth Fund records, Turndown Lists, SG 1, Series 33 - unprocessed</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA306/overview">FA306 Commonwealth Fund records, Vertical File (R. Fitz), SG 1, Series 34  - unprocessed</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA307/overview">FA307 Commonwealth Fund records, Visual Materials, SG 1, Series 35</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA389/overview">FA389 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Historical Files, SG 1, Series 1</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA390/overview">FA390 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Officers Files, SG 1, Series 2</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA429/overview">FA429 Commonwealth Fund records, President, Margaret E. Mahoney, SG 2, Series 1</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA430/overview">FA430 Commonwealth Fund records, Book Program, SG 2, Series 2</extref>
      </p>
    </otherfindaid>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Medicine -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Mental health</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Medical research</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Medicine, Rural</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Legal research</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Medical education</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Law</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Legal issues</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Education, Rural</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Hygiene</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Child psychology</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Child welfare</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Child mental health</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">War relief</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Public welfare</subject>
      <geogname source="lcsh">United States</geogname>
      <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State)</geogname>
      <subject source="lcsh">Public health</subject>
      <corpname source="lcnaf">Phillips Exeter Academy</corpname>
      <corpname source="lcnaf">Columbia University</corpname>
      <corpname source="lcnaf">Yale University</corpname>
      <corpname rules="dacs">Social Science Research Council</corpname>
      <corpname source="lcnaf">Harvard University</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref42_76j" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Case Files - Access Regulations and Destruction of Files</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1929/1937" type="inclusive">1929-1937</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_61b3ddddddbf7622240e419857f70318" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_891adf329b09ff953b7c89d89b59d2e7" parent="aspace_61b3ddddddbf7622240e419857f70318" type="folder">1</container>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="aspace_b276937744b261d2adc3d2269d61b111">
          <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
          <p>Restricted - Confidential material. Requires prior archival review.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref44_zek" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - Accounting Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1927/1929" type="inclusive">1927-1929</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_73a75ef7903b30321bf444c4daaef6ec" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_b7be2d49cd25234ce67af079ee4c5d4e" parent="aspace_73a75ef7903b30321bf444c4daaef6ec" type="folder">2</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref45_cnk" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - Accounting Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1930/1933" type="inclusive">1930-1933</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_b860bd310983954c34652ebaa6b29f72" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_1159ca8f1a952ec3b72c401e9a4f0937" parent="aspace_b860bd310983954c34652ebaa6b29f72" type="folder">3</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref46_t94" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - Accounts and Expenditures</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1927/1928" type="inclusive">1927-1928</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_9748ddae50fc17d2ca862ebd62fdde60" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_d9c9837ea2b0ebdfb882858a184838f8" parent="aspace_9748ddae50fc17d2ca862ebd62fdde60" type="folder">4</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref47_6c3" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - Accounts and Expenditures</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1929/1930" type="inclusive">1929-1930</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_2f784cce09c236d787a5896d5bfd6a35" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_1c7ae3eb8a59d71a1b172cb42e802fa9" parent="aspace_2f784cce09c236d787a5896d5bfd6a35" type="folder">5</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref48_hqa" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - Accounts and Expenditures</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1931/1931" type="inclusive">January-December, 1931</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_ca398e07d04a263b55cb75b48dce2470" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_f1aab1cc04674174630ba0a8135e867e" parent="aspace_ca398e07d04a263b55cb75b48dce2470" type="folder">6</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref49_az9" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - Accounts and Expenditures</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1932/1933" type="inclusive">1932-1933</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_e1be34cb3928e7d85afd80128220487e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_b4315f08997e7034657433d402534559" parent="aspace_e1be34cb3928e7d85afd80128220487e" type="folder">7</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref50_c19" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - Audits</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1927/1931" type="inclusive">1927-1931</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_d6b24dd40412f6397cc35ca2abff2630" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_14b5ea84f9a9f5310fce0998a71d1d70" parent="aspace_d6b24dd40412f6397cc35ca2abff2630" type="folder">8</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref51_lg8" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - Audits</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1932/1933" type="inclusive">1932-1933</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_3dc70c3bd148878e3941901a5cf0e458" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_f407e26940905f29733a93c92e8bfb77" parent="aspace_3dc70c3bd148878e3941901a5cf0e458" type="folder">9</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref52_5oh" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - Bank of United States - Liquidation</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1930/1951" type="inclusive">1930-1951</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_e57d84bb0225e4c3d664f97c3959214d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_16c1622389075c152be779d766b9172d" parent="aspace_e57d84bb0225e4c3d664f97c3959214d" type="folder">10</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref53_ezy" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - Budget/Budget Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1926/1930" type="inclusive">1926-1930</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_2a9b1acd20a2a3ddb2d41de30c379c56" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_4c98b3d83c3c70502347ae1e3f3dcfa3" parent="aspace_2a9b1acd20a2a3ddb2d41de30c379c56" type="folder">11</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref54_p32" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - Budget/Budget Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1931/1932" type="inclusive">1931-1932</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_524c6dc23f916a323b059facaf839257" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_42e676e2f7a13bd5aa51beb408f9f4e9" parent="aspace_524c6dc23f916a323b059facaf839257" type="folder">12</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref55_112" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - Fellowship Accounts</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1931/1933" type="inclusive">1931-1933</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_115b36e017c745a3ca8dc4661febdca2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_f911018e22144884489fa3e0ade85217" parent="aspace_115b36e017c745a3ca8dc4661febdca2" type="folder">13</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref56_r4k" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - Income Tax</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1933/1933" type="inclusive">1933</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_01fde37e809b0d53136583a6f0ace688" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_dd4fd27dfb8c2fcd21478f96d05820d3" parent="aspace_01fde37e809b0d53136583a6f0ace688" type="folder">14</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref57_561" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - New York Trust Company Account</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1933/1940" type="inclusive">1933-1940</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_f04f06a81650cd34651b858618f615ba" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_9d92dbc7c9a5c6de982381cbc92fbca1" parent="aspace_f04f06a81650cd34651b858618f615ba" type="folder">15</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref58_oyt" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - Personnel Bonuses</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1932/1933" type="inclusive">1932-1933</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_db36c01d1eee11b8515607eadd1eec48" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_48793b7f407a860d233472d6758cb087" parent="aspace_db36c01d1eee11b8515607eadd1eec48" type="folder">16</container>
        </did>
        <accessrestrict id="aspace_04eb2d4bdd58025b3a1f88208de3ea82">
          <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
          <p>Restricted - Confidential material.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref60_gpg" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - Treasurer's Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1926/1927" type="inclusive">1926-1927</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_125880c79c11c74a87088d468477f83c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_88684ebac95f93f18c6cd193c78dc00a" parent="aspace_125880c79c11c74a87088d468477f83c" type="folder">17</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref61_0y3" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - Treasurer's Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1928/1929" type="inclusive">1928-1929</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_fce7b56688dc1a1ae8a118933abb49b2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_7d9ea812c3ac6fc15733db16af2b519c" parent="aspace_fce7b56688dc1a1ae8a118933abb49b2" type="folder">18</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref62_36j" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - Treasurer's Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1930/1931" type="inclusive">1930-1931</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_e2711d671d5814f1c42574aaeff34e2b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_0b195e46629e7eff02029adf201bd441" parent="aspace_e2711d671d5814f1c42574aaeff34e2b" type="folder">19</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref63_055" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - Treasurer's Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1932/1933" type="inclusive">1932-1933</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_151eae9ecac9eeffbc6cc81dbcd51949" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_5db08a4a55c49dccaf4698feba4bf3cb" parent="aspace_151eae9ecac9eeffbc6cc81dbcd51949" type="folder">20</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref64_st7" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Financial Records - Treasurer's Reports</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1927/1933" type="inclusive">1927-1933</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_4e83a238ef79f6aa5df425ac64ba9de7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
          <container id="aspace_87e2e2f0766eeefa6b548e14a0fc9779" parent="aspace_4e83a238ef79f6aa5df425ac64ba9de7" type="folder">21</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref65_l4t" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Incorporation (By-laws, Certificate and Correspondence)</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1926/1932" type="inclusive">1926-1932</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_2be08f263f1e2dcfc4a42cc4b272521d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
          <container id="aspace_c67cc7edc3dfa33e03bb53ad8217cb7b" parent="aspace_2be08f263f1e2dcfc4a42cc4b272521d" type="folder">22</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref66_gka" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Incorporation (Dissolution)</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1933/1951" type="inclusive">1933-1951</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_4c44833b627d4cc2f3548fceeefaa703" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
          <container id="aspace_35e3bfe557d0fd9b77c1797b2fb1028c" parent="aspace_4c44833b627d4cc2f3548fceeefaa703" type="folder">23</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref67_o5v" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Minutes</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1927/1933" type="inclusive">1927-1933</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_2c74450fdba4b657a20a9e460ff6a37c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
          <container id="aspace_846f05dd6b4d49fc594c5b1479dee825" parent="aspace_2c74450fdba4b657a20a9e460ff6a37c" type="folder">24</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref68_sdr" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Property Inventories</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1927/1933" type="inclusive">1927-1933</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_a983e1ae0712d4bce010d29a3dc7e1ae" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
          <container id="aspace_b25d6f2533837ee75ea5c0b836033eac" parent="aspace_a983e1ae0712d4bce010d29a3dc7e1ae" type="folder">25</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref69_psc" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Property Inventories</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1927/1933" type="inclusive">1927-1933</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_7de2ebd12ce418422bae4d6e31708bd5" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
          <container id="aspace_222c8c5d43bcd8c227a94239110bb774" parent="aspace_7de2ebd12ce418422bae4d6e31708bd5" type="folder">26</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref70_ahc" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Property Inventories - Correspondence Concerning the Distribution of Assets</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1932/1933" type="inclusive">1932-1933</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_3640bc772574447778ed7b8230af12ee" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
          <container id="aspace_d90b9c0990f3d2bbb8dcad2681df7765" parent="aspace_3640bc772574447778ed7b8230af12ee" type="folder">27</container>
        </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
