<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xd="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/doc/xsl" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd" version="3.4">
  <identifier type="local">LI00949</identifier>
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Making nonprofits work :
a report on the tides of nonprofit management reform</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <originInfo>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="text">Washington, D.C.</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <publisher>Aspen Institute : Brookings Institution Press</publisher>
    <dateIssued>2000</dateIssued>
  </originInfo>
  <note>Includes bibliographical references (p. 101-107) and index.</note>
  <abstract>"In Making Nonprofits Work, Paul C. Light charts the current trends of management reform in the nonprofit sector and assess the climate for reform at the local and national levels. Light examines the four popular philosophies, or "tides," being advocated - scientific management, liberation management, war on waste, and watchful eye - offering examples and caveats from a portfolio of recent experience.". "Drawing on confidential interviews with leaders in nonprofit management reform, a detailed search of Internet sources, and a survey of state associations of nonprofit organizations, Light's findings suggest that the nonprofit sector has a remarkable opportunity to prevent the excesses and fadism that have dominated reform efforts in government and the private sector. He cautions leaders in the nonprofit sector to recognize the limits of various reform models, to set priorities carefully, and to limit investments of reform energy to a handful of priorities. Finally, he urges reformers to boost the sector's ability to implement new systems and reforms by focusing more closely on capacity building."--BOOK JACKET.</abstract>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Management</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Organizational effectiveness</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Nonprofit organizations</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcnaf">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Light, Paul Charles</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Ford Foundation Circulating collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Rockefeller Foundation records, Grants
Accession number: 2013:047
Box: R40272001 WC 024 (A013) R4027</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <identifier type="isbn">0815752458</identifier>
  <genre>volume</genre>
  <classification>658.048 LIG</classification>
  <genre>volume</genre>
  <classification>658.048 LIG</classification>
</mods>
