<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="under_revision" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>FA865.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper type="filing">Rockefeller University records, Corporation, Treasurer and Assistant Treasurer, Administrative Correspondence</titleproper>
        <titleproper>A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Corporation, Treasurer and Assistant Treasurer, Administrative Correspondence
 <num>FA865</num></titleproper>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline>
          <addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline>
          <addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-10-26 08:01:22 -0400</date>.</creation>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <date>2010 November 12</date>
      <item>Paper finding aid converted to EAD/XML by AureXus in 2010. Imported into the Archvists’ Toolkit by Becky Robbins.</item>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Rockefeller University records, Corporation, Treasurer and Assistant Treasurer, Administrative Correspondence</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="aut" source="lcnaf">Rockefeller University</corpname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="ctb" source="lcnaf">Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research</corpname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname source="lcnaf">Gates, Frederick Taylor</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>FA865</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.88 Cubic Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">2 boxes</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1910/1954" type="inclusive">1910-1954 April</unitdate>
      <physdesc id="aspace_21e3bd09df0877a7d91f746ef780e7c4">
        <extent>2 boxes.</extent>
      </physdesc>
    </did>
    <phystech id="aspace_f1edf2fd6a70ccd212538cedc582eacf">
      <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
      <p>Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment</p>
      <p>Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.</p>
    </phystech>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_a841451a4499a378cb55ab3ede5ac43b">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>Correspondence with Business Manager and Bursar. Includes statements of the income account of the Institute during coming fiscal year. Much of the correspondence in the early years deals with construction costs and results from the fact that the Institute's growth constantly outstripped bookkeeping methods. Includes requests and letters of transmittal of checks from Treasurer for Institute's current expenses. Later correspondence is mostly letters of transmittal and acknowledgement, including financial reports and budgets for the operation of the Treasurer's office. Includes also assessed valuations and tax exemptions for a number of years and some estimates of income. Some copies of minute from the Finance Committee.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_8fd784fc4a9afccc10c28e49e85ba06d">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>Chronological.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <bioghist id="aspace_b6b080cba4c2cdaca200180f04ead56a">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>By the By-Laws of the Corporation adopted in 1910, a Treasurer of the Corporation was to be elected by the Board of Trustees at the annual meeting. The Treasurer was designated as the officer to have custody of the permanent funds and securities of the Corporation, to pay bills incurred by resolution of the Board of Trustees under the authority of the Executive Committee, and to make payments to the Board of Scientific Directors upon authorized requisition from them. It was the duty of the Treasurer to keep proper books, to present at each meeting an exact accounting of receipts and disbursements and to present an annual report of the accounts of the year. Additions to the Rules of the Board of Trustees provided that the Treasurer act as secretary of. the Finance Committee and have custody, of its minutes and other papers and documents relating to the work of the committee.</p>
      <p>The first treasurer of the Corporation was Louis Guerineau Myers who served until 1932. Costs of the Treasurer's office were shared among several of the Rockefeller philanthropic enterprises such as the General Education Fund and the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Fund. The Board of Trustees was empowered to appoint an Assistant Treasurer and Lefferts Mason Dashiell was appointed in 1923. He became Acting Treasurer in 1932 upon the death of Louis G. Myers and was appointed Treasurer of the Corporation in 1939. Edward Robinson became Assistant Treasurer and Treasurer in 1939 with Benson Blake as Assistant Treasurer. In 1942 Edward Emerson became Assistant Treasurer and in 1954 he was succeeded by Robert Letort.</p>
      <p>In 1953 new By-Laws of the Corporation were adopted, and under the reorganization then instituted a complete study of the business and financial administration of the Institute was authorized. Over a period of several years thoroughgoing changes of positions and responsibilities were established.</p>
      <p>Between 1955-1959 Edward Robinson served as Treasurer and Robert Letort as Assistant Treasurer. Lindsley F. Kimball became Treasurer April 1959 (though elected to take office January 1, 1959) and William E. Dietz took office as Assistant Treasurer in March 1959. The office of William Dietz was enlarged to include the newly created office of Comptroller which included supervision of the office of the Bursar which in 1961 became the Bursar and Deputy Assistant Treasurer.</p>
      <p>In May 1965 when Lindsley F. Kimball retired, J. Richardson Dilworth, who as Trustee had been very active and influential on the Finance Committee became Treasurer. Until 1969, while new patterns were developing, William E. Dietz, as Assistant Treasurer and Controller supervised much of the financial management of the University. William E. Dietz retired December 1969.</p>
      <p>Finally a clear-cut division between the management of the University's business and the management of financial properties and investments was established. Joseph Richardson Dilworth served as Treasurer, Sydney Anglin Woodd-Cahusac as Associate Treasurer and Arthur Francis Hubbard as Deputy Assistant Treasurer. In May 1971 J. Richardson Dilworth, who continued as a trustee of the University and chairman of its Finance Committee was succeeded as Treasurer by Sydney A. Woodd-Cahusac and in 1972 Arthur F. Hubbard became Assistant Treasurer.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <prefercite id="aspace_f59023397e0d184eb73d70cac6f6106a">
      <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
      <p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>
    </prefercite>
    <fileplan id="aspace_47b9331abe055ebb04779b5a7f7dc82f">
      <head>File Plan note</head>
      <p>Former Classification: I 190</p>
    </fileplan>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_5ebfe0fd1f19ff3f2e9b95d5cbaaef1b">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
      <p>This collection is open for scholarly research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <controlaccess>
      <corpname role="aut" source="lcnaf">Rockefeller University</corpname>
      <corpname role="ctb" source="lcnaf">Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research</corpname>
      <persname source="lcnaf">Gates, Frederick Taylor</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref983_5tr" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1910/1935" type="inclusive">1910-1935</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_d3ce5809bf5d5d4b241f9595afc153c7" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref984_xzg" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Non-routine items include</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_bfa9436bba420eda743951cdd6bb83a4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
          <c id="aspace_ref645_myy" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Accountant's report of Dr. Carrel's credit account for temporary Hospital at Compiègne</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1917 February 7</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_04fa71fa740290060d505be094d5590d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref646_ubd" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Correspondence relating to Foundation grant for War Relief and Research</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1917/1917" type="inclusive">1917</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_c06be8fcfa003f31daf746eb055d10f2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref647_4jp" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Covering letter to E.B. Smith and copy of letter sent to John d. Rockefeller expressing appreciation for grant</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1920 July 24</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_e6c16cfdb7501587b572a27de397f657" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref648_wvl" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Correspondence dealing with coverage for insurance against fire risk</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1921 August</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_62bafa5451b03492bf2e20e0efa09ec6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref649_2t3" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Report from E.M. Smillie on conditions at Clyde Farm</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1929 December 10</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_09b4b7419773e1d8342dea3d09ad7400" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref650_48r" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Handwritten note to Simon Flexner from Mrs. Myers expressing thanks for expression of sympathy at death of L.G. Myers</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1932 February 9</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_3c0e887a61f61d1f9d598bd2a4439d8b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref651_xmm" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Memorial minute read at Corporation meeting at death of L.G. Myers</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1932 October 28</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_315cda7cdc9b1abc64123b525efae642" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref652_ekr" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Correspondence regarding mortgage on farm at Clyde</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1933 December</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_f9337883898f5e25997c46c74746b8cf" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref653_jsu" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Outline of financial accounting procedure at RIMR</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1934 October 26</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_325926856a2671ac86a10dcd0a1028fc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
            </did>
          </c>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref985_pm4" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1936/1954" type="inclusive">1936-1954</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_fc204e378109d31d84eeb9cc7fa3dc7d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref986_td5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Non-routine items include</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_f51cfded2c49b004307146218b38e88c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
          <c id="aspace_ref654_d5a" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Copy of letter from Squires and Co. in regard to treatment and disposition of premiums and discounts</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1938 April 14</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_adaacdd4952f6d2b84d1ff93d0b3c55b" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref655_057" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Memorial minute in honor of Lefferts Mason Dashiell as sent to Mrs. Dashiell and acknowledgment</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1938 June 30</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_3618cd900648886175aabd7e62bb8cbc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_0266a6e8bc72b8a111e888fc13c4b7e1">
              <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
              <p>Also includes newspaper notice of death on February 28, 1938.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref657_fbc" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>To Trustees of Institute from Edward Robinson explaining projected plan to adopt accounting procedures 'recommended by Squires and Co. that securities value on books be carried at original cost'</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1941 May 2</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_d830016046e96b9566af503fbd72c6a8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref658_8dg" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Correspondence regarding removal of papers of historical interest from Chase National Bank to Institute's safe</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1942 February 17</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_b8e5dd49c248363a40d8f8fc67a44ca0" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref659_otz" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Copy of suggested simplified form of balance sheet that can be made public</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1944 May 9</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_76cec19b003ba78ff37ef8106efd15d2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref660_0ya" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Correspondence regarding practice of entering authorizations before disbursements are made</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1946 October 18</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_7b811d2a797ccdb9ac7e630b20d56b91" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref661_xs6" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Copy of new Workmen's Compensation Board regulations regarding self-insurance security deposit</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1947 February 5</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_5765e4ac88920a6886aca15dc3e57d78" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref662_xpg" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Compilation from Minute Books and Manager's Annual Reports of operating and construction expenses of Institute 1901-1917/18 as requested by Mr. Fosdick</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1949 February 10</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_124315e002a59b775cd76f79ba000336" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref663_hkc" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Salary scale as compiled by Edward Emerson</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1949 May 6</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_7efd8fcc10ac96df022add251dfa6066" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref664_3or" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Copy of Bursar's statement of Receipts and Disbursements July 1951-June 1952 and Valuation schedule with group of supporting schedules</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1952 September 2</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_6ff902475a5a821cd24af9301fc6429d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
            </did>
          </c>
        </c>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
