<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA1570.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">National Committee on United States-China Relations records</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the National Committee on United States-China Relations records <num>FA1570</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-10-04 06:01:18 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>National Committee on United States-China Relations records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" rules="local" source="naf">National Committee on United States-China Relations</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA1570</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">260.81 Cubic Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1948/2014" type="inclusive">1948-2014</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="445d086ad08986aa2173a03169f1728e">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The National Committee on United States – China Relations (NCUSCR) was established in 1966 as a nonprofit educational organization with a mission to encourage mutual understanding and dialogue between citizens of the United States and China. </p>

<p>The National Committee came into being through the cooperative efforts of scholars and civic, religious, and business leaders who, at a time of mutual hostility between the two countries, sought to stimulate public discussion about China and the United States' relations with it by sponsoring conferences, seminars, publications, and other education and outreach programs. In 1972, the National Committee sponsored the Chinese table tennis team's historic U. S. visit. This round of "Ping Pong Diplomacy," which followed closely on Richard Nixon's visit to China in February 1972, helped pave the way for later exchanges and, eventually, for the normalization of relations with China in 1979. Building on these cultural exchanges, the National Committee came to be a primary organizer of professional and policy exchanges between the two countries (and including Hong Kong and Taiwan), in the areas of foreign affairs and international relations, economic development, governance and legal affairs, education, mass media, environmental and global issues, etc. As its role in exchanges became more prominent, the National Committee turned over some of its educational programs to the Asia Society in the late 1970s, but it continues its educational role through public education events and ongoing outreach.</p>

<p>Funding for the National Committee comes from the United States government (especially the Department of State), corporations, and foundations, as well as from its individual membership.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="e1c1f6d0db6ee9e77e4000a2cc81920a">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <prefercite id="20ea247fec93751f4642a8a2e364945c">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>  </prefercite>
  <arrangement id="462d75c6992fb29347184b58e44df78e">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Arranged in ten record groups, each comprised of multiple series. The first nine record groups and associated accessions are representative solely of when the materials were processed by RAC, and do not imply an original order of the records. Record Group 10 consists of audiovisual materials. Additional finding aids are created as records are processed and open for research.</p><p>The collection is arranged in the following series across all record groups (not all series appear in every record group):
Series 1: Events
Series 2: Exchanges – General
Series 3: Exchanges to China
Series 4: Exchanges from China
Series 5: Conferences, Seminars, Workshops, and Dialogues
Series 6: Publications and Reports
Series 7: Art and Archaeology
Series 8: Programs, Projects and Proposals
Series 9: Ping Pong Diplomacy
Series 10: Development
Series 11: Board of Directors, Committees and Members records
Series 12: HIV/AIDS
Series 13: America-China Society / America-China Forum Programs and Staff 
Series 14: NCUSCR Presidents' Files
Series 15: Clippings and Reference
Series 17: Sister Cities
Series 18: Special Formats: General
Series 19: Personnel records (Restricted)</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="7b305a371815348f2de320c5eac3e47a">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection documents all aspects of the National Committee's programs, activities and administration.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
