<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>FA547.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper type="filing">Ford Foundation records, International Division, Office Files of Forrest F. Hill</titleproper>
        <titleproper>A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Office Files of Forrest F. Hill
 <num>FA547</num></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by Brian Bleich and Nancy Ng Tam, The Winthrop Group</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>July 2011</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline>
          <addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline>
          <addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2016-10-02 00:20:39 -0400</date>.</creation>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Ford Foundation records, International Division, Office Files of Forrest F. Hill</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="aut" source="lcnaf">Ford Foundation</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>FA547</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.8 Cubic Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1952/1966" type="inclusive">Bulk, 1955-1966 1952-1966</unitdate>
      <unitdate normal="1955/1966" type="bulk">bulk</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_e208514446f0c69d228837a398bedd53">The office files of Dr. Forrest F. Hill span from 1952 to 1966. The bulk of his files begin in 1955, when he joined the Foundation; the earlier documents are primarily reports and reference material. Dr. Hill's files document his efforts to establish international research centers, including the International Rice Research Institute in the Philippines and the International Institute of Tropical Agriculture in Nigeria. The files also detail his continuing work with agricultural development. They contain information about the early development of Foundation overseas policies, as well as the proposed, but eventually rejected, Foundation office in Afghanistan (1956-1963). Forrest F. “Frosty” Hill left Cornell in 1955 to become the Vice President of Overseas Development for the Ford Foundation. From 1963 to 1978 he was Chairman of the Board of IRRI. He also served as president of the American Agricultural Economics Association, and between 1955 and 1960, served on the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York. Dr. Hill retired to Ithaca, New York in 1976 and died in 1988.</abstract>
      <physdesc id="aspace_79c9520ed2aebd28f95dc609be08563c">
        <extent>(2 Hollinger document boxes)</extent>
      </physdesc>
    </did>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_32b7706f7441b12fe055e08b922cddbe">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
      <p>Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <userestrict id="aspace_69ff5417d3d9d2bb86a09f25f66770c2">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
      <p>Completion of a use agreement is required prior to providing scholarly access. See RAC Head of Reference (or applicable designee) for details. Ford Foundation holds title, copyright and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them. The Rockefeller Archive Center has authority to grant permission to cite and publish material from the collection for scholarly purposes. Permission to publish extensive excerpts, or material in its entirety, will be referred to the Ford Foundation.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_58c98fc9492653558204ac97893d8736">
      <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
      <p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>
    </prefercite>
    <bioghist id="aspace_384a47f26a3912a9299dd67168f39a8a">
      <head>Biographical Note</head>
      <p>Forrest F. “Frosty” Hill was born in 1900. He received a bachelor’s degree from the University of Saskatchewan in 1923 and was awarded a PhD in Agricultural Economics by Cornell University in 1930. Dr. Hill subsequently became a professor of Land Economics at Cornell. He taught until 1938 when he was appointed Governor of the Farm Credit Administration (FCA) by President Roosevelt. He resigned in 1940, after a dispute with Secretary of Agriculture Henry A. Wallace over the autonomy of the FCA. Returning to Cornell, Dr. Hill worked for the next 15 years as a professor, chairman of the Department of Agricultural Economics, and provost of the university.</p>
      <p>In 1955, Dr. Hill left Cornell to become the Vice President of Overseas Development for the Ford Foundation. During his time with the Foundation, he worked in partnership with the Rockefeller Foundation to establish international research centers, such as the International Rice Research Institute (IRRI) in the Philippines and the International Maize and Wheat Improvement Center in Mexico. From 1963 to 1978 he was Chairman of the Board of IRRI. He also served as President of the American Agricultural Economics Association and, between 1955 and 1960, sat on the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York.</p>
      <p>Dr. Hill retired to Ithaca, New York in 1976 and died in 1988.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <separatedmaterial id="aspace_72c268569b86d78ee2d61bd3710d8788">
      <head>Separated Materials Note</head>
      <p>Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.</p>
    </separatedmaterial>
    <bioghist id="aspace_7af40a5e604d295eb0cec96ef34752b2">
      <head>Organizational History</head>
      <p>The Ford Foundation established the Overseas Development Program, one of its first grant programs, in 1951. Its granting goals were to increase agricultural production, improve health and living conditions, and advance education. India and Pakistan were the focus of the initial grants, with a more limited number of grants issued in Indonesia and Burma. A program for smaller regional and national grants was initiated for the Near East region later the same year.</p>
      <p>As part of a Foundation reorganization in 1966, the Overseas Development Program, along with other international Foundation programs such as International Training and Research and Population, became part of a unified International Division. Following another Foundation reorganization in 1983, the International Division was eliminated and two program divisions were created – the United States and International Affairs Program (USIAP) and Developing Countries Program (DCP).</p>
    </bioghist>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_f141a156888a44f690ee3b80fbdbc1f1">
      <head>Related Collections</head>
      <p>Ford Foundation Resource Identifier: ACC91/1 – This collection contains additional office files for Forrest F. Hill, 1953-1975, 1966-1975 (bulk).</p>
      <p>FA565 Ford Foundation records, International Division, Office Files of F. Champion Ward contains additional information about the Overseas Development program can be found in the office files of C.F. Ward, 1956-2002, bulk 1961-1978. Dr. Ward joined the Foundation in 1954 as Director of the Overseas Development Program for the Middle East and Africa and later was promoted to Deputy Vice President for International Programs. Dr. Ward worked closely with Dr. Hill and many of the topics covered in their files are related.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <processinfo id="aspace_133178927a0139a2f1aeec3bab51713c">
      <head>Processing Information Note</head>
      <p>The documents comprising this collection of Dr. Hill's papers were separated from C. F. Ward's files. Evidently files kept by Dr. Hill and Dr. Ward were labeled with post-it notes and interfiled when they were sent to storage. The post-it notes were used to guide the sorting and separation of Dr. Hill's and Dr. Ward's files. Dr. Ward served as Director of Overseas Development when Dr. Hill was Vice President of that division.</p>
      <p>Dr. Hill's files appear to have been minimally processed prior to this work. The total volume of the combined Hill and Ward papers was 7 cubic feet when accessioned by the Ford Foundation Archives in 2011. Of these, 0.66 cubic ft. were separated for processing as the office files of Dr. Hill.</p>
      <p>Duplicates, reference files, grant proposals, and files that addressed purely financial matters were not retained.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_867869acaf127de2bcbaadf992796ddc">
      <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
      <p>The office files of Dr. Forrest F. Hill span from 1952 to 1966. The bulk of his files date from 1955, when Dr. Hill joined the Foundation; the earlier documents are primarily reports and reference material. His files document his efforts to establish international research centers, including the International Rice Research Institute in the Philippines and the International Institute of Tropical Agriculture in Nigeria. The files detail his continuing work in agricultural development. In addition, they contain information about the development of Foundation overseas policies and a proposed, but eventually rejected, Foundation office in Afghanistan (1956-1963).</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_3230e0d993ba9382ab6a55550eabbebc">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <bioghist id="aspace_d86b95bba2f95c9a7c49adc46599202f">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Segment One: International Activities of the Ford Foundation: An Overview</emph>
      </p>
      <p>The Foundation's aspiration to become a national and international philanthropy for the advancement of human welfare was first formally expressed in the seminal 1949 report of the Gaither Study Committee, &gt;<emph render="italic">Report of the Study for the Ford Foundation on Policy and Program</emph> (RAC Library, call letters 361.7 GAI ), which was commissioned by the Board of Trustees to chart the Foundation’s future. Foundation Trustees launched Ford’s international grantmaking activities in 1950 when they approved the committee’s report and its embrace of peace, democracy, and freedom.  Since then, the Foundation has tackled these goals using a variety of strategies and responding to changing contexts, from the Cold War to the 1989 fall of the Berlin Wall and beyond.</p>
      <p>Toward the Foundation’s aspiration‎al goal, "the establishment of peace", its international activities have comprised a wide range of conceptual approaches and focus areas. These include international affairs, international studies, international understanding, arms control and disarmament, international law, international economic concerns, and overseas development in nearly every region of the world. Three distinct periods emerge for the international grantmaking defined by external contextual changes and internal changes in Foundation leadership and structures: the expansion era of 1950-1965; the transition and restructuring years of 1966-1988; and the post-1989 shift away from Cold War dichotomies.  During each of the distinct historical periods the consistent objectives were: 1) to ensure freedom and democracy in developed countries; 2) to foster education and international understanding in all countries; and 3) to contribute to the social, economic, and political development of less developed countries.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref14_ry9" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Subject Files</unittitle>
          <unitid>I</unitid>
          <unitdate normal="1952/1966" type="inclusive">1952-1966</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_ad073667e8dce0b8c603193adce23b2d">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The files, arranged alphabetically, document Dr. Hill’s years as Vice President of Overseas Development and his specialization in agriculture-related research. They contain correspondence, memoranda, reports and notes to and from Dr. Hill and grantees, colleagues, consultants and Foundation personnel.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="aspace_ref15_flt" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Asia and the Pacific (A&amp;P) -- Afghanistan -- Re: Possible FF Involvement</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1956/1963" type="inclusive">1956-1963</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_bcc2cdfda85a49b79d18c81810073da4" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_d756b03b8d0a057c35df3463734c4d94" parent="aspace_bcc2cdfda85a49b79d18c81810073da4" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref16_h9x" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>A&amp;P -- Burma -- Program Report</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1953/1965" type="inclusive">1953-1965</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_88118daed6927dc252244e40a8782fb9" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_afc438ccdc8f69905baa272f653aa62d" parent="aspace_88118daed6927dc252244e40a8782fb9" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref17_qjs" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>A&amp;P -- Indonesia -- Info Re: Closing of Office</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1961/1965" type="inclusive">1961-1965</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_520484bd505987a6df379676671ec005" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_be342d8c82d13ba0b24dd3ca2e5f11e6" parent="aspace_520484bd505987a6df379676671ec005" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref18_5so" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>A&amp;P -- International Rice Research Institute (IRRI) -- Discussion Notes, Background, etc.</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1959/1964" type="inclusive">1959-1964</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_f9fb8b646a04ba0811b15232afc4d90e" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_cabb1d38cb8632fdd62e7b707791a580" parent="aspace_f9fb8b646a04ba0811b15232afc4d90e" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref19_d20" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>A&amp;P -- Japan -- Re: Economics, FF Activities, Visit Plan</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1957/1961" type="inclusive">1957-1961</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_4e7528e5890ea7b223877116e3441dfe" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_c2648e16a33ebdd0bb3eb4ed40580fcc" parent="aspace_4e7528e5890ea7b223877116e3441dfe" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref20_vee" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>A&amp;P -- Pakistan -- Reports, Background</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1952/1965" type="inclusive">1952-1965</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d523db6f9d5db918abca8a31d9cc690c" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_716b4c5b10d85c54f701a4f64c6a5515" parent="aspace_d523db6f9d5db918abca8a31d9cc690c" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref21_c4i" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>A&amp;P -- Pakistan -- Harvard-Pakistan Planning Commission -- David Bell</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1960/1964" type="inclusive">1960-1964</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_e7c7c0957f0df88a945d938f097b7f15" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_ce9df3b1c8c4fee235869dd0ec34b438" parent="aspace_e7c7c0957f0df88a945d938f097b7f15" type="folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref22_758" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>A&amp;P -- Philippines -- Re: Manila Office and IRRI</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965" type="inclusive">Jul 15, 1965</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_33ce1aa1a492eed698ed7d6f064334a8" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_7371eed06fc8566b1bb5e0629a26878c" parent="aspace_33ce1aa1a492eed698ed7d6f064334a8" type="folder">8</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref23_tf4" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>A&amp;P -- Singapore -- Re: Separation from Malaysia</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1962/1965" type="inclusive">1962-1965</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_21412bff044555cc9c803fb87e828055" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_3c642fdd6a0900843f06d3e6ef765488" parent="aspace_21412bff044555cc9c803fb87e828055" type="folder">9</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref24_wav" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>A&amp;P -- Staffing -- Memoranda, Budgets</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1957/1965" type="inclusive">1957-1965</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_20dffe42c45d2633572ff2bc4ecd2e66" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_65d9bf09fe2ef01b9b3afd793b0d882c" parent="aspace_20dffe42c45d2633572ff2bc4ecd2e66" type="folder">10</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref25_389" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>A&amp;P -- Vietnam -- Re: Vietnam Project, Mekong Meeting, etc.</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1960/1962" type="inclusive">1960-1962</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_622eb020355dd41d81354aaf2ad2d0f5" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_76eecc520e43bc02457f5c9738596e1d" parent="aspace_622eb020355dd41d81354aaf2ad2d0f5" type="folder">11</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref26_wcs" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bechtel, Stephen D. -- Correspondence Re: Bechtel Corporation, India Trip, etc.</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1961/1965" type="inclusive">1961-1965</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_b9d39702882b9c57edb01d15ebb79a91" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_3cd867a92c1f113885bf7eaad0f29c71" parent="aspace_b9d39702882b9c57edb01d15ebb79a91" type="folder">12</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref27_lo8" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Brookings Institution -- Correspondence Re: OD Grant for Study of U.S. Foreign Aid</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1962/1965" type="inclusive">1962-1965</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_5dbe2f6f652c8184944895b09ed79a49" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_99c89a3f2ec1dcca570062d5cb69a283" parent="aspace_5dbe2f6f652c8184944895b09ed79a49" type="folder">13</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref28_0n2" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Budget -- Balance of Payments</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1966" type="inclusive">1965-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_4d1b804c05f981b1353872027b966616" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_31bf3402378020dfe5ec78c3714808f3" parent="aspace_4d1b804c05f981b1353872027b966616" type="folder">14</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref29_2x1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Budget -- Endowment Grants</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1956/1965" type="inclusive">1956-1965</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_774dd6c30068847f389ff668a21750a6" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_086604d42d7e239da10bc84f066e3950" parent="aspace_774dd6c30068847f389ff668a21750a6" type="folder">15</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref30_a5t" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Budget -- Overhead Charges</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1963/1963" type="inclusive">1963</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_66cadae2032e31fd3c6da31be9a19fe0" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_23d89422c8ce976be0772e399ba2f2ab" parent="aspace_66cadae2032e31fd3c6da31be9a19fe0" type="folder">16</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref31_z00" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Education in India -- Correspondence Re: Douglas Ensminger</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1953/1955" type="inclusive">1953-1955</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_163e976728775f66163918665113b2fd" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_e2c101c82bbd7c9936494ef27741a86c" parent="aspace_163e976728775f66163918665113b2fd" type="folder">17</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref32_fo1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Europe and International Affairs (EIA) -- USSR and East Europe -- Memorandum Re: Communism and FF Projects</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1959/1959" type="inclusive">1959</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_e39907128a4e7df11fbe936f500a8a75" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_5a9530f7f39e9a9e39de66c01e669342" parent="aspace_e39907128a4e7df11fbe936f500a8a75" type="folder">18</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref33_a51" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Evaluation of Overseas Program Grants</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1959/1963" type="inclusive">1959-1963</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_27dbb1f85e934a456d8da0d036db576f" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_dd84e309f85d90ff6e8d9815b1da70dd" parent="aspace_27dbb1f85e934a456d8da0d036db576f" type="folder">19</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref34_7ns" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>FF International Activities -- Organization -- David Bell Memoranda</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1956/1966" type="inclusive">1956-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_67a6342f6fc59e0f2964bc2e51604da0" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_e8c9c4a90d8acda41f19ee96b18d313a" parent="aspace_67a6342f6fc59e0f2964bc2e51604da0" type="folder">20</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref35_2t2" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>FF Population Program -- Program Planning Memoranda, Press Releases, etc.</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1959/1966" type="inclusive">1959-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_241bb613d3a1f376a685bb11926c3d5f" label="Documents (507960.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_c6ab81c30cc161d371ab3544f1af8808" parent="aspace_241bb613d3a1f376a685bb11926c3d5f" type="folder">21</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref36_mue" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Foundations (Other) -- Memoranda Re: Meetings with FF, etc.</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1956/1964" type="inclusive">1956-1964</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_fc4b92949dd33342c9ef2d2c50b69f89" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_a5340db4d3791204e807ee7d5f880a3e" parent="aspace_fc4b92949dd33342c9ef2d2c50b69f89" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref37_jsm" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Institute for Human Reproduction -- Discussion Paper, Interim Report, etc.</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1963/1965" type="inclusive">1963-1965</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_46d41f2a359abb87677c01f694bb0679" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_eafab41e22f1ea1fb9ec13817456ec0f" parent="aspace_46d41f2a359abb87677c01f694bb0679" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref38_94m" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>International Institute of Tropical Agriculture (IITA), Nigeria -- Memoranda, Proposals, Decrees</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1963/1966" type="inclusive">1963-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_5e513c2fa4503a6d2a6e12287457ce3d" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_027beb511759d1f7adcecb6a04586b73" parent="aspace_5e513c2fa4503a6d2a6e12287457ce3d" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref39_tmh" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Latin America and the Caribbean (LAC) -- Brazil</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1959/1966" type="inclusive">1959-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_2ce54d9f5d4150d56ae86fe57b6cec38" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_915d42183bbf61a499a1a00c01f48f72" parent="aspace_2ce54d9f5d4150d56ae86fe57b6cec38" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref40_3vc" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>LAC -- Caribbean --Dominican Republic, Puerto Rico</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1958/1965" type="inclusive">1958-1965</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_0e1aa1dd65bdea6cdfc84655a69d3414" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_a6a8eb570bb02313827f6b88bcfd2e5b" parent="aspace_0e1aa1dd65bdea6cdfc84655a69d3414" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref41_ut8" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>LAC -- Central America -- Proposed FF Activities</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1959/1963" type="inclusive">1959-1963</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_450fe82f0eb9f0673d66184085bf2e4f" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_2ebcc5054347be48c74b2101f9e0b809" parent="aspace_450fe82f0eb9f0673d66184085bf2e4f" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref42_znu" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>LAC -- General -- Organization and Personnel</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1959/1966" type="inclusive">1959-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_120722491f594971256e61b6eb14ab90" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_a70458117635e5a3d5aa4f389b0ac007" parent="aspace_120722491f594971256e61b6eb14ab90" type="folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref43_loj" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>LAC -- Other Latin America -- Uruguay, Paraguay</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1963/1965" type="inclusive">1963-1965</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_31ccd6d1b1f7f400607d04b4468f7bf5" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_6b05613aba3c26e50e9165ec3818ccb3" parent="aspace_31ccd6d1b1f7f400607d04b4468f7bf5" type="folder">8</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref44_qyt" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Middle East and Africa (MEA) -- Africa General -- Correspondence Re: Trips, Grant Activity, etc.</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1957/1963" type="inclusive">1957-1963</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_90fc8d983f7f0ab2705b3fe4a8380cc9" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_ea5508300718be7aaf7108231fb1e812" parent="aspace_90fc8d983f7f0ab2705b3fe4a8380cc9" type="folder">9</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref45_0ta" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>MEA -- Congo and Other West Africa -- Memoranda Re: Togo, Abidjan, etc.</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1959/1966" type="inclusive">1959-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_363de31e8cb1b821f73a2318d3471be0" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_ab3ae83235e746c598a8fd58986933c1" parent="aspace_363de31e8cb1b821f73a2318d3471be0" type="folder">10</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref46_f29" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>MEA -- Nigeria -- Memoranda Re: Kingsley</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1960/1962" type="inclusive">1960-1962</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_a49ed3de19aa3946801a50498af225b7" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_f493bbf1a381a2d9ea7cad42f72f7a47" parent="aspace_a49ed3de19aa3946801a50498af225b7" type="folder">11</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref47_sw6" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>MEA -- North Africa (Former Tunis Office) -- Memoranda Re: Personnel</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1957/1961" type="inclusive">1957-1961</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_239f6db0bf403a55b259d2d6c8a73475" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_40761417ae641a4d637bb150baf4f0e0" parent="aspace_239f6db0bf403a55b259d2d6c8a73475" type="folder">12</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref48_dvh" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>MEA -- South Africa -- Correspondence Re: Port Elizabeth</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965" type="inclusive">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_180e08c48a0c22cfd38c1e42226293f0" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_68b381e73df19f0bde0dd4938f5deed4" parent="aspace_180e08c48a0c22cfd38c1e42226293f0" type="folder">13</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref49_7uy" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>MEA -- United Arab Republic (Egypt) -- Correspondence and Memoranda Re: Situation, Grants</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1957/1966" type="inclusive">1957-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_31f86d6d7d4f130fbec2ca941ba9488b" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_46e2856a0da1794fba34c6cf2fd8eba6" parent="aspace_31f86d6d7d4f130fbec2ca941ba9488b" type="folder">14</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref50_ouf" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Overseas Development (OD) Control Unit Grant Making -- Re: Grant Status, Program Meetings, etc.</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1961/1966" type="inclusive">1961-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_7503dec5c96a5363c1cbe107889cdc2c" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_6a52a49fc55cf3d849232700cb716d8f" parent="aspace_7503dec5c96a5363c1cbe107889cdc2c" type="folder">15</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref51_bnb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>OD Representatives' Conference, Mexico City -- David Bell -- Reports, Agenda, Program</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1964/1964" type="inclusive">Sep 1964</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_6351751520d46e4082c0f2b911d85c1b" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_bd90985765ff803f268ca2aa5ade604d" parent="aspace_6351751520d46e4082c0f2b911d85c1b" type="folder">16</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref52_8tl" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>OD Representatives' Meetings -- Programs</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1959/1962" type="inclusive">1959-1962</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_0ca57e4c5f64503d3ce31f7da21a342d" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_80b0b75c9fd7c3fa1ecae9fe12a587bb" parent="aspace_0ca57e4c5f64503d3ce31f7da21a342d" type="folder">17</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref53_8jz" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>OD Review Seminar -- Memoranda Re: Program, Operation Janus</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966" type="inclusive">Mar 2-May 20, 1966</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_4ffd62ca541f4d34e9424b8ba9dff623" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_bcba3d8ef22860f9a19f735d7f1b022c" parent="aspace_4ffd62ca541f4d34e9424b8ba9dff623" type="folder">18</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref54_qp6" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Planning Budgets FY 1963-1965 -- David Bell</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1962/1966" type="inclusive">1962-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_1cf1c7e37d63dbed4e6e5911cfbb8d19" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_6dbbaef2d24b26b85d41cb49d81b60f8" parent="aspace_1cf1c7e37d63dbed4e6e5911cfbb8d19" type="folder">19</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref55_0vl" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Wyzanski, Charles E. -- Correspondence Re: Trips to Turkey and Israel, Asia Programs</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1956/1964" type="inclusive">1956-1964</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_bc4b114c74a87fbc1fca6a01a0fbe0ee" label="Documents (507960.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_fa2cc8a35524d9005444f4aa645ebe93" parent="aspace_bc4b114c74a87fbc1fca6a01a0fbe0ee" type="folder">20</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
