<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xd="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/doc/xsl" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd" version="3.4">
  <identifier type="local">LI01084</identifier>
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Ask the children :
what America's children really think about working parents</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name>
    <namePart>Galinsky, Ellen</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="lcnaf">aut</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>William Morrow and Company</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="lcnaf">pbl</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="text">New York</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <publisher>William Morrow</publisher>
    <dateIssued>1999</dateIssued>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <extent>1 Bound Volumes</extent>
  </physicalDescription>
  <note>Includes bibliographical references and index.</note>
  <abstract>"Here is important news for the millions of parents struggling to manage work and family, says Ellen Galinsky in this extraordinary study--the first comprehensive study ever conducted that asks children and parents for their views on work and family life today. The responses she has gleaned from in-depth interviews and nationally representative surveys of children and parents are surprising, useful, and guaranteed to break the frantic cycle of guilt and stress that often traps parents." "Five years in the making, the Ask the Children study questions accepted thinking on such issues as quality time vs. quantity time, how mothers parent their children compared to fathers, how much children really know about the daily lives of parents at work, how much parents like their work, what messages we're sending children about work, and much more. For example, while many parents worry that they may not be spending enough time with their children, time is not at the top of children's lists when they are asked to name their one wish for changing how their parents' work affects their lives. And while the debate rages about whether mothers' working is good or bad for children, it turns out that children learn more about the world of work from their mothers than they do from their fathers." "For the first time, parents will hear children's perceptions and opinions--both reassuring and insightful--on these and many other topics. They'll see stereotypes blown and politically correct ideas challenged. They'll hear parents and children talking about what works to keep families close and why. They'll find practical advice for a better family life and a brilliant new set of operating principles to help them feel more in command and control at work and at home." "As the century closes on a generation of working parents, we have a unique opportunity to view how far we have come as families and to chart the course ahead. Ask the Children provides a positive basis for understanding our past and is a point of departure for our future. Book jacket."--BOOK JACKET.</abstract>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Children of working parents</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Work and family</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Working mothers</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <geographic>United States</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Parent and child</topic>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Circulating collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <identifier type="isbn">9780688147525</identifier>
  <genre>volume</genre>
  <classification>306.89 GAL</classification>
</mods>
