<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xd="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/doc/xsl" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd" version="3.4">
  <identifier type="local">LI04173</identifier>
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Patronizing the public: American philanthropy's transformation of culture, communication, and the humanities</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name>
    <namePart>Lexington Books</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="">pbl</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Buxton, William J.</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="">edt</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="text">Lanham, Md.</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <publisher>Lexington Books, 2009</publisher>
    <dateIssued>2009</dateIssued>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <extent>1 Bound Volumes</extent>
  </physicalDescription>
  <relatedItem type="series">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Critical Media Studies</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <abstract>Includes: Buxton, William J. Civil society and its discontents: bringing culture, communication and the humanities into the history of philanthropy; Buxton, William J. From the Rockefeller center to the Lincoln center: musings on the Rockefeller half-century"; Theresa Richardson. Transformation and continuity in Rockefeller child-related programs: implications for the emergence of communications as a field of concern; Buxton, William J. Communication practice and theory in the "new humanities" and "new general-education" programs of Rockefeller philanthropy, 1933-1940; Cramer, Gisela. The Rockefeller foundation and Pan American radio; Wasson Haidee. Hollywood bypass: MoMA, the Rockefeller Foundation, and new circuits of cinema; Gall, Johannes C. An "art of fugue" of film scoring: Hans Eisler's Rockefeller foundation-funded film music project (1940-1942); Niquette, Manon and William J. Buxton. "Sugar-coating the educational pill": Rockefeller support for the communicative turn in science museums; Brison, Jeffrey. The political economy of rockefeller support for the humanities in Canada, 1941-1957; Wrenn, Marion. Inadvertent architects of twentieth-century media convergence: private foundations and the reorientation of foreign journalists; Acland, Charles R. Screen technology, mobilization, and adult education in the 1950s; McCarthy, Anna. The television activities of the fund for the republic; Foulkes, Julia L. "The weakest point in our record": philanthropic support of dance and the arts."</abstract>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Charities -- History</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Cultural industries</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Rockefeller Foundation -- History</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Lexington Books</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Buxton, William J.</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-0-7391-2305-8</identifier>
  <identifier type="lccn">2009007251</identifier>
  <genre>volume</genre>
  <classification>361.7632 PAT CHC</classification>
  <genre>volume</genre>
  <classification>361.7632 PAT CHC</classification>
</mods>
