<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>FA505.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper type="filing">Ford Foundation records, Asia Programs, Regional Director, Office Files of Peter F. Geithner</titleproper>
        <titleproper>A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Asia Programs, Regional Director, Office Files of Peter F. Geithner
 <num>FA505</num></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by Brian Bleich, The Winthrop Group</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>February 2011</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline>
          <addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline>
          <addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2016-10-03 00:32:24 -0400</date>.</creation>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Ford Foundation records, Asia Programs, Regional Director, Office Files of Peter F. Geithner</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="aut" source="lcnaf">Ford Foundation</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>FA505</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.8 Cubic Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1990/1994" type="inclusive">1990-1994</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_ce248f63be0c4f1bd0004324aceb0fc2">The Asia Programs office originated in 1958 as the Office for South and Southeast Asia, a subdivision of the Overseas Development Program. After a Foundation reorganization in 1966, the Office for South and Southeast Asia became part of the International Division, and in 1968, was renamed Asia and the Pacific. In 1981, the Office for Asia and the Pacific became part of the Developing Countries Program. In 1989, the Asia Programs was constituted as a full program area. Peter F. Geithner joined the Ford Foundation in 1966 and became Assistant Representative of the India Office in 1968. He served as Representative of the Southeast Asia office and later Representative in China before being appointed Regional Director of the Asia Programs in 1990, a position he held until 1996. The Office Files of Peter F. Geithner span in date from 1990 to 1994, during the time he served as Regional Director of the Asia Programs. The bulk of the files consists of correspondence concerning the Ford Foundation’s work in assisting the economic development of Vietnam. Other files document the Foundation’s relations with the government of Vietnam, including the process of seeking and obtaining permission from the Vietnamese government to operate within its national borders. There are also files containing materials from the Aspen Institute Indochina Policy Project (1991-1992) and the Vietnam Reconstruction Conference in Arlington, Virginia (1992).</abstract>
      <physdesc id="aspace_86b96f6d56e67df6191b056213cf59d1">
        <extent>(2 document boxes)</extent>
      </physdesc>
    </did>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_687b2a86760fdb54ab616e28875bd31c">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
      <p>Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_6c504712a3fa59cb528d4c9be9741378">
      <head>Organizational History</head>
      <p>The Asia Programs office originated in 1958 as a division of the Overseas Development program then called the Overseas Development/South and Southeast Asia. In 1966, South and Southeast Asia office shifted to the International Division program area as part of a Foundation reorganization and, in 1968, the office was renamed Asia and the Pacific. In 1981, the office became part of the Developing Countries Program. The Asia Programs became a full program area in 1989.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <bioghist id="aspace_ac754e32fcabec37db4511c105452cbb">
      <head>Biographical Note</head>
      <p>Peter F. Geithner joined the Ford Foundation in 1966 and became Assistant Representative of the India Office in 1968. He subsequently served as Representative of the Southeast Asia office and later Representative in China before being appointed Regional Director of the Asia Programs in 1990, a position he held until 1996.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <arrangement id="aspace_2165125efd2c439220e0df76fa73f477">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>The files are arranged into 2 series.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_c9daa2f40a8d1ef9645a1ec338445f70">
      <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
      <p>The Office Files of Peter F. Geithner span from 1990-1994, the period of the time Mr. Geithner was Regional Director of the Asia Programs. The bulk of the files consist of correspondence regarding the Ford Foundation’s work in Vietnam.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <processinfo id="aspace_99fa782cfd80836fe4ac87a9d13bd79a">
      <head>Processing Information Note</head>
      <p>The original volume of 2 cubic feet accessioned by the Foundation Archives in 2011 was reduced during processing to two Hollinger document boxes.</p>
      <p>Duplicates, reference files about non-Foundation related or personal interests, applications for fellowships and CVs, and rejected and unsolicited grant requests were not retained.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <separatedmaterial id="aspace_22381e64f485518e537b16d890791f92">
      <head>Separated Materials</head>
      <p>Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.</p>
    </separatedmaterial>
    <prefercite id="aspace_f2e65b7cc45e197612890c10455efe4e">
      <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
      <p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>
    </prefercite>
    <userestrict id="aspace_77d083ff6e9c529e78bc95ce945b3490">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
      <p>Completion of a use agreement is required prior to providing scholarly access. See RAC Head of Reference (or applicable designee) for details. Ford Foundation holds title, copyright and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them. The Rockefeller Archive Center has authority to grant permission to cite and publish material from the collection for scholarly purposes. Permission to publish extensive excerpts, or material in its entirety, will be referred to the Ford Foundation.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_73e32935b2bd71c652e3ed84a720031b">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <bioghist id="aspace_fc75916ad8af5531ae7b6c3008e05cee">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Segment One: International Activities of the Ford Foundation: An Overview</emph>
      </p>
      <p>The Foundation's aspiration to become a national and international philanthropy for the advancement of human welfare was first formally expressed in the seminal 1949 report of the Gaither Study Committee, <emph render="italic">Report of the Study for the Ford Foundation on Policy and Program</emph> (RAC Library, call letters 361.7 GAI ), which was commissioned by the Board of Trustees to chart the Foundation’s future. Foundation Trustees launched Ford’s international grantmaking activities in 1950 when they approved the committee’s report and its embrace of peace, democracy, and freedom.  Since then, the Foundation has tackled these goals using a variety of strategies and responding to changing contexts, from the Cold War to the 1989 fall of the Berlin Wall and beyond.</p>
      <p>Toward the Foundation’s aspiration‎al goal, "the establishment of peace", its international activities have comprised a wide range of conceptual approaches and focus areas. These include international affairs, international studies, international understanding, arms control and disarmament, international law, international economic concerns, and overseas development in nearly every region of the world. Three distinct periods emerge for the international grantmaking defined by external contextual changes and internal changes in Foundation leadership and structures: the expansion era of 1950-1965; the transition and restructuring years of 1966-1988; and the post-1989 shift away from Cold War dichotomies.  During each of the distinct historical periods the consistent objectives were: 1) to ensure freedom and democracy in developed countries; 2) to foster education and international understanding in all countries; and 3) to contribute to the social, economic, and political development of less developed countries.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref14_aq4" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Conferences</unittitle>
          <unitid>I</unitid>
          <unitdate normal="1991/1992" type="inclusive">1991-1992</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_614431b8859fa2f912cbc9007ff01ec7">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The Conferences series contains two folders. The first holds notes, background reading, the official conference report, and participant list for the Aspen Institute Indochina Policy Project (1991-1992). The second file consists of notes, agenda, background reading, and a speech by a Vietnamese official from the Vietnam Reconstruction Conference in Arlington, Virginia (1992).</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="aspace_ref15_qdc" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Aspen Institute Indochina Policy Project -- Correspondence, Notes, Participant List, Background</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1991/1992" type="inclusive">Sep 3, 1991-Aug 10, 1992</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_ba96c8e5195e719c70a214ff79fbc13e" label="Documents (505797.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_c323641c6ddaf8a24eda6639bccf4aec" parent="aspace_ba96c8e5195e719c70a214ff79fbc13e" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref16_gmi" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Vietnam -- Reconstruction Conference, Arlington, VA -- Agenda, Notes, Background Papers, Speech</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1992/1992" type="inclusive">May 21-22, 1992</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_052bb0b0aa8c580e5d0fe2b7d2d2aec6" label="Documents (505797.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_a26e30e4f9e7dbdcdfabfdb4f4a21a6b" parent="aspace_052bb0b0aa8c580e5d0fe2b7d2d2aec6" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref17_gvj" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitid>II</unitid>
          <unitdate normal="1990/1994" type="inclusive">1990-1994</unitdate>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="aspace_19263b3614371c021b2e2c3bf8724acd">
          <head>Arrangement</head>
          <p>Mr. Geithner’s correspondence is organized by subject and arranged chronologically.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_680f1310f83f1dc60095a775d336fc27">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The files reflect a focus by the Foundation to assist in the economic development of Vietnam. The Foundation found it necessary to closely coordinate with and achieve the permission of the Vietnamese Government to operate within the borders of Vietnam. The file for the Vietnam Ministry of Foreign Affairs (1991-1993) holds internal Foundation memoranda as well as correspondence with grant partners about gaining necessary permissions from the Vietnamese Ministry for Foundation grant recipients to travel to and from Vietnam. It also contains correspondence with the Vietnamese Embassy intended to help develop a closer relationship between the United States and Vietnam. Another example is the file on Vietnam’s National Economics University (1991-1992), which contains letters, memoranda and a newspaper clipping about Foundation support for a National Economics University in Hanoi.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="aspace_ref18_uof" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Vietnam -- National Center for Social Sciences -- Correspondence, Background, Proposal</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1990/1993" type="inclusive">Oct 3, 1990-Jan 5, 1993</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_88dffdf3e1681ea69e1c509ab1a5792f" label="Documents (505800.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_04139292eb65b83729f468a3256524b4" parent="aspace_88dffdf3e1681ea69e1c509ab1a5792f" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref19_sxw" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>University of California, Berkeley -- Correspondence, Memoranda</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1991/1993" type="inclusive">Mar 19, 1991-Nov 16, 1993</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_3aed1b196b3b742f8107493aeb360ee7" label="Documents (505800.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_8d9ac1c687362078530331b214ff4ead" parent="aspace_3aed1b196b3b742f8107493aeb360ee7" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref20_l1p" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Vietnam / Harvard Institute for International Development (HIID) -- Correspondence, Memoranda, Reports</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1991/1992" type="inclusive">Apr 4, 1991-Aug 10, 1992</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_495d4ba1d400db60b634a2aee1d53b79" label="Documents (505800.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_47e9b3c1fb123d8dca37cb0197eef6e4" parent="aspace_495d4ba1d400db60b634a2aee1d53b79" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref21_nkp" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Law and Legal Reform, General -- Correspondence, Memoranda, Clippings</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1991/1992" type="inclusive">May 6, 1991-Jul 6, 1992</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_79d7d6a0a1e12ccb30c78806b8cb4908" label="Documents (505800.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_d3fc1d780bf40d848469214b1099febd" parent="aspace_79d7d6a0a1e12ccb30c78806b8cb4908" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref22_pz0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Vietnam Central Institute for Economic Management -- Correspondence, Notes</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1991/1993" type="inclusive">Jul 20, 1991-Jan 19, 1993</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_14a001ea1a361928ce18d09bf92e5860" label="Documents (505800.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_72ee6b9d831967927625d4a5110a78bc" parent="aspace_14a001ea1a361928ce18d09bf92e5860" type="folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref23_lc7" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Vietnam -- Volunteers in Asia -- Correspondence, Notes</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1991/1992" type="inclusive">Jul 29, 1991-Mar 31, 1992</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_a64c38b5bdb3d3ec5b39b8bf1472e1f5" label="Documents (505800.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_b8576f66069457ec809b41e9d8920de3" parent="aspace_a64c38b5bdb3d3ec5b39b8bf1472e1f5" type="folder">8</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref24_4as" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Vietnam -- Ministry of Foreign Affairs -- Correspondence, Memoranda</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1991/1993" type="inclusive">Aug 5, 1991-May 21, 1993</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_7fc0ba611b5d304e0f03900ac5be3ace" label="Documents (505800.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_888edc259a7d5f5e3c6158ea0f89d6be" parent="aspace_7fc0ba611b5d304e0f03900ac5be3ace" type="folder">9</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref25_xv0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Vietnam -- People's Aid Coordination Committee (PACCOM): Correspondence, Memoranda</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1991/1991" type="inclusive">Aug 5-6, 1991</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_2d3b3cbbf1c1ff89d9626bda5346e1e1" label="Documents (505800.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_873366c9aed872e33ce07e72d3c78619" parent="aspace_2d3b3cbbf1c1ff89d9626bda5346e1e1" type="folder">10</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref26_nlr" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>General Communications 1991 -- Travel, Government, Project LINK</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1991/1991" type="inclusive">Aug 7-Oct 16, 1991</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_1f75147559fd58d3c194a0b959d86820" label="Documents (505800.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_0241bfc79439026582e835d0f0bce51f" parent="aspace_1f75147559fd58d3c194a0b959d86820" type="folder">11</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref27_utx" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Vietnam Upland Management -- Correspondence, Memoranda, Background</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1991/1992" type="inclusive">Aug 8, 1991-Jun 7, 1992</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_32d01a61a7c94d4773dd1acfd9fa9ef4" label="Documents (505800.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_ee9bfee0247729b141633c30ae113bf9" parent="aspace_32d01a61a7c94d4773dd1acfd9fa9ef4" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref28_6vy" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Economic Institute -- Correspondence, Program Discussions, Notes</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1991/1992" type="inclusive">Sep 24, 1991-Oct 19, 1992</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_7e2959ba9c8c2eb4f99b5452a0d2cfea" label="Documents (505800.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_ffea539fbd24440840338621a73f10cf" parent="aspace_7e2959ba9c8c2eb4f99b5452a0d2cfea" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref29_xeo" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Vietnam -- National Economics University -- Correspondence, Memoranda, Clippings</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1991/1993" type="inclusive">Oct 11, 1991-Nov 4, 1993</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_11985d13cdbec943d18e5f2ed997bee2" label="Documents (505800.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_fe0d32aa54c8577643ee582f15f1bbde" parent="aspace_11985d13cdbec943d18e5f2ed997bee2" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref30_ra0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Vietnam -- Indochina Project -- Correspondence, Background, Notes</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1991/1995" type="inclusive">Nov 5, 1991-Mar 1, 1995</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_62b26631c854ce3d6463638aec1b2f84" label="Documents (505800.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_21874cdfc4320bd81e0b4ff727270b5e" parent="aspace_62b26631c854ce3d6463638aec1b2f84" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref31_e1j" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Vietnam -- National Academy of Sciences -- Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1991/1992" type="inclusive">Nov 22, 1991-Oct 13, 1992</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_fdaeeef313fd42e768209f95024f5a26" label="Documents (505800.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_40e0db6ed413219aef26bbad393a0b2f" parent="aspace_fdaeeef313fd42e768209f95024f5a26" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref32_mrb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Vietnam -- London School of Economics -- Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1991/1992" type="inclusive">Nov 25, 1991-Apr 29, 1992</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_96e5a3477a9f141eae9990d9d5cdf4b2" label="Documents (505800.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_37741342be6c604c5699e0af3d4c9206" parent="aspace_96e5a3477a9f141eae9990d9d5cdf4b2" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref33_fzs" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Vietnam -- Institute of Economic Research -- Correspondence, Memoranda, Notes, Clippings</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1991/1994" type="inclusive">Dec 2, 1991-Apr 9, 1994</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_e2d362a378cd32ba4ff5cfb7d2fdc09b" label="Documents (505800.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_849b20462f1dfbbd3963da1f348975d4" parent="aspace_e2d362a378cd32ba4ff5cfb7d2fdc09b" type="folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref34_2qo" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Australian National University -- Correspondence, Notes</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1992/1992" type="inclusive">Jan 10-Apr 10, 1992</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_a7e80d0a080423cf081fb80638c344ab" label="Documents (505800.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_edeb6e914e05e82a3287b3079d42b472" parent="aspace_a7e80d0a080423cf081fb80638c344ab" type="folder">8</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref35_0e8" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Vietnam -- The Asia Foundation -- Correspondence, Memoranda</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1992/1993" type="inclusive">Feb 14, 1992-Dec 8, 1993</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_17de5ec425af7e57178bcff70b305b76" label="Documents (505800.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_5874a056e5fffc5a1670d5ecee92d354" parent="aspace_17de5ec425af7e57178bcff70b305b76" type="folder">9</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref36_07v" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Vietnam -- Center for National Resources Management and Environmental Studies at Hanoi University: Correspondence, Memoranda</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1992/1992" type="inclusive">Mar 23-May 28, 1992</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_c758b16985136e18f94c492c1d5dc37a" label="Documents (505800.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_609bd21618f771c53c42643afd57ea4c" parent="aspace_c758b16985136e18f94c492c1d5dc37a" type="folder">10</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref37_ogk" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Vietnam -- American Council of Learned Societies - Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1992/1993" type="inclusive">Aug 3, 1992-Aug 2, 1993</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_c42c2dc8c269d0b1766c3da51b92110f" label="Documents (505800.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_f65a536cb8962d233b498c79d3d68a25" parent="aspace_c42c2dc8c269d0b1766c3da51b92110f" type="folder">11</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref38_pap" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Vietnam -- National Endowment for Democracy -- Memoranda on Deportment of NED Representative</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">Nov 23, 1993</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_e46226ec6eb10d29c1652dd47358fe34" label="Documents (505800.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_22bdaab3376d7615af11c5124ec7457c" parent="aspace_e46226ec6eb10d29c1652dd47358fe34" type="folder">12</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref39_62j" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Vietnam -- Ministry of the Interior -- Memoranda</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1994/1994" type="inclusive">Apr 25, 1994</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_3092a582bc2332348f3e16567edd2833" label="Documents (505800.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_960e7d8398a9db1d21c5129498f245f4" parent="aspace_3092a582bc2332348f3e16567edd2833" type="folder">13</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
