<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xd="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/doc/xsl" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd" version="3.4">
  <identifier type="local">LI10293</identifier>
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Broadcast hysteria : Orson Welles's War of the Worlds and the art of fake news.</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name>
    <namePart>Schwartz, A Brad </namePart>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <dateIssued>2015</dateIssued>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <extent>1 Bound Volumes</extent>
  </physicalDescription>
  <abstract>In Broadcast Hysteria, A. Brad Schwartz boldly retells the story of Welles's famed radio play and its impact. Did it really spawn a "wave of mass hysteria," as The New York Times reported? Schwartz is the first to examine the hundreds of letters sent to Orson Welles himself in the days after the broadcast, and his findings challenge the conventional wisdom. Few listeners believed an actual attack was under way. But even so, Schwartz shows that Welles's broadcast became a major scandal, prompting a different kind of mass panic as Americans debated the bewitching power of the radio and the country's vulnerability in a time of crisis. When the debate was over, American broadcasting had changed for good, but not for the better. As Schwartz tells this story, we observe how an atmosphere of natural disaster and impending war permitted broadcasters to create shared live national experiences for the first time. We follow Orson Welles's rise to fame and watch his manic energy and artistic genius at work in the play's hurried yet innovative production. And we trace the present-day popularity of "fake news" back to its source in Welles's show and its many imitators. Schwartz's original research, gifted storytelling, and thoughtful analysis make Broadcast Hysteria a groundbreaking new look at a crucial but little-understood episode in American history.</abstract>
  <subject authority="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
    <topic>Welles, Orson, -- 1915-1985 -- Criticism and interpretation.</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
    <topic>Mass media and public opinion.</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
    <topic>Hoaxes in mass media.</topic>
  </subject>
  <identifier type="isbn">9780809031610</identifier>
  <genre>item</genre>
  <classification>791.447 2 SCH</classification>
</mods>
