<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>FA522.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper type="filing">Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Correspondence Files of William D. Carmichael</titleproper>
        <titleproper>A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Correspondence Files of William D. Carmichael
 <num>FA522</num></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by Brian Bleich and Nancy Ng Tam, The Winthrop Group</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>August 2011</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline>
          <addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline>
          <addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2016-10-02 00:31:51 -0400</date>.</creation>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Correspondence Files of William D. Carmichael</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="aut" source="lcnaf">Ford Foundation</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>FA522</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.8 Cubic Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1971/1989" type="inclusive">1971-1989</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_112f11e866cda048362d9b61cfebd165">William D. Carmichael joined the Foundation in 1968 as Representative in the Brazil office, a position he held until 1971. In July of 1971, he was promoted to Head of the Office of Latin America and the Caribbean. In September of 1977, he was transferred and became Head of the Middle East and Africa office. Dr. Carmichael was promoted to Vice President in charge of the new Developing Countries Program in March of 1981, a position he held until his retirement on September 30, 1989. The collection consists of correspondence files spanning from 1971 to 1989, with a small gap from 1975 through 1976. The files begin with Dr. Carmichael's appointment as head of the Office of Latin America and the Caribbean (OLAC) and continue until his retirement in 1989. During this time he also was head of the Middle East and Africa (MEA) office and Vice President of the Developing Countries Program (DCP). The files include correspondence with and memoranda about grantees, including approvals for grant extensions and modifications. Memoranda in the files also discuss issues regarding Foundation policy such as budget review questions and internal affirmative action policy.</abstract>
      <physdesc id="aspace_05d26b7c2a3e0d1df415613421d3a8b2">
        <extent>(7 Hollinger document boxes)</extent>
      </physdesc>
    </did>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_d2ce011de1d9136f4e79e73fbc524868">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
      <p>Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <userestrict id="aspace_e48a15cd0d34cbc29620e95a7398f504">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
      <p>Completion of a use agreement is required prior to providing scholarly access. See RAC Head of Reference (or applicable designee) for details. Ford Foundation holds title, copyright and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them. The Rockefeller Archive Center has authority to grant permission to cite and publish material from the collection for scholarly purposes. Permission to publish extensive excerpts, or material in its entirety, will be referred to the Ford Foundation.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_e9c4a274484769bfeeaa2a34b730a348">
      <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
      <p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>
    </prefercite>
    <separatedmaterial id="aspace_c6fed1c4a601a2533356f7f1ebe64f05">
      <head>Separated Materials Note</head>
      <p>Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.</p>
    </separatedmaterial>
    <bioghist id="aspace_6616d667406c1c8f63cd84ce12610a0c">
      <head>Organizational History</head>
      <p>The Ford Foundation established the Overseas Development Program, one of its first grant programs, in 1951. Its granting goals were to increase agricultural production, improve health and living conditions, and advance education. India and Pakistan were the focus of the initial grants, with a more limited number of grants issued in Indonesia and Burma. A program for smaller regional and national grants was initiated for the Near East region later that same year.</p>
      <p>As part of a Foundation reorganization in 1966, the Overseas Development Program, along with other international Foundation programs such as Population and International Training and Research, became part of a unified International Division. Following an additional reorganization in 1983, the International Division was eliminated and two program divisions were created—the United States and International Affairs Program (USIAP) and the Developing Countries Program (DCP). During the Foundation reorganization of 1989, the Developing Countries Program was broken down into its regional components, and separate programs were created for individual regions and countries.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <bioghist id="aspace_9bf833309b09b31e06f835ec5eb92a41">
      <head>Biographical Note</head>
      <p>Born on September 5, 1929, Dr. William D. Carmichael received a B.A. in Economics from Yale in 1950. In 1952 he received an M.P.A. in Public and International Affairs and an M.A. in Economics from Princeton University. He received a BLitt from Oxford University in Economics in 1955, and was awarded a PhD in Economics by Princeton in 1959. Between 1962 and 1968, Dr. Carmichael served as Dean of Cornell University's Graduate School of Business and Public Administration.</p>
      <p>Dr. Carmichael joined the Foundation in 1968 as Representative in the Brazil office, a position he held until 1971. In July of 1971, he was promoted to Head of the Office of Latin America and the Caribbean. In September of 1977, he was transferred to and became Head of the Middle East and Africa office. Dr. Carmichael became Vice President in charge of the new Developing Countries Program in March of 1981, a position he held until his retirement on September 30, 1989.</p>
      <p>After his retirement Dr. Carmichael served as Executive Director of Soviet Union and Eastern European Programs for the Institute of International Education from 1989 to 1993. Since 1993, he has worked as an independent consultant to foundations, NGOs, and universities.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <arrangement id="aspace_a3119e44e7f9c3495043de8d2ae94930">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>Records are arranged into one series.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_ac6fb2e8f90769c6f4e4f14132e38768">
      <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
      <p>The collection consists of correspondence files spanning from 1971 to 1989, with a small gap from 1975 through 1976. The files begin with Dr. Carmichael's appointment as head of the Office of Latin America and the Caribbean (OLAC) and continue through to his retirement in 1989. During this time, he also directed the Middle East and Africa (MEA) office and served as Vice President of the Developing Countries Program (DCP). The files include correspondence with and memoranda about grantees, including approvals for grant extensions and modifications. Memoranda in the files also discuss issues regarding Foundation policy such as budget review questions and internal affirmative action policy.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <processinfo id="aspace_a8d95625567033ccdc2f5fa077b47308">
      <head>Processing Information Note</head>
      <p>Dr. Carmichael originally kept his files in strict chronological order. Beginning in October of 1981, he began to keep his correspondence alphabetically in monthly increments.</p>
      <p>The original volume of 6 cubic feet accessioned by the Ford Foundation Archives in 2011 was reduced during processing to 2.8 cubic feet.</p>
      <p>Form rejection letters for unsolicited grant requests were not retained.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_52d73329adaf5623e4164d27ce547aa6">
      <head>Related Collections</head>
      <p>Other information about the Africa and Middle East (AME) Programs can be found in Program Staff Files, 1965-1976, 1987-1994 (FA503).</p>
      <p>Additional information about the Developing Countries Program can be found in the Program Staff Files, 1960-1983. The files were maintained by Elisa Scatena and Richard W. Dye, both of whom reported to Dr. Carmichael as head of DCP. A portion of these files have been transferred to Rockefeller Archive Center as FA528 Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Program Staff Files, 1973-1978.</p>
      <p>Ford Foundation records, Developing Countries Program, Vice President, Office files of William D. Carmichael, 1968-1989, document his oversight of the administration and program activities of Foundation field offices around the world, and of New York-based program staff responsible for grants in developing countries. The files contain correspondence, memoranda, reports, grant proposals, conference materials and Board of Trustees meeting files.
This collection is available for research at the Rockefeller Archive Center. Please see an Archivist for further assistance.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_833b1f68826c5f0a7399e803fab27664">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <bioghist id="aspace_686f861b7816dea007d8df7d57055864">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Segment One: International Activities of the Ford Foundation: An Overview</emph>
      </p>
      <p>The Foundation's aspiration to become a national and international philanthropy for the advancement of human welfare was first formally expressed in the seminal 1949 report of the Gaither Study Committee, &gt;<emph render="italic">Report of the Study for the Ford Foundation on Policy and Program</emph> (RAC Library, call letters 361.7 GAI ), which was commissioned by the Board of Trustees to chart the Foundation’s future. Foundation Trustees launched Ford’s international grantmaking activities in 1950 when they approved the committee’s report and its embrace of peace, democracy, and freedom.  Since then, the Foundation has tackled these goals using a variety of strategies and responding to changing contexts, from the Cold War to the 1989 fall of the Berlin Wall and beyond.</p>
      <p>Toward the Foundation’s aspiration‎al goal, "the establishment of peace", its international activities have comprised a wide range of conceptual approaches and focus areas. These include international affairs, international studies, international understanding, arms control and disarmament, international law, international economic concerns, and overseas development in nearly every region of the world. Three distinct periods emerge for the international grantmaking defined by external contextual changes and internal changes in Foundation leadership and structures: the expansion era of 1950-1965; the transition and restructuring years of 1966-1988; and the post-1989 shift away from Cold War dichotomies.  During each of the distinct historical periods the consistent objectives were: 1) to ensure freedom and democracy in developed countries; 2) to foster education and international understanding in all countries; and 3) to contribute to the social, economic, and political development of less developed countries.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref14_uxb" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Chronological Correspondence Files</unittitle>
          <unitid>I</unitid>
          <unitdate normal="1971/1989" type="inclusive">1971-1974; 1977-1989</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_73291d86e6d2fccce357d1a9fa3e7505">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series contains Dr. Carmichael's chronological correspondence files dating from 1971 to 1989, with a two-year gap between 1975 and 1976. The files from October 1981 to 1989 are arranged in yearly increments and then alphabetically by recipient’s last name.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="aspace_ref15_dmc" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1971 Chron File (1 of 3)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1971/1971" type="inclusive">Jan-Jun 1971</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_03513cc8289dad8a17420a94a2f8b52a" label="Documents (506590.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_10cd4e6c68a1a0a44eaef23c7d1b2ae2" parent="aspace_03513cc8289dad8a17420a94a2f8b52a" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref16_hr4" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1971 Chron File (2 of 3)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1971/1971" type="inclusive">Jul-Oct 1971</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_4a9697b008f51cde059120853809f6eb" label="Documents (506590.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_fe14c3e0adca0d91f1a18e4f4786350e" parent="aspace_4a9697b008f51cde059120853809f6eb" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref17_deo" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1971 Chron File (3 of 3)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1971/1971" type="inclusive">Nov-Dec 1971</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_f69291993588fdc3c19a90807d864d61" label="Documents (506590.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_2ccf18cf1910d358bf1093fd4deb8f11" parent="aspace_f69291993588fdc3c19a90807d864d61" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref18_gxz" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1972 Chron File (1 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">Jan-Mar 1972</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_108b4be2ea98a524f94d7d1c16ef78f7" label="Documents (506590.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_0e758c471bf3e2f71df4d0808e153fa6" parent="aspace_108b4be2ea98a524f94d7d1c16ef78f7" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref19_ual" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1972 Chron File (2 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">Apr-Jun 1972</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_37f4f6dc92cb5432be219bd31f91c7cb" label="Documents (506590.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_30f41a6b7cb2ac0d6140e6590bbc61c7" parent="aspace_37f4f6dc92cb5432be219bd31f91c7cb" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref20_t7x" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1972 Chron File (3 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">Jul-Sep 1972</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_a89a3384f5bf5508859b20253d3325cb" label="Documents (506590.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_67f0b846b18ba25a51f07539b0d86843" parent="aspace_a89a3384f5bf5508859b20253d3325cb" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref21_x42" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1972 Chron File (4 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">Oct-Dec 1972</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_3a4bc71a76761aa6b38cc1fe8da8ad61" label="Documents (506590.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_3683df2cf94c8387d13271974dd7e170" parent="aspace_3a4bc71a76761aa6b38cc1fe8da8ad61" type="folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref22_2hs" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1973 Chron File (1 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">Jan-Mar 1973</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_9421e52bae8155376fa0ca1fd956fe27" label="Documents (506590.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_b2e5287b6b3f0caa1ab2b312fdfc5050" parent="aspace_9421e52bae8155376fa0ca1fd956fe27" type="folder">8</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref23_5wk" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1973 Chron File (2 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">Apr-Jun 1973</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_a1d2099b27cde43ea4f35000f2212d26" label="Documents (506590.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_7b79218ad686d98aff97b7d4a858ddb7" parent="aspace_a1d2099b27cde43ea4f35000f2212d26" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref24_cmd" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1973 Chron File (3 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">Jul-Sep 1973</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_b93f3110203fb62158904d606f7c50e9" label="Documents (506590.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_95d4b13de8415bad5e76fc6fc7dc9b04" parent="aspace_b93f3110203fb62158904d606f7c50e9" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref25_av0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1973 Chron File (4 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">Oct-Dec 1973</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_1ad58e6bab2867f6c169890abfca9e33" label="Documents (506590.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_986cbee7f5f90e8065371ff8ecebcb07" parent="aspace_1ad58e6bab2867f6c169890abfca9e33" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref26_aco" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1974 Chron File (1 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">Jan-Mar 1974</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_c7929c6f448c7649a1a95b0e8a73f896" label="Documents (506590.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_c14d095c06b439560b9144dc29e4df89" parent="aspace_c7929c6f448c7649a1a95b0e8a73f896" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref27_zuw" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1974 Chron File (2 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">Apr-Jun 1974</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d9cc9eda2d0ccd557e3eb584317d4bca" label="Documents (506590.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_872dc2c48f48ba112aab75a3ef8aff4b" parent="aspace_d9cc9eda2d0ccd557e3eb584317d4bca" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref28_rsh" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1974 Chron File (3 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">Jul-Sep 1974</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_0422c0cdec6e38e6635ba46c6fbff155" label="Documents (506590.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_58218f1c06da8eb8e03ef65e18904df3" parent="aspace_0422c0cdec6e38e6635ba46c6fbff155" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref29_mz3" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1974 Chron File (4 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">Oct-Dec 1974</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_f8e021ac09517bebe411ae04b7086a78" label="Documents (506590.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_b9c6c0c3296bb641577ccf075381e3e2" parent="aspace_f8e021ac09517bebe411ae04b7086a78" type="folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref30_wsb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1977 Chron File</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1977/1977" type="inclusive">1977</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_8e4cad47c190436e3d6937dc7ba75be5" label="Documents (506590.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_2a048a65924923315d2dc6ecf51644cd" parent="aspace_8e4cad47c190436e3d6937dc7ba75be5" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref31_685" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1978 Chron File</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1978/1978" type="inclusive">1978</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_eecd9dcca401d1d21aac74757dccf39e" label="Documents (506590.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_12c272386fec8323dc682a1cd543c740" parent="aspace_eecd9dcca401d1d21aac74757dccf39e" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref32_fcz" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1979 Chron File (1 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1979/1979" type="inclusive">Jan-Jul 1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_a939429cab2128344f2d7673b2150022" label="Documents (506590.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_9ace2b1550c22a3fe31b50b68dc0848d" parent="aspace_a939429cab2128344f2d7673b2150022" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref33_wsv" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1979 Chron File (2 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1979/1979" type="inclusive">Aug-Dec 1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_8218c08d16f06d5295ad3193c11054c8" label="Documents (506590.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_21163d6543dd7c2015450130d70ebaae" parent="aspace_8218c08d16f06d5295ad3193c11054c8" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref34_g0k" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1980 Chron File (1 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1980/1980" type="inclusive">Jan-Jun 1980</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_c9ac12f1df9fe23bca044de2dcfe5038" label="Documents (506590.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_0e0a2a6f6c8b1634d6424cd55bd98f7d" parent="aspace_c9ac12f1df9fe23bca044de2dcfe5038" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref35_4bg" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1980 Chron File (2 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1980/1980" type="inclusive">Jul-Dec 1980</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_0dee895b8f228e6e129910b41cc2652c" label="Documents (506590.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_d68f0d4091a9c2c0f6b5eca31717a569" parent="aspace_0dee895b8f228e6e129910b41cc2652c" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref36_l0a" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1981 Chron File</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1981/1981" type="inclusive">Jan-Sep 1981</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_2a06ba5d6bd8b2d9fee79de4904559f6" label="Documents (506590.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="aspace_96a0df65b49067c0d50b406c4bcbe1b5" parent="aspace_2a06ba5d6bd8b2d9fee79de4904559f6" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref37_qyv" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1981-1982 Chron File (alphabetical) (1 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1981/1982" type="inclusive">Oct 1981-Mar 1982</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_ae00209ab811b55597a1688176787603" label="Documents (506590.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="aspace_9ad8a48a11009135322d83762eee0f4a" parent="aspace_ae00209ab811b55597a1688176787603" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref38_rwf" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1982 Chron File (alphabetical) (2 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1982/1982" type="inclusive">Apr-Jun 1982</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_b77898fdf8ad0e4bec0600405b5f53c6" label="Documents (506590.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="aspace_e5121614ca0fc0d67937039f930496b5" parent="aspace_b77898fdf8ad0e4bec0600405b5f53c6" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref39_exz" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1982 Chron File (alphabetical) (3 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1982/1982" type="inclusive">Jul-Sep 1982</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_4abcbd4ea0d3a4f0b14cd95c6c959aeb" label="Documents (506590.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="aspace_1b6efaa2bd9cf43824a6996e2f856dd2" parent="aspace_4abcbd4ea0d3a4f0b14cd95c6c959aeb" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref40_9ur" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1982 Chron File (alphabetical) (4 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1982/1982" type="inclusive">Oct-Dec 1982</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_fafa438c0eb5dd77718b31109924cc81" label="Documents (506590.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="aspace_51f10361cbf108e5017810ca60a8bb9c" parent="aspace_fafa438c0eb5dd77718b31109924cc81" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref41_49d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1983 Chron File (A-L) (1 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1983/1983" type="inclusive">Jan-Jun 1983</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_affae1f662908872b7853c6cd4ecee9e" label="Documents (506590.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="aspace_b2c2d41613a4054e7920adedc2aebbe9" parent="aspace_affae1f662908872b7853c6cd4ecee9e" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref42_g6f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1983 Chron File (M-Z) (2 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1983/1983" type="inclusive">Jan-Jun 1983</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_a9ccdbc05f9b9971b5a4fe1e98c3e9bb" label="Documents (506590.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="aspace_00908b2c902dfeadb3ebd93cb7c7010b" parent="aspace_a9ccdbc05f9b9971b5a4fe1e98c3e9bb" type="folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref43_ku7" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1983 Chron File (A-L) (1 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1983/1983" type="inclusive">Jul-Dec 1983</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_21d6d417709afc568587c6b4109f5d68" label="Documents (506590.5.318)" type="box">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_37824b538f02d58e6a27f548eeeccc0d" parent="aspace_21d6d417709afc568587c6b4109f5d68" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref44_tme" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1983 Chron File (M-Z) (2 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1983/1983" type="inclusive">Jul-Dec 1983</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_4205dc1363f4c54f3ee0b6c65d652ee2" label="Documents (506590.5.318)" type="box">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_9c0728f316cb5983edbb8e9a706dede9" parent="aspace_4205dc1363f4c54f3ee0b6c65d652ee2" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref45_q2h" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1984 Chron File (A-L) (1 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1984/1984" type="inclusive">Jan-Jun 1984</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_501f843c560ee8943dcfbf4a1f40f61a" label="Documents (506590.5.318)" type="box">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_7beb61aab4c7315924f4e5b2327ec663" parent="aspace_501f843c560ee8943dcfbf4a1f40f61a" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref46_wtx" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1984 Chron File (M-Z) (2 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1984/1984" type="inclusive">Jan-Jun 1984</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_715f1ec15e3316e528990b879b3cf177" label="Documents (506590.5.318)" type="box">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_fb4005bf807fff24c4e39e45277186a5" parent="aspace_715f1ec15e3316e528990b879b3cf177" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref47_fgu" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1984 Chron File (A-L) (1 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1984/1984" type="inclusive">Jul-Dec 1984</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_cf86bbf3a13c7b48a32d57643ff880fa" label="Documents (506590.5.318)" type="box">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_722aab2344aed060c9adb9c1e13136de" parent="aspace_cf86bbf3a13c7b48a32d57643ff880fa" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref48_to0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1984 Chron File (M-Z) (2 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1984/1984" type="inclusive">Jul-Dec 1984</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_b37c888fdf55e06a99ff18a9c8c7dbb9" label="Documents (506590.5.318)" type="box">5</container>
            <container id="aspace_5db18b852c8a12d7d14790f91572bf54" parent="aspace_b37c888fdf55e06a99ff18a9c8c7dbb9" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref49_ua7" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1985 Chron File (alphabetical)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1985/1985" type="inclusive">Jan-May 1985</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_98028a0b34dbd6e76cce39b3533342da" label="Documents (506590.6.318)" type="box">6</container>
            <container id="aspace_e00c91baf63cf7a23cefcc3643e35ea0" parent="aspace_98028a0b34dbd6e76cce39b3533342da" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref50_yrf" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1985 Chron File (A-L) (1 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1985/1985" type="inclusive">Jun-Dec 1985</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_281c4ccab913a8c4f79b2ce10ac444b5" label="Documents (506590.6.318)" type="box">6</container>
            <container id="aspace_afe1b7ecf9b00dc80b64585a7cbe1d37" parent="aspace_281c4ccab913a8c4f79b2ce10ac444b5" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref51_zyj" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1985 Chron File (M-Z) (2 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1985/1985" type="inclusive">Jun-Dec 1985</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_313d747c4160a11b99fb31e8b6af7226" label="Documents (506590.6.318)" type="box">6</container>
            <container id="aspace_beef91c3bc6738c5ad242393ea237eaa" parent="aspace_313d747c4160a11b99fb31e8b6af7226" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref52_vd9" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1986 Chron File (A-L) (1 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1986/1986" type="inclusive">Jan-Aug 1986</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_72c49dd8f63f62c3325fd4779ccc2c75" label="Documents (506590.6.318)" type="box">6</container>
            <container id="aspace_ebb59bf243d35931f4cfadab79a2b63b" parent="aspace_72c49dd8f63f62c3325fd4779ccc2c75" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref53_3wv" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1986 Chron File (M-Z) (2 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1986/1986" type="inclusive">Jan-Aug 1986</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_56cf3b3ca5b3409b2e5f9f6dac7dbaed" label="Documents (506590.6.318)" type="box">6</container>
            <container id="aspace_c2a07845c4efc94c4d6a16c4b5111178" parent="aspace_56cf3b3ca5b3409b2e5f9f6dac7dbaed" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref54_iwv" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1986 Chron File (alphabetical)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1986/1986" type="inclusive">Sep-Dec 1986</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_ea06dda6459e9b212077be4c3ad81c98" label="Documents (506590.6.318)" type="box">6</container>
            <container id="aspace_eed77795762dd4c07eb807d851dc3d3f" parent="aspace_ea06dda6459e9b212077be4c3ad81c98" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref55_be1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1987 Chron File (alphabetical) (1 of 3)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1987/1987" type="inclusive">Jan-Mar 1987</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_955e777fde5e8273d06b1ed4479aaeaa" label="Documents (506590.7.318)" type="box">7</container>
            <container id="aspace_b8fe19f295add6b9a2d38379abdc315e" parent="aspace_955e777fde5e8273d06b1ed4479aaeaa" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref56_5un" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1987 Chron File (alphabetical) (2 of 3)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1987/1987" type="inclusive">Apr-Aug 1987</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_f7fa2759ef3f78d44bb057a88b82dcf4" label="Documents (506590.7.318)" type="box">7</container>
            <container id="aspace_c591fef9d8f449d90d4919e23363c8cc" parent="aspace_f7fa2759ef3f78d44bb057a88b82dcf4" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref57_eyk" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1987 Chron File (alphabetical) (3 of 3)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1987/1987" type="inclusive">Sep-Dec 1987</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_180f3f0df1ddea6d7c011fbd2650b30e" label="Documents (506590.7.318)" type="box">7</container>
            <container id="aspace_cd3011066033739289f7e86a0b994a65" parent="aspace_180f3f0df1ddea6d7c011fbd2650b30e" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref58_t17" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1988 Chron File (alphabetical) (1 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1988/1988" type="inclusive">Jan-Jul 1988</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_a3f0e490c4ad3ef48ee5b065546332fe" label="Documents (506590.7.318)" type="box">7</container>
            <container id="aspace_a783a1ac84783804aef0a95a1291224b" parent="aspace_a3f0e490c4ad3ef48ee5b065546332fe" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref59_e44" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1988 Chron File (alphabetical) (2 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1988/1988" type="inclusive">Aug-Dec 1988</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_eb188d80747bd7ed2944f7574f7d2792" label="Documents (506590.7.318)" type="box">7</container>
            <container id="aspace_80830851f58dc57ecde5596723d4c97f" parent="aspace_eb188d80747bd7ed2944f7574f7d2792" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref60_bkb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1989 Chron File (alphabetical)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1989/1989" type="inclusive">Jan-Sep 1989</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_c594ed3fc59b4e10a752df47c2bf6619" label="Documents (506590.7.318)" type="box">7</container>
            <container id="aspace_277bb829d8db4435614bd35b316cae7b" parent="aspace_c594ed3fc59b4e10a752df47c2bf6619" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
