<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="under_revision" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>FA570.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper type="filing">Ford Foundation records, International Division, Population Program, Office Files of Robert S. Wickham</titleproper>
        <titleproper>A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Population Program, Office Files of Robert S. Wickham
 <num>FA570</num></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by Rachel Moskowitz and Brian Bleich, The Winthrop Group</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>September 2011</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline>
          <addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline>
          <addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2016-11-03 12:39:08 -0400</date>.</creation>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Ford Foundation records, International Division, Population Program, Office Files of Robert S. Wickham</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="aut" source="lcnaf">Ford Foundation</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>FA570</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.2 Cubic Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1964/1970" type="inclusive">1964-1970</unitdate>
      <abstract id="356e555827731a47145c88dd047e94ad">The Population Program was created in 1963 to better facilitate research and more efficiently handle grant proposals pertaining to the health and welfare of communities in the United States and abroad. The Population program became a sub-division of the Foundation’s International Division in 1966. In 1981, it again gained independent program status. Due to subsequent reorganizations the Population Program now falls under the purview of the Sexuality and Reproductive Health and Rights division of the Education, Creativity and Free Expression program. Robert Saunderson Wickham joined the Ford Foundation in 1956 as a staff associate for the South and Southeast Asia program. During his tenure at the Foundation, he served as a regional representative and a program director, and by his retirement had been promoted to Program Officer of the International Division’s Population Office. This small collection of his papers contains materials from two conferences, the Foundation’s Population Conference held in Lake Como, Italy in April 1968 and the Family Planning Evaluation Conference held in Marino, Italy from April 20-24, 1970. The files include agendas, published and unpublished papers, and discussion topics and notes from one session of the Foundation’s 1968 conference and materials from all twelve sessions of the 1970 conference.</abstract>
      <physdesc id="b56509fe0fd26375aa89090bda04856c">
        <extent>(3 Hollinger document boxes)</extent>
      </physdesc>
    </did>
    <acqinfo id="2686e23679f2581bbc1b66cfa7381a87">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
      <p>Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <userestrict id="eb5865697c668e2399fe662e4b6aedca">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
      <p>Completion of a use agreement is required prior to providing scholarly access. See RAC Head of Reference (or applicable designee) for details. Ford Foundation holds title, copyright and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them. The Rockefeller Archive Center has authority to grant permission to cite and publish material from the collection for scholarly purposes. Permission to publish extensive excerpts, or material in its entirety, will be referred to the Ford Foundation.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="7133b66fe755e97055d4dfef8a009261">
      <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
      <p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="41a5337a9ccc9d454e5ae88cc84a24d2">
      <head>Processing Information Note</head>
      <p>The original volume of one cubic foot accessioned by the Ford Foundation in 2011 was transferred to three Hollinger document boxes during processing. The collection consists entirely of conference materials. All documents were retained.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <arrangement id="e5150f07f9962559be8c14f80034b72f">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>The collection contains one series.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <scopecontent id="c1e84304bfb3d297ba3ff52140e3e8ac">
      <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
      <p>This small collection of office files of Robert Wickham consists of materials from two conferences, the Foundation’s Population Conference in Lake Como, Italy from April 8-11, 1968 and the Family Planning Evaluation Conference in Marino, Italy from April 20-24, 1970. The collection contains files from one session of the Foundation’s 1968 conference and from all twelve sessions of the 1970 conference.</p>
      <p>Reports written by Ford Foundation employees on reproductive health and population control form the bulk of the collection. They address the demographic effects of family planning programs, the awareness and use of contraceptives, the application of computer-generated surveys and software options for tabulating and monitoring family planning programs, and a myriad of fertility-related studies carried out in the United States and abroad.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <bioghist id="e96f12691d76c4147acea5267812ec5c">
      <head>Biographical Note</head>
      <p>Robert Saunderson Wickham was born on May 11, 1925. Mr. Wickham joined the U.S. Army in 1943 and served until 1946. Following the end of World War II and his service in the Army, Mr. Wickham enrolled at Haverford College. In 1950, he graduated cum laude with a Bachelor of Arts in Political Science and as a member of the national honor society, Phi Beta Kappa. From 1950 to 1952, Mr. Wickham worked for the U.S. Department of the Interior as a management trainee and a foreign affairs analyst for the Division of International Activities. From 1952 to 1953, the U.S. Technical Cooperation Administration employed him as chief of their training branch and as a program and budget officer for activities in Tehran, Iran. From 1954 through the spring of 1956, Mr. Wickham was involved in highly classified work for the U.S. government.</p>
      <p>Mr. Wickham joined the Ford Foundation’s Overseas Development Division as a staff associate for the South and Southeast Asia region in April 1956. In October 1957, he transitioned into the role of Program Assistant for the Latin America and the Caribbean (LAC) region. From 1958 to 1959, Mr. Wickham attended Harvard University’s Kennedy School of Government where he earned a Master of Public Administration in economic development and, in October 1960, received a promotion to Program Associate of LAC. He became the Foundation’s representative to Colombia, Venezuela, and Peru in September 1962, and in May 1965 his responsibilities expanded when he became Representative of Mexico, all of Central America, and Venezuela. The following year, in October 1966, Mr. Wickham rose to Associate Director of Latin America and the Caribbean, and, in September 1968, became the Program Officer for the Latin American region. Mr. Wickham transferred to the International Division’s Population Office as its Program Officer in August 1971.</p>
      <p>Mr. Wickham retired from the Foundation on June 27, 1983 and moved to Santa Fe, New Mexico.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <bioghist id="2c3cb3e5ec015cf38ef7edd73e25a46b">
      <head>Organizational History</head>
      <p>The Ford Foundation’s Population Program was created in 1963 to provide improved support for research and to more efficiently handle grant proposals pertaining to the health and welfare of communities in the United States and abroad. In 1966, the Population program became a sub-division of the Foundation’s International Division and remained so until 1981 when it again gained independent program status. Following a reorganization of the Foundation in 1992, the newly formed Reproductive Health and Population program absorbed the existing Population program. The ASSETS program (Asset Building and Community Development Program) was introduced in 1997 and included a subdivision focused on Human Development and Reproductive Health. Though the Human Development and Reproductive Health program was canceled in 2002, the Education, Creativity and Free Expression program restored the Foundation’s work in population health in 2009 with the creation of a subdivision focused on Sexuality and Reproductive Health and Rights.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <separatedmaterial id="3d6ad935156babe49c20e280d9a3ff3b">
      <head>Separated Materials</head>
      <p>Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.</p>
    </separatedmaterial>
    <accessrestrict id="9987199ade67c4f9d03fd24363cc422f">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <bioghist id="20974016a7e4b38c5a8e620a0c2906b8">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Segment One: International Activities of the Ford Foundation: An Overview</emph>
      </p>
      <p>The Foundation's aspiration to become a national and international philanthropy for the advancement of human welfare was first formally expressed in the seminal 1949 report of the Gaither Study Committee, <emph render="italic">Report of the Study for the Ford Foundation on Policy and Program</emph> (RAC Library, call letters 361.7 GAI ), which was commissioned by the Board of Trustees to chart the Foundation’s future. Foundation Trustees launched Ford’s international grantmaking activities in 1950 when they approved the committee’s report and its embrace of peace, democracy, and freedom.  Since then, the Foundation has tackled these goals using a variety of strategies and responding to changing contexts, from the Cold War to the 1989 fall of the Berlin Wall and beyond.</p>
      <p>Toward the Foundation’s aspiration‎al goal, "the establishment of peace", its international activities have comprised a wide range of conceptual approaches and focus areas. These include international affairs, international studies, international understanding, arms control and disarmament, international law, international economic concerns, and overseas development in nearly every region of the world. Three distinct periods emerge for the international grantmaking defined by external contextual changes and internal changes in Foundation leadership and structures: the expansion era of 1950-1965; the transition and restructuring years of 1966-1988; and the post-1989 shift away from Cold War dichotomies.  During each of the distinct historical periods the consistent objectives were: 1) to ensure freedom and democracy in developed countries; 2) to foster education and international understanding in all countries; and 3) to contribute to the social, economic, and political development of less developed countries.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <dsc>
      <c id="ref14_b86" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Population and Family Planning Conferences</unittitle>
          <unitid>I</unitid>
          <unitdate normal="1964/1970" type="inclusive">1964-1970</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="0533e7830a2445b20e7dcfd18fd5796d">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The records of the two conferences comprise this series and contain agendas, a list of attendees, unpublished background and position papers, published articles, and discussion topics provided to participants of both the 1968 Population Conference and the 1970 Family Planning Evaluation Conference.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="ref15_j63" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1968 Family Planning Conference (1 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1964/1968" type="inclusive">1964-1968</unitdate>
            <container id="2f9b0c805dc1dc81ffcbc7c67df10396" label="Documents (510403.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="92eab46ff57ef9139723a36635429e0a" parent="2f9b0c805dc1dc81ffcbc7c67df10396" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref16_yfx" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1968 Family Planning Conference (2 of 2) (reports separated)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1964/1968" type="inclusive">1964-1968</unitdate>
            <container id="93ca2f047bf53494999eda48143f0662" label="Documents (510403.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="635ceaebc6d8ee220b31987dea140d10" parent="93ca2f047bf53494999eda48143f0662" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref17_r3p" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Marino Family Planning Evaluation Conference (April 1970) -- Sessions 1, 2</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1969/1970" type="inclusive">1969-1970</unitdate>
            <container id="ccd0bd6bd225549d31ab432e703fe37e" label="Documents (510403.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="420d4a761054d1157c3786fedf9c155b" parent="ccd0bd6bd225549d31ab432e703fe37e" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref18_rsw" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Marino Family Planning Evaluation Conference (April 1970) -- Session 3</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1967/1970" type="inclusive">1967-1970</unitdate>
            <container id="f886969fb87ac7a8e3094d52da0c0a16" label="Documents (510403.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="6e55c8ed1df118db963c83765a8e3c96" parent="f886969fb87ac7a8e3094d52da0c0a16" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref19_akw" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Marino Family Planning Evaluation Conference (April 1970) -- Session 4</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1967/1970" type="inclusive">1967-1970</unitdate>
            <container id="b71d43192df5c5af5a0db44270819825" label="Documents (510403.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="c91012b7baab042069ab5ef8b5dc63ca" parent="b71d43192df5c5af5a0db44270819825" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref20_3om" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Marino Family Planning Evaluation Conference (April 1970) -- Session 5</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1967/1970" type="inclusive">1967-1970</unitdate>
            <container id="e67c8c5514db82e517253f40f7f46b7a" label="Documents (510403.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="93a1110539d513c272bd7333521c3a0f" parent="e67c8c5514db82e517253f40f7f46b7a" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref21_jlh" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Marino Family Planning Evaluation Conference (April 1970) -- Session 6</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1968/1970" type="inclusive">1968-1970</unitdate>
            <container id="5281b9c5c8eaf0942d5c2126aac630f4" label="Documents (510403.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="65d57f3b1624282cb06714e290ed080d" parent="5281b9c5c8eaf0942d5c2126aac630f4" type="folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref22_k9y" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Marino Family Planning Evaluation Conference (April 1970) -- Session 7 (folder 1 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1970" type="inclusive">1965-1970</unitdate>
            <container id="d8a3b1e0473d748e7e00dda80f0de252" label="Documents (510403.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aa326a611110361745daea19bd15ed30" parent="d8a3b1e0473d748e7e00dda80f0de252" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref23_6et" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Marino Family Planning Evaluation Conference (April 1970) -- Session 7 (folder 2 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1970" type="inclusive">1965-1970</unitdate>
            <container id="5cb302dd92e8d7c0012bb761167011d7" label="Documents (510403.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="6748184e03c922e46dfcc16e29c65023" parent="5cb302dd92e8d7c0012bb761167011d7" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref24_3xg" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Marino Family Planning Evaluation Conference (April 1970) -- Session 7 (folder 3 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1970" type="inclusive">1965-1970</unitdate>
            <container id="d4871793d1a9c7d917ae142d8a648c23" label="Documents (510403.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="6e99bd10946a0d7bd517537bc2268d6f" parent="d4871793d1a9c7d917ae142d8a648c23" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref25_gls" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Marino Family Planning Evaluation Conference (April 1970) -- Session 7 (folder 4 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1970" type="inclusive">1965-1970</unitdate>
            <container id="9babd60fc5974f0c45249d4bf3ec127c" label="Documents (510403.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="475db152976f13d21c1b7690c72e2494" parent="9babd60fc5974f0c45249d4bf3ec127c" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref26_xnn" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Marino Family Planning Evaluation Conference (April 1970) -- Session 8</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1970" type="inclusive">1965-1970</unitdate>
            <container id="b726c72d6ba19d9582c999e29cf31dc5" label="Documents (510403.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="7be1bfd41bf845688dc55ad87644f734" parent="b726c72d6ba19d9582c999e29cf31dc5" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref27_7b2" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Marino Family Planning Evaluation Conference (April 1970) -- Session 9 (folder 1 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1967/1970" type="inclusive">1967-1970</unitdate>
            <container id="b0c87fe738e3d44865c0fc28092730bd" label="Documents (510403.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="4ed57ba2fd91fb72fa8486b77b6c9a16" parent="b0c87fe738e3d44865c0fc28092730bd" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref28_sou" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Marino Family Planning Evaluation Conference (April 1970) -- Session 9 (folder 2 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1967/1970" type="inclusive">1967-1970</unitdate>
            <container id="0d83441043e5681ca2135ba5ff230df2" label="Documents (510403.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="2ea52ee9f5a4d955445f019cb3dbc07f" parent="0d83441043e5681ca2135ba5ff230df2" type="folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref29_5e8" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Marino Family Planning Evaluation Conference (April 1970) -- Session 10 (folder 1 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1968/1970" type="inclusive">1968-1970</unitdate>
            <container id="07713be4af50abb9b1925ab506f28684" label="Documents (510403.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aa504ebfef717ff8b8fc143bcf4d74eb" parent="07713be4af50abb9b1925ab506f28684" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref30_f1f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Marino Family Planning Evaluation Conference (April 1970) -- Session 10 (folder 2 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1968/1970" type="inclusive">1968-1970</unitdate>
            <container id="c552cc92960de0409eb791b4fa503833" label="Documents (510403.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="d53f88740d957b1f4d476803e71bcd9d" parent="c552cc92960de0409eb791b4fa503833" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ref31_qdo" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Marino Family Planning Evaluation Conference (April 1970) -- Sessions 11, 12</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1970" type="inclusive">1966-1970</unitdate>
            <container id="c443bd26147e2273a5ac8cd579a046fa" label="Documents (510403.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="d3bcb715d2cce2444911904fd590d0c9" parent="c443bd26147e2273a5ac8cd579a046fa" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
