<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>FA552.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper type="filing">Ford Foundation records, International Division, Asia and Pacific, Office Files of Reed Hertford</titleproper>
        <titleproper>A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Asia and Pacific, Office Files of Reed Hertford
 <num>FA552</num></titleproper>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline>
          <addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline>
          <addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2016-10-02 00:07:22 -0400</date>.</creation>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Ford Foundation records, International Division, Asia and Pacific, Office Files of Reed Hertford</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="aut" source="lcnaf">Ford Foundation</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>FA552</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 Cubic Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1952/1981" type="inclusive">1952-1981</unitdate>
    </did>
    <processinfo id="aspace_7bacb4cdd03cd7515d662f60389ba26f">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Level 1 Minimal Processing has been conducted to establish basic intellectual and physical control of the material and assess immediate preservation and conservation needs. Material remains as received, in original folders and storage boxes.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <userestrict id="aspace_8681218f727c684fa57afba8ff29485e">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
      <p>Completion of a use agreement is required prior to providing scholarly access. See RAC Head of Reference (or applicable designee) for details. Ford Foundation holds title, copyright and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them. The Rockefeller Archive Center has authority to grant permission to cite and publish material from the collection for scholarly purposes. Permission to publish extensive excerpts, or material in its entirety, will be referred to the Ford Foundation.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_72e794326cec37a589efc7c95ba9a1c8">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
      <p>Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_369b66de5d2b790a5f6ffb89ff7b4498">
      <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
      <p>General citation: Rockefeller Archive Center, Ford Foundation records, Title of applicable records, Box number, Folder number and/or Folder Title</p>
      <p>Preferred citation for Ford Foundation Grants: Rockefeller Archive Center, Ford Foundation records, Grants, Grant #</p>
      <p>Preferred citation for Ford Foundation Unpublished Reports: Rockefeller Archive Center, Ford Foundation records, Unpublished Reports, Report #, Box number</p>
    </prefercite>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_cb8230729dbf4632731ba97969aeb64f">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <arrangement id="aspace_45b57deceb16b789d091d379ea1977c6">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>Arranged in 3 series:
1. Correspondence.
2. Trip, Conference Files.
3. Subject Files.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_8213ced8c5bef6d66605ea4ef3de43d4">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>Primarily contains Subject Files and Trip and Conference Files, with a selection of general correspondence (1980-1981).</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <bioghist id="aspace_438a7548f0678250c9dd288f0aaf2688">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Segment One: International Activities of the Ford Foundation: An Overview</emph>
      </p>
      <p>The Foundation's aspiration to become a national and international philanthropy for the advancement of human welfare was first formally expressed in the seminal 1949 report of the Gaither Study Committee, &gt;<emph render="italic">Report of the Study for the Ford Foundation on Policy and Program</emph> (RAC Library, call letters 361.7 GAI ), which was commissioned by the Board of Trustees to chart the Foundation’s future. Foundation Trustees launched Ford’s international grantmaking activities in 1950 when they approved the committee’s report and its embrace of peace, democracy, and freedom.  Since then, the Foundation has tackled these goals using a variety of strategies and responding to changing contexts, from the Cold War to the 1989 fall of the Berlin Wall and beyond.</p>
      <p>Toward the Foundation’s aspiration‎al goal, "the establishment of peace", its international activities have comprised a wide range of conceptual approaches and focus areas. These include international affairs, international studies, international understanding, arms control and disarmament, international law, international economic concerns, and overseas development in nearly every region of the world. Three distinct periods emerge for the international grantmaking defined by external contextual changes and internal changes in Foundation leadership and structures: the expansion era of 1950-1965; the transition and restructuring years of 1966-1988; and the post-1989 shift away from Cold War dichotomies.  During each of the distinct historical periods the consistent objectives were: 1) to ensure freedom and democracy in developed countries; 2) to foster education and international understanding in all countries; and 3) to contribute to the social, economic, and political development of less developed countries.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <bioghist id="aspace_2948dfecc03dac6a914897ba1ee6d406">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Segment 2.  Period Sketch - The Expansion Era 1950-1965</emph>
      </p>
      <p>The Ford Foundation’s expansion era (1950-1965) began when the Gaither Study Committee Report placed “peace” as the area of top priority for the Foundation and set the Ford Foundation on a global course.  Board Chair Henry Ford II writing in the 1951 Annual Report of the Foundation, identified “the danger of war” as the “the prime threat to human welfare today.” Under the leadership of the three Ford Foundation presidents in this period-- Paul Hoffman, H. Rowan Gaither and Henry Heald--and several key trustees, notably the two seriatim chairs, John J. McCloy and Julius A. Stratton, the Foundation programs were largely informed by the post-World War II desire to avoid nuclear war and promote greater understanding among the world’s peoples, strengthening of the United Nations, and enhancing both private and public American participation in world affairs. The strong board presence of university presidents and former leaders of postwar reconstruction efforts in Europe also helped to inform Ford’s approach to building the field of peace and international security in the United States and encouraged extensive overseas activities.</p>
      <p>For example, the first three presidents of the expanded Foundation ranged from government and business leadership experience to academic and nonprofit: Paul Hoffman (at Ford, 1950-1953) ran the Marshall Plan in Europe; H. Rowan Gaither Staffer (1948-1953), President (1953-1956) and Trustee (1956-1958) had MIT and Rand experience; Henry Heald, former president, Illinois Institute of Technology and New York University, President (1956-1966). The trustees also ran the leadership gamut from government and nonprofits to academic: Trustee John J. McCloy (from 1953; chair, 1959-1965) was assistant Secretary of War during World War II and chairman of the Council on Foreign Relations; and Trustee Julius A. Stratton (Trustee from 1955; chair, 1966-1970) was president of MIT.</p>
      <p>When Ford became an international foundation in 1950, it had a small staff and operated through separate funds. The expansive period in the 1950s and 1960s resulted in a large number of field offices, which increased Ford’s global footprint. Support focused on a mix of US university-based programs for research and training; think-tanks for policy-oriented meetings and policy research; and action projects specifically in less developed countries. The Foundation’s focus on peace, freedom, and democracy played out against the Cold War backdrop for scientific and military competition between the United States, the Soviet Union and China.</p>
      <p>Under President Hoffman, the Foundation’s work was organized by the areas identified in the Gaither Committee Report: Area One, the Establishment of Peace; Area Two, The Strengthening of Democracy; Area Three, The Strengthening of the Economy; Area Four, Education in a Democratic Society; and Area Five, Individual Behavior and Human Relations.</p>
      <p>Program differentiation began in the Gaither era. When he began in 1953, he introduced the following programs, with international work under nearly all of them: International Programs, Public Affairs Programs, Program in Economic Development and Administration (mainly U.S. based), Education Program, The TV-Radio Workshop, and Behavioral Sciences Program. In 1954, the Foundation gave prominence to the international work explicitly through changing the program names and separating international affairs and overseas development. The 1954 program names were: The Advancement of Education, Education for Democracy, Increasing Knowledge of Foreign Areas, Economic Development and Administration, the Behavioral Sciences, and Overseas Development.  In 1955, Increasing Knowledge of Foreign Areas became Increasing International Understanding. In 1956, the last year of the Gaither presidency, the program roster read: Education in the United States, The Behavioral Sciences, Public Affairs, Hospital Aid (only in the U.S.), Economic Development and Administration, International Understanding, and Overseas Development. Names changed but the program focus often remained the same.</p>
      <p>President Heald maintained the areas of international interest of Hoffman and Gaither. The International Affairs program housed the programs based in the United States, Europe and Japan, with a few activities linking American and developing countries institutions. The Overseas Training and Research Program took over the efforts to increase American understanding of international issues.  From 1957-1959, an International Legal Studies program, run from New York, helped build law programs in developing countries. Starting in 1959, the Overseas Development program comprised all the regional and country offices. In fiscal year 1964, Heald convinced the trustees to add a new focus on population, with grants both in the United States and overseas.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <bioghist id="aspace_87de938c211411dd06b26f1a90a47b31">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Segment 2.  Period Summary - The Expansion Era 1950-1965</emph>
      </p>
      <p>With the ever-increasing budget and trustee willingness to invade capital, presidents Hoffman, Gaither and Heald oversaw vast growth in the Foundation's international activities in the United States, other developed countries and developing countries. Activities crossed disciplines, institutions, and national boundaries, although few crossed intra-foundation boundaries. Under the three presidents, Foundation staff in various domestic and international offices from New York interacted with the regional and country offices headed by representatives. Usually in this period, however, these offices in fact worked more closely with local governments than with New York staff, reinforcing the commitment to locally led social and economic development in less-developed countries.</p>
      <p>The shared values of this early period reflected as much the continuing competition between the Communist and capitalist worlds as the concerns about maintaining peace. The Cold War provided the contextual continuity for grantmaking on the core themes of increasing American understanding of the rest of the world, building and strengthening connections not only with European and Asian democracies but also with Eastern European countries, the Soviet Union, China, and Cuba.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref76_cac" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitid>I</unitid>
          <unitdate normal="1980/1981" type="inclusive">1980-1981</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref8_wek" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1980 Chronological Correspondence/Memoranda, A-M</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">May-Dec 1980</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_c1f6a1c99efe751af0e01bf2fb97817e" label="Mixed Materials (508369.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref9_ntf" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1980 Chronological Correspondence/Memoranda, N-Z</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">May-Dec 1980</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_684bcb6502856d7d34766b752d551ffe" label="Mixed Materials (508369.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref10_an5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1980-1981 Chronological Correspondence/Memoranda, A-B</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Dec 1980-1981</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_2e82253e09823594b913cddd149aab72" label="Mixed Materials (508369.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref11_zhb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1980-1981 Chronological Correspondence/Memoranda, C-G</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Dec 1980-1981</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_98948dfe5897a26a9c1c70418f0496dc" label="Mixed Materials (508369.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref12_xfp" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1980-1981 Chronological Correspondence/Memoranda, H-O</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Dec 1980-1981</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_b4bc683c8d909079528e17c3f80ede01" label="Mixed Materials (508369.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref13_i4d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1980-1981 Chronological Correspondence/Memoranda, P-R</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Dec 1980-1981</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_8a62f8c7fe6dd67c23d0b2fd5b429091" label="Mixed Materials (508369.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref14_13x" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1980-1981 Chronological Correspondence/Memoranda, S-T</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Dec 1980-1981</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_b7f454ff822be79399f20cded8dc54cb" label="Mixed Materials (508369.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref15_o97" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>1980-1981 Chronological Correspondence/Memoranda, U-Z</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Dec 1980-1981</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_1059beafb51eada779777a2e084b6b41" label="Mixed Materials (508369.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref16_yzc" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Reed Hertford -- Correspondence and Memoranda (misc)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1980</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_b40031dcc1f8ed0cff9ec90e60028ea5" label="Mixed Materials (508369.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref77_9zy" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Trip, Conference Files</unittitle>
          <unitid>II</unitid>
          <unitdate normal="1976/1981" type="inclusive">1976-1981</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref18_ku9" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>John Gerhart Latin America Trip -- Report, Memoranda, Related Documents Re: Latin America</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1978</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_5cb30e466669c71a70f86860cea5a06f" label="Mixed Materials (508379.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref19_o2j" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Mexico Trip (mid-February 1978)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1976-1978</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_916e6064bc4b76c59787bbcb0ae02bbd" label="Mixed Materials (508379.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref20_npg" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>European Trip (March 2-11, 1978)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1978</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_a1e4155ed246a3662621662afec7e21d" label="Mixed Materials (508379.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref21_psw" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Toronto Trip (April 12-14, 1978) Re: Robert Burke Dissertation</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1978</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_c9d7b3ff7ac9aa40daefbf27d5b76526" label="Mixed Materials (508379.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref22_hch" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Princeton Meeting (Sep 7-9, 1978) Re: Office of Latin America and the Caribbean Agriculture and Rural Development</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1978</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_b41d48e95b21c489fdefcdec354b14c5" label="Mixed Materials (508379.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref23_irg" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Asia Trip (Sep-Oct 1978)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Sep-Oct 1978</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_398fcb348627595ec1148732b585f627" label="Mixed Materials (508379.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref24_evk" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Latin America and the Caribbean Representatives' Meeting (Nov 13-15, 1978) - Program and Budget Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1978</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_ace77646c7735acf98a37aa34eb53a18" label="Mixed Materials (508379.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref25_wsh" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>International Division Conference (Mar 21-24, 1979) -- Planning Materials</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_748b36106d4e9b7f64bfa1a200fc8a3a" label="Mixed Materials (508379.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref26_fcp" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>International Division Conference (Mar 21-24, 1979) -- Papers (1 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1975-1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_4594b16806a2c10ef3ea052bdd68c389" label="Mixed Materials (508379.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref27_vnm" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>International Division Conference (Mar 21-24, 1979) -- Papers (2 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1975-1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_5cb6098d77ec97bfb997ab463bc27717" label="Mixed Materials (508379.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref28_cea" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Working Group on Food Security Issues in Asia and the Pacific, First Meeting, East-West Center (Honolulu, June 18-30, 1979) -- Papers (1 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_83f05ce500b02e81adfd19ff974501ce" label="Mixed Materials (508379.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref29_x00" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Working Group on Food Security Issues in Asia and the Pacific, First Meeting, East-West Center (Honolulu, June 18-30, 1979) -- Papers (2 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d0cb1b55fb98f8a1c706727a0626c1cb" label="Mixed Materials (508379.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref30_ko0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Agricultural Development Council (ADC) and International Crops Research Institute for the Semi-Arid Tropics (ICRISAT) Conference on Rural Labor Markets (Aug 22-24, 1979) -- Papers (1 of 3)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_74ab8b739b203ce94582143a08c8205f" label="Mixed Materials (508379.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref31_yf2" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Agricultural Development Council (ADC) and International Crops Research Institute for the Semi-Arid Tropics (ICRISAT) Conference on Rural Labor Markets (Aug 22-24, 1979) -- Papers (2 of 3)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_6bc5042b9e0d911bfa9b195bb346e25d" label="Mixed Materials (508379.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref33_1of" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Agricultural Development Council (ADC) and International Crops Research Institute for the Semi-Arid Tropics (ICRISAT) Conference on Rural Labor Markets (Aug 22-24, 1979) -- Papers (3 of 3)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_004c424fc37340a7571b280ca0ca520f" label="Mixed Materials (508379.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref34_u0t" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>India -- Trip Files (Fall 1979) Re: Agriculture, Food, and Rural Development</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_eaf93671741abe92c4a7503c8e09337b" label="Mixed Materials (508379.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref35_bl4" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Yogjakarta Meeting -- Asia and the Pacific Agriculture and Resources (Nov 13-17, 1979) -- Memoranda, Draft Papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_36caac13b2079d04d269503e87014d0c" label="Mixed Materials (508379.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref36_t3w" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Proceedings of the Yogjakarta Conference (Nov 13-17, 1979) (1 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Nov 13-17, 1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_2c89cf6733d4a8d23842748373b8b9dc" label="Mixed Materials (508379.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref37_r8t" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Proceedings of the Yogjakarta Conference (Nov 13-17, 1979) (2 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Nov 13-17, 1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_8ead91a4b10d28c5e0150f39bd64d6a6" label="Mixed Materials (508379.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref38_p5n" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Final Papers for Yogjakarta Conference (Nov 1979)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_05ffeae3bea9ab6ce991a95a17b5f192" label="Mixed Materials (508379.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref39_uay" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Food, Employment, and the Role of Women in Indonesia" (Yogjakarta conference paper and recommendation for Foundation action)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_424febb3b6eed3f85c112e04647ceae8" label="Mixed Materials (508379.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref40_2um" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Nov 1979 -- Trip to Pakistan, Indonesia -- Yogjakarta Agriculture Meeting</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1979-1980</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_6393fa5948b8d69fe94772742a93791d" label="Mixed Materials (508379.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref41_61o" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bangladesh -- Trip Report, Grant Proposals, Memoranda Re: Budget</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d0eacd0a7d6e1da182b7760292eb0883" label="Mixed Materials (508379.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref42_7jc" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Colombia/Jamaica Trip</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_4980331bb5c474e648ec29f22d54bb98" label="Mixed Materials (508379.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref43_tha" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Agriculture, Natural Resources and Related Rural Development Meeting -- Rapporteur Notes</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Jun 1981</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_ab71f4aac9c0461af66919ecb9688abc" label="Mixed Materials (508379.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref78_rk1" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Subject Files</unittitle>
          <unitid>III</unitid>
          <unitdate normal="1952/1981" type="inclusive">1952-1981</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref45_qi3" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Affirmative Action -- Report</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Mar 1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d6ae80609ba6a3b5c07f58ae34ae7282" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref46_i2q" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Agricultural Research -- Englander</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1980</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_9ad2404a4c4a32785328852c338eff76" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref47_81f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>American Agricultural Economics Association -- Correspondence, Memoranda</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1976-1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d2e2bc041c60f2f18659ca2bb10ce070" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref48_dz3" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>American Agricultural Economics Association (AAEA) -- Report on India and Agricultural Economics</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Dec 1978</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_620f98c66521d11e40f760e5b52003b2" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref49_fcx" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>American Agricultural Economics Association (AAEA) Surveys Re: Agricultural Economics Training</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_1eb17dc50af02d188f865845d9444e2d" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref50_t1w" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Antique Upland Development Program -- Re: Philippines Agriculture</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1976-1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d6eaded2997663ff51dc87ec315ccd15" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref51_uvp" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Bibliography of Substantive Writings" -- The Ford Foundation India and Nepal</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1969</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_bf189f6fbc9b243ba9646e19e65846bb" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref52_f5j" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Building National Capacity to Develop Water User' Associations: Experience from the Philippines"by Frances F. Korten</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Jul 27, 1981</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_a958c525dfb5226ceaf38a02a9b29d0a" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref53_ltk" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Community Organization and Rural Development: A Learnng Process Approach" by David C. Korten</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Apr 1980</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_2c379b6bf9378360e1fc37aa8acd9048" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref54_2lz" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Exchange Rate, Commercial Policy and Agricultural Development: The Experience of Colombia from 1953 to 1978" by Jorge Garcia Garcia (1 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Sep 1980</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_2397bc5e870e244ace6751652dc0b6ed" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref55_rto" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Exchange Rate, Commercial Policy and Agricultural Development: The Experience of Colombia from 1953 to 1978" by Jorge Garcia Garcia (2 of 2)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Sep 1980</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_7dd0f1e4c0fc839e9fefd436ef18ddf5" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref56_71d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Food, Agriculture and Nutrition Policy and Activity -- Memoranda, Reports</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1977-1981</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_5e3ab3d4bed7e9fc4c5aa36c8f7d4e8a" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref57_822" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Health" Memorandum Re: Health Priorities Withing Ford Foundation International Program</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Jun 13, 1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_859926b11df2ac08d59d354c336a58bb" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref58_zs0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Irrigation and Water Management and Improvement in Southeast Asia -- Papers and Memorandum</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1980-1981</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_f7a7e5f861bc0388c653b581d49145af" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref59_0ch" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous Files -- Agrarian Research, Resources and the Environment, Social Development, Asia Trip Files, Program Planning, etc.</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1978-1981</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_66eea4be562c6bacaccacd3859bc8ae0" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref60_mpu" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Nature and Measurement of Economic Efficiency in Indian Agriculture" by R.K. Sampath</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1978</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_82e216d1552a46c645f06bb193d8f95d" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref61_2lj" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Nutrition, Agriculture and Food Policy -- Papers, Remarks</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1978-1980</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d9f9b7420568c6f6e9ad9cc0705ea793" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref62_iaq" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Pakistan</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1978-1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_14942482871f7db82d2b701069d556fa" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref63_be5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Plans for Resources and the Environment Program" -- Information Paper for the Trustee Committee on Education and Public Policy</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Dec 1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_8144381f0202ad7a61d5312b5d108279" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref64_y81" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Program Review -- Division of Education and Public Policy -- Resources and the Environment</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Jan 14, 1981</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_b3d6ef143c4532198eaeaf12bedb8c31" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref65_kus" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Review of Public Policy and Social Organization Program</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Jan 19, 1981</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_4b19a00bfbcdea7c2bf7328814073aca" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref66_51p" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Review of Research on Women in Agriculture and Rural Development</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1980</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_af294af4b4a3800fdb6378a7be15cf10" label="Mixed Materials (508405.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref68_tsu" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Rural Development, Agriculture, Labor Supply and Wages, Land Reform -- Papers/Research Funded by Ford Foundation</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1978-1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_bf78b9bc53e8981243805dd5ebfa0296" label="Mixed Materials (508405.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref69_uqg" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Rural Resources and Development, Women, Urban Poverty and the Disadvantaged -- Grant Proposals, Memoranda, Reports, etc.</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1980-1981</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_e1f1368088a4fbfdc61b5a04716e1594" label="Mixed Materials (508405.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref70_5gt" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Siblings and Schooling in Urban Colombia" (dissertation researched with Ford Foundation funding) by Nancy Monica Birdsall</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1979</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_141518b4819463782a1125460ff9c8a4" label="Mixed Materials (508405.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref71_qx4" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Some Observations on Ford Foundation Supported Community Development Corporations and their Significance for Implementation of Government Policies and Programs" by Sol Chafkin</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">Oct 1977</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_e7adbe84bc1ba3666eb088aed86cb964" label="Mixed Materials (508405.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref72_d6p" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Southeast Asia-An Annotated Bibliography of Selected Reference Sources" -- Library of Congress Orientalia Division</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1952</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_0ed757f06883ce03176fb1e9ba5f60da" label="Mixed Materials (508405.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref73_qxq" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Una Evaluacion de la Intervencion del Gobierno en el mercado de arroz en Colombia" by Nestor Gutierrez and Reed Hertford (in Spanish)</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1974</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_6423e9a261bcf1df51aabce3c52edd69" label="Mixed Materials (508405.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref74_afv" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Working Group -- Rural Resources and Development and Women's Programs</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1980-1981</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_c4a33a77d47fb4ed79ac5f86ec0fbf2a" label="Mixed Materials (508405.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
