<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>FA721.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper type="filing">Ford Foundation records, Latin America and the Caribbean Program Files on the 1973 Coup d'Etat in Chile
</titleproper>
        <titleproper>A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Latin America and the Caribbean Program Files on the 1973 Coup d'Etat in Chile

 <num>FA721</num></titleproper>
        <author>Arranged and described by Nancy E. Weltchek, Ford Foundation Archives; Reformatted by Lucas Buresch, Rockefeller Archive Center</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>November 1985; Reformatted September 2012</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline>
          <addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline>
          <addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-12-04 00:46:57 -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Ford Foundation records, Latin America and the Caribbean Program Files on the 1973 Coup d'Etat in Chile</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="aut" source="lcnaf">Ford Foundation</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>FA721</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.88 Cubic Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">1 standard box</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1971/1978" type="inclusive">1971-1978</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_52f5df19691f3c5766c98439fac908e7">In the summer of 1985, these papers from the Santiago, Chile field office were given to the Archives by Jeffrey Puryear. They were processed in the fall of 1985, and are contained in two Hollinger boxes in the Records Storage Center. The bulk of the papers cover the period 1973 to 1974, but also include a few documents from 1971 and 1978. The records were re-housed into a single Hollinger box in 2015.</abstract>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_4971b2f2e5d7353ce5066c412bffcc30">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.</p>
      <p>Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_ae1876e0f9807b62848deda6ecbd64b0">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
      <p>Completion of a use agreement is required prior to providing scholarly access. See RAC Head of Reference (or applicable designee) for details. </p>
      <p>Ford Foundation holds title, copyright and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them.</p>
      <p>The Rockefeller Archive Center has authority to grant permission to cite and publish material from the collection for scholarly purposes. Permission to publish extensive excerpts, or material in its entirety, will be referred to the Ford Foundation.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_eb74cb243ff2a907c79646a91b4acb28">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
      <p>Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_9f2c4db80884817d1dabdc75f9cf707a">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref>.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <phystech id="aspace_a3caf89259fa57f5e9692ba6aedbb3b9">
      <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
      <p>Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. </p>
      <p>Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.</p>
    </phystech>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_44b6958d662e436aa8896f4a1b0bf1cd">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>These papers from the Santiago, Chile field office span the years 1971 to 1978, but the vast majority deal with the period from September 1973 to September 1974. They are concerned with the effect that the September 11, 1973 military coup had on Ford Foundation grantees in Chile, and on the field office itself.</p>
      <p>The papers are comprised primarily of memoranda between the Santiago and New York offices, memoranda among staff within the Santiago office, and outside correspondence. The memoranda include several reports on the status of grants. These note the effects that the change in government had on various Ford Foundation grantees. The papers also contain numerous clippings, in Spanish, from Chilean newspapers which provide the official account of the coup and of its aftermath. Also included in the papers are published articles, in English, which appeared in the North American press.</p>
      <p>The papers document the Foundation's monitoring of the situation, and contain many assessments by Foundation staff of the significance of the coup, the nature of the new regime, the changed work context for the Foundation, and the future role for the Foundation in Chile. At the time of the coup, the Foundation had many grants underway in Chilean universities. The papers illustrate the high priority that the field office staff gave to documenting the changes the military made in the universities, and particularly within the social science departments. (One such change, well noted in these papers, was the May 2, 1974 decree, "Controloria Interna de la Universidad de Chile"). They also reflect the priority that the Foundation placed on assistance to displaced Chilean scholars. The Foundation was able to use its existing graduate fellowship programs, and to work with grantees such as CLACSO (Latin American Center for Social Sciences) to relocate intellectuals affected by the coup to other Latin American countries and to the United States.</p>
      <p>The papers convey the volatility of the political environment and the uneasiness that was felt by the Ford Foundation staff in Santiago. Because of the uncertain situation, the Foundation was required to reconsider the feasibility and effectiveness of a continued Ford Foundation presence in Chile.</p>
      <p>The papers also demonstrate the staff's concern for victims of the coup. There are some memoranda relating to the arrest of Clodomire Almeyda, Foreign Minister during much of Allende's regime, and to the detentions of Dr. Mariano Requena, Technical Director of the National Health Service, and Dr. Giorgio Solimano, Director of the Ministry of Health's nutrition programs.</p>
      <p>There are also a few brief references to Mr. Charles Horman, including a copy of a letter from his mother, Mrs. Elizabeth Horman, to McGeorge Bundy thanking him for the Foundation's assistance during the search for her son. A good account of Mr. Horman's disappearance is contained in an October 8, 1973 letter from Mr. Richard Fagen, a former full-time consultant to the Foundation in Santiago, to Senator J. William Fulbright. However, at the time the letter was written, Mr. Horman's death had not yet been confirmed. Finally, two 1978 reports by Richard Dye, are insightful, brief analyses of Chile in the international context. They contain comments on the investigation into the 1976 assassination of Orlando Letelier, Chilean Ambassador to Washington under the Allende Administration.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <bioghist id="aspace_946fb0ba6cb2507bfd75fb3936571fea">
      <head>Historical Sketch of Santiago Office</head>
      <p>The Ford Foundation opened a field office in Santiago, Chile, in 1966. Two staff members were assigned. By 1973, there were seven residential, New York-appointed staff members in the Santiago office. After the military coup on September 11, 1973, the Foundation made plans to decrease the number of Foundation employees in Chile. At different points during the year, several of the staff members listed below were reassigned elsewhere. By September 1974 the office was closed.</p>
      <p>From 1974 until 1981, grants to Chile were monitored by the Bogota office. In 1981, the Foundation's office in Lima became the main office for the Andean Region and the Southern Cone, and took over responsibility for grants to Chile. The papers include memoranda from the following Latin American and Caribbean (LAC) program staff:</p>
      <p>NEW YORK-BASED STAFF
William Carmichael - Head, LAC Program
Richard Dye - Deputy Head, LAC Program
Kalman Silvert - Program Advisor</p>
      <p>SANTIAGO-BASED STAFF
Peter Bell - Representative
Gary Horlick - Assistant Representative
Peter Hakim - Assistant Representative
Jeffrey Puryear - Program Assistant
Thomas McCarthy - Program Assistant
Nita Manitzas - Program Advisor
Lovell Jarvis - Program Advisor (1972-1973) Consultant to Chile (1974)</p>
    </bioghist>
    <arrangement id="aspace_360bdca594b15d4fbb509f684aaed8b2">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>The papers are contained in nineteen folders, and they are arranged in chronological order. When a document is accompanied by a cover memorandum, the two are filed together, with the date of the cover memo determining their place among the material.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Civil society -- Chile</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Social Justice--Chile</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Human rights -- Chile</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Chile -- Politics and government -- 1973-1988</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Non-governmental organizations--Chile--Chile</subject>
      <geogname source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">Chile--History--Coup d'état, 1973</geogname>
      <geogname source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">Coups d'état--Chile</geogname>
      <corpname role="aut" source="lcnaf">Ford Foundation</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref10_g3o" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1971/1971" type="inclusive">1971 December</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_53782b8a5e46f3e8b8da979e44140972" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_09dcadf0b6b79f415c872b6447b8939c" parent="aspace_53782b8a5e46f3e8b8da979e44140972" type="folder">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_52c555a1aea18bbed8c8316d0d45e7b0">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Includes ‘Santiago [Chile] Office Report on Fiscal Year 1971’ by Peter Bell, and a list of Chile office graduate fellowships for FY 1971.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref11_dpa" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">1973 September 12 - 28</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_6c5568ecefd52146fbe730706e4796a6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_0f4cb05ef2d191339b506117d1ea1adb" parent="aspace_6c5568ecefd52146fbe730706e4796a6" type="folder">2</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_8dfba19b0c3f9334e12f4a6976491f16">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Includes Thomas McCarthy memos on grantees: University of Chile, Faculty of Physical and Mathematical Sciences (PA67-569), reproductive biology (PA69-703, PA72-384), State Technical Institute (PA71-505), Ministry of Education - Normal Schools Project (PA69-741), National Health Service - Nutrition (PA72-445), National Institute for Agricultural Research (PA72-435).</p>
          <p>Nina Manitzas memos: “Don Clodomiro Almeyda”, “National Secretariat of Women”, “Pontifical Catholic University of Chile - Institute of Sociology (PA64-452)”, “Pontifical Catholic University of Chile - Center for Urban and Regional Development (PA66-30), “Pontifical Catholic University of Chile - Institute of Political Science (PA72-59), “Pontifical Catholic University of Chile - Center for Legal Assistance (PA73-538), and “Institute for Legal Teaching and Research (PA72-261)”.</p>
          <p>Lovell S. Jarvis memos: “Conversation with Staff from CPI-INTEC”, “Center for National Planning Studies (CEPLAN), Catholic University”, “Current situation in Institute of Economics, Catholic University”, “Current status of the Department of Economics, West Campus, and Department of Political Economy, North Campus, University of Chile”, “Department of Industry, University of Chile”
Peter Bell memos: “First Post-Coup Status Report on the Foundation’s Program in Chile”, “Faculty of Sciences, University of Chile (PA65-327)”, and “Catholic University of Chile, Department of Rural Development (L73-40)”.</p>
          <p>Alain de Janvry memos: “ICIRA”, “Catholic University of Chile - Postgraduate program in rural economics”, and “Land Tenure Center Project in Chile”.</p>
          <p>Also includes misc. correspondence, clippings, telegrams, etc.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref12_ndw" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">1973 October 1 - 9</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_0907cd3db5b94f07606f9967ce3a4702" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_bd423cf1c2af2bb92324f737a4c6fe02" parent="aspace_0907cd3db5b94f07606f9967ce3a4702" type="folder">3</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref13_e3z" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">1973 October 10 - 18</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_48595220d3d23d1c4d9ae95dfc9e996e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_4d9af96449a7c7b515cf9cd2a76c72ef" parent="aspace_48595220d3d23d1c4d9ae95dfc9e996e" type="folder">4</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref14_yvi" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">1973 October 18 - 25</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_439a9f852d6e3a684de0051eedb77b57" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_4162d4eb801af6bd3232b71570a4a5f1" parent="aspace_439a9f852d6e3a684de0051eedb77b57" type="folder">5</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref15_pza" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">1973 October 24 - 30</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_f4de479058cb744da212a86c3dc6eb1f" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_7ff7edd92a5b4d89e7e5fcab2a6dc1da" parent="aspace_f4de479058cb744da212a86c3dc6eb1f" type="folder">6</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref16_n9h" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">1973 November 1 - 30</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_47db4fe6d38bc7eb028789639665667c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_23a512fa4f9b471dfcc371cd2cec5e0f" parent="aspace_47db4fe6d38bc7eb028789639665667c" type="folder">7</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref17_d8h" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1973/1974" type="inclusive">1973 December 5 - 1974 January 16</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_2d00d26dd34c32b35d3f8b02e28c6d35" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_b9742de2e0b4d32bdcd3d422474c31de" parent="aspace_2d00d26dd34c32b35d3f8b02e28c6d35" type="folder">8</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref18_dnw" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">1974 January 21 - February 27</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_6ef19c7f45b7fe11a66acb158391d730" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_3d79ff098ceffda1a0b1d23e05c5a4e5" parent="aspace_6ef19c7f45b7fe11a66acb158391d730" type="folder">9</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref19_z4b" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">1974 March 2 - 21</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_b38b665cbc1194e5a5fb4bede49bb607" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_20f53e502243f56e8c3c286d041dbd83" parent="aspace_b38b665cbc1194e5a5fb4bede49bb607" type="folder">10</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref20_tjy" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">1974 March 22 - 30</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_92e7a3ad882d7511ca98dd8d7e11e5bc" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_22248fab022152b95d4e39b7a8fe3088" parent="aspace_92e7a3ad882d7511ca98dd8d7e11e5bc" type="folder">11</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref21_xj5" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">1974 April 1 - 5</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_e72768ca24f8704bc1d813361a763af0" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_929fe646249154401443808bd38d4313" parent="aspace_e72768ca24f8704bc1d813361a763af0" type="folder">12</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref22_v3l" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">1974 April 8 - 18</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_ec75b7c3bcede3ec531b3266fcbf08c2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_ba32f9e9b7fe75b009cd7b41da932ea9" parent="aspace_ec75b7c3bcede3ec531b3266fcbf08c2" type="folder">13</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref23_f08" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">1974 April 19 - May 1</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_243e7867789e38695edc99322b3c1c14" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_100d426b33cf7fb4b3e5a13e9e40d96e" parent="aspace_243e7867789e38695edc99322b3c1c14" type="folder">14</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref24_8g5" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">1974 May 2 - 20</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_169459f6db71eab3e7b3ef26889fc43d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_acfa96f1eb0c2842e01a01989426a77e" parent="aspace_169459f6db71eab3e7b3ef26889fc43d" type="folder">15</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref25_vul" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">1974 May 22 - 27</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_042b66a7314c930274c28826fc456955" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_1eb3cb753ed6a47a277408c7f28378d3" parent="aspace_042b66a7314c930274c28826fc456955" type="folder">16</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref26_1wp" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">1974 July 1 - 22</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_edc6d9b628f64795eae4f770371a0f16" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_08f185dfd007371944950420cda5dea3" parent="aspace_edc6d9b628f64795eae4f770371a0f16" type="folder">17</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref27_xaj" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">1974 July 25 - September 23</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_7250d09506ae754980bf15856453c2c0" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_d5b2fadceb21e6d9027443098b40c784" parent="aspace_7250d09506ae754980bf15856453c2c0" type="folder">18</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref28_78o" level="file">
        <did>
          <unitdate normal="1978/1978" type="inclusive">1978 March 28 - July 27</unitdate>
          <container id="aspace_78ce005aebfec0c0b1f7b04237b0dbdb" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
          <container id="aspace_be56ae081a66aae1fe6be9be39b4f44e" parent="aspace_78ce005aebfec0c0b1f7b04237b0dbdb" type="folder">19</container>
        </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
