<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>FA517.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper type="filing">Ford Foundation records, Board on Overseas Training and Research, Office of the Chairman, Office Files of Gordon Gray</titleproper>
        <titleproper>A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Board on Overseas Training and Research, Office of the Chairman, Office Files of Gordon Gray
 <num>FA517</num></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by Rachel Moskowitz, The Winthrop Group</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>September 2011</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline>
          <addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline>
          <addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2016-01-15 01:23:57 -0500</date>.</creation>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Ford Foundation records, Board on Overseas Training and Research, Office of the Chairman, Office Files of Gordon Gray</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="aut" source="lcnaf">Ford Foundation</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>FA517</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.2 Cubic Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1952/1955" type="inclusive">Bulk, 1952-1954 1952-1955</unitdate>
      <unitdate normal="1952/1954" type="bulk">bulk</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_9b2a04ff2b95798fb1d7c6bd15078684">The Board on Overseas Training and Research records span from 1952 to 1955 and comprise the office files of Mr. Gray, the first chairman of the Board on Overseas Training and Research. The Overseas Training and Research program was established in 1952 as a means of demystifying the cultures and communities overseas and improving the skills of social service professionals serving both in the United States and abroad. The program’s board launched a fellowship to encourage college graduates, graduate students, and young professionals to pursue compelling research projects of cultural, educational, and historic value. The collection includes correspondence concerning the establishment of the Board on Overseas Training and Research, meeting minutes of the Board, reports regarding the development and expansion of the program and the grants offered, and statistical analyses of applicants and recipients of the foreign study fellowships. Gordon Gray, President of the University of North Carolina and former attorney, state senator, and Secretary of the Army, accepted the position of Chairman of the Board on Overseas Training and Research upon the program’s inception in 1952. The collection spans from 1952 to 1955, when Mr. Gray left to become Assistant Secretary of Defense for International Security Affairs.</abstract>
      <physdesc id="aspace_e59603935140906b69f57f5c3fc0d801">
        <extent>(3 document boxes)</extent>
      </physdesc>
    </did>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_075bb1d18efcb3b379971cde0632ec93">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
      <p>Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <phystech id="aspace_dc0b2bdcdfc8f02d55256ace2716afc5">
      <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
      <p>Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.</p>
    </phystech>
    <bioghist id="aspace_2d233dc23654a14983940c4961829f64">
      <head>Organizational History</head>
      <p>In March 1952 the Ford Foundation announced the establishment of the Overseas Training and Research program (OTR) in an effort to promote peace, education, and the value of social welfare and to improve the skills of social service professionals serving both in the United States and abroad. The OTR program was designed to strengthen cultural connections between countries and help Americans to better understand the practices and politics of other countries. Such work was crucial according to Paul Hoffman, Director of the Ford Foundation, who wrote in a letter to Gordon Gray, dated March 31, 1952, that “we must find ways to improve our training for international service. And we all felt the need for a comprehensive effort to fill in the gaps in our knowledge concerning so many peoples of the world” (Box 1, Folder 1). Soon thereafter, a board of directors was appointed to oversee the program.</p>
      <p>The Board on Overseas Training and Research established a fellowship for college graduates, graduate students, and young professionals with compelling research projects of cultural, educational, and historic value intended to enhance an “understanding of these areas, to afford advanced training to specialists, and to enable professional men and women to study, work and live” in their country of choice (Ford Foundation press release, March 1952; Box 1, Folder 1). The initial fellowships were directed at projects in Asia, the Near East and the Middle East. During the spring of 1952, the Board actively circulated fellowship applications during the spring of 1952 to universities, corporations, government agencies, charitable foundations, and individuals. More than eighty applicants received funding for research during the first year of the program.</p>
      <p>By 1955, the Overseas Training and Research program had been renamed the International Training and Research program and the board which oversaw the unit became an Advisory Committee. The International Training and Research program merged with several other Foundation programs in 1966 to create the International Division, a single unit comprising all international work undertaken by the Foundation. A reorganization in 1981 included the creation of the Developing Countries Program which continued the work of the former International Division. In 1989, the Developing Countries Program was subdivided, separating work done in Asia, Africa and the Middle East, and Latin America and the Caribbean into distinct program areas.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <bioghist id="aspace_6d6fa6b1d609ef5a587daaac92067430">
      <head>Biographical Note</head>
      <p>Gordon Gray was born on May 30, 1909 in Baltimore, Maryland. In 1930, Mr. Gray received his bachelor’s degree from the University of North Carolina and, in 1933, graduated from Yale Law School. Mr. Gray worked at a New York law firm until 1935 when he left to practice law in North Carolina. By 1937, he had become the president of the Piedmont Publishing Company, responsible for the publication of the Winston-Salem Journal and the Twin City Sentinel as well as the operations of radio station WSJS.</p>
      <p>Interrupted only by his service in the military, Mr. Gray served as a member of the North Carolina State Senate from 1939 to 1942 and again from 1945 to 1947. During World War II he joined the Headquarters of the Twelfth Army Group abroad. Following his return to North Carolina and second stint as a senator, Mr. Gray was appointed Assistant Secretary of the Army on September 24, 1947 and served in that capacity until May 1949, when he became Under Secretary of the Army. The following month, on June 20, 1949, he was appointed Secretary of the Army. Mr. Gray resigned as Secretary in April 1950 to accept the presidency of the University of North Carolina (then referred to as the Consolidated University of North Carolina). Despite his new position, he remained in Washington, D.C. for a year to serve as a special assistant on issues of foreign economic policy to U.S. President Harry S. Truman.</p>
      <p>In 1952, Mr. Gray accepted the position of Chairman of the Ford Foundation’s newly established Board on Overseas Training and Research. He was instrumental in the early development of the Board and the program, and oversaw the creation of the OTR fellowship program, the refinement of the applicant selection rubric, and the appraisal of and search for activities and opportunities abroad.</p>
      <p>Following his resignation as president of the University of North Carolina in 1955, Mr. Gray returned to government work as the Assistant Secretary of Defense for International Security Affairs, a position he held from 1955 through 1957. He also served as director of the Office of Defense Mobilization, Special Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs, and a member of the President’s Foreign Intelligence Advisory Board. Throughout his career, Mr. Gray retained his interests in broadcast and publishing and served as Chairman of the boards of the Piedmont Publishing Company, Triangle Broadcasting Company, and Summit Communications, Inc. He died on November 26, 1982, in Washington, D.C.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <arrangement id="aspace_692a3404b6c954e30aca333a3cdef099">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>The collection is arranged into 4 series.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_13f23a4222d81a50580483d0c45af20a">
      <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
      <p>The Board on Overseas Training and Research records span from 1952 to 1955 and comprise the office files of Mr. Gray, the first chairman of the Board on Overseas Training and Research. His earliest files describe the establishment of the Overseas Training and Research program, the recruitment of potential applicants for the Board’s first fellowship offering in 1952, and the evaluation of research proposals.</p>
      <p>In addition, the meeting minutes of the Board on Overseas Training and Research chart the progress of the OTR program as it expanded and gained greater recognition among institutions and individuals pursuing international studies.</p>
      <p>Also found within the collection are reports produced by and for the Board on Overseas Training and Research about the development and expansion of the program and the grants offered, and statistical analyses of fellowship applicants and recipients of the Board on Overseas Training and Research foreign study fellowships.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <separatedmaterial id="aspace_e6e0c5bdee725a567a5784884e03f1b5">
      <head>Separated Materials</head>
      <p>Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.</p>
    </separatedmaterial>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_9a07a2d01758fdcf678a0f7873585121">
      <head>Related Collections</head>
      <p>Additional collections of Mr. Gray’s papers reside in several other libraries. Summaries are provided below. Please contact the respective institutions for more information and access requirements.</p>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Harry S. Truman Library and Museum</emph>
      </p>
      <p>Records of the Agency for International Development: Records of Gordon Gray (Record Group 286), 1948-1952.</p>
      <p>Gordon Gray Papers, 1946-1979.</p>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Louis Round Wilson Special Collections Library at the University of North Carolina</emph>
      </p>
      <p>Gordon Gray Papers (collection number 03824), 1919-1982.</p>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Dwight D. Eisenhower Presidential Library and Museum</emph>
      </p>
      <p>Gordon Gray Papers, 1946-1976.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <processinfo id="aspace_7bdb316cab0336208d493a31cdb12707">
      <head>Processing Information Note</head>
      <p>This 1.2 cubic foot collection was transferred from one cubic foot storage box to three Hollinger document boxes during processing. Weeding was limited to the removal of duplicate reports and research proposals.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_abfc90490575822654104054af657bed">
      <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
      <p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>
    </prefercite>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_0993f85bf12a281dfb45f2f15e70b41c">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
      <p>Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.</p>
      <p>Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_207599db8602c1ef8c0ceb95f1ee651d">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
      <p>Completion of a use agreement is required prior to providing scholarly access. See RAC Head of Reference (or applicable designee) for details. Ford Foundation holds title, copyright and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them. The Rockefeller Archive Center has authority to grant permission to cite and publish material from the collection for scholarly purposes. Permission to publish extensive excerpts, or material in its entirety, will be referred to the Ford Foundation.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <controlaccess>
      <corpname role="aut" source="lcnaf">Ford Foundation</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref14_4x9" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitid>I</unitid>
          <unitdate normal="1952/1955" type="inclusive">1952-1955</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_09033e9e5ac88af6cff3aef2cc8cd48a">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series consists of the correspondence files maintained by Mr. Gray pertaining to the Overseas Training and Research program and the work of its board. The files have been arranged chronologically. The files contain letters of congratulations to Mr. Gray regarding his appointment as Chairman of the Board and his involvement with the program’s development. The bulk of the later files from 1953 through 1955 consist of letters to the Board about research projects and possible funding. Also included are periodic progress and status reports produced by the Board on Overseas Training and Research, as well as memoranda regarding board meetings, potential cooperation with other foundations and institutions of higher education, and possibilities for improving the value of continued funding of overseas research.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="aspace_ref15_r30" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chronological Files, 1952 (1 of 5)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1952/1952" type="inclusive">Mar-Apr 1952</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_2161b148f6d69e256d57b411f21e9c6e" label="Documents" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_ec523ada82acb407d33bbf0b803cf857" parent="aspace_2161b148f6d69e256d57b411f21e9c6e" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref16_65y" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chronological Files, 1952 (2 of 5)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1952/1952" type="inclusive">Mar-Apr 1952</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_06b733b442a635ad9ce8b02d3609de37" label="Documents" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_cf2f91e4678f1bccc4c75607964f3ec5" parent="aspace_06b733b442a635ad9ce8b02d3609de37" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref17_jjt" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chronological Files, 1952 (3 of 5)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1952/1952" type="inclusive">May 1952</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_313fd703139c2a7994614d2b0182b8c5" label="Documents" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_4f932192e29189448e96347d2f3d7da0" parent="aspace_313fd703139c2a7994614d2b0182b8c5" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref18_0zj" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chronological Files, 1952 (4 of 5)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1952/1952" type="inclusive">Jun 1952</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_869615a8dc48bd1af26503fe2ab2dddf" label="Documents" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_6d4b1356b116f79b00460acfe284713a" parent="aspace_869615a8dc48bd1af26503fe2ab2dddf" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref19_wtl" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chronological Files, 1952 (5 of 5)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1952/1952" type="inclusive">Jul-Dec 1952</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_9faaa563144fdd1503c86335e463bbb4" label="Documents" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_57e988ab3168430fd580a1a4a7dc1f93" parent="aspace_9faaa563144fdd1503c86335e463bbb4" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref20_t30" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chronological Files, 1953 (1 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1953/1953" type="inclusive">Jan-Apr 1953</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_dd6b884ca5e8f3f304ba04a7c2a03f2b" label="Documents" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_024bc3fde15e7b7f3c1aca97da3ddcf7" parent="aspace_dd6b884ca5e8f3f304ba04a7c2a03f2b" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref21_yna" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chronological Files, 1953 (2 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1953/1953" type="inclusive">Jun 1953</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_ffa85b76875b8babc30cde58e0890c2f" label="Documents" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_3d733fda9b9387a2cf09532ec22d350c" parent="aspace_ffa85b76875b8babc30cde58e0890c2f" type="folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref22_wt4" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chronological Files, 1953 (3 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1953/1953" type="inclusive">Jul-Sep 1953</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_ed6e8e51cec5b19f2e10cc2b2aec5fee" label="Documents" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_b64415f3643e90153b89bd69956277e8" parent="aspace_ed6e8e51cec5b19f2e10cc2b2aec5fee" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref23_d37" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chronological Files, 1953 (4 of 4)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1953/1953" type="inclusive">Oct-Dec 1953</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_6b530be040b273638747247e3e0ce5da" label="Documents" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_b23f96d7e81dbc2e49654fdef903bb5e" parent="aspace_6b530be040b273638747247e3e0ce5da" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref24_q3c" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chronological Files, 1954</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1954/1954" type="inclusive">Jan-Mar 1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_9ba8a8ca688f707075b89b5aa4ccd479" label="Documents" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_86a23febc260f6e84cbc71c19e6737ec" parent="aspace_9ba8a8ca688f707075b89b5aa4ccd479" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref25_wf7" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chronological Files, 1955</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1955/1955" type="inclusive">Apr-July 1955</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_17fd8c90fbec56bbad667f1ca741909f" label="Documents" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_1b95c4dfd65654cfac7626a598344295" parent="aspace_17fd8c90fbec56bbad667f1ca741909f" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref26_zfz" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Meeting Minutes and Materials</unittitle>
          <unitid>II</unitid>
          <unitdate normal="1952/1955" type="inclusive">1952-1955</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_aa08a7638ce57017062ac79b811a9886">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series consists of the materials distributed at each meeting of the Board on Overseas Training and Research and the resulting minutes. The meeting materials and the minutes were located in separate folders when the collection was accessioned. This original arrangement has been preserved. The files have been arranged chronologically by meeting date. The files of meeting materials precede the files of meeting minutes. One additional folder of meeting materials contains documents distributed during the Conference on Soviet and Slavic Area Studies held on October 9-10, 1953. The Board on Overseas Training and Research organized the conference in an attempt to define existing gaps in area studies, establish additional fellowship opportunities and discuss the Ford Foundation’s role in better preparing Soviet and Slavic studies scholars and public servants.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="aspace_ref27_s3c" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Board Meeting Materials, 3/18/1952</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1952/1952" type="inclusive">Mar 18, 1952</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_b2c72c357021a95b3100b4c740b4f8f7" label="Documents" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_08ef881301174a100e0ecea450bd8c8e" parent="aspace_b2c72c357021a95b3100b4c740b4f8f7" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref28_0i0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Board Meeting Materials, 5/22/1952</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1952/1952" type="inclusive">May 22, 1952</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_67741fb837462028632ea3824d48d4c1" label="Documents" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_c983dfb3b29a18d3d1eecc880b6d2764" parent="aspace_67741fb837462028632ea3824d48d4c1" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref29_n53" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Board Meeting Materials, 6/18/1952</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1952/1952" type="inclusive">Jun 18, 1952</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_335407d9f280441f97845edeea5c3d60" label="Documents" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_57a9d5c57cdb95f0005d4572b286d371" parent="aspace_335407d9f280441f97845edeea5c3d60" type="folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref30_cae" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Board Meeting Materials, 9/17/1952</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1952/1952" type="inclusive">Sep 17, 1952</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d2c43c13bbfb4bb7193820b2bcbd6bc6" label="Documents" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_6a02b302848671ba6ccc8e462903441c" parent="aspace_d2c43c13bbfb4bb7193820b2bcbd6bc6" type="folder">8</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref31_d88" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Board Meeting Materials, 11/13/1952</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1952/1952" type="inclusive">Nov 13, 1952</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_d62621b42a8278c615a6c27820a9046c" label="Documents" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_e50489439e60d6ffafd61704eb73bb9a" parent="aspace_d62621b42a8278c615a6c27820a9046c" type="folder">9</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref32_gxr" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Board Meeting Materials, 2/2/1953</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1953/1953" type="inclusive">Feb 2, 1953</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_f8967524154d52eca67b58df20365aa2" label="Documents" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_22e6bc80ae4549768dfbb8f868e1c1c3" parent="aspace_f8967524154d52eca67b58df20365aa2" type="folder">10</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref33_9xw" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Board Meeting Materials, 5/5/1953</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1953/1953" type="inclusive">May 5, 1953</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_999df5de836ec22b493eabc9245b0182" label="Documents" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_25e03bed03fad8051c2439804aa9a36c" parent="aspace_999df5de836ec22b493eabc9245b0182" type="folder">11</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref34_vqk" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Board Meeting Materials, 9/15/1953</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1953/1953" type="inclusive">Sep 15, 1953</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_128c19845d6201db7f662bfaab3fbfd2" label="Documents" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="aspace_7cf4ded9611417d45e35e74704c0f84c" parent="aspace_128c19845d6201db7f662bfaab3fbfd2" type="folder">12</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref35_rbh" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Board Meeting Materials, 11/18/1953</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1953/1953" type="inclusive">Nov 18, 1953</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_db2a3417b9c9eca9fc892c8ffe942663" label="Documents" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_c31810ac075614951d8db8028507844a" parent="aspace_db2a3417b9c9eca9fc892c8ffe942663" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref36_qwd" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Board Meeting Materials, 3/31/1954</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1954/1954" type="inclusive">Mar 31, 1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_60a0b03bf7615eaa2ea33e255ad46a98" label="Documents" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_62e79ce09b70567c20db2cdafff9a8ca" parent="aspace_60a0b03bf7615eaa2ea33e255ad46a98" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref37_eq5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>International Training and Research Advisory Committee Meeting Materials, 4/29/1955</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1955/1955" type="inclusive">Apr 29, 1955</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_6efb24b23371bcb98444569e9550829b" label="Documents" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_8e44e6bcd838861647eed073a9bd5dd4" parent="aspace_6efb24b23371bcb98444569e9550829b" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref38_hxx" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Board Meeting Minutes, 1952</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1952/1952" type="inclusive">Mar-Nov 1952</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_3dac93fc90ef224b308a21a84ba3b6ac" label="Documents" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_ffa003d3d34e77e9136753a57d40d0b1" parent="aspace_3dac93fc90ef224b308a21a84ba3b6ac" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref39_xkv" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Board Meeting Minutes, 1953</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1953/1953" type="inclusive">Feb-Nov 1953</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_2822bd208011f4cb698d388e530d9edb" label="Documents" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_7be4a0ac2665a7495676247c17ffae47" parent="aspace_2822bd208011f4cb698d388e530d9edb" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref40_8d8" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Conference on Soviet and Slavic Area Studies Materials, 10/9-10/1953</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1953/1953" type="inclusive">Oct 9-10, 1953</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_7c2004396517176a9cefe5755a9b3c20" label="Documents" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_c0add353ff4913e4e2dd2315725cd185" parent="aspace_7c2004396517176a9cefe5755a9b3c20" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref41_182" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Reports</unittitle>
          <unitid>III</unitid>
          <unitdate normal="1952/1954" type="inclusive">1952-1954</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_3991be73c1b8ee606a5b09b4ca769326">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This series contains reports and evaluations of the OTR program and is arranged chronologically with two undated reports placed at the end. The reports examine opportunities for international education and service, and include recommendations for the recruitment and selection of applicants, evaluations of submitted research proposals, and suggestions for long-term maintenance of the program. There is also a 1952 progress report on the work of the Division of Overseas Activities, which includes an update on the activities of the OTR program.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="aspace_ref42_l8f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Report on Training for Specialized Mission Personnel" by Wallace Sayre and Clarence Thurber</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1952/1952" type="inclusive">April 1952</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_a91962f6cf3ea055ddc41f42679a9e91" label="Documents" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_bb862a89719ff18a6c24cad9c3e0685e" parent="aspace_a91962f6cf3ea055ddc41f42679a9e91" type="folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref43_c5j" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Division of Overseas Activities Standard Report No. 2</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1954/1954" type="inclusive">Feb 15, 1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_ca8fb76006fd20dc7233c85fbc7ca10c" label="Documents" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_2f4d1983e45409859d2c3ce5eca19835" parent="aspace_ca8fb76006fd20dc7233c85fbc7ca10c" type="folder">8</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref44_gxg" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"BOTR Fellowships in Asia: Conclusions and Recommendations Regarding Recruitment, Selection, Terms of Award" by William Lockwood</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1954/1954" type="inclusive">March 1, 1954</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_96a15249dbb9f14272956926fdbf4f5a" label="Documents" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_a1b03eb5b0edd769e736da5b9f7029fb" parent="aspace_96a15249dbb9f14272956926fdbf4f5a" type="folder">9</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref45_cr0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Procedures for the Selective Support of Investigation Relating to Asia and the Middle East" by Clarence E. Thurber</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1958/1958" type="inclusive">1958</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_b182426b23f5ce90b4c60ea416c5e75e" label="Documents" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_8f15e2b418b23b07c2209cbff8f47b13" parent="aspace_b182426b23f5ce90b4c60ea416c5e75e" type="folder">10</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref46_lxp" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Recommendations for Support of Future Overseas Training and Research Activities for Discussion at Feb 23 Trustees Meeting by Carl B. Spaeth and Cleon O. Swayzee</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">n.d.</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_43d4cf7f06d54e363dd2a0947cdc1e3a" label="Documents" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_a126d8eac339dee2d69a619f45133803" parent="aspace_43d4cf7f06d54e363dd2a0947cdc1e3a" type="folder">11</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref47_fmc" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Fellowship Applications and Proposals</unittitle>
          <unitid>IV</unitid>
          <unitdate normal="1952/1953" type="inclusive">1952-1953, n.d.</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_f9e94612a7eee7825e65b58a4b23e93b">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The four files in this series pertain to fellowship applications and proposals, and contain documents detailing the procedures governing the selection of candidates. A summary of projects under consideration as well as sample blank application forms are included. The files are arranged alphabetically by subject. Three of the folders are undated, but their contents suggest they fall within the 1952-1955 period.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="aspace_ref48_s04" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Overseas Training and Research Announcements, Applications and Reference Forms</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1952/1953" type="inclusive">1952-1953</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_f09cc967a985e14a1b10d9a40b33ccbb" label="Documents" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_f7349e7870df2e90b573218573fc1e2e" parent="aspace_f09cc967a985e14a1b10d9a40b33ccbb" type="folder">12</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref49_58n" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Statistics on Fellowship Applicants/Recipients</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">n.d.</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_58994d0f25f82a82a11b42382b3549e8" label="Documents" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_320f3a48cc02e03d777926ef0e950afd" parent="aspace_58994d0f25f82a82a11b42382b3549e8" type="folder">13</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref50_jo9" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Summary of Research Projects for Consideration by Board on Overseas Training and Research</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">n.d.</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_710b17df3839972135a076496db6e1a4" label="Documents" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="aspace_f265adb8a2f27d371df3c67f0697b1a4" parent="aspace_710b17df3839972135a076496db6e1a4" type="folder">14</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
