<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="under_revision" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>FA859.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper type="filing">Rockefeller University records, Corporation, Board of Trustees, Secretary</titleproper>
        <titleproper>A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Corporation, Board of Trustees, Secretary
 <num>FA859</num></titleproper>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline>
          <addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline>
          <addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2016-10-29 21:39:19 -0400</date>.</creation>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <date>2010 November 12</date>
      <item>Paper finding aid converted to EAD/XML by AureXus in 2010. Imported into the Archvists’ Toolkit by Becky Robbins.</item>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Rockefeller University records, Corporation, Board of Trustees, Secretary</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="aut" source="lcnaf">Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research</corpname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="aut" source="lcnaf">Rockefeller University</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>FA859</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5 Box(es)</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1910/1956" type="inclusive">1910-1956</unitdate>
      <physdesc id="aspace_bcd2b92c1da787ef1248adc80a6264b3">5 boxes.</physdesc>
    </did>
    <bioghist id="aspace_ec4f4e335ef0dacca9d85aa464a679f7">
      <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
      <p>CORPORATION</p>
      <p>The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research was founded in 1901, in New York City, by John D. Rockefeller for the purpose of medical research with special reference to the prevention and treatment of disease. Control rested in seven Directors of the Corporation. Funds from the original grant, provided up to an average of $ 20,000 a year for ten years. In June 1902, a second pledge of $ 1,000,000 over ten years was made. These funds were informally handled by drawing upon Mr. Rockefeller's office against the amounts which had been pledged. In November 1907, when Mr. Rockefeller announced an endowment fund to the Institute of $ 2,600,000 in stocks and bonds, the transfer could not be made directly to the Directors since the Charter of 1901 did not give the Corporation specific authority to hold invested funds. The funds earmarked for the Institute were thus included in a gift to the General Education Board.</p>
      <p>In May 1908 the Charter was amended to permit the Corporation to create, either by contract or by-law with the donor, a Board of Trustees empowered to hold investments. October 15, 1910 By-Laws for a Board of Trustees were adopted and a further gift of $3,820,000 was announced, thus providing an endowment of $ 6,420,000. Additional gifts from John D. Rockefeller gave the Trustees of the Institute more than $34,000,000 in land, buildings and endowment over the first twenty years. In 1928 Mr. Rockefeller made another gift of $ 20,000,000. By 1953 the dollar value of the Institute's endowment was $ 107,000,000.</p>
      <p>The Board of Directors was supplanted, in the Charter amendment of 1908, by a Board of Trustees and a Board of Scientific Directors, (the original Board of Directors) as members of the Corporation. As provided in the 1910 By-Laws, the real property and the principal of all permanent funds were under the exclusive control of the Board of Trustees; all of the scientific work of the Institute, including the work of the Hospital was to be under the exclusive control of the Board of Scientific Directors.</p>
      <p>The Corporation functioned through a five-man Budget Committee comprised of three members chosen by the Board of Scientific Directors and two members chosen by the Board of Trustees. Further changes in By-Laws in 1928 provided that of the three Budget Committee members representing the Scientific Directors, at least one, was to be also a member of the Board of Trustees. In 1937 further changes in By-Laws provided that any portion of the income for any year not expended in accordance with the budget for that year, was to be under the exclusive control of the Board of Trustees.</p>
      <p>The Board of Trustees elected the President, Vice-President, Secretary and Treasurer of the Corporation, of whom the first three officers were also the officers of the Board of Trustees. The first President was Frederick T. Gates, succeeded 1929-1950 by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., and succeeded in 1950 by David Rockefeller.</p>
      <p>In 1953 an extensive reorganization began. New By-Laws, adopted June 23, 1953 provided [?]. The Members of the Corporation shall consist of the members of the Board of Trustees and the members of the Board of Scientific Directors as those Boards are constituted on the twenty-third day of June 1953, and hereafter the said Boards shall be merged into one Board Known as the Board of Trustees.</p>
      <p>The Board of Trustees was also designated the Corporate Board of Directors. Elected officers were Chairman of the Board, Vice-chairman, President, Vice-President, Secretary and Treasurer. David Rockefeller was named the first Chairman of the Board and Detlev W. Bronk was named the first President of the Institute.</p>
      <p>November 19, 1954 the Charter of the Institute was amended by the Board of Regents, for and on behalf of the Education Department of the State of New York, so as to authorize the Institute to grant degrees. The Corporation thus became part of the University of the State of New York, subject to the jurisdiction and visitation of the Regents of the said University in all respects as though the Corporation had been originally incorporated by the Regents. June 1958 the Charter of the Institute was again amended to change the name from The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research to The Rockefeller Institute.</p>
      <p>On May 27, 1965 the Board of Regents amended the Charter of the Institute in its entirety and changed the corporate name from The Rockefeller Institute to The Rockefeller University.</p>
      <p>In accordance with By-Laws adopted October 17, 1966 the Corporation shall consist of the members of the Board of Trustees as constituted from time to time.</p>
      <p>CORPORARTION (101) Board of Directors (1901-1910)</p>
      <p>Under certificate of incorporation dated May 28, 1901 and filed in the office of the Secretary of State and of the Clerk of New York County on June 13, 1901, control of the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research rested in a seven-man Board of Directors. May 6, 1908 the Charter was amended to allow creation of a Board of Trustees by by-law or contract. By-Laws for this change were not adopted until October 15, 1910.</p>
      <p>At the first meeting, June 14, 1901 the officers elected were: William H. Welch, President; T. Mitchell Prudden, Vice-President; L. Emmett Holt, Secretary, and Christian A. Herter, Treasurer. Three other Directors were Theobald Smith, Hermann M. Biggs and Simon Flexner who at a meeting on October 25, 1902 was unanimously elected Director of the Institute.</p>
      <p>Planning, business and work of the Institute were carried on under the direction of the seven Directors, operating through an Executive Committee, composed of three members and the President, and amended April 21, 1906 to four elected members and the Director of the Laboratories, ex-officio. Special committees, such as a Committee on Library and Supplies, a Building Committee and a Committee on Equipment were appointed for short periods and special ongoing needs. April 10, 1909 a Finance Committee, of three members from the Executive Committee was established. Administrative functions were carried by the Directors until January 1906 when James U. Norris, Superintendent; N. Curtice Holt, Clerk (to keep books and accounts of the Institute) and a library stenographer were employed.</p>
      <p>When the main laboratory with animal house and power house were ready for use a formal dedication was held on May 11, 1906 with addresses by L. Emmett Holt, William H. Welch, President Nicholas Murray Butler of Columbia University and Charles W. Eliot of Harvard.</p>
      <p>By July 1910, a General Manager, Jerome D. Greene was added to the administrative staff.</p>
      <p>Board of Scientific Directors (1910-1953):</p>
      <p>As provided by the By-Laws of 1910 control of all scientific work of the Institute, including the work of the Hospital was under the exclusive control of the not-more than seven-man Board of Scientific Directors. The Charter change in 1910 provided that successors of the first Board of Directors be elected by the Board of Trustees from candidates nominated by the Scientific Directors.</p>
      <p>Executive organization consisted of an Executive Committee, Budget Committee and a Committee on the Hospital, which last was dropped in the amended Rules January 19, 1918. Committee members were elected at the Annual Meeting, but amended in 1946 to provide that the term be for one year and until the election of successors. Administrative officers were the Director (clearly provided after 1924), Director of the Laboratories, Director of the Hospital, between 1915-1930 a Director of the Department of Animal Pathology, and between 1930-1951 a Director of the Department of Animal and Plant Pathology. Another administrative officer was a General Manager, to be Treasurer of the Board of Scientific Directors (amended October 14, 1911... shall act as treasurer...). The General Manager (amended January 11, 1913 to Manager; amended April 20, 1918 to Business Manager) was authorized to draw upon the Treasurer of the Board of Trustees for the sums of money needed to meet Institute expenses authorized under the budget. Administrative officers were originally elected by the Board of Scientific Directors to serve at its pleasure. Later amendments provided that the Director be an appointment of the Corporation on nomination of a committee composed of three from the Scientific Directors and three from the Board of Trustees. The Business Manager, selected by the Scientific Directors was appointed by the Board of Trustees. Other administrative officers were elected by the Board itself. Appointive positions, at the discretion of the Board of Scientific Directors, were Deputy Business Manager, Assistant Business Manager, Bursar and a group of hospital positions.</p>
      <p>Changes in the By-Laws of the Corporation in 1928 provided that the not-more than seven-man Board of Scientific Directors have no more than two who were actively engaged in scientific work for the Corporation. This was further modified in 1934 so that the Board of Scientific Directors was to consist of the Director and no more than six others with only the Director of the Institute being an. active member of the staff engaged in scientific work for the Corporation. Also provided was that the appointment of the Director of the Institute was to constitute his election as a member of the Board of Scientific Directors to hold office until the end of his service as Director of the Institute. October 28, 1933 the By-Laws of the Corporation were amended to provide that a member of the Board of Scientific Directors, on retirement from the Board, could, on recommendation or with the approval of the Board of Scientific Directors be given, by the Board of Trustees, the honorary title of Member Emeritus of the Board of Scientific Directors. At the same time, the By-Laws regarding a vacancy on the Board of Scientific Directors provided that for each vacancy at least two candidates be nominated by the Scientific Directors for election by the Board of Trustees.</p>
      <p>The members of the original Board of Directors became the Board of Scientific Directors and remained unchanged except that in 1911 Theodore C. Janeway was elected to fill the vacancy created by the death of Christian A. Herter. T.C. Janeway died in 1918 and until 1920 the Board of Scientific Directors consisted of only six members. In 1920 W.J.V. Osterhout was added to the Board. In 1923 Hermann M. Biggs died, and in 1924 both L. Emmett Holt and T. Mitchell Prudden died. Francis Gilman Blake and John Howland were named in 1924 to fill two of the vacancies. In 1925 W.J.V. Osterhout resigned to join the scientific staff of the Institute and in 1926 Charles R. Stockard was elected to fill this vacancy. In 1926 Francis W. Peabody was elected to succeed T. Mitchell Prudden but he died less than a year later. John Howland died in 1926, and Eugene L. Opie, elected to fill that vacancy served on the Board of Scientific Directors 1929-1932. In 1930 James B. Conant was elected to fill the vacancy created by the death of Francis W. Peabody. William H. Welch resigned in 1933 and Warfield T. Longcope was elected to that vacancy in 1934. Theobald Smith died in 1934. In 1935 A. Raymond Dochez was elected to succeed Francis G. Blake, and in October of that same year Herbert S. Gasser succeeded Simon Flexner as Director of the Institute and on the Board of Scientific Directors. In 1936 Walter B. Cannon and George H. Whipple were elected to the Board. Charles Rupert Stockard died in 1939 and was succeeded by Ross G. Harrison. Walter B. Cannon died in 1945 and was succeeded in 1946 by Detlev W. Bronk. James B. Conant resigned in 1949 and Vincent du Vigneaud was elected to that vacancy. Warfield T. Longcope resigned in 1952.</p>
      <p>The original elected officers of the Board of Scientific Directors were William H. Welch, President; T. Mitchell Prudden, Vice-President; and L. Emmett Holt, Secretary. In 1924 Theobald Smith was elected Vice-President and Francis G. Blake, Secretary. In 1933, Theobald Smith was elected President and Charles R. Stockard, Vice-President. Charles R. Stockard was elected President and A. Raymond Dochez, Secretary in 1935- The office of Vice-President was not filled until 1937 when Warfield T. Longcope was elected Vice-President. Warfield T. Longcope became President in 1939 and in 1940 Ross G. Harrison became Vice-president. In 1952 when Warfield T. Longcope resigned from the Board of Scientific Directors, Ross G. Harrison was elected President; A. Raymond Dochez, Vice-President and Vincent du Vigneaud, Secretary.</p>
      <p>William H. Welch and Simon Flexner were the original representatives of the Board of Scientific Directors on the Board of Trustees. When Simon Flexner retired as Director of The Institute he was succeeded on the Board of Trustees by Herbert S. Gasser, and in 1936 Charles R. Stockard was appointed to succeed the late William H. Welch. In 1939 Charles R. Stockard was succeeded by George H. Whipple.</p>
      <p>In 1953 an extensive reorganization began. The Rules for the Board of Scientific Directors were repealed. New By-Laws for the Corporation provided that the members of the Board of Scientific Directors as constituted on June 23, 1953, and the members of the Board of Trustees on that same date, merge to form one Board known as the Board of Trustees.</p>
      <chronlist>
        <head>Governing Boards of The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, 1901-1911, from information in the Minutes of the Board of Scientific Directors, May 1901-June 1911 (The first minutes of the Board of Trustees are dated 17 October 1910)</head>
        <chronitem>
          <date>24 June 1901</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Board of Directors; William H. Welch, President; T. Mitchell Prudden, Vice President; Christian A. Herter, Treasurer; L. Emmett Holt, Secretary; Hermann M. Biggs; Simon Flexner; Theobald Smith</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>12 April 1902</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Directors Flexner and Holt, elected for three years to succeed themselves. Officers of previous year re-elected.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>11 April 1903</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Directors Herter and Smith, elected for three years to succeed themselves. Officers of previous year re-elected.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>13 June 1904</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Directors Biggs, Prudden, and Welch, elected for three years to succeed themselves. Officers of previous year re-elected.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>15 April 1905</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Directors Holt and Flexner, elected for three years to succeed themselves. Officers of previous year re-elected. New officer: "Directors of Laboratories - Dr. Simon Flexner."</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>21 April 1906</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Directors Smith and Herter, elected for three years to succeed themselves. Officers of previous year re-elected.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>13 April 1907</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Directors Welch, Biggs, and Prudden, elected for three years to succeed themselves. Officers of previous year re-elected</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>11 April 1908</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Directors Flexner and Holt, elected for three years to succeed themselves. Officers of previous year re-elected.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>10 April 1909</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Directors Smith and Herter, elected for three years to succeed themselves. Officers Welch, Prudden, and Flexner re-elected. L. Emmett Holt, Secretary and Treasurer. New Officer: "Director of the Hospital - Dr. Rufus I. Cole."</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>9 April 1910</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Directors Welch, Prudden, and Biggs, elected for three years to succeed themselves. Officers of previous year re-elected.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>15 October 1910</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Board of Directors adopts new By-laws, establishing Board of Trustees, to consist of not more than 9 members, and Board of Scientific Directors, to consist of not more than 7 members.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>First Board of Trustees: William H. Welch, Frederick T. Gates, Simon Flexner, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>First Board of Scientific Directors: Simon Flexner, L. Emmett Holt, Theobald Smith, Christian A. Herter, William H. Welch, T. Mitchell Prudden, Hermann Biggs.</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>21 January 1911</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Recorded as "Regular Quarterly Meeting of the Board of Directors."</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
        <chronitem>
          <date>8 April 1911</date>
          <eventgrp>
            <event>Recorded as "Regular Quarterly Meeting of the Board of Scientific Directors."</event>
          </eventgrp>
        </chronitem>
      </chronlist>
    </bioghist>
    <prefercite id="aspace_c8dff162082e9eb5f35c0f7016541e52">
      <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
      <p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>
    </prefercite>
    <fileplan id="aspace_f825d5fb6ed8a495c5e610073e4eca2e">
      <head>File Plan note</head>
      <p>Former Classification: I 130-6</p>
    </fileplan>
    <bioghist id="aspace_f1cd181a38d7821820728a0d2a06e7b0">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>CORPORATION</p>
      <p>In May 1908 the Charter of The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research was amended to permit the creation of a not more than nine member Board of Trustees to have exclusive control of the real property and the principal of all permanent funds of the Corporation. By-Laws for the Corporation were established October 1910. The members of the first Board of Trustees were: William H. Welch, Frederick T. Gates, Simon Flexner, Starr J. Murphy and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. The first meeting of the Board of Trustees was held October 17, 1910.</p>
      <p>Elected officers were President, Vice-President, Secretary and Treasurer of the Corporation. The first three names were required to be members of the Board of Trustees. The Trustees were empowered to appoint, on the nomination of the Board of Scientific Directors, a General Manager to represent the Board of Trustees in the care and maintenance of the real property of the Corporation. Functioning of the Board of Trustees was through an Executive Committee (of not more than six, including the President) and a Finance Committee (composed of three members elected from the Board by the Board) which was deemed to be in continuous session. Two members were elected for the Budget Committee, a joint committee with the Board of Scientific Directors to approve the annual budget for the scientific work of the Institute, within the limits of the yearly balance of available income. The Board was empowered to appoint such assistants to the Treasurer or other agents and employees as were necessary.</p>
      <p>The original By-Laws of the Corporation provided a relatively complicated formula for determining the composition of the members elected to the Board of Trustees, but amendment to the By-Laws in 1928 simplified the Rules to provide for two Trustees appointed by the Scientific Directors, one Trustee named by John D. Rockefeller or John D. Rockefeller, Jr., and the remaining members on a majority vote of the members of the Corporation at an annual meeting or special meeting called for that purpose. May 28, 1914 additional clarifications were made in the Trustees' Rules to further define the authority and powers of the Finance Committee.</p>
      <p>Resolutions were taken from time to time, governing the use of income. In 1915 it was resolved that any surplus income accumulated in any one year be added to permanent endowment to be used for non-recurring expenses. However, by 1939, in an effort to secure a downward trend in the size of the budget and to adjust to changes in the economy the 1915 resolution was rescinded.</p>
      <p>The first addition to the Board of Trustees was in 1913 when Jerome D. Greene was elected, to the Board. He served until 1932. Starr J. Murphy died in 1921 and was replaced by Raymond B. Fosdick (1921-1936). The next added was Trevor Arnett (1926-1937). Further additions to the Board of Trustees were: Charles W. Appleton (1928-1940), George Murnane (1928- ), Henry James (1929-1947), John D. Rockefeller, 3rd (1932-1950), David Rockefeller (1940-), who wan on leave with the Armed Forces 1942-45, John C. Traphagen (1936-1959), Frederick Osborn, (1938-1946), Barklie Henry (1947-1966), Lindsley F. Kimball (1947-1971), Donald K. David (1950-1971). From the Board of Scientific Directors, Herbert S. Gasser succeeded Simon Flexner in 1935; Charles R. Stockard succeeded William H. Welch in 1936, and George H. Whipple succeeded Charles Stockard in 1939.</p>
      <p>The first officers of the Board of Trustees were: Frederick T. Gates, President; William H. Welch, Vice-President; and Starr J. Murphy, Secretary. Upon the death of F.T. Gates in 1929, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. was elected President of the Board of Trustees and was reelected until he requested that his name not be placed in nominational the expiration of his term October 1950. (He resigned as a Trustee in 1954). John D. Rockefeller, Jr. was succeeded as President in 1950 by David Rockefeller. William H. Welch was succeeded as Vice-President in 1933 by Simon Flexner who retired in 1935. No action was taken on the vice-presidency until 1937 when Henry James was elected and served until 1947. George Hoyt Whipple was elected Vice-President in 1947. Starr J. Murphy resigned as secretary in 1921 and was succeeded by Raymond Blaine Fosdick who resigned in 1936. Trevor Arnett was elected Secretary in 1936 and resigned within a year. In 1937 Edric B. Smith (who was also Business Manager of the Institute) became Secretary and served until 1954.</p>
      <p>Starr J. Murphy served also as Counsel to the Board of Trustees until his death in 1921; Aubin L. Boulware was Counsel 1921-June 1923. A more formal arrangement started September 1924 with Thomas McElrath Debevoise who served until 1958; Associate Counsel 1934-1947 was Chauncey Belknap and from 1947 John Edwards Lockwood. Mr. Lockwood became Counsel in 1959 and served until 1968/69. Donal Clare O'Brien, Associate Counsel from 1955/56 became Counsel in 1969/70.</p>
      <p>In 1953 an extensive reorganization began. New By-Laws adopted June 23, 1953 provided that "The members of the Corporation shall consist of the members of the Board of Trustees and the members of the Board of Scientific Directors as those Boards are constituted on the 23rd day of June 1953 and hereafter the said Boards shall be merged into one Board known as the Board of Trustees".</p>
      <p>The new By-Laws for the Corporation were adopted to implement the recommendations made in the Report of the Committee on Nomination and Review which had been appointed October 26, 1951 to "review the fundamental policies of the Institute." The Chairman of the Board was designated the chief policy officer of the Corporation to interpret the policies determined by the Board of Trustees, and the President the chief executive officer of the Corporation to have general supervision over the business of the Corporation and over the several staff officers subject to the control of the Board of Trustees and responsible for the work of the Institute.</p>
      <p>The business of the Board of Trustees was implemented by three elected committees: and Executive Committee of between 5 and 7 members including the Chairman; a Finance Committee of between 3 and 5 members (as amended January 1957) to handle investments and advise on financial policy and a policy; and a Budget Committee of between 3 and 5 members to review the budget proposed by the President each year and recommend on its adoption by the Board of Trustees. At the moment of reorganization much of the administrative procedure was determined by Resolution to continue in previous patterns while business and financial studies were in progress.</p>
      <p>The first officers elected were: David Rockefeller, Chairman of the Board; George Hoyt Whipple, Vice-Chairman; Detlev Bronk, President; Thomas M. Rivers, Vice-President. Executive officers were Edward Robinson as Treasurer and Edric Brooks Smith who continued as Business Manager and Secretary until his retirement October 1955. Other members of the new Board of Trustees were: Lindsley Fiske Kimball, Donald Kirk David, Ross Granville Harrison, John C. Traphagen, Alphonse Raymond Dochez, Vincent du Vigneaud, Barklie Henry, George Murnane and John Davison Rockefeller, Jr.</p>
      <p>As the changing character of the Institute evolved, By-Laws were amended, Resolutions were rescinded and changes were instituted to provide for the development of the Institute along the lines suggested by the Report of the Committee on Nomination and Review. To the three committees originally provided in the By-Laws was added an elected Committee on Audit. Added also were appointive committees: Committee on Educational Policies, Committee on Research, Committee on Business Operations, Committee on Buildings and Grounds and a Committee on Nominations. January 30, 1957 a Committee on Hospital Affairs was appointed to review present and future hospital policies.</p>
      <p>In 1955, Thomas M. Rivers, Vice-President and Director of the Institute retired and at that time resolutions were taken to discontinue the division of the Institute into Departments, to eliminate the position of Director of the Institute and to provide for several Vice-Presidents, Frank L. Horsfall served as Vice-President for Clinical Studies 1955-1957 and Douglas Whitaker was Vice-President for Administration 1955-1964. When Edric Smith retired in 1955, John E. Lockwood then Assistant Counsel became, in addition, Secretary of the Board and after the death in 1958 of Thomas Debevoise he became in 1959 both Secretary and Counsel.</p>
      <p>New members of the Board of Trustees were: in 1954, Robert Loeb, Eli Whitney Debevoise, Kenneth C. Brownell (1954-1958); in 1956, William J. Robbins; in 1957, Philip Bard; in 1958, Albert L. Nickerson; in 1960, J. Richardson Dilworth and William O. Baker; in 1961 Baron Edgar Douglas Adrian; in 1966 George F. Bennett and Frederick Seitz; in 1968, Philip Handler and John W. Gardner; in 1969, Thomas Grady Cousins, Walter N. Rothschild, Jr., Robert Gregg Stone and Chauncey William Wallace Cook; in 1970, Christian Archibald Herter, Jr. Resignations from the Board of Trustees were: in 1954, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; 1955, Thomas M. Rivers; 1957 Ross Granville Harrison; 1959 John C. Traphagen and Alphonse Raymond Dochez; 1964 George Murnane; 1965 Baron Edgar Douglas Adrian; 1966 William J. Robbins and Barklie McKee Henry died in 1966.</p>
      <p>George H. Whipple who had served on the Board of Scientific Directors and been their elected representative on the Board of Trustees and its Vice-President became a member of the newly constituted Board of Trustees in 1953. He was elected Vice-Chairman and held that office until his resignation in October 1960. Robert F. Loeb was then elected Vice-Chairman of the Board where he served until he resigned May 1970 and was succeeded by William O. Baker.</p>
      <p>Changes in Charter and By-Laws were made as the changes in Institute organization developed. In May 1965 the Corporate name was changed to The Rockefeller University and the new Charter and amended By-Laws were published in 1966. They provided that the number of Trustees be between five and twenty-five; that elected officers be a Chairman, Vice-Chairman, and a President all of whom shall be or become Trustees. Other elected officers were to be Secretary and Treasurer, one or more Vice-Presidents, Assistant Secretaries and Assistant Treasurers and other officers as considered necessary by the Board. One person may be elected to more than one office except that President and Secretary may not be the same person. Officers are elected for one year or until respective successors are elected.</p>
      <p>On the retirement of Detlev Bronk (who became a Trustee Emeritus) in October 1968, Frederick Seitz was elected President; C. Eugene Sunderlin was elected to succeed John E. Lockwood as Secretary at the time of Mr. Lockwood's retirement and Donal C. O'Brien, Jr. became Counsel at that time.</p>
      <p>Board changes:</p>
      <p>Additions: Bearn, Alexander G. 1970; Hildebrand, John G. 1970; Kac, Mark 1970; Yang, Chen Ning 1970; Bassine, Charles C. 1971; Casimir, Hendrik E.G. 1971; Haggerty, Patrick E. 1971; Heiskell, Marion S. 1971; Rockefeller, David, Jr. 1971; Whitehead, Edwin C. 1971; Linen, James A. III 1972; Astor, Brooke (Mrs. Vincent Astor) 1972</p>
      <p>Retirements or Resignations: David, Donald K. 1971; Gardner, John W. 1971; Kimball, Lindsley 1971; Cook, Chauncey William W. 1972</p>
      <p>Resignation: Kac, Mark 1973; Hildebrand, John G. 1973</p>
      <p>Additions: Griffin, Donald R. 1973; Williams, Robley C. Jr. 1973</p>
      <p>Additions: Ralph E. Ablon 1974; Nicholas F. Brady 1974</p>
      <p>In October of 1975 David Rockefeller resigned as Chairman of the Board of Trustees and became Chairman of the Trustees' Executive Committee in order to concentrate his attention on the University's program to broaden its base of private support. He was succeeded as Chairman of the Board by Patrick E. Haggerty.</p>
      <p>New Board appointments: Dr. Lewis Thomas 1975; Dr. Seymour S. Kety 1976; Mrs. Anne E. Reed 1976; Dr. P. Roy Vagelos 1976; Richard M. Furlaud 1976; John R. Stevenson 1976; Neva Rockefeller Kaiser 1977; Norman F. Ramsey 1977; Alexander D. Forger 1978; J. Paul Sticht 1978; Frank T. Cary 1978; Pamela Harriman 1979; David A. Hamburg 1979; Curtis L. Blake 1980</p>
      <p>Retirements: resignations: Philip Bard 1974-1975; David Rockefeller, Jr. 1977; Patrick E Haggerty died suddenly October 1, 1980; William O. Baker elected Chairman of Bd. of Trustees October 21, 1980</p>
    </bioghist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_21e4eb33468d80752a18cc9985351195">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
      <p>This collection is open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of the RAC.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_5d65859eef92275ba4b425efd246bfe5">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>Contains files of Starr Murphy, Raymond Fosdick, Trevor Arnett and Edric Smith.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref437_hz0" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Starr J. Murphy (1911-1921); Raymond B. Fosdick (1921-1936); Trevor Arnett (1936); Edric B. Smith (1936-1955)</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1910/1955" type="inclusive">1910-1955</unitdate>
          <physdesc id="aspace_6591ff2e7941fc53e4eb7d482f2a81bf">4 boxes</physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_3b5747d735d1c418a7df3cde4cc2cae2">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>Administrative papers and correspondence.</p>
          <p>The kinds of material included varies greatly depending upon who filled the office of Secretary of the Board of Trustees but in general deals with the business of the Trustees in maintaining and developing Institute properties and appointments. Includes correspondence with Trustees, Officers, and Business Manager. Items from the Director of the Institute to be placed on Docket for meetings. Preliminary drafts of Minutes of meetings and Resolutions. Includes notices of nominations made by the Board of Scientific Directors to fill vacancies in the membership of the Scientific Directors.</p>
          <p>Includes some preliminary dockets, or dockets and some notices of meetings and invitations also including some proxies and replies.</p>
          <p>From 1944 some original signed approvals of actions of the Executive Committee.</p>
          <p>Originals of action on budget signed by Budget Committee for the years of 1925/1926, 1926/1927, 1927/1928, 1930/1931, 1932/1933.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="aspace_95864295b1de4e49883e2373835b801b">
          <head>Arrangement note</head>
          <p>Arranged in chronological order.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <c id="aspace_ref981_6v6" level="file">
          <did>
            <unitdate normal="1910/1926" type="inclusive">1910-1926</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_6eed72d1b74f7a82dc9745c480f5f507" label="Mixed Materials (559251.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
          </did>
          <c id="aspace_ref985_fca" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Items of interest include:</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_fc639d60aa8ee10a4094392e4992705d" label="Mixed Materials (559252.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
            </did>
            <c id="aspace_ref439_83l" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Notice of special meeting June 12, 1911 signed by Starr J. Murphy to adopt new article to the Trustees' Rules to provide for a Finance Committee</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1911 May 31</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_b9c2ee6cc808e1162d0558ee2ca94216" label="Mixed Materials (559253.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref440_tp3" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Report to Board of Trustees from Committee (Henry James, Starr J. Murphy, Jerome D. Greene) on Fire risk and suggested coverage (Committee on Insurance)</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1916 February 3</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_a1ccbc504bf396b9b464beb742915646" label="Mixed Materials (559253.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref441_z6d" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Correspondence concerning laboratory of Social Hygiene, Bedford Hills, NY - Miss Davis; Mabel R. Fernald</unittitle>
                <unitdate normal="1913/1915" type="inclusive">1913-1915</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_a1c330c75109054a00fc8e166703db65" label="Mixed Materials (559253.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref442_6uf" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Letter from Starr J. Murphy to Henry James stating that formal authorizations of budgets be filed with Minute Book</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1916 April 27</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_3c2f7f19838925407ad562e5821a9237" label="Mixed Materials (559253.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref443_ge1" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Correspondence between Starr J. Murphy and Simon Flexner dealing with plans for an international commission to study tuberculosis as an activity of the Rockefeller Foundation including a projected compilation of funds required for Rockefeller Foundation activities 1916-1921 (dated December 7, 1916)</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1916 November 6[?]-15</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_75f8a4ae84cf04518a0ad82a330198f9" label="Mixed Materials (559253.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref444_j0c" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>To Henry James from Starr J. Murphy regarding use of name of Institute in advertisements of Duffy Malt Whiskey Company recommending use of whiskey in treatment of diabetes</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1916 November 22</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_5afff226fb7ec08917f1f9a3cf154cb6" label="Mixed Materials (559253.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref445_ma6" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Hand written report on war activities by Simon Flexner for submission to Rockefeller Foundation</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1918 July 1</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_c6e5b25f0f7ec1ef43f0e9996462cdda" label="Mixed Materials (559253.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref446_ceq" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Handwritten letter from William Welch accepting election as Vice-president of Corporation</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1922 January 27</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_af4ae495146bb84d6e28d93477948afd" label="Mixed Materials (559253.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref447_7mw" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Correspondence between L.G. Myers, Treasurer, F.T. Gates, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Raymond Fosdick, Secretary on revising manner of composition and operation of Finance Committee to avoid possible accusation of tax evasion. Four page handwritten letter by F.T. Gates explaining his stand</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1923 December 3-1924 February 7</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_f001c2018721bf7ba51b1e59e1e2d4ce" label="Mixed Materials (559253.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref448_vze" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Correspondence between F.T. Gates, Bertram Cutler, Simon Flexner and Raymond Fosdick regarding F.T. Gates resignation from Finance Committee and Institute Board</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1925 December 19-1926 January 26</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_2266883f875e55a5fead1d676c0bb223" label="Mixed Materials (559253.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref449_22v" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>An extract from a letter written Oct. 1926 by F.T. Gates to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. dealing with pattern for electing Institute Boards</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_b33df4585aa44c7c6274a73618ab5726" label="Mixed Materials (559253.1.318)" type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c>
          </c>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref982_oxz" level="file">
          <did>
            <unitdate normal="1927/1937" type="inclusive">1927-1937</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_a5840aa227f6188851f154897bf45a6a" label="Mixed Materials (559251.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
          <c id="aspace_ref986_4pe" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Items of interest include:</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_051361c6cd64e44b1aa3d3a815db4cb0" label="Mixed Materials (559265.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
            </did>
            <c id="aspace_ref450_kdj" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Handwritten letter from William Welch to Raymond Fosdick on departure to Europe for study of institutions related to history of medicine</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1927 May 8</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_a456d3f86a809cb0299241952b08f9a9" label="Mixed Materials (559266.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref451_kyr" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Correspondence dealing with change of name of Avenue A in view of land purchase by Society of New York Hospital</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1927 December 28</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_5212edf9499312b3368d818b39e07af9" label="Mixed Materials (559266.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref452_s6i" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>From Simon Flexner to Raymond Fosdick a list of items to be presented to Trustees for appropriations including developments in Plant and Animal Pathology at Princeton</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1929 February 18</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_9b1f04aa931c4960121e35b687d52f8c" label="Mixed Materials (559266.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref453_97f" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Copy of letter from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to William Welch on his naming as President of the Board of Trustees and acknowledgement of thanks for gift of block South of 64th Street</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1929 November 20</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_c55e269188881e02a9074a24f8fe2742" label="Mixed Materials (559266.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref454_xuv" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Handwritten draft by Thomas Debevoise of resolution regarding closing of streets in accordance with agreement with City in consideration of Mr. Rockefeller's gift of property known as Billings Estate</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1930 October 29</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_c9fb0491bfe5fb26c30db69346bffe64" label="Mixed Materials (559266.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref455_we1" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Handwritten letter from Eugene L. Opie to Raymond Fosdick regretting he could not attend memorial service for L.G. Myers</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1932 February 1</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_6a0cb2c0fab94436238e819708183ca7" label="Mixed Materials (559266.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref456_gsp" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Signed amendment with eleven affected members for changes in Rules Governing Retiring Allowances</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1934 February</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_01d51ae902c48d5de4436818dcc73f6a" label="Mixed Materials (559266.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref457_ocm" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Group of letters dating back to Oct. 31, 1916 reviewing and reopening question of depreciation, allowances</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1934 June 15</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_9714298cd3320b3dc08b21132108988e" label="Mixed Materials (559266.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref458_22n" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Letter from Edric B. Smith to Simon Flexner listing gifts made to Institute by the Rockefeller. Foundation 1915-1917</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1934 June 25</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_faee5e69c9fa040f31676af2c12652f0" label="Mixed Materials (559266.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref459_wb7" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Letter from John D. Rockefeller, Jr; deeding property bounded by 67th-68th Streets and First and York Avenues to Rockefeller Institute which is to be transferred to Memorial Hospital, if within five years Memorial Hospital is financially in a position to use the land.</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1934 September 25</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_65651940823b3c999643471ba62139f1" label="Mixed Materials (559266.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref460_rob" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Letter from Henry James to Raymond Fosdick regarding additional honorarium for Simon Flexner in his retirement</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1935 October 3</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_9b4077d05506dfe4271c32d3df8d3543" label="Mixed Materials (559266.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref461_zjz" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>John D. Rockefeller, Jr. 'S copy of remarks he made on the occasion of Simon Flexner's retirement and election of Herbert S. Gasser as Director of the Rockefeller Institute</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1935 October 7</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_0a275175154c1ea0a5b3651feb0b752b" label="Mixed Materials (559266.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref462_0an" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Simon Flexner letters of resignation as Director of the Institute and member of the Board of Trustees</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1935 October 4 1935 October 17</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_04b8eaa74b95f040d24214ad39763894" label="Mixed Materials (559266.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref463_qoz" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Comments by Henry James pointing out there is no need for Trustees to ratify each and every action of Finance Committee. Trustees need only to be informed of actions for fiscal year</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1936 September 30</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_7b8d74fd71d96df3d3410edcfd36e1dc" label="Mixed Materials (559266.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref464_t9c" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Correspondence from July 5, 1934 regarding Van Heusen Estate</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1936 November 18</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_38a5405bc21c11240ad9c6ea17159142" label="Mixed Materials (559266.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref465_o84" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Copy of letter from Rockefeller Foundation concerning change in policy regarding capital gifts</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1937 May 12</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_46302ed61155299e5b74a6d728e174c2" label="Mixed Materials (559266.2.318)" type="box">2</container>
              </did>
            </c>
          </c>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref983_izb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unitdate normal="1938/1955" type="inclusive">1938-1955</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_f72e6767360ae19eae4cc16faac89431" label="Mixed Materials (559251.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
          </did>
          <c id="aspace_ref987_653" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Items of interest include:</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_99e74107a5ca706bf159df792ce7d794" label="Mixed Materials (559283.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
            </did>
            <c id="aspace_ref466_cc7" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Copy of Promise and Agreement between City of New York and Rockefeller Institute in construction of tunnel under East River Drive</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1939 October</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_767df88eb9d1aef80b17952aa3b186ad" label="Mixed Materials (559284.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref467_gm6" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Correspondence between John D. Rockefeller Jr. and Dr. Gasser regarding illness of Judge Appleton and election of David Rockefeller to Board of Trustees</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1940 September 9 1940 September 12 1940 September 16</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_36b2987b968d1adde189d222812c1498" label="Mixed Materials (559284.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref468_rag" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Draft of resolution that Institute not accept $ 25,000 grant from National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1940 October 25</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_4edb270798d02e92f271cf8ff8a24e8e" label="Mixed Materials (559284.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref469_lll" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Correspondence dealing with insurance considered because of war risks</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1942 July</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_c347d9eaa76c797ebc5a4395689199dd" label="Mixed Materials (559284.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref470_h1r" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Various resignations, appointments and proxies dealing with the merger of the two Boards and planned reorganization</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1953 May-June</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_c9ee46521d42c7605df747cd31e60b19" label="Mixed Materials (559284.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref471_f9b" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Letter from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to David Rockefeller consenting to new By-Laws for Corporation</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_a43c6ad7d1e103f81f202968c111946b" label="Mixed Materials (559284.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref472_l3j" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Circulated votes on appointment, salary and leave of absence for Haldan Keffer Hartline and Frank Brink, Jr.</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1953 July 17</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_0741a7a215ebbfae3c7efd7498465579" label="Mixed Materials (559284.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref473_slh" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Waiver of notice of meeting to amend Charter to make Institute part of University of State of New York and power to grant degrees</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1954 October 15</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_28f62643054020aef283e8d6ec4e2696" label="Mixed Materials (559284.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref474_ywu" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Invitation and Program for 50th Anniversary Convocation</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_699990aafbfd5fbee5da5a12e2284472" label="Mixed Materials (559284.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref475_ip1" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Signed approvals of Executive Committee for action to be taken regarding Rudolph Winterberg Estate</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1955 May 4</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_8e15e9f0716c1999182a42d44e40313c" label="Mixed Materials (559284.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref476_cu2" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Signed proxies for meeting to amend By-Laws (Art. XV: Budget)</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1955 June 27</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_ff1f9b5204d1977771370084a76239e6" label="Mixed Materials (559284.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref477_pdu" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Copy of correspondence regarding bill of William M. Ellard for survey and Analysis 66th-67th-Street and York Avenues</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1955 June 28</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_5795f2ea76b5ed1c47565b089bcadb08" label="Mixed Materials (559284.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref478_aau" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Preliminary memo prepared by Debevoise, Plimpton and McLean on proposed York Ave. Redevelopment Project</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1955 July 9</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_29b98ceb9937a6c2967d5310847900bc" label="Mixed Materials (559284.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref479_98u" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Signed proxies to amend Art. VI and Art. X and repeal Art. XI (Officers, Vice-President, Directors)</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1955 August 15</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_4122aaaf5d714c20e613b8e7d9c40fe4" label="Mixed Materials (559284.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
              </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ref480_8bk" level="item">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Two letters dealing with real estate on the West side of York Avenue.</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1957 September 6 1959 February 4</unitdate>
                <container id="aspace_5a343d2f3fb05ab40e479cc3d4f8de2c" label="Mixed Materials (559284.3.318)" type="box">3</container>
              </did>
            </c>
          </c>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref984_j28" level="file">
          <did>
            <unitdate normal="1910/1956" type="inclusive">1910-1956</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_ad85393b65373bf18a96d2af89998f4c" label="Mixed Materials (559251.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
          </did>
          <c id="aspace_ref481_9o9" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Notices of meetings of Board of Trustees, Corporation or Committees and signed proxies.</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1910/1936" type="inclusive">1910-1936</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_fa10253bf57333156cd27f041e90771f">3 folders</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_d46156f201ec0889ca39ddfcc107c526" label="Mixed Materials (559300.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref483_krj" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Dockets of meetings</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1924/1956" type="inclusive">1924-1938 1939-1950 1951-1956</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_9185950f587412f2bd7faa2401e3a13d" label="Mixed Materials (559300.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref484_rv9" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Secretary's Exhibit Book</unittitle>
              <physdesc id="aspace_b002adbe4bf93f02b76a019c97ad84cf">3 folders and 2 envelopes</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_ac152e14e9bedf05b8834dada4fa9bae" label="Mixed Materials (559300.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
            </did>
            <arrangement id="aspace_17feadb52bd492b94545af2e95890da7">
              <head>Arrangement</head>
              <p>Arranged chronologically (as per minutes).</p>
            </arrangement>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_895c3419ba6de69f12f26866e1493f69">
              <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
              <p>Special items as follows:.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="aspace_ref989_m9s" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Items of interest include:</unittitle>
              </did>
              <c id="aspace_ref486_vec" level="item">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Photographic copy of engrossed memorial to Frederick Taylor Gates</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1929 February 6[?]</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_3029544379fe928f71c33b8f5096f35c" label="Mixed Materials (559304.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
                </did>
              </c>
              <c id="aspace_ref487_j33" level="item">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Original minutes on occasion of William H. Welch resignation from Board of Trustees. Signed by Raymond B. Fosdick, Henry James, Simon Flexner</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1933 October 27</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_b30fb5ce0443f30644567093aa087c27" label="Mixed Materials (559304.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
                </did>
              </c>
              <c id="aspace_ref488_nkn" level="item">
                <did>
                  <unittitle>Photographic copy of engrossed memorial to John Davison Rockefeller</unittitle>
                  <unitdate type="inclusive">1937 May 23</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_3b3ce36a7efd57e95160703575d7c7ed" label="Mixed Materials (559304.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
                </did>
              </c>
            </c>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref490_6sk" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondence</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1934/1950" type="inclusive">1934-1950</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_fa5581d6d971f8c7bce8a309a78986fd" label="Mixed Materials (559300.4.318)" type="box">4</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_5d5c20579471e7d6e3ffb17c82a9fd6e">
              <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
              <p>Letter (copy) November 7, 1934 from Janet Warfield, secretary, acknowledging October 23, 1934 letter (copy) from Simon Flexner in appreciation of gift of the parcel of land bounded by 67th-68th Streets, York Avenue and 1st and calling attention to letter (copy) written by William Welch, November 15, 1929 in appreciation of gift of land 63rd-64th Streets, York and East River and acceptance of Corporation presidency.</p>
              <p>Letter (copy) April 24, 1950 from H.S. Gasser to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. on his request that he not be renominated for Presidency of Board of Trustees. October 27, 1950 letter (copy) sent to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. from Board of Trustees on his retirement as President and excerpt from Board of Trustees Minutes October 27, 1950 with copy of John D. Rockefeller's letter to H.S. Gasser of April 17, 1950.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref494_fiw" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Edric B. Smith</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1943/1953" type="inclusive">1943-1953</unitdate>
          <physdesc id="aspace_e9b6f06c4897e8e7fba530b986d8650a">1 box (2 1/2 inches)</physdesc>
          <container id="aspace_4b27f1bf88909a711e719914360634e0" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_50893b05b9d6c0d23fc7a75579e5bccf">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>Administrative papers and correspondence.</p>
          <p>This collection is an addition to RG 130.6 (3) and is for the period 1943 June to April 1953. Any user should note the gap from July 1942 to May 1953.</p>
          <p>Consists of correspondence between members of the Board of Trustees and the secretary of the Board, Edric B. Smith. Deals with the business of the Board, including retirements, budget approvals, expenditure approvals, building remodeling, integration of Princeton and New York City laboratories, and elections to the Board. Correspondence with Thomas Debevoise deals with approvals of form and content of the Minutes of Board meetings. Also included are copies of signed approvals of certain actions taken by the Board.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="aspace_865adeda47c4d8d524b13f9a6eae8395">
          <head>Arrangement note</head>
          <p>Arranged in chronological order: 1943 June-November 1947; 1948 January-November 1950; 1951 January-April 1953.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <c id="aspace_ref990_qug" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Items of interest include:</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c id="aspace_ref496_xng" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Action taken by Trustees to consider Integration of Princeton and New York City laboratories</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1947 May 2</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_6457c1b2e130a6203792bc6abb3158a5" label="Mixed Materials (559310.5.318)" type="box">5</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref497_izv" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Agreement to accept 70% settlement on loss of principle in a remainder interest under the will of Edith A. Cohen</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1947 November 18</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_cbecf12240d3c6399d53e00cdf5ef5df" label="Mixed Materials (559310.5.318)" type="box">5</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref498_ezv" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Letter to H.S. Gasser from J.D. Rockefeller, Jr. with details of a 13-year Trust Fund providing income for The RIMR (copy)</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1948 June 16</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_f383d4fa2ebc9446c2bbc3c0e8a96fed" label="Mixed Materials (559310.5.318)" type="box">5</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref499_kyx" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>John D. Rockefeller approval for proceeding with Hospital construction despite high cost, (copy)</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1949 February 9</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_d32bd8d543c6a190354895c714f8b7b1" label="Mixed Materials (559310.5.318)" type="box">5</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref500_c55" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Copy of Dr. Gasser's Minute at decision of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. decision not to stand for reelection as President of the Board of Trustees</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1950 October</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_b736048fad0ce7da97962ee66bb0bf81" label="Mixed Materials (559310.5.318)" type="box">5</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref501_lbg" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>From John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to Members of Corporation acknowledging Minute expressing appreciation of his role in RI history</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1951 January 19</unitdate>
              <physdesc id="aspace_84982ceeb4bd45944a5965e3ab22f7f2">(multigraph copy)</physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_7a94674c2224771a86a42fa74d202d74" label="Mixed Materials (559310.5.318)" type="box">5</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="aspace_ref503_m4r" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Approval for additional annuities for employees retired before benefits from Social Security established</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1951 June 29</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_483044a76a531c5579b167f38abacebd" label="Mixed Materials (559310.5.318)" type="box">5</container>
            </did>
          </c>
        </c>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
