<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>FA1068.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper type="filing">Rockefeller University records, Index Cards</titleproper>
        <titleproper>A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Index Cards
 <num>FA1068</num></titleproper>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline>
          <addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline>
          <addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2015-08-26 11:39:15 -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Rockefeller University records, Index Cards</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="aut" source="library of congress authority files">Rockefeller University</corpname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="aut" source="library of congress authority files">Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>FA1068</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Cubic Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1960/1990" type="inclusive">1960's-1990</unitdate>
      <unitdate normal="1970/1990" type="bulk">bulk</unitdate>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_01e13711f220e416073fa9675bb19447">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Index cards are open for scholarly research. Select archival materials described by the index cards may be restricted from scholarly research in accordance with all access conditions and stipulations of the pertinent collections.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_d6d85aa14a2ac465c350652fa9f33389">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>
    </prefercite>
    <otherfindaid id="aspace_58682a56e38ad6bf47a16e9d11ba0905">
      <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
      <p>All Rockefeller University collection titles are preceded by the term Rockefeller University records (unless otherwise noted)</p>
      <p>Former Classification is provided following the current title.</p>
      <p>Corporation</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA211/overview">FA211 Corporation, Charter and Charter Amendments</extref> (Former Classification: I 100)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA853/overview">FA853 Corporation, Board of Directors/Board of Scientific Directors, Dockets</extref> (Former Classification: I 103)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA854/overview">FA853 Corporation, Board of Directors/Board of Scientific Directors, Secretary’s File</extref> (Former Classification: I 103)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA855/overview">FA855 Corporation, Board of Directors/Board of Scientific Directors, Executive Committee</extref> (Former Classification: I 105)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA856/overview">FA856 Corporation, Board of Directors/Board of Scientific Directors, Minutes</extref> (Former Classification: I 110-2)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA857/overview">FA857 Corporation, Minutes</extref> (Former Classification: I 120-2)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA858/overview">FA858 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Minutes</extref> (Former Classification: I 130-2)</p>
      <p>FA982 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Master Books (Former Classification: I 130-2-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA983 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Reports (Former Classification: I 130-5-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA859/overview">FA859 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Secretary</extref> (Former Classification: I 130-6)</p>
      <p>FA998 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Working Files (Former Classification: I 130-6-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA860/overview">FA860 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Committees</extref> (Former Classification: I 130-8)</p>
      <p>FA999 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Committees, Ingests, post-1979 (Former Classification: I 130-8-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA861/overview">FA861 Corporation, Board of Trustees, University Council</extref> (Former Classification: I 130-9)</p>
      <p>FA1001 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Presidential Search Committee (Former Classification: I 131-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1002 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Committee on Scientific Affairs (Former Classification: I 132-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1003 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Nominating Committee (Former Classification: I 133-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA862/overview">FA862 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Budget Committee</extref> (Former Classification: I 134)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA863/overview">FA863 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Budget Committee, Budgets</extref> (Former Classification: I 134-3)</p>
      <p>FA1015 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Committee on Budget and Operations (Former Classification: I 134-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1004 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Hospital Committee (Former Classification: I 135-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA1016/overview">FA1016 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Minutes</extref> (Former Classification: I 138)</p>
      <p>FA1005 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Minutes (Former Classification: I 138-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1006 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Working Files (Former Classification: I 138-6-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA1017/overview">FA1017 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Finance Committee</extref> (Former Classification: I 140)</p>
      <p>FA1007 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Finance Committee (Former Classification 140-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA864/overview">FA864 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Finance Committee, Ledgers and Account Books</extref> (Former Classification: I 140-4)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA865/overview">FA865 Corporation, Treasurer and Assistant Treasurer, Administrative Correspondence</extref> (Former Classification: I 190)</p>
      <p>FA1008 Corporation, Treasurer, Sydney Woodd-Cahusac (Former Classification: I 190-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA866/overview">FA866 Corporation, Treasurer, Ledgers and Account Books</extref> (Former Classification: I 190-4)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA867/overview">FA867 Corporation, Treasurer, Financial Report and Supplement</extref> (Former Classification: I 190-5)</p>
      <p>FA1009 Corporation, Treasurer, Financial Report, Monthly, Microfiche (Former Classification: I 190-6-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA868/overview">FA868 Corporation, Treasurer, Vouchers</extref> (Former Classification: I 190-7)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA869/overview">FA869 Corporation, Auditor</extref> (Former Classification: I 192)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA870/overview">FA870 Corporation, Counsel</extref> (Former Classification: I 195)</p>
      <p>FA1084 Corporation, Counsel, General Counsel (Former Classification: I 195-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1010 Corporation, Counsel, Technology Transfer (Former Classification: I 195-1-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1011 Corporation, Counsel, Addenda (Former Classification: I 195-9-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA871 Corporation, Counsel, Assistant Counsel (Former Classification: I 196-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA872/overview">FA872 Corporation, Biography</extref> (Former Classification: I 199)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA990/overview">FA990 Corporation, Biography, Frederick Talyor Gates</extref> (Former Classification: I 199-31)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA991/overview">FA991 Corporation, Biography, Theophil Mitchell Prudden</extref> (Former Classification: I 199-72)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA992/overview">FA992 Corporation, Biography, Rockefeller Family</extref> (Former Classification: I 199-77)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA993/overview">FA993 Corporation, Biography, Theobald Smith</extref> (Former Classification: I 199-82)</p>
      <p>FA994 Corporation, Board of Trustees, Biography (Former Classification: I 199-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>Business Manager</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA811/overview">FA811 Business Manager, Henry James, Subject Files, Series 1</extref> (Former Classification: I 210-1)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA808/overview">FA808 Business Manager, Correspondence, Series 2</extref> (Former Classification: I 210-2)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA137/overview">FA127 Business Manager, Subject Files, Series 3</extref> (Former Classification: I 210-3)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA808/overview">FA809 Business Manager, Annual Reports (Financial Reports), Series 4</extref> (Former Classification: I 210-4)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA810/overview">FA810 Business Manager, Budget Histories, Series 7</extref> (Former Classification: I 210-7)</p>
      <p>
Assistant Business Manager</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA806/overview">FA806 Assistant Business Manager, Correspondence, Series 2</extref> (Former Classification: I 212-2)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA013/overview">FA013 Assistant Business Manager, Subject Files, Series 3</extref> (Former Classification: I 212-3)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA807/overview">FA807 Assistant Business Manager, Social Service Records, Personnel, Series 5</extref> (Former Classification: I 212-5)</p>
      <p>Bursar</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA213/overview">FA213 Bursar, Administrative Correspondence, Series 2</extref> (Former Classification: I 214-2)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA812/overview">FA812 Bursar, Reports, Series 6</extref> (Former Classification: I 214-6)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA214/overview">FA214 Director of Administrative Services, Roger C. Elliot, Subject Files, Series 3</extref> (Former Classification: I 216-3)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA215/overview">FA215 Controller</extref> (Former Classification: I 240)</p>
      <p>FA1085 Plant Operations (Former Classification: I 275-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA216/overview">FA216 Accounting Servicesr</extref> (Former Classification: I 280)</p>
      <p>Director of Computer Services (Former Classification: I 285) – Finding aid not yet available.</p>
      <p>
Service Departments</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA901/overview">FA901 Service Departments, Safety</extref> (Former Classification: I 291)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA217/overview">FA217 Service Departments, Housing</extref> (Former Classification: I 292)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA820/overview">FA820 Service Departments, Purchasing</extref> (Former Classification: I 293)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA821/overview">FA821 Service Departments, Purchasing, Stock Catalogs</extref> (Former Classification: I 293-1)</p>
      <p>FA1018 Service Departments, Subject Files (Former Classification: I 293-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>
Director or President</p>
      <p>Simon Flexner</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA138/overview">FA138 Director, Simon Flexner, Administrative Correspondence, Series 2</extref> (Former Classification: I 301-2)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA139/overview">FA139 Director, Simon Flexner, Biographical Materials, Reprints, Phonorecords, and Bas Relief, Series 6</extref> (Former Classification: I 301-6)</p>
      <p>
Herbert Spencer Gasser</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA143/overview">FA143 Director, Herbert Spenser Gasser, Correspondence, Series 2</extref> (Former Classification: I 302-2)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA813/overview">FA813 Director, Herbert Spenser Gasser, Subject Files, Series 4</extref> (Former Classification: I 302-4)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA814/overview">FA814 Director, Herbert Spenser Gasser, Biographical Material, Series 6</extref> (Former Classification: I 302-6)</p>
      <p>
Detlev W. Bronk</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA140/overview">FA140 President, Detlev W. Bronk, Administrative papers</extref> (Former Classification: I 303)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA914/overview">FA914 President, Detlev W. Bronk, General Professional correspondence</extref> (Former Classification: I 303-1)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA964/overview">FA964 President, Detlev W. Bronk, Biographical and Personal Material</extref> (Former Classification: I 303-6)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA965/overview">FA965 President, Detlev W. Bronk, Personal and Professional paapers</extref> (Former Classification: I 303-U)</p>
      <p>
Frederick Seitz</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA141/overview">FA141 President, Frederick Seitz, Business, Series 1</extref> (Former Classification: I 304)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA815/overview">FA815 President, Frederick Seitz, Chronological Files, Series 2</extref> (Former Classification: I 304)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA816/overview">FA816 President, Frederick Seitz, Archive Center, Series 3</extref> (Former Classification: I 304)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA817/overview">FA817 President, Frederick Seitz, Campus, Series 4</extref> (Former Classification: I 304)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA818/overview">FA818 President, Frederick Seitz, General Administration, Series 5</extref> (Former Classification: I 304)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA819/overview">FA819 President, Frederick Seitz, Personal, Biographical and Miscellaneous, Series 6</extref> (Former Classification: I 304)</p>
      <p>FA1069 President, Frederick Seitz (Former Classification: I 304-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA1118/overview">FA1118 President, Joshua Lederberg</extref> (Former Classification: I 305)</p>
      <p>FA1088 President, Joshua Lederberg (Former Classification: I 305-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1087 Joshua Lederberg personal papers, Subject File (Former Classification: I 305-1-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA219/overview">FA219 President, David Baltimore</extref> (Former Classification: I 306)</p>
      <p>FA1086 President, David Baltimore, Ingests, 2003 (Former Classification: I 306-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1089 President, Torsten Wiesel (Former Classification: I 307-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1090 President, Arnold Levine (Former Classification: I 308-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1102 President (Acting), Thomas Sakmar (Former Classification: I 309-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA220/overview">FA220 Executive Assistant Mabel Bright</extref> (Former Classification: I 320)</p>
      <p>FA1091 President, General Administration (Former Classification: I 325-1-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1092 President, General Files (Former Classification: I 325-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1093 President, Special Events Coordinator (Former Classification: I 330-4-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1094 Executive Vice President, Director of Special Projects (Former Classification: I 331-U)</p>
      <p>
Vice President</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA221/overview">FA221 Vice President, Thomas Milton Rivers, Administrative Correspondence, Series 2</extref> (Former Classification: I 341-2)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA902/overview">FA902 Vice President, Thomas Milton Rivers, Biographical Material, Series 6</extref> (Former Classification: I 341-6)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA822/overview">FA822 Vice President, Frank Lappin Horsfall, Jr.</extref> (Former Classification: I 342-2 and 342-6)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA903/overview">FA903 Vice President, Frank Lappin Horsfall, Jr., Subject Files, Series 4</extref> (Former Classification: I 342-4)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA823/overview">FA823 Vice President, Douglas Whitaker</extref> (Former Classification: I 343)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA824/overview">FA824 Vice President, Carl Pfaffmann</extref> (Former Classification: I 345)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA825/overview">FA825 Vice President, C. Eugene Sunderlin</extref> (Former Classification: I 346)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA144/overview">FA144 Vice President, Rodney W. Nichols</extref> (Former Classification: I 347)</p>
      <p>FA1070 Vice President, Rodney W. Nichols, Ingests, post-1989 (Former Classification: I 347-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA826/overview">FA826 Vice President, Albert Gold</extref> (Former Classification: I 348)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA827/overview">FA827 Vice President, David J. Lyons</extref> (Former Classification: I 349)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA1019/overview">FA1019 Vice President, David J. Lyons, Faculty records</extref> (Former Classification: I 349-1)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA828/overview">FA828 Vice President, Richard Young</extref> (Former Classification: I 350)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA829/overview">FA829 Vice President, James Shannon</extref> (Former Classification: I 351)</p>
      <p>FA1020 Vice President, General Files (Former Classification: I 359-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA222/overview">FA222 Director of Program Planning and Development</extref> (Former Classification: I 360)</p>
      <p>
FA1095 Development Office (Former Classification: I 360-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA1021/overview">FA1021 Development Office, Publications</extref> (Former Classification: I 360-9)</p>
      <p>
Office of Communications and Public Affairs</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA223/overview">FA223 Office of Communications and Public Affairs, News Releases, Series 1</extref> (Former Classification: I 365-1)</p>
      <p>FA1096 Office of Communications and Public Affairs, Clippings, Series 2 (Former Classification: I 365-2-U) CLOSED to scholarly research. </p>
      <p><extref href="../FA1022/overview">FA1022 Office of Communications and Public Affairs, Public Relations, Subject Files, Series 3</extref> (Former Classification: I 365-3)</p>
      <p>FA1023 Office of Communications and Public Affairs, Subject Files, Series 3 (Former Classification: I 365-3-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1097 Office of Communications and Public Affairs, Audio, Series 4 (Former Classification: I 365-4-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1024 Office of Communications and Public Affairs, Video and Film, Series 5 (Former Classification: I 365-5-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA830/overview">FA830 Office of Communications and Public Affairs, Publications, Series 6</extref> (Former Classification: I 365-6)</p>
      <p>		
FA1025 Office of Communications and Public Affairs, New Media and Design, Series 7 (FC: I 365-7-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>
FA1026 Office of Communications and Public Affairs, Special Events Coordinator, Series 8 (Former Classification: I 365-8-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>		
FA1027 Office of Communications and Public Affairs, Marketing Communications, Series 9 (Former Classification: I 365-9-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>
FA1028 Editor, News and Notes, Robert Brown (Former Classification: I 366-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>Dean of Graduate Studies</p>
      <p>FA1029 Dean of Graduate Studies, Series 1 (Former Classification: I 380-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA224/overview">FA224 Dean of Graduate Studies, Publications, Series 2</extref> (Former Classification: I 380-2)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA831/overview">FA831 Dean of Graduate Studies, Convocation Programs, Series 4</extref> (Former Classification: I 380-4)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA832/overview">FA832 Dean of Graduate Studies, Frank Brink, Jr., Series 6</extref> (Former Classification: I 380-6)</p>
      <p>
FA1030 Vice President, Office of Academic Affairs (Former Classification: I 381-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1031 Office of Graduate Studies, Supplementary Alumni Files (Former Classification: I 385-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1032 Associate Vice President for Administration, Subject Files (Former Classification: I 395-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA225/overview">FA225 Associate Vice President for Administration, Fairfield Osborn Lectures</extref> (Former Classification: I 395-1)</p>
      <p>
History of the University</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA226/overview">FA226 History of the University</extref> (Former Classification: I 400)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA905/overview">FA905 History of the University, Addresses, Announcements and News Articles</extref> (Former Classification: I 401)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA906/overview">FA906 History of the University, John D, Rockefeller Memorial</extref> (Former Classification: I 408)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA907/overview">FA907 History of the University, John D, Rockefeller and Office Correspondence</extref> (Former Classification: I 409)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA908/overview">FA908 History of the University, Rockefeller Foundation</extref> (Former Classification: I 410 and I 411)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA910/overview">FA910 History of the University, Site History</extref> (Former Classification: I 412)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA911/overview">FA911 History of the University, Visitor’s Book</extref> (Former Classification: I 413)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA912/overview">FA912 History of the University, Endowments</extref> (Former Classification: I 415)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA913/overview">FA913 History of the University, Confidential papers</extref> (Former Classification: I 417 and I 417-1)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA915/overview">FA915 Catalogue</extref> (Former Classification: I 419)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA916/overview">FA916 Catalogs, Scientific and Educational Programs</extref> (Former Classification: I 419-1)</p>
      <p>
Laboratory of Electronics</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA227/overview">FA227 Laboratory of Electronics, Technical Report</extref> (Former Classification: I 421-1)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA833/overview">FA833 Laboratory of Electronics, Subject Files</extref> (Former Classification: I 421-4)</p>
      <p>AC.2007.070 Laboratory of Electronics (Former Classification: I 421-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>AC.2010.059 Laboratory of Electronics. CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>
Laboratory Animal Research Center (LARC)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA966/overview">FA966 Laboratory Animal Research Center (LARC), Correspondence</extref> (Former Classification: I 422-2)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA967/overview">FA967 Laboratory Animal Research Center (LARC), Subject Files</extref> (Former Classification: I 422-4)</p>
      <p>FA1033  Laboratory Animal Research Center (LARC), Director, Dennis M. Stark  (Former Classification: I 422-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>
Department of Animal and Plant Pathology, Princeton, NJ</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA834/overview">FA834 Department of Animal and Plant Pathology, Princeton, NJ, Correspondence</extref> (Former Classification: I 425-2)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA835/overview">FA835 Department of Animal and Plant Pathology, Princeton, NJ, Subject Files</extref> (Former Classification: I 425-3)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA968/overview">FA968 Department of Animal and Plant Pathology, Princeton, NJ, Carl TenBroeck papers</extref> (Former Classification: I 425-6)</p>
      <p>FA1099 Carl TenBroeck Papers, Lab Notebooks and Reprints (Former Classification: I 425-6-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA969/overview">FA969 Department of Animal and Plant Pathology, Princeton, NJ, Publications</extref> (Former Classification: I 427)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA836/overview">FA836 Field Research Center, Millbrook, NY</extref> (Former Classification: I 428)</p>
      <p>
Hospital</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA228/overview">FA228 Hospital, General Files, Series 1</extref> (Former Classification: I 430)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA837/overview">FA837 Hospital, Administrative Correspondence, Series 2</extref> (Former Classification: I 430-2)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA838/overview">FA838 Hospital, Subject Files, Series 3</extref> (Former Classification: I 430-3)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA909/overview">FA909 Hospital, Collected Reprints, Series 4</extref> (Former Classification: I 430-4)</p>
      <p>FA1034 Hospital, Administration (Former Classification: I 430-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>
FA145 Scientific Reports (Former Classification: I 439). Finding aid not yet available.</p>
      <p>
Academic Senate</p>
      <p>FA1035 Academic Senate, Master Books, Series 2 (Former Classification: I 440-2-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1036 Academic Senate, Working Files, Series 6 (Former Classification: I 440-6-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>
Academic Council</p>
      <p>FA1037 Academic Council, Master Books, Series 2 (Former Classification: I 445-2-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1038 Academic Council, Subject Files, Series 4 (Former Classification: I 445-4-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1039 Academic Council, Working Files, Series 6 (Former Classification: I 445-6-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA424 Institutional Review Board. CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA229/overview">FA229 Lectures and Research Colloquia</extref> (Former Classification: I 449)</p>
      <p>Faculty papers</p>
      <p>Collection titles reference the academic standing held by each individual (as applicable):</p>
      <p>Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research Scientific Staff</p>
      <p>Rockefeller University Faculty</p>
      <p>or as otherwise noted.</p>
      <p>	
FA995 Agosta, William C. (Former Classification: I 450 Ag75-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1042 Ahrens, Edward H., Jr. (Former Classification: I 450 Ah73-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA996 Allfrey, Vincent (Former Classification: I 450 Al510-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA146/overview">FA146 Archibald, Reginald M.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 Ar25)</p>
      <p>FA1071 Archibald, Reginald M., Ingests, post-1987 (Former Classification: I 450 Ar25-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA147/overview">FA147 Auer, John</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 Au34)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA230/overview">FA230 Avery, Oswald T.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 Av37)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA007/overview">FA007 Bearn, Alexander G.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 B838)</p>
      <p>FA1083 Bearn, Alexander G., Ingests, post 1990 (Former Classification: I 450 B38-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA148 Beg, Mirza A.B. (Former Classification: I 450 B394-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA001/overview">FA001 Bergmann, Max</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 B454)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA008/overview">FA008 Berlin, Theodore H.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 B456)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA009/overview">FA009 Braun, Armin C.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 B739)</p>
      <p>FA801 Braun, Armin C., Ingests, post-1985 (Former Classification: I 450 B739-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1043 Brink, Frank, Jr. (Former Classification: I 450 B771-U). CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA149/overview">FA149 Bronfenbrenner, Jacques J.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 B788) </p>
      <p><extref href="../FA010/overview">FA010 Brown, Wade H.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 B815) </p>
      <p><extref href="../FA231/overview">FA231 Carrel, Alexis</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 C232) </p>
      <p><extref href="../FA150/overview">FA150 Chase Merrill W.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 C386)</p>
      <p> 
FA1072 Chase, Merrill W., Ingests, post-1981 (Former Classification: I 450 C386-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA151/overview">FA151 Choppin, Purnell W.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 C455)</p>
      <p> 
FA1073 Choppin, Purnell W. (Former Classification: I 450 C455-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA152/overview">FA152 Claude, Albert</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 C571)</p>
      <p> 
FA1116 Cohen, E.G.D. (Former Classification: I 450 C66-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA132/overview">FA132 Cohn, Alfred E. </extref> (Former Classification: I 450 C661)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA802/overview">FA802 Cohn, Alfred E.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 C661-U)</p>
      <p>FA1105 Cohn, Zanvil (Former Classification: I 450 C662-U) CLOSED to scholarly research</p>
      <p>FA153 Connelly, Clarence (Former Classification: I 450 C762-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA154/overview">FA154 Cool, Rodney L.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 C766 and C766-U)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA155/overview">FA155 Cowdry, E. Vincent</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 C838)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA134/overview">FA134 Craig, Lyman C.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 C844)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA156/overview">FA134 Cranefield, Paul F.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 C850)</p>
      <p>AC.2004.070 Cranefield, Paul F. (Former Classification: I 450 C850-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA157/overview">FA157 De Kruif, Paul H.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 D369)</p>
      <p>
AC.2013.004 de Duve, Christian. CLOSED to scholarly research.
 </p>
      <p><extref href="../FA158/overview">FA158 Diacumakos, Elaine G.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 D54)</p>
      <p>
FA1074 Diacumakos, Elaine G. (Former Classification: I 450 D54-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA159/overview">FA159 Dobzhansky, Theodosius G..</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 D656)</p>
      <p>FA411 Dole, Vincent P. (Former Classification: I 450 D688-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA730/overview">FA730 Dole, Vincent P., Correspondence, Series 1</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 D688-U)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA122/overview">FA122 Dole Dubos, Rene J.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 D851)</p>
      <p>FA1106 Edelman, Gerald (Former Classification: I 450 E27-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA980/overview">FA980 Evans, Herbert M.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 Ev11)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA160/overview">FA160 Field, Frank H.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 F454)</p>
      <p>FA1107 Friedheim, Ernst (Former Classification: I 450 F913-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA161/overview">FA161 Gates, Frederick Lamont</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 G223)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA981/overview">FA981 Glaser, Rudolph W.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 G462)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA162/overview">FA162 Goebel, Walther F.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 G55)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA979/overview">FA979 Gowen, John W.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 G747)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA232/overview">FA232 Granick, Sam</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 G766)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA163/overview">FA163 Gregory, John</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 G862)</p>
      <p>FA1075 Gregory, John, Ingests, 1991-1993 (Former Classification: I 450 G862-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA164 Griffin, Donald R. (Former Classification: I 450 G875-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1112 Hanafusa, Hidesaburo (Former Classification: AI 450 H190-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA165/overview">FA165 Harter, Donald H.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 H252)</p>
      <p>FA1108 Hartline, H. Keffer (Former Classification: I 450 H255-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>AC.2012.083 Heintz, Nathaniel. CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA166/overview">FA166 Hervey, John P.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 H446)</p>
      <p>FA1109 Hirsch, James (Former Classification: I 450 H616-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>	
FA1110 Hirsch, Jules. CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>
FA1044 Ho, David (Former Classification: I 450 H650-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA167/overview">FA167 Hoagland, Charles L.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 H65)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA129/overview">FA129 Holmes, Francis O.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 H735)</p>
      <p>FA803 Holmes, Francis O., Ingests, post-1988 (Former Classification: I 450 H735) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA168/overview">FA168 Hotchkiss, Rollin D.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 H797)</p>
      <p>FA1076 Hotchkiss, Rollin D., Ingests, post-2004 (Former Classification: I 450 H797-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1045 Hurlbut, William P. (Former Classification: I 450 H939-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA169/overview">FA169 Jacobs, Walter A.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 J156)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA1111/overview">FA1111 Jesaitis, Margeris</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 J347)</p>
      <p>FA1046 Jesaitis, Margeris (Former Classification: I 450 J347-U). CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA170/overview">FA170 Kac, Mark</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 K11)</p>
      <p>AC.2006.064 Kac, Mark (Former Classification: I 450 K11-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1047 Kaiser, Emil T. (Former Classification: I 450 K123-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1048 Kappas, Attallah (Former Classification: I 450 K142-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA1049/overview">FA1049 Koide, Sam</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 K829)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA171/overview">FA171 Kunitz, Moses</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 K962)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA273/overview">FA273 Kunkel, Henry G.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 K964)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA172/overview">FA172 Kunkel, Louis O.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 K963)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA173/overview">FA173 Lancefield, Rebecca C.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 L221)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA126/overview">FA126 Landsteiner, Karl</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 L239)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA174/overview">FA174 Levene, Phoebus A.T.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 L657)</p>
      <p>FA1050 Levine, Philip (Former Classification: I 450 L579-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA175/overview">FA175 Lewis, Paul A.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 L588)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA123/overview">FA123 Lipmann, Fritz Albert</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 L667)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA176/overview">FA176 Loeb, Jacques</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 L823)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA177/overview">FA177 Longsworth, Lewis G.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 L866)</p>
      <p>FA1051 Luck, David (Former Classification: I 450 L963-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1052 McCarty, Maclyn (Former Classification: I 450 M127-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA178/overview">FA178 MacInnes, Duncan A.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 M189)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA1053/overview">FA1053 MacLeod, Colin M.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 M225)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA179/overview">FA179 McMaster, Philip D.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 M227)</p>
      <p>FA1054 Mauro, Alexander (Former Classification: I 450 M447-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1055 Mauzerall, David (Former Classification: I 450 M449-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA180/overview">FA180 Meltzer, Samuel J.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 M496)</p>
      <p>FA415 Merrifield, R. Bruce (Former Classification: I 450 M552-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA181/overview">FA181 Michaelis, Leonor</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 M582)</p>
      <p>FA986 Michaelis, Leonor, Ingests, post-1989 (Former Classification: I 450 M582-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA1056/overview">FA1056 Miller, Neal</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 M616)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA131/overview">FA131 Mirsky, Alfred E.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 M679)</p>
      <p>AC.2012.10 Mojsov, Svetlana. CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1057 Model, Peter (Former Classification: I 450 M720-U). CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA111/overview">FA111 Moore, Stanford</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 M786 and M786-U)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA182/overview">FA182 Murphy, James B.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 M955-U)</p>
      <p>FA1058 Murphy, James S. (Former Classification: I 450 M955-U) CLOSED to scholarly research,</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA183/overview">FA183 Nelson, John B.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 N334)</p>
      <p>FA987 Nelson, John B., Ingests, post-1974 (Former Classification: I 450 N334-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA988 Nelson, Warren O. (Former Classification: I 450 N338-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA121/overview">FA121 Noguchi, Hideyo </extref> (Former Classification: I 450 N689)</p>
      <p>FA1066 Northrup, John H. (Former Classification: I 450 N818-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>AC.2012.046 Nussenzweig, Michel. CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA184/overview">FA184 Olitsky, Peter K.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 O14)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA185/overview">FA185 Opie, Eugene L.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 Op3)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA186/overview">FA186 Osterhout, Winthrop J.V.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 Os7)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA014/overview">FA014 Pais, Abraham</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 P166)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA187/overview">FA187 Palade, George E.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 P171)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA188/overview">FA188 Pearce, Louise</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 P315)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA189/overview">FA189 Perlmann, Gertude E.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 P422)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA190/overview">FA190 Pfaffman, Carl</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 P471)</p>
      <p>FA1079 Pfaffman, Carl, Ingests, post-1984 (Former Classification: I 450 P471-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1059 Poole, Brian H. (Former Classification: I 450 P785-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA128/overview">FA128 Rademacher, Hans</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 R117)</p>
      <p>AC.2008.062 Rademacher, Hans (Former Classification: I 450 R117) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA191/overview">FA191 Riordan, John F.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 R479)</p>
      <p>FA1060 Rizack, Martin (Former Classification: I 450 R529-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA192/overview">FA192 Robertson, Oswald H.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 R548)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA193/overview">FA193 Rothen, Alexandre</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 R743)</p>
      <p>FA989 Rothen, Alexandre, Ingests, 1983, 1988 (Former Classification: I 450 R743-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA194/overview">FA194 Rous, F. Peyton</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 R762)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA195/overview">FA195 Rudzinska, Maria</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 R836)</p>
      <p>FA1080 Rudzinska, Maria, Ingests, post-1991 (Former Classification: I 450 R836-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA196/overview">FA196 Sabin, Albert B.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 Sa131)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA197/overview">FA197 Sabin, Florence</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 Sa13)</p>
      <p>FA1061 Sassa, Shigeru (Former Classification: I 450 Sa790-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA977 Sato, Yoshio (Former Classification: I 450 Sa83-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1067 Schreiber, Morris (Former Classification: I 450 Sch72-U) CLOSED to scholarly research,</p>
      <p>FA1117 Seitz, Frederick (Former Classification: I 450 Se450-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA198/overview">FA198 Senior, James K.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 Se570)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA130/overview">FA130 Shedlovsky, Theodore</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 Sh34)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA199/overview">FA199 Shope, Richard E.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 Sh77)</p>
      <p>FA1062 Siekevitz, Phillip (Former Classification: I 450 Si150-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA200/overview">FA200 Stanley, Wendell M.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 St25)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA127/overview">FA127 Stein, William H.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 St34)</p>
      <p>FA1113 Steinman, Ralph (Former Classification: I A450 St36-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA233/overview">FA233 Stoll Norman R.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 St68)</p>
      <p>FA1100 Stoll, Norman R., Ingests, 1977 (Former Classification: I 450 St68-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA201/overview">FA201 Swift, Homer F.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 Sw54)</p>
      <p>FA1063 Tamm, Igor (Former Classification: I 450 T15-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA133/overview">FA133 Tatum, Edward Lawrie </extref> (Former Classification: I 450 T189)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA202/overview">FA202 Trager, William</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 T677)</p>
      <p>FA1081 Trager, William, Ingests, post-2000 (Former Classification: 450 T677-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA125/overview">FA125 Uhlenbeck, George E.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 U600)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA203/overview">FA203 Van Slyke, Donald D.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 V364)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA274/overview">FA274 Wang, Hao</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 W184-U)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA204/overview">FA204 Webster, Leslie T.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 W395)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA124/overview">FA124 Weiss, Paul A.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 W436)</p>
      <p>FA1064 Wilson, Victor J. (Former Classification: I 450 W698-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1065 Wood, Henry N. (Former Classification: I 450 W850-U) CLOSED to scholarly research,</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA205/overview">FA205 Woolley, Dilworth W</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 W885)</p>
      <p>FA1082 Woolley, Dilworth W., Ingests 2006-2011 (Former Classification: I 450 W885-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA1000/overview">FA1000 Wykoff, Ralph W.G.</extref> (Former Classification: I 450 W972)</p>
      <p>FA997 Zinder, Norton (Former Classification: I 450 Z670-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA1000/overview">FA259 Campus Office Biographical Files</extref> (Former Classification: I A451)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA260/overview">FA260 Scientific Staff Biographical Files</extref> (Former Classification: I 450.1)</p>
      <p>FA206 Carol Moberg, Rockefeller University Research Associate (Former Classification: I 450.3 M712-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA207/overview">FA207 Catalogs and Directories</extref> (Former Classification: I 455)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA234/overview">FA234 Telephone Directory</extref> (Former Classification: I 457)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA839/overview">FA839 Directory</extref> (Former Classification: I 458)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA840/overview">FA840 Photographic Directory</extref> (Former Classification: I 459)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA235/overview">FA235 Student records, Nicholas A. Acheson</extref> (Former Classification: I 460 Ac45)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA841/overview">FA841 Directory of Graduates</extref> (Former Classification: I 462)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA842/overview">FA842 Student Life and Activities</extref> (Former Classification: I 465)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA843/overview">FA843 Courses for Students</extref> (Former Classification: I 470)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA904/overview">FA904 Reports of Students</extref> (Former Classification: I 470-1)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA1040/overview">FA1040 Dissertations of Students</extref> (Former Classification: I 475-U)</p>
      <p>
Rockefeller University Press</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA236/overview">FA236 Rockefeller University Press, Correspondence</extref> (Former Classification: I 500)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA917/overview">FA917 Rockefeller University Press, Subject Files</extref> (Former Classification: I 501 and I 501-U)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA918/overview">FA918 Rockefeller University Press, Editor, Helene Jordan, Correspondence</extref> (Former Classification: I 505)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA919/overview">FA919 Rockefeller University Press, Publication Division, Early History</extref> (Former Classification: I 515)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA920/overview">FA920 Rockefeller University Press, Journals Department, Manager, Margaret Broadbent</extref> (Former Classification: I 515-1)</p>
      <p>FA921 Rockefeller University Press, Journals, Microfilm (Former Classification: I 515-5) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA922/overview">FA922 Rockefeller University Press, Journals Department, Studies</extref> (Former Classification: I 516)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA923/overview">FA923 Rockefeller University Press, Journals, Correspondence and Financial Reports</extref> (Former Classification: I 517)</p>
      <p>FA924 Journal of General Physiology, Microfiche, Series 1 (FC: I 517-1) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA925/overview">FA925 Rockefeller University Press, Journal of General Physiology, Editorial Correspondence, Series 2</extref> (Former Classification: I 517-1)</p>
      <p>
FA1101 Rockefeller University Press, Journal of General Physiology (Former Classification: I 517-1-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA971/overview">FA971 Rockefeller University Press, Journal of Experimental Medicine, Microfiche</extref> (Former Classification: I 517-2)</p>
      <p>FA972 Rockefeller University Press, Journal of Experimental Medicine (Former Classification: I 517-2-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA926/overview">FA926 Rockefeller University Press, Journal of Clinical Investigation, Microfiche</extref> (Former Classification: I 517-3)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA927/overview">FA927 Rockefeller University Press, Biophysical Journal, Microfiche</extref> (Former Classification: I 517-4)</p>
      <p>FA928 Rockefeller University Press, Journal of Cell Biology (Former Classification: I 518) Finding Aid not yet available.</p>
      <p>
FA1041 Rockefeller University Press, Journal of Cell Biology, Correspondence (Former Classification: I 518-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA929/overview">FA929 Rockefeller University Press, Journal of Cell Biology, Microfiche, Series 1</extref> (Former Classification: I 518-1)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA930/overview">FA930 Rockefeller University Press, Journal of Cell Biology, Editors Meetings, Minutes, Series 2</extref> (Former Classification: I 518-2)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA931/overview">FA931 Rockefeller University Press, Graphic Services, Early History</extref> (Former Classification: I 520)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA932/overview">FA932 Rockefeller University Press, Graphic Services, Cuts</extref> (Former Classification: I 522)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA933/overview">FA933 Rockefeller University Press, Graphic Services, Christmas Lecture Drawings for Posters</extref> (Former Classification: I 523)</p>
      <p>FA934 Rockefeller University Press, Graphic Services, Photographs (Former Classification: I 524 - I 529). Finding Aid not yet available.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA935/overview">FA935 Rockefeller University Press, Books and Reports Department, Subject Files</extref> (Former Classification: I 530-3)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA936/overview">FA936 Rockefeller University Press, Books and Reports Department, Special Items</extref> (Former Classification: I 531)</p>
      <p>FA970 Rockefeller University Press, Books and Reports Department, Graphic Design (Former Classification: I 531-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA937/overview">FA937 Rockefeller University Press, Books and Reports Department, Special Projects</extref> (Former Classification: I 532)
<extref href="../FA938/overview">FA938 Rockefeller University Press, Books and Reports Department, Serials</extref> (Former Classification: I 533)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA939/overview">FA939 Rockefeller University Press, Quarterly; Review </extref> (Former Classification: I 534)</p>
      <p>FA940 Rockefeller University Press, Quarterly; Review, Ingests, post-1978 (Former Classification: I 534-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA941/overview">FA941 Rockefeller University Press, Semi-annual List; Lists of Publications</extref> (Former Classification: I 535)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA942/overview">FA942 Rockefeller University Press, News and Notes</extref> (Former Classification: I 536)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA943/overview">FA943 Rockefeller University Press, Calendar of Events, Series 1</extref> (Former Classification: I 537)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA944/overview">FA944 Rockefeller University Press, Calendar of Events, Series 2</extref> (Former Classification: I 537-2)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA945/overview">FA945 Rockefeller University Press, Program Committee</extref> (Former Classification: I 537)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA946/overview">FA946 Rockefeller University Press, Faculty and Student Handbooks</extref> (Former Classification: I 538)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA947/overview">FA947 Rockefeller University Press, Research Profiles</extref> (Former Classification: I 539)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA948/overview">FA947 Rockefeller University Press, Search Magazine</extref> (Former Classification: I 540)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA949/overview">FA949 Rockefeller University Press, Occasional Papers</extref> (Former Classification: I 541)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA950/overview">FA950 Rockefeller University Press, Journal of Experimental Medicine Supplements</extref> (Former Classification: I 543)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA951/overview">FA951 Rockefeller University Press, Monographs</extref> (Former Classification: I 544)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA952/overview">FA952 Rockefeller University Press, Books</extref> (Former Classification: I 549)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA953/overview">FA953 Rockefeller University Press, Audiovisual Material, Lectures and Assorted Events</extref> (Former Classification: I 550)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA954/overview">FA954 Rockefeller University Press, Audiovisual Material</extref> (Former Classification: I 551)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA955/overview">FA955 Rockefeller University Press, Institute for Comparative Human Development (ICHD)</extref> (Former Classification: I 560)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA956/overview">FA956 Rockefeller University Press, Safety Committee, Safety Manual</extref> (Former Classification: I 563)</p>
      <p>FA957 Rockefeller University Press, Visit to China (Former Classification: I 564). Finding aid not yet available.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA958/overview">FA958 Rockefeller University Press, Ingests, 1982</extref> (Former Classification: I 580)</p>
      <p>FA973 Rockefeller University Press, Ingests, post-1982 (Former Classification: I 580-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>
Special Events and Activities</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA142/overview">FA142 Special Events and Activities, Anti-vivisection Activities</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-1)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA012/overview">FA012 Special Events and Activities, War Demonstration Hospital</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-2)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA874/overview">FA874 Special Events and Activities, Naval Research Unit at RIH</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-3)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA875/overview">FA875 Special Events and Activities, Summer Program for High School Students</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-4)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA876/overview">FA876 Special Events and Activities, Alfred E. Mirsky Christmas Lectures, Tapes</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-5)</p>
      <p>FA873 Special Events and Activities, Alfred E. Mirsky Christmas Lectures, Budget Account Statements (Former Classification: I 600-5-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA877/overview">FA877 Special Events and Activities, Medical Electronics Center</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-6)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA878/overview">FA878 Special Events and Activities, Center for the Prevention of Premature Arterioscleroses (CPPA)</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-7)</p>
      <p>
FA985 Special Events and Activities, Center for the Prevention of Premature Arterioscleroses (CPPA), Microfilm  (Former Classification: I 600-7-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA879/overview">FA879 Special Events and Activities, Rockefeller University Concerts</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-8)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA880/overview">FA880 Special Events and Activities, 75th Anniversary Planning Committee</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-9)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA881/overview">FA881 Special Events and Activities, Visit to China</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-10)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA882/overview">FA882 Special Events and Activities, Botany Exhibit</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-11)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA883/overview">FA883 Special Events and Activities, Alfred E. Mirsky collection, Exhibits</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-12)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA884/overview">FA884 Special Events and Activities, Exhibits and Exhibitions</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-13)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA885/overview">FA885 Special Events and Activities, Fairfield Osborn Memorial Lectures</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-14)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA886/overview">FA886 Special Events and Activities, RUnion, 25th Anniversary Reunion</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-15)</p>
      <p>FA984 Special Events and Activities, RUnion, Questionnaires (Former Classification: I 600-15-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA887/overview">FA887 Special Events and Activities, Symposium on the 35th Anniversary of Avery et al papers</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-16)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA888/overview">FA888 Special Events and Activities, Beckman Symposium</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-18)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA889/overview">FA889 Special Events and Activities, James G. Hirsch Memorial</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-19)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA890/overview">FA890 Special Events and Activities, Philip Levine Memorial</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-20)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA891/overview">FA891 Special Events and Activities, Swedish Industrial Delegation to the United States</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-21)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA892/overview">FA892 Special Events and Activities, Rockefollies</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-23)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA893/overview">FA893 Special Events and Activities, “Fifty Years of DNA”</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-24)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA894/overview">FA894 Special Events and Activities, Rockefeller University Centennial</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-25)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA895/overview">FA895 Special Events and Activities, Alumni Centennial Symposium and Reunion</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-26)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA896/overview">FA896 Special Events and Activities, Lewis Thomas Prize</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-27)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA897/overview">FA897 Special Events and Activities, Peggy Rockefeller Concert Series</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-28)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA898/overview">FA898 Special Events and Activities, Lecture Series</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-29)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA899/overview">FA899 Special Events and Activities, The Henry Kunkel Society Meetings</extref> (Former Classification: I 600-30)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA237/overview">FA237 Rockefeller University, The Faculty and Students Club, Inc. collection</extref> (Former Classification: I 650-1)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA238/overview">FA238 Rockefeller University, Union Church (Pocantico Hills, NY), Collection of Images of Marc Chagall Windows</extref> (Former Classification: I 650-2)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA239/overview">FA239 Rockefeller University, Sigma Xi records</extref> (Former Classification: I 650-3)</p>
      <p>FA1104 Rockefeller University, Rene Dubos Center collection (Former Classification: I 650-4-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA208/overview">FA208 Theodore Malinin collection of Alexis Carrel and Charles Lindbergh papers</extref> (Former Classification: I 650-5)</p>
      <p>AC.2003.090 Theodore Malinin collection of Alexis Carrel and Charles Lindbergh papers (Former Classification: I 650-5-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA135/overview">FA135 Paul Ehrlich papers</extref> (Former Classification: I 650 Eh89)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA072/overview">FA072 Paul Ehrlich papers, Pinkus Family collection</extref> (Former Classification: I 650-2 Eh89)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA136/overview">FA136 Paul Ehrlich and Martha Marquardt papers (Wellcome collection)</extref> (Former Classification: I 650-3 Eh89)</p>
      <p>FA804 Paul Ehrlich papers, Elizabeth Brody collection (Former Classification: I A650-5 Eh89-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA805 Paul Ehrlich papers, Beate I. Hirsch research files (Former Classification: I 650-4 Eh89-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>
FA978 Efim London papers (Former Classification: I 650 L846-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>FA1114 Rockefeller University records, Archives (Former Classification: I A720) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA1115/overview">FA1115 Rockefeller University records, Archives, Gladys Lewis Files</extref> (Former Classification: I A721)</p>
      <p>Auxiliary Services
	
FA1012 Auxiliary Services, Seven Springs Center (Former Classification: I 800-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA240/overview">FA240 Auxiliary Services, Instruments</extref> (Former Classification: I 851)</p>
      <p>FA1013 Auxiliary Services, Scientific Instrument Collection (Former Classification: I 852-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA844/overview">FA844 Auxiliary Services, Rockefeller University and Cornell Medical College Biomedical Seminars</extref> (Former Classification: I 870)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA845/overview">FA845 Auxiliary Services, Tri-Institutional Recitals</extref> (Former Classification: I 871)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA846/overview">FA846 Auxiliary Services, Harvey Society Lectures</extref> (Former Classification: I 872)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA847/overview">FA847 Auxiliary Services, The New York University and Rockefeller University Joint Committee on the Humanities</extref> (Former Classification: I 874)</p>
      <p>FA1014 Auxiliary Services, Program for the Human Environment (Former Classification: I 875-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA848/overview">FA848 Auxiliary Services, Women and Science</extref> (Former Classification: I 876)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA849/overview">FA849 Auxiliary Services, Site Development</extref> (Former Classification: I 880)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA850/overview">FA850 Auxiliary Services, Reproductions Supplied by Other Institutions or Individuals</extref> (Former Classification: I 890)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA851/overview">FA851 Auxiliary Services, Published Works Using Materials from the RU Archives</extref> (Former Classification: I 895)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA852/overview">FA852 Auxiliary Services, Other Secondary Sources Relevant to RIMR/RU History</extref> (Former Classification: I 897)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA241/overview">FA241 Rockefeller University collection of The Medical Letter publication</extref> (Former Classification: I 891)</p>
      <p>FA1103 Rockefeller University collection of The Medical Letter publication (Former Classification: I 891-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA974/overview">FA974 Society for Neuroscience</extref> (Former Classification: I 950-1)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA975/overview">FA975 The Neurosciences Institute</extref> (Former Classification: I 970)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA976/overview">FA976 Ephemera</extref> (Former Classification: I 995)</p>
      <p><extref href="../FA437/overview">FA437 Memorabilia</extref> (Former Classification: I 1000)</p>
      <p>Photographs
Photographs at the RAC (Former Classification: I 1100). Finding Aid not yet available.</p>
      <p>FA1078 Rockefeller University records, Photographs (Former Classification: I 1100-U) CLOSED to scholarly research.</p>
      <p>Slides at the RAC (Former Classification: I 1150). Finding Aid not yet available.</p>
      <p>Photographs at RU (Former Classification: I 1200). Finding Aid not yet available.</p>
      <p>Slides at RU (Former Classification: I 1250). Finding Aid not yet available.</p>
    </otherfindaid>
    <arrangement id="aspace_49a8e88f4ec35a9430e0900183ec6a38">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>Index cards are arranged alphabetically by personal or institutional name or subject.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <originalsloc id="aspace_14a5d1c822e2b872a4ebe649ed166d90">
      <head>Existence and Location of Originals</head>
      <p>The original index cards are physically available on-site at RAC.</p>
    </originalsloc>
    <processinfo id="aspace_5d0d027102cba42f1efcf73e665a104d">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>All index cards are presented in this finding aid as PDF digital objects. See each file level entry for applicable content.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_a3de4c0c061300eb2675368278b29efc">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>Use of the card index to the Rockefeller University collections ---</p>
      <p>There are three elements that compose each card.</p>
      <p>At the top of each card appears as personal or institutional name or subject.</p>
      <p>Below the name or subject appears a description of the material indexed. A given entry may describe a collection, a file, or one or more items.</p>
      <p>At the left side of the card appear filing information. For example, 190 (1) signifies the formerly classified record group 190, Box 1. (1) 14 signifies Box 1, Folder 14.</p>
      <p>The cards bear Record Group numbers, such as 450 H735. The use of these numbers and their associated classification system have been discontinued by RAC.</p>
      <p>Please see the "Other Finding Aids" note placed in the Access and Use Information at the top level of this finding aid. Within this "Other Finding Aids" note you will find a listing of all Rockefeller University holdings along with the current Finding Aid Number (FA#), correlated former classification number, and hyperlinks which facilitate access to all ther finding aids that are currently open for research. The former classification number is also provided in the "File Plan" note of each individual finding aid.</p>
      <p>The Finding Aid number (FA#), and associated finding aid hyperlinks, can be used to locate material through the RAC DIMES website and request records and papers.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <bioghist id="aspace_bca931508043a332e394d622ecbbe14d">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>The Rockefeller University, established in 1901 by John D. Rockefeller as The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, was the first institution in the United States devoted solely to biomedical research. The earliest work was carried on through grants-in-aid to researchers in various American, and a few European, laboratories, but that program was phased out after the Institute's own laboratories were opened on its New York City campus in 1906. In 1954, the Institute became part of the University of the State of New York and acquired the right to confer graduate degrees, awarding its first Ph.D. in 1959. The Institute became The Rockefeller University in 1965.</p>
      <p>The University archives delineate the growth of research programs which from the beginning were aimed at developing fundamental knowledge of disease and physiology. Research is carried out in interdisciplinary laboratories headed by leading scientists, who were known for more than fifty years as Members of the Institute and subsequently as Professors. A hospital was opened in 1910 and has remained an integral part of the research program. </p>
      <p>Many Rockefeller University scientists have been recognized for excellence in their respective fields. As of 2014, 24 Rockefeller University associated scientists have received Nobel Prizes, fourteen scientists have been awarded the National Medal of Science, and 21 have received the Albert Lasker Medical Research Award.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <custodhist id="aspace_85b104a0ecb173893fe8078bbcd93f57">
      <head>Custodial History</head>
      <p>The RU index cards were created as a reference tool in the 1960s by the Rockefeller University library staff initially in charge of the RU Archives.  The cards included name, subject, and archival collection headings.  Two identical sets of catalog cards were maintained, one at the Archives Office, on campus and the other at the Rockefeller Archive Center, to which most of the RU Archives’ records were transferred, starting in the mid-1970s.  The RU index card catalog was maintained until 1990, at which time all collection description was created in standard archival finding aids.  Despite the end date for this catalog system, the item-level description of the materials in the RU Archives makes it an important reference resource for scholars.</p>
    </custodhist>
    <controlaccess>
      <corpname role="aut" source="library of congress authority files">Rockefeller University</corpname>
      <corpname role="aut" source="library of congress authority files">Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref1_voe" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>A</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref27_xds" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Abderhalden, Emil - Amano, T.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_aa-am.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Abderhalden, Emil - Amano, T.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Abderhalden, Emil - Amano, T.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref29_3xj" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>American Academy of Arts and Sciences - Ansdell, Carrol W.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_am-an.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="American Academy of Arts and Sciences - Ansdell, Carrol W.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>American Academy of Arts and Sciences - Ansdell, Carrol W.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref31_voc" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Antibiotics - Awards</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_an-aw.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Antibiotics - Awards">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Antibiotics - Awards</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref33_i7x" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Awards</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_awards.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Awards">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Awards</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref2_fy1" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>B</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref35_9df" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Babkin, Boris - Berkeley, G.H.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_ba-be.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Babkin, Boris - Berkeley, G.H.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Babkin, Boris - Berkeley, G.H.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref37_x0n" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Berlin, Theodore H. - Blumer, George</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_be-bl.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Berlin, Theodore H. - Blumer, George">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Berlin, Theodore H. - Blumer, George</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref39_ogt" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Board of Scientific Directors - Bohr, Niels</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_bo.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Board of Scientific Directors - Bohr, Niels">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Board of Scientific Directors - Bohr, Niels</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref41_6ch" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bohr, Niels - Bronowski, J.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_bo-br.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Bohr, Niels - Bronowski, J.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Bohr, Niels - Bronowski, J.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref43_pwn" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Brookhaven National Laboratory - Butterick, Wallace</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_br-bz.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Brookhaven National Laboratory - Butterick, Wallace">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Brookhaven National Laboratory - Butterick, Wallace</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref45_534" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bytniewska, Irene Alexandra - Casapersson, T.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_by-ca.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Bytniewska, Irene Alexandra - Casapersson, T.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Bytniewska, Irene Alexandra - Casapersson, T.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref3_4wv" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>C</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref48_qxl" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Catalogue - Christmas Lectures</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_ca-ch.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Catalogue - Christmas Lectures">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Catalogue - Christmas Lectures</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref50_5mx" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Chua, Nam-Hai - Collier, H. Bruce</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_ch-co.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Chua, Nam-Hai - Collier, H. Bruce">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Chua, Nam-Hai - Collier, H. Bruce</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref52_qv4" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Comcowich, William J. - Couper, William</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_co.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Comcowich, William J. - Couper, William">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Comcowich, William J. - Couper, William</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref54_uqs" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Courant, Richard - Cushing, Harvey</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_co-cz.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Courant, Richard - Cushing, Harvey">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Courant, Richard - Cushing, Harvey</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref57_9y0" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>D</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref4_8ev" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>DNA - Djerassi, Carl</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_d-dj.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="DNA - Djerassi, Carl">
              <daodesc>
                <p>DNA - Djerassi, Carl</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref58_9tk" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Djerassi, Carl - Dworkin, Ronald</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_dj-dw.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Djerassi, Carl - Dworkin, Ronald">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Djerassi, Carl - Dworkin, Ronald</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref5_k1s" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>E</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref61_j43" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Dziewiatkowski, D. - Endocrinology</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_dz-en.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Dziewiatkowski, D. - Endocrinology">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Dziewiatkowski, D. - Endocrinology</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref63_wva" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Endowments</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_en.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Endowments">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Endowments</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref65_8ho" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Entringer, R.C. - Fabisch, Walter</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_en-fa.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Entringer, R.C. - Fabisch, Walter">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Entringer, R.C. - Fabisch, Walter</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref6_uy5" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>F</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref67_56e" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Faculty and Student Club, Inc. - Flanders, Harley</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_fa-fl.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Faculty and Student Club, Inc. - Flanders, Harley">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Faculty and Student Club, Inc. - Flanders, Harley</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref69_s56" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Flexner, Abraham - Flexner, Simon</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_fl.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Flexner, Abraham - Flexner, Simon">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Flexner, Abraham - Flexner, Simon</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref71_rio" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Flinn, Waldo - Gabrio, Beverly W.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_fl-ga.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Flinn, Waldo - Gabrio, Beverly W.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Flinn, Waldo - Gabrio, Beverly W.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref7_vlc" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>G</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref73_9rr" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Gaffron, Hans - Gasser, Herbert S.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_ga.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Gaffron, Hans - Gasser, Herbert S.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Gaffron, Hans - Gasser, Herbert S.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref75_i1t" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Gasser, Herbert S. - Grant, Theodore J.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_ga-gr.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Gasser, Herbert S. - Grant, Theodore J.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Gasser, Herbert S. - Grant, Theodore J.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref77_twb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Grant records - Guy, Richard K.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_gr-gz.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Grant records - Guy, Richard K.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Grant records - Guy, Richard K.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref8_r7k" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>H</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref79_qen" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Hadassah Medical Organization - Haurowitz, Felix</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_ha.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Hadassah Medical Organization - Haurowitz, Felix">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Hadassah Medical Organization - Haurowitz, Felix</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref81_glb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Health Coverage - Historic Preservation</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_he-hi.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Health Coverage - Historic Preservation">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Health Coverage - Historic Preservation</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref83_6v9" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>History</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_hi.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="History">
              <daodesc>
                <p>History</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref86_si3" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Hoehling, A.A. - Horsfall, Frank L. Jr.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_ho.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Hoehling, A.A. - Horsfall, Frank L. Jr.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Hoehling, A.A. - Horsfall, Frank L. Jr.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref88_ytz" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Horsfall, Frank Lappin - Hotchkiss, Rollin D.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_ho-hot.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Horsfall, Frank Lappin - Hotchkiss, Rollin D.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Horsfall, Frank Lappin - Hotchkiss, Rollin D.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref90_vb0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Hotchkiss, Rollin D. - Illustration Division</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_hot-i.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Hotchkiss, Rollin D. - Illustration Division">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Hotchkiss, Rollin D. - Illustration Division</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref9_8g0" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>I</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref92_xpe" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Immigration - Izard, Camille</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_i.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Immigration - Izard, Camille">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Immigration - Izard, Camille</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref10_g0g" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>J</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref94_44w" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Jacobi, Abraham - Jane Coffin Childs Memorial Fund</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_ja.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Jacobi, Abraham - Jane Coffin Childs Memorial Fund">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Jacobi, Abraham - Jane Coffin Childs Memorial Fund</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref96_lc8" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Janeway, Theodore Caldwell - Jusserand</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_ja-ju.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Janeway, Theodore Caldwell - Jusserand">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Janeway, Theodore Caldwell - Jusserand</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref11_k7u" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>K</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref98_bm8" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Jusserand - Kohler, Erich</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_ju-ko.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Jusserand - Kohler, Erich">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Jusserand - Kohler, Erich</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref100_4xp" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Knuth, Donald E. - Labor</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_kn-la.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Knuth, Donald E. - Labor">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Knuth, Donald E. - Labor</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref12_4mh" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>L</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref102_1fz" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Laboratory Animal Research Center (LARC) - League of Nations</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_la-le.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Laboratory Animal Research Center (LARC) - League of Nations">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Laboratory Animal Research Center (LARC) - League of Nations</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref104_9xd" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Leake, James P. - Library</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_le-li.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Leake, James P. - Library">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Leake, James P. - Library</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref106_og3" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Lighting Design - Lyons, David J.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_li-ly.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Lighting Design - Lyons, David J.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Lighting Design - Lyons, David J.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref13_kvi" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>M</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref108_gd9" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>McCallen, S.E.A. - Martin, Mark W.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_mc-ma.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="McCallen, S.E.A. - Martin, Mark W.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>McCallen, S.E.A. - Martin, Mark W.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref110_bso" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Mattson, Harold - Microbiology</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_ma-mi.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Mattson, Harold - Microbiology">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Mattson, Harold - Microbiology</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref112_yp5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Middlebrook, Gardner - Motion Pictures</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_mi-mo.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Middlebrook, Gardner - Motion Pictures">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Middlebrook, Gardner - Motion Pictures</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref114_a94" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Muller, Mikles - Myers, Louis Guerineau</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_mu-my.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Muller, Mikles - Myers, Louis Guerineau">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Muller, Mikles - Myers, Louis Guerineau</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref14_hoa" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>N</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref116_i1a" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Myers, Louis Guerineau - Nichols, Rodney W.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_my-ni.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Myers, Louis Guerineau - Nichols, Rodney W.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Myers, Louis Guerineau - Nichols, Rodney W.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref118_7o1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Nickerson, Albert - Oberholzer, Rudi</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_ni-ob.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Nickerson, Albert - Oberholzer, Rudi">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Nickerson, Albert - Oberholzer, Rudi</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref15_i3o" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>O</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref121_3go" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Obsolescence Fund - Oxygen Chamber</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_o.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Obsolescence Fund - Oxygen Chamber">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Obsolescence Fund - Oxygen Chamber</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref16_v77" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>P</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref123_pjh" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Packard, Charles - Penndorf, Paul</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_pa-pe.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Packard, Charles - Penndorf, Paul">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Packard, Charles - Penndorf, Paul</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref125_uwq" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Pensions - Plesset, Isabel R.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_pe-pl.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Pensions - Plesset, Isabel R.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Pensions - Plesset, Isabel R.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref127_1sp" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Pneumonia, Pursuit of Excellence</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_pn-pu.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Pneumonia, Pursuit of Excellence">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Pneumonia, Pursuit of Excellence</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref17_ndh" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Q, R</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref129_q3y" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Quatain - Responsibility in Science</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_q-re.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Quatain - Responsibility in Science">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Quatain - Responsibility in Science</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref131_3vr" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Retirement - Roca, Emilio G.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_re-ro.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Retirement - Roca, Emilio G.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Retirement - Roca, Emilio G.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref133_9eb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich - Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_ro1.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich - Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich - Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref135_1pw" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research - RI Scientific Staff</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_ro2.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research - RI Scientific Staff">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research - RI Scientific Staff</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref137_al5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Rockefeller, John Davison - Rockefeller, John Davison, Jr.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_ro3.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Rockefeller, John Davison - Rockefeller, John Davison, Jr.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Rockefeller, John Davison - Rockefeller, John Davison, Jr.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref139_tjr" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Rockefeller, Peggy - Rockefeller University Press</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_ro4.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Rockefeller, Peggy - Rockefeller University Press">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Rockefeller, Peggy - Rockefeller University Press</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref141_zae" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Rockefeller University Press - Ruzicka, Rudolph</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_ro-ru.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Rockefeller University Press - Ruzicka, Rudolph">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Rockefeller University Press - Ruzicka, Rudolph</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref19_mgx" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>S</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref143_ujh" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Sabin, Albert - Schultz, E.S.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_sa-sc.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Sabin, Albert - Schultz, E.S.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Sabin, Albert - Schultz, E.S.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref146_5dw" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Schutzenberger, M.P. - Serum</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_sc-se.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Schutzenberger, M.P. - Serum">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Schutzenberger, M.P. - Serum</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref148_jlg" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Serum - Singleton, W.R.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_se-si.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Serum - Singleton, W.R.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Serum - Singleton, W.R.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref150_g3g" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Site Development - Smith, Edrick B.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_si-sm.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Site Development - Smith, Edrick B.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Site Development - Smith, Edrick B.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref152_2dk" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Smith, Emil L. - Stafford, Jean</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_sm-st.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Smith, Emil L. - Stafford, Jean">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Smith, Emil L. - Stafford, Jean</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref154_eea" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Stafleu, Frans. A. - Szent-Gyordyi, A.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_st-sz.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Stafleu, Frans. A. - Szent-Gyordyi, A.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Stafleu, Frans. A. - Szent-Gyordyi, A.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref20_dmd" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>T</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref156_7kf" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Szilard, Leo - Toyota</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_sz-to.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Szilard, Leo - Toyota">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Szilard, Leo - Toyota</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref158_qqd" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Traeger, William - Twenty-Five Year Report of RIMR</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_tr-tw.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Traeger, William - Twenty-Five Year Report of RIMR">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Traeger, William - Twenty-Five Year Report of RIMR</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref160_6ow" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Twenty Fifth Anniversary - Valleau, W.D.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_tw-va.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Twenty Fifth Anniversary - Valleau, W.D.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Twenty Fifth Anniversary - Valleau, W.D.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref22_lja" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>U, V</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref162_h2w" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Van de Sande Bakhuyzen, H.L. - Vosburgh, Gilbert J.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_va-vo.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Van de Sande Bakhuyzen, H.L. - Vosburgh, Gilbert J.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Van de Sande Bakhuyzen, H.L. - Vosburgh, Gilbert J.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref23_rpw" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>W</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref165_09o" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Voyage to Lourdes - Webster, Leslie Tillotson</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_vo-we.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Voyage to Lourdes - Webster, Leslie Tillotson">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Voyage to Lourdes - Webster, Leslie Tillotson</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref167_m38" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Weed, Lewis Hill - Wheeler, George C.</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_we-wh.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Weed, Lewis Hill - Wheeler, George C.">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Weed, Lewis Hill - Wheeler, George C.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref170_4bj" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Whetzel, H.H. - X-Ray</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_wh-x.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="Whetzel, H.H. - X-Ray">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Whetzel, H.H. - X-Ray</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="aspace_ref24_cep" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>X-Z</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref172_jnz" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>X-Ray - Zworykin, Vladimir</unittitle>
            <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://storage.rockarch.org/FA1068_x-z.pdf" xlink:show="embed" xlink:title="X-Ray - Zworykin, Vladimir">
              <daodesc>
                <p>X-Ray - Zworykin, Vladimir</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
