<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="under_revision" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>FA910.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper type="filing">Rockefeller University records, History of the University, Site History</titleproper>
        <titleproper>A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, History of the University, Site History
 <num>FA910</num></titleproper>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline>
          <addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline>
          <addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-11-18 00:53:56 -0500</date>.</creation>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <date>2010 October 12</date>
      <item>Paper finding aid converted to EAD/XML by AureXus in 2010. Imported into the Archvists’ Toolkit by Becky Robbins.</item>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Rockefeller University records, History of the University, Site History</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="ctb" source="naf">Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research</corpname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="aut" source="naf">Rockefeller University</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>FA910</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.28 Cubic Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">3 boxes and 2 packages (Boxes 4 and 5).</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1901/2000" type="inclusive">1901-2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <bioghist id="80a7ac044371ef2a654b8a79f87447fd">
      <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
      <p>The work of The Institute concentrated on basic research. The hope was that the discoveries might, in the long run, be applied to the public welfare, but the basic purpose was to provide an environment for exploratory original research by individuals under no compulsion to produce immediately useful results.</p>
      <p>Scientific work of The Institute was first carried on through grants-in-aid made to researchers in scattered laboratories. This program decreased as the Institute's own laboratories developed. July 1, 1904 temporary quarters were rented at 127 East 50th Street, New York and work began there about Nov. 1, 1904. Those recruited for the first staff were Eugene L. Opie, Samuel J. Meltzer, Hideyo Noguchi and Joshua Edwin Sweet. Added to the staff very shortly were Phoebus Aaron Theodor Levene and John Auer. Alexis Carrel joined The Institute in 1906 and Jacques Loeb in 1910. On June 13, 1907 the Board of Directors voted to establish various classes of association with The Institute. The classes were: Member (for an indefinite period); Associate Member (for five year periods; amended in 1911 Rules to "a term of years); Associate of The Institute; Fellow of The Institute; Scholar of The Institute (which was dropped in the Rules amended 1928). The first Members of The Institute were Simon Flexner, S.J. Meltzer, E.L. Opie, and P.A.T. Levene.</p>
      <p>In April 1906 the Central Laboratory with animal house and power house, located on York Avenue and 66th Street were ready for use. Simon Flexner, the first Director of the laboratories had been unanimously elected Director of The Institute on Oct. 25, 1902. However, not until a meeting on Jan. 17, 1920 did the Board make clear its sense that these were two offices, both held by Simon Flexner. The Office of Director of The Institute was clearly added in amended Rules Oct. 18, 1924. Simon Flexner was Director of The Institute and Director of the laboratories until his retirement in 1935. He was succeeded in both offices by Herbert S. Gasser, 1935-1953.</p>
      <p>In 1910, at the York Avenue site a Hospital was opened so that the investigations of the Laboratories could be supplemented by the study of certain diseases as they actually occur in man. The Rules for the Scientific Directors as adopted on Jan. 21, 1911, provided that The Institute be comprised of two coordinate departments, Laboratories and Hospital. Rufus Cole was the first Director of the Department of the Hospital and continued in this post until his retirement in 1937 when he was succeeded by Thomas M. Rivers. The Hospital accepted only a limited number of patients, limited further to classes of diseases under study in the Hospital laboratories. The By-Laws of the Corporation provided that The Institute make no charge to persons treated at the Hospital for professional care rendered or for board and lodging. Classes of appointment to the Hospital were Physician, Assistant Physician, Resident Physician, Superintendent and Assistant Superintendent. In 1946 an amendment to the Rules provided that the titles be as follows: Physician-in-Chief to the Hospital; Physician to the Hospital; Assistant Physician to the Hospital; Resident Associate Physician; Senior Assistant Physician; Superintendent of the Hospital; Assistant Superintendent of the Hospital.</p>
      <p>In 1914, at a location about three miles from Princeton, N.J. with Theobald Smith as Director, a new Department of Animal Pathology was established. In June 1915 the Rules were amended to make this coordinate with the Departments of Laboratories and Hospital. When Theobald Smith retired in 1930 Carl TenBroeck became Director of the Department which in 1931 was expanded by the appointment of Louis O. Kunkel who headed the new division of plant pathology into the Department of Animal and Plant Pathology.</p>
      <p>The Director of each Department was appointed by the Board of Scientific Directors, and the Director of The Institute by the Corporation. In the different departments separate laboratories were organized under the guidance of a Member or Associate Member. The broad divisions of scientific fields varied from time to time in accordance with scientific developments and the interests of the Members, but always with consultation, approval and direction of the Board of Scientific Directors.</p>
      <p>In 1953, after the retirement of Herbert S. Gasser, an extensive reorganization was undertaken. Thomas M. Rivers, who served for two years as Vice-President of the Corporation and at the same time, Director of the Laboratories, Director of the Department of the Hospital and Physician-in-Chief to the Hospital retired in 1955. The position of Director of The Institute was abolished and also the organization into departments.</p>
      <p>On and after November 19, 1954 when the Charter of the Corporation was amended so that the Corporation became part of the University of the State of New York The Institute had the power to confer degrees. On June 27, 1958 by amendment to the Charter the corporate name was changed to The Rockefeller Institute and on May 27, 1965 the Charter of The Institute was amended in its entirety and the name changed to The Rockefeller University.</p>
      <p>The University is organized into laboratories, each headed by one or two senior scientists rather than into categorical departments. The scientific work of the laboratories is under the direction of the President.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <fileplan id="d79b7c493875855837ffaa404071b5f3">
      <head>File Plan note</head>
      <p>Former Classification: I 412</p>
    </fileplan>
    <prefercite id="e9ed74b0de2275063d4fa0713e4ca195">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>
    </prefercite>
    <arrangement id="99c0c1b4fe300b2c0a66a48e41c88f6d">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>Arranged by subject.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <scopecontent id="44d51a2add5a440fdc2a457d1a0754af">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>Photographs, pamphlets, news, articles, summaries, notes, drawings.</p>
      <p>A collection of historical material related to The University site collected from varying sources over a period of time by the Business Manager.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <accessrestrict id="95ef9d5e59cffc14d73090fc6ad341ce">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
      <p>This collection is open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Medical research</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Operations management</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Life sciences</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Medical sciences</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Medical education</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Cell and biomolecular sciences</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Biology -- Research</subject>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="100b57b0367d460aade43e35370ac30e" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>History of site</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c id="1c4526879e8a4e18bd3e223b096b9131" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Six pamphlet publications about the East Side in Early New York City. In one is picture of Schermerhorn farm house at foot of East 64th Street</unittitle>
            <container id="f60b004d2692fe80b43fd3f8a63a34f2" label="mixed materials (A0000000085502)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="078f80104daf485e8bf9c2b3986d3e8f" parent="f60b004d2692fe80b43fd3f8a63a34f2" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="df82fa121c024e23a48f09dfb93b7ecd" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Newspaper articles, A sampling of the newspaper articles which showed recurrent interest in East Side properties</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1921/1964" type="inclusive">1921-1964</unitdate>
            <container id="94a071445234da16535c572af0e427c7" label="mixed materials (A0000000085502)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="ccc3dbd9cca06edc69c3c4e7debade75" parent="94a071445234da16535c572af0e427c7" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="c87758510772418bb8dec98a0c5bd702" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Photographs and historical notes</unittitle>
            <container id="3f55ab45c44e94ae79a26e9029793dd5" label="mixed materials (A0000000085502)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="649ec9bb2e91fc0b17c8225ac398fcae" parent="3f55ab45c44e94ae79a26e9029793dd5" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
          <c id="4634f01620034919bb7c454e0b23e185" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>3 photographs of Pastime Athletic Club at 66th Street and East River circa 1889 with collection of handwritten notes by T.M. Prudden</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1879/1899" type="inclusive">circa 1889</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="538da8f4e8a94863b83d8c0f26cc40f0" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1 photograph of temporary laboratory building at 127 East 50th Street</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1904/1906" type="inclusive">1904-1906</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="f8d16abe3e654844b7e4b6b5752a9ed4" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1 photograph of 1908 housekeeping staff</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1908/1908" type="inclusive">1908</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="add965904b344e0f92f5b198927966cb" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1 photograph showing original building, animal house and power house</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1906/1906" type="inclusive">1906</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="46971ab40f754f7b8334b14c2dc63ac2" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>5 snapshots supplied by Jerome P. Jacobsen, resident construction engineer for Shepley, Rutan and Coolidge, showing cornerstone laying; animal house; power house; laboratory</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="a9caae3e1d3043fea3ca452bd0032598" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>6 photographs showing various glimpses of Schermerhorn Farm house</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="1e7fcee8fddf47f4af46b69381480f19" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>13 photographs showing various stages of growth and additions</unittitle>
              <unitdate>1973 April</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="f4e4c8c41a9ce421b63536d61e7692ce">
              <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
              <p>Includes air rights hearing</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c>
          <c id="be1ed3e0a90645208a817f81b753900f" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>"An Anniversary Album" photographs used for exhibit</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c>
        </c>
        <c id="ece6561de6f5419fb33c31556e94fa68" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Notes and summaries on property through</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1947/1947" type="inclusive">1947</unitdate>
            <container id="f41355ae39c3c329e804d8c396efa8dd" label="mixed materials (A0000000085502)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="6d49e11246dc040ebd04e956ba2f9177" parent="f41355ae39c3c329e804d8c396efa8dd" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
          <c id="42e9d372055e4ca9ad6db3863fa0d58d" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Evening Telegram</unittitle>
              <unitdate>1903 February 13</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="b2d5142893084c45974cc99729f4eff0" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>New York Sun</unittitle>
              <unitdate>1903 October 18</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="420b12ecef214af5ada6bc84ab0afae1" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Typescript copies of articles which appeared at time of land purchase</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="ec80be38dfa346f19081057f8b50ea44" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Notes about Schermerhorn Farm house (primarily made by T.M. Prudden)</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="ca481614c1084b6ba877bb0d2c97a62a" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Copy of notes placed in cornerstone</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1904/1904" type="inclusive">1904</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="ef8715884e8e47bbb385344c733d78e5" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Accounting sheets showing costs and taxes on Schermerhorn property</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1903/1911" type="inclusive">1903-1911</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="efc4a2d779bd467bad4cd043087934ec" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Listing of investments and valuations</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1908/1910" type="inclusive">1908-1910</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="b02bdc25bea2417c879fd67bbbe09aec" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Description of buildings from standpoint of fire insurance</unittitle>
              <unitdate>1919 October 10</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="087486056f3f4149ab8d7556d41a415f" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Extracts from Minutes on location of RIMR; purchase of land; original staff</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="78e2e73b2c0a47bbb3826153f13c4045" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Miscellaneous notes regarding location in NYC of RIMR</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1937/1957" type="inclusive">circa 1947</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
        </c>
        <c id="1547984e23054387a95994abe67e4cca" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Notes and correspondence about property and buildings</unittitle>
            <container id="9030eed28bec6aa8d1c54f20ba47e512" label="mixed materials (A0000000085502)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="43f532acc8e3f806d4ebc83ad0b47815" parent="9030eed28bec6aa8d1c54f20ba47e512" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
          <c id="485adeb1031b430485ae43c00c5a571e" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Summary of gifts; land acquisitions; buildings and costs</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1901/1912" type="inclusive">1901-1912</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="7ce3534735ad4f27bf851c12b28f689c" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>10 Letter from E.B. Smith to S. Flexner on Dean and Sheppard (occupants of buildings on North Plot)</unittitle>
              <unitdate>1920 September</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="b7ab7c2cc0eb4ba48ca0992ba5aa1845" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Memo from T.M. Prudden notes of role played by L. Emmett Holt in early history of Institute</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1924/1924" type="inclusive">1924</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="d9798bbf2f864e019cd7f07d5576912e" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Letter from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to Simon Flexner about mantel in old Schermerhorn house</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1929/1929" type="inclusive">1929</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="f77f0ee9b17a44288cb63b75e07bbc71" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Summary of construction dates, costs and valuations of buildings 1906-1934</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1935/1935" type="inclusive">1935</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="947abe1ca93743d39823a1f706f169cd" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Copy of address apparently made at opening of playground on land held for Memorial Hospital</unittitle>
              <unitdate>1935 October 14</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="37e14e6e3dfa43398ebcc308678a8ebf" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>8 items dealing with appraisal of RIMR buildings and grounds done by Douglas Gibbons and Co. for John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</unittitle>
              <unitdate>1947 January-February</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="885b56344a284b0e80ef1fcf35ab78e6" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>6 items dealing with history of Institute site, including copy of painting at foot of 61st Street including old stone house and copied group of informational items from Museum of City of New York</unittitle>
              <unitdate>1949 May-July</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="938301e4ebe5407f9576199b1425e5ae" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Correspondence with Jerome P. Jacobsen, sending snapshots of cornerstone and early buildings</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1954/1954" type="inclusive">1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="4c2b20dde56b49498da106872e19e600" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Certificate of Occupancy - Welch Hall</unittitle>
              <unitdate>1956 April 11</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="d565acf5e45c4102b0538a64c5da0fee" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>9 Items on lighting for library</unittitle>
              <unitdate>1957 April-August</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="62c0c11ebcea494d9a204f7cc67c74e4" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>2 Items on building contract for new laboratory</unittitle>
              <unitdate>1957 August</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="4fa85cc343d240f4b50a8fc32e68b168" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>3 announcements on new buildings</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1962/1965" type="inclusive">1962-1965</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="9bd6661b8eff4f57979174dd6430c185" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>3 Items on landmark status for Founder's Hall</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">1974</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c id="9ff011d23eaf46c99d7a4593466cff0f" level="item">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Apartment building at 500 East 63rd St</unittitle>
              <unitdate normal="1975/1975" type="inclusive">1975</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c>
        </c>
        <c id="4710db86771e41069df616c5556f0e0f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Drawings of Proposed Hospital Building, 1931 (not used)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1931/1931" type="inclusive">1931</unitdate>
            <container id="4a25cc86609da5a1f91731daf68b551d" label="mixed materials (A0000000085502)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="883fb80c49d068e4c68b59f45d8b9e10" parent="4a25cc86609da5a1f91731daf68b551d" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="40a0a173296a40a8a39af0aab0b0212b" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clipping book</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1928/1960" type="inclusive">1928-1960</unitdate>
            <physdesc id="1dd368d775970555a8f5d32e52253734">1 book</physdesc>
            <container id="4027cea98dfd7eb0d7fc7428e483b354" label="mixed materials (A0000000085503)" type="box">2</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="04a069d5f948dc8826e5e06303dc304b">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Collection of clippings dealing with real estate development of East Side area.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c>
        <c id="c44c4a6595fd4d308d965937dcf54f05" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"Life on the East River, Part I" Avenue Magazine, May 1984</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1906/1906" type="inclusive">1906</unitdate>
            <container id="41fd961275dd2ca2d786be903f21154e" label="mixed materials (A0000000085504)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="689bf4aa87613317a82b7c6885121827" parent="41fd961275dd2ca2d786be903f21154e" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="39426e3939885860199259ccfca13d6a">
            <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
            <p>Includes photograph of Schermerhorn house and the summer camp for babies (1906). pp. 72-73.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c>
        <c id="07a225c05a6c4cada97f312217155330" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Articles, The New York Times, 1910. "Rockefeller Gives Word" 17 April 1910, "Summer Camp for Babies"</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1910 June 15</unitdate>
            <container id="8845760d94728039da642dbbdaf1867f" label="mixed materials (A0000000085504)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="35863b1646ca3905b79c9ea5b87dbea9" parent="8845760d94728039da642dbbdaf1867f" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="e242c942ec0f4f259fc8701d7aae933d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and David Rockefeller Building - Dedication, September 23-26, 1992. Booklet outlining the ceremonies and events</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1992 September 23-26</unitdate>
            <container id="a03ced5da8c7f6c72a1e83de64dfaceb" label="mixed materials (A0000000085504)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="cdbe75fcc322732532cb9f13c5e8ea15" parent="a03ced5da8c7f6c72a1e83de64dfaceb" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="cc66d7e72e624f93890a3d9866102bcb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>"The Rockefeller University: A Building-By-Building Guide"</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1992/1992" type="inclusive">1992</unitdate>
            <container id="04d2018e93442090b4f8f3eaffdbf0fb" label="mixed materials (A0000000085504)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="eb288be5d296255d43eeedd46923b3f3" parent="04d2018e93442090b4f8f3eaffdbf0fb" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="a2fe07058ac84a71b75ddaa6574e1c2d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Clarke and Rapuano, Inc., "The Rockefeller University Master Plan"</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972</unitdate>
            <container id="aa9651dedaa55b651001b9394c9ecb37" label="mixed materials (A0000000085504)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="c4ab784c9e248e2d9c859a88bbca178c" parent="aa9651dedaa55b651001b9394c9ecb37" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="37b331c9e21d409fbc29eae1dadfdd90" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>The Rockefeller University - Plaza Dedication, Thursday, Booklet</unittitle>
            <unitdate>2000 May 25</unitdate>
            <container id="5d5e8ba94d307d328193b19ade596bbf" label="mixed materials (A0000000085504)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="12e5bf0c90b28c068354e3db7d169503" parent="5d5e8ba94d307d328193b19ade596bbf" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="511892e9396f48158afe56119708fc8c" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>A Guide to the Campus Landscape and Sculpture</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1997 May</unitdate>
            <container id="876925ff00692f16059b0b5283339024" label="mixed materials (A0000000085504)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="6c92e4df2d18b1031552594af2c3e6ae" parent="876925ff00692f16059b0b5283339024" type="folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="7195629f9ed94c14a135711b7d9dbcfa" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>A Guide to the President's House</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1997 May</unitdate>
            <container id="aaafe931fed165bc0806e3aa68f340c9" label="mixed materials (A0000000085504)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="7fc49f4a5a2563680d867fa41113b5ef" parent="aaafe931fed165bc0806e3aa68f340c9" type="folder">8</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="b3c0eb69a11b4356917eac09315f0867" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Certificate from Department of the Interior, designating Founder's Hall "A National Historic Landmark"</unittitle>
          <unitdate>1974 September</unitdate>
          <physdesc id="aebaffe27c4dbe07b59e06fef5ac1f96">package</physdesc>
          <container id="8017ee29a50f29a75ba1a826bcbd25e8" label="mixed materials" type="box">4</container>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c id="9845e31c9f434c28ab9bee5b87295c59" level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Charts</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1951/1951" type="inclusive">1951</unitdate>
          <physdesc id="fb8408f002aeec07777e7695c40ac061">1 package (roll, 3 feet in length)</physdesc>
          <container id="e0bfb58c8d6a2b381932da29050b70eb" label="mixed materials" type="box">5</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="42335a319dd3b56a93993e01f59cf064">
          <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
          <p>Data assembled by the Housing Office of Memorial Center and arranged on charts.</p>
          <p>Deals with the area extending from 59th Street to 72nd Street and East from 3rd Avenue.</p>
          <p>Charts deal with: Assesses valuations of land parcels, Present zoning: use height and area districts, Joint area study - land use, Age of buildings, Prospective new construction.</p>
          <p>Framed color print, Schermerhorn Farm House. Gift of Dr. Joshua Lederberg, March 1983. Hanging in University Librarian's Office. [See Corner's History, Appendix II pp. 585-86].</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
