<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA098.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Jacocks (William P.) photographs</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the William P. Jacocks photographs
 <num>FA098</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><p><date>2009</date></p><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>Telephone: 914-631-4505</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 914-631-6017</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-07-01 00:28:46 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>William P. Jacocks photographs</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="naf">Jacocks, William Picard (1877-1965)</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA098</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.1 Cubic Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1915/1941" type="inclusive">1915-1941</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="6978d1920a172f9032e6877124bcfcf1">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>William P. Jacocks was born in Windsor, North Carolina, in 1877. He attended the University of North Carolina from which he received an A.B. in 1904 and an A.M. in 1905. He graduated from the University of Pennsylvania in 1911 with an M.D. Continuing his education, he attended Johns Hopkins School of Hygiene and Public Health in 1925.</p><p>Dr. Jacocks was associated with the North Carolina State Board of Health from 1912-1913, with the Rockefeller Sanitary Commission in 1913-1914, and again with the North Carolina State Board of Health in 1914-1915. In 1915 he became Director of the Hookworm program in St. Vincent, British West Indies, and the following year was Acting Regional Director for the area. Through 1917-1918 he was Director of the Hookworm program in Ceylon.</p><p>Dr. Jacocks joined the United States Army Medical Corps during World War I as a Captain. After leaving the service, he was Director of Cooperative Work in Ceylon through 1922. Returning to the United States, Dr. Jacocks worked with John A. Ferrell in making surveys of state and county health programs. In 1925 he returned to Ceylon, in 1929 becoming the Advisor in Public Health to the government of Ceylon. Dr. Jacocks served in that capacity until 1934 when he became Regional Director for Ceylon and India.</p><p>Dr. Jacocks retired from the Rockefeller Foundation in 1942 to become the Coordinator of School Health Services for the North Carolina State Board of Health. He was the author of a history of Bertie County, North Carolina.</p><p>Dr. Jacocks died in 1965.</p>  </bioghist>
  <userestrict id="0eee57d943e4366d776de335770066fd">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The Rockefeller Foundation has title, copyright, and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them. Rockefeller Archive Center has authority to grant permission to cite and publish archival material from the collection.</p>  </userestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="4cb41c29467120854b60800ef85b85d7">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="d2accd1c5fd392a896990c244a024f52">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
<p>William P. Jacocks deposited his photographs with the Rockefeller Foundation Archives in 1969.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <scopecontent id="5223715b9e2f0220ae01734b8cdff1d7">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection contains four photograph albums of Jacocks' trips to Egypt, Asia (1916-1917), Trinidad (1916), and the British West Indies (1916-1918). The photographs depict shipboard activities, the Suez Canal and Port Said; and the pitch industry, "coolies," and scenic views of Trinidad. There are a few photographs of India and Ceylon (1935) and a photograph of the American High Commissioners in India (1941). Also included are 27 lantern slides showing snail clearance from irrigation ditches and fields in Egypt (1930s).</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="3fbaf365b5b6653bc28d6a076d89bed2">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>As received.</p>  </arrangement>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">West Indies, British</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Trinidad</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Asia</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Egypt</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">West Indies</geogname>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Photographs</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="bc7bf3d9d1d0458f83ac72e80b214bef" level="series"><did><unittitle>William P. Jacocks</unittitle><unitid>1055</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1915/1941" type="inclusive">1915-1941</unitdate></did><c id="cf97dbe6bffe4a758dff76029997758f" level="file"><did><unittitle>William P. Jacocks, Albums 1-4.</unittitle><container altrender="15 x 10 Oversize Document Box" id="6fa15935ef8f711aee3acbb39b182def" label="Still Image [A0000000100607]" type="box">1</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
