<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="https://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="under_revision" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA107</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Rockefeller (Blanchette H.) papers</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Blanchette H. Rockefeller Papers
 <num>FA107</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>Telephone: 914-631-4505</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 914-631-6017</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-01-01 05:00:32 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Blanchette H. Rockefeller papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="naf">Rockefeller, Blanchette Hooker</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="ctb" source="naf">Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA107</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/resources/264</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">45.22 Cubic Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">95 containers</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1745/1994" type="inclusive">1745, 1884-1994, bulk 1910-1994</unitdate>
    <physdesc id="d0a3bb0fcb20e6cf6abf042bc55fea8d" label="General Physical Description note">82 Boxes, 45 cubic feet</physdesc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="60cc227f43648642bec68c0e4742af18">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Material in the Rockefeller family collections that provides the names, correspondence, or activities of living members of the Rockefeller family, and/or documents the net wealth of any Rockefeller family members, is restricted from access. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <arrangement id="1a1fad97f8282f5a8c676af3f1fc044d">
    <head>Arrangement note</head>
<p>The papers of Blanchette H. Rockefeller are divided into the following seven series:</p><p>Series 1 - Hooker and Ferry Families Files, 1745, 1884-1992
Series 2 - Rockefeller Family Files, 1932-1991
Series 3 - Subject Files, 1933-1994
Series 4 - Museum of Modern Art Files, 1951-1992
Series 5 - Political Files, 1961-1992
Series 6 - Restricted Material
Series 7 - Photographs</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="9c4e2527fcc34e9da5921e5a7dd58585">
    <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
<p>Blanchette Ferry Hooker was born in New York City on October 2, 1909, the youngest of the four daughters of Blanche Ferry, an heiress to the Ferry seed fortune, and Elon Huntington Hooker, an engineer and president of the Hooker Electro-Chemical Company. From 1918 through 1927 she was a student at Miss Chapin's School for Girls. During her childhood Blanchette acquired a nickname, "Hookie," by which she would be known to family and close friends throughout her life.</p><p>In 1927 she began her studies at Vassar College, which culminated with an A.B. degree in music in 1931. Blanchette was president of her senior class and was voted the "Most Perfect Lady" as well as the "Most Respected" member of her graduating class. A year later (November 11, 1932) she married John D. Rockefeller 3rd, the eldest of the five sons of John D. Rockefeller Jr., at the Riverside Church in New York City. Together they raised four children. They maintained principal residences in New York City and at Fieldwood Farm in Mt. Pleasant in Westchester County, New York.</p><p>Blanchette Rockefeller began her life-long involvement in New York City's charitable and civic activities by joining the Community Service Society in 1933 as a member of its Central Council. She was also a trustee of the Brearley School, Vassar College, and The Juilliard School. Mrs. Rockefeller's lengthy affiliation with the Museum of Modern Art began in 1949 with her role as founding chair of its Junior Council. She served the museum in various capacities (including two terms as president) until her election as President Emeritus in 1987.</p><p>From 1974 to 1980 Mrs. Rockefeller was a member of the National Council on the Humanities. She was appointed to the New York State Council on the Arts in 1979 and was re-appointed in 1981 for a six-year term. In 1985 she was elected to the board of the Vivian Beaumont Theater. Her memberships included the New York Philharmonic Symphony Society, the English-Speaking Union, the American Federation of Arts, the Riverside Church, and the River Club as well as numerous other leading cultural institutions.</p><p>Mrs. Rockefeller shared many of her husband's philanthropic interests. She was a member of the Asia Society, which he founded, as well as a member of both the Society's Gallery Advisory Committee and the Friends of Asia House. She was also a member of the Gallery Committee of the Japan Society and of the American Advisory Committee to the Japan Foundation. Their mutual deep interest in Asia and Asian art had begun in the early 1950s with Mr. Rockefeller's appointment to John Foster Dulles' Peace Treaty Mission to Japan, a country that would become almost a second home to the couple.</p><p>Throughout their marriage, Blanchette and John 3rd devoted a great deal of time to art collecting. They gradually assembled world-class collections of Asian and American art, which were donated to the Asia Society and to San Francisco's DeYoung Museum respectively.</p><p>Blanchette Ferry Hooker Rockefeller died from Alzheimer's disease complicated by pneumonia on November 29, 1992, at her home in Mt. Pleasant. She was 83 years old. A memorial service was held at the Riverside Church in New York City on December 4 of that year.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="e3268ff0d60bf9c0ca7292291dcb2d48">
    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
<p>The papers of Blanchette Ferry Hooker Rockefeller (1909-1992) span the years 1884 to 1994. They document the various roles she played throughout her lifetime, including that of daughter, wife, mother, daughter-in-law, aunt, friend, philanthropist, art collector, and political fundraiser. The papers contain her personal and family correspondence, photographs, and memorabilia as well as the records generated by her philanthropic activities. They provide information on her ancestors; education; relationships with family members, friends, and associates; travels; and on her social concerns and benevolences. While the bulk of the papers deals with Mrs. Rockefeller's lifetime, some items relating to her forebears predate her birth. Due to shared interests and activities in many areas, Blanchette Rockefeller's papers parallel and complement the papers of her husband, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, which are also housed at the Rockefeller Archive Center and are open to researchers.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aa30fefe381aa98c165cdc8508901dd0">
    <head>Related Archival Materials note</head>
<p>The most significant other collections at the Rockefeller Archive Center containing material relevant to the life and work of Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller are all papers of Rockefeller family members. They include the Abby Aldrich Rockefeller papers, which form series Series AA of the Office of the Messrs Rockefeller records; the Nelson A. Rockefeller Personal papers, Series C.3 Art, Series H Family and Friends, and Series L Projects (under Museums - MoMA); and the John D. Rockefeller 3rd papers.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="2c653203fc83430295b5922ab89d1eaf">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
<p>The forty-five cubic feet of material that comprise the Blanchette H. Rockefeller (BHR) Papers were transferred to the Rockefeller Archive Center from the Rockefeller family offices in New York City in five installments from February through April 1995. </p><p>The collection was donated to the RAC by the estate of Blanchette H. Rockefeller in 2005.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="ef64a6afdab2538ca0ab8eb81fe434ac">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The Rockefeller Archive Center has title, copyright, and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them, and has authority to grant permission to cite and publish archival material from the collection.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Arts</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Rockefeller, Blanchette Hooker, 1909-1992 -- Political activity</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art -- Collectors and collecting</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art</subject>
    <subject source="local">Philanthropy</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc>