<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA1133.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Rockefeller Foundation records, International Centers and Institutes</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, International Centers and Institutes <num>FA1133</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-09-02 19:52:54 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Rockefeller Foundation records, International Centers and Institutes</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" source="naf">Rockefeller Foundation</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" rules="local" source="naf">International Laboratory for Research on Animal Diseases</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" source="naf">Consultative Group on International Agricultural Research</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" source="naf">International Center for Living Aquatic Resources Management</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" source="naf">Centro Internacional de Agricultura Tropical</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA1133</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">19.05 Cubic Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">39 legal document boxes
3 half legal document boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1969/1984" type="inclusive">1969-1984</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="c9a4646f79f643eaa56712422d644386">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="5261251062109fb1f550aa34315cfc84">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Types of records include: correspondence, reports, photographs, newspaper articles, and oversized architectural plans.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="1b9d65457a3c1a3785ff3cd2e6659db4">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>International Laboratory for Research on Animal Diseases (ILRAD) was established in Nairobi in 1973 by agreement between the Government of Kenya and the Rockefeller Foundation acting for the Consultative Group on International Agricultural Research. The mandate of the Laboratory is to develop safe, effective and economically feasible control measures for livestock diseases which seriously limit world food production.</p><p>International Center for Living Aquatic Resources Management (ICLARM) was organized in 1975 and incorporated in 1977 in the Philippines where it maintains its headquarters. The Rockefeller Foundation developed the concept leading to ICLARM, and remains its principal donor. The rationale behind the Rockefeller initiative was that there appeared to be a need in fisheries for an organization similar to the international agricultural centers which operate under the aegis of the Consultative Group on International Agricultural Research (CGIAR). It would be an organization that could conduct long-term coordinated research on the principal fisheries problems in the developing world.</p><p>International Center for Tropical Agriculture (CIAT) was backed by the Colombian government and Rockefeller, Ford, and Kellogg Foundations, CIAT was formally established in 1967 and began its research in 1969. While aware of the many constraints to farming in the tropics, CIAT's founders saw this vast region as a world of promise, where agriculture, with the aid of modern science, might contribute substantially to reducing hunger and poverty. Since no single organization can address the whole of tropical agriculture, CIAT complements the efforts of others by focusing on selected crops and research areas.</p><p>Technical Advisory Committee (TAC) was created to support the activities of CGIAR. Located in Rome, Italy and composed of a small number of independent scientists in disciplines related to agricultural development.</p><p>Consultantive Group on International Agricultural Research (CGIAR) is a global research partnership for a food-secure future. CGIAR science is dedicated to reducing poverty, enhancing food and nutrition security, and improving natural resources and ecosystem services. Its research is carried out by 15 CGIAR centers in close collaboration with hundreds of partners, including national and regional research institutes, civil society organizations, academia, development organizations and the private sector.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="e5798ba126e832a5c7a63a5cb55c69ce">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Series 1-International Laboratory for Research and Animal Diseases (ILRAD)</p><p>Series 2-International Center for Living Aquatic Resources Management (ICLARM)</p><p>Series 3-International Center for Tropical Agriculture (CIAT)</p><p>Series 4-Technical Advisory Committee (TAC)</p><p>Series 5-Consultative Group on International Agricultural Research (CGIAR)</p>  </arrangement>
  <dsc>