<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA1282.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Kerr (J. Austin) papers</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the J. Austin Kerr papers <num>FA1282</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>Telephone: 914-631-4505</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 914-631-6017</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-03-13 17:00:21 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>J. Austin Kerr papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="naf">Kerr, J. Austin (1900-1990)</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="ctb" source="naf">Rockefeller Foundation</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA1282</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4.2 Cubic Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">5 letter document boxes, 4 legal document boxes, 1 flat file folder, and 1 half legal document box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1925/1976" type="inclusive">1925-1976</unitdate>
    <langmaterial id="20d6d3e698f801e383c38eae538b1121">Some materials in Portuguese</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="2bb24f1bb0123ed7027196c81f9217e8">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="d4f82b50df346d03410a09a4b0117a82">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The J. Austin Kerr papers document Dr. Kerr's 40-year career with the Rockefeller Foundation where he studied and implemented methods to control and eradicate yellow fever, malaria, and hookworm disease. During his career, Kerr lived in Paraguay, Brazil, Nigeria, Colombia, Egypt, Italy, India, the Philippines, and the U.S. The collection contains memos, personal and professional correspondence, critiques of institutions, drafts of papers, notes, research reports, photographs, gifts presented to Kerr, and Kerr's manuscript collection. The manuscript collection is comprised of 159 documents cataloged by Kerr that include published papers, memos, drafts, personal correspondence, and reflections on his work. The majority of the materials in series 1 are duplicated in series 2. Kerr annotated many of the documents from 1970-1976 during his retirement.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="e4e090599129e2fc6bb26352179791c2">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>John Austin Kerr was born July 15, 1900, in Chicago, Illinois. He received a B.S. from Northwestern University in 1923, and he received an M.D. from Northwestern Medical School in 1924. From 1923 to 1925, he completed an internship at St. Luke's Hospital in Chicago. From July 1925 to June 1926, he conducted epidemiological field studies of hookworm infestations in Alabama and Florida at the Field Training Station of the International Health Board of the Rockefeller Foundation (IHB/RF) in Andalusia, Alabama. This assignment started his long career with the Rockefeller Foundation. From June to September 1926, he worked at the Malaria Field Station of the IHB/RF at Edenton, North Carolina where he studied malaria and malaria control. Starting in October 1926 until March 1928, Kerr worked with Brazil's Yellow Fever Service learning antilarval techniques in Salvador, Bahia, Brazil. From May 1928 to April 1929, Kerr worked in Paraguay on a hookworm control program. From April to June 1929, Kerr worked in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil during the yellow fever epidemic. Following the death of Dr. Paul Lewis from yellow fever in June 1929, Kerr worked at the Yellow Fever Laboratory in Bahia, Brazil. At this time, he contracted yellow fever himself. </p><p>From 1930-1931, he was assigned to the Rockefeller Foundation's Yellow Fever Laboratory in Lagos, Nigeria. In 1932, Kerr married Janet MacLennan. From March to November 1932, he investigated potential yellow fever cases in Colombia. He returned to Brazil from 1933 to 1936 to lead the Bahia Laboratory following the death of Dr. Nelson Davis. From 1936 to 1938, he oversaw construction of a lab in Bogota to investigate yellow fever activity in Colombia. From 1939 to 1943, Kerr was stationed in Brazil again where he worked on yellow fever studies and supervised large scale production of 17D yellow fever vaccines. After a few months at the Virus Laboratory of the California State Health Department, he was appointed to the Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission and as a Consultant to the Secretary of War. From July-November 1945, Kerr was Director of the Gambiae Eradication Service of Egypt. From September 1946 to October 1947, he accepted a Rockefeller Foundation assignment to Sardinia to serve as Superintendent of Ente Regionale per la Lotta Anti-Anofelica in Sardegna (ERLAAS), a temporary government entity created to eradicate Anopheles labranchiae. From 1947 to 1951, Kerr worked at the Virus Laboratories of the Rockefeller Foundation located at the Rockefeller Institute (now University) in New York City. There, he studied the influenza virus and arboviruses and wrote the chapter on Clinical Aspects in Yellow Fever edited by George K. Strode. From 1951-1955, Kerr was the Director of Virus Research Centre in Poona, India. From 1955-1965, he served as Director of the Pan American Health Organization (PAHO) stationed in Washington, D.C. After 40 years with the Rockefeller Foundation, Kerr retired on March 31, 1965 just prior to his mandatory retirement from the Foundation. </p><p>In March 1965, he was appointed Regional Malaria Advisor for the Far East Region of the Agency for International Development of the U.S. (AID) stationed in Manila, Philippines. In 1966, he was transferred to Washington and discharged from service after critiquing the agency's malaria eradication methods. In 1967, Kerr spent a year as a consultant to the Malaria Eradication Branch of the Pan American Health Organization. There, he translated malariological studies from Portuguese to English. The studies had been conducted in El Salvador by the Epidemiological Study Team of PAHO. In 1968, he was a Guest Scholar at the National Library of Medicine to assist his friend and colleague Fred Soper (sometimes abbreviated FLS) in editing his book, "Selections from the Papers of Fred L. Soper." Kerr lived in Chevy Chase, Maryland until 1986. He died December 12, 1990 in Ossining, New York.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="5c09e81a982a1feb5a0df7da082c75b9">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged "as received" in two series:</p><p>1. Personal Papers, 1925-1976</p><p>2. Manuscripts, 1927-1974</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="6780964d167ba55b1d494afe0f65c8c9">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>The J. Austin Kerr papers arrived in several shipments from 1968-1976. George Harrar, president of the Rockefeller Foundation, first contacted J. Austin Kerr about donating his personal papers to the Rockefeller Foundation in 1967. In May 1968, Kerr donated two memos: 1.) A review of the efficacy of vaccination against yellow fever as applied in 1938 and 1939 in Brazil; and 2.) Further considerations on the results obtained following the use of the "17DD high" substrain of 17D virus as vaccine. </p><p>Archivist Mary Boccaccio followed up with Kerr about donating more of his materials in March 1969. In January 1970, he donated two manuscripts 1.) "Sylvan, or jungle, yellow fever in southern Brazil, 1932-1942;" and 2.) "The eradication of Anopheles gambiae from Egypt." </p><p>In June 1970, Kerr donated a yellow fever manuscript and 20 miscellaneous memos and reports. These materials comprise the first series in the collection. In correspondence from June 1970, he describes his 100+ papers that make up his manuscripts collection. He was still in the process of cataloging the early material at this time. The manuscript materials arrived in five packages in September and October 1974. Series 2 is composed of this material. In 1976, Kerr donated a leather souvenir portfolio and inscribed parchment presented to him in Cagliari, Sardinia.</p><p>This material was originally labelled as Accession 13.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="350058b5e1f4e17df566680f3627a532">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Rockefeller Foundation has title, copyright and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them. Rockefeller Archive Center has authority to grant permission to cite and publish material from the collection.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Yellow fever</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Malaria</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Viruses -- Research</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Epidemiology</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">DDT (Insecticide)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Aedes aegypti</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Anopheles gambiae</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hookworm disease</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Yellow fever -- Vaccination</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="b6d1e4db674fe896d501d116ff5c5c19" level="series"><did><unittitle>Personal Papers</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.47 Cubic Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">2 letter document boxes, 1 legal document box, and 1 half-legal box</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1925/1976" type="inclusive">1925-1976</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="70b96993ed68215319c989e30a00089a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains memos, drafts, notes, research reports, photographs, and gifts presented to Kerr. Many of the reports and drafts are duplicated in Kerr's manuscript collection in series 2. The items in this series were sent to the Rockefeller Archive Center between 1968 and 1970. Around the time of donation, Kerr added additional notes to many of the papers included either in the margins or in letters accompanying the documents.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="9804a8f7f1bc13b7936c0c4a287f1440"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged "as received."</p></arrangement><c id="c631a50a9e095648a2da0cc74794743e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Organization of Campaigns Against Yellow Fever by J. H. White, International Health Board of the Rockefeller Foundation</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1925/1925">1925</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="5edb9756a7dbba10748e7a070d1593f5" label="mixed materials [A0000000118236]" type="box">1</container><container id="8c31ca1339da706ee0ff59a76dcf3511" parent="5edb9756a7dbba10748e7a070d1593f5" type="folder">1</container></did></c><c id="af38c001be37ddc70bc1f9ebdbbfc167" level="file"><did><unittitle>Technic for the Use of White Mice for the Recovery of Yellow Fever Virus, From Suspect Human Cases of Yellow Fever - Draft with Edits</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1935-11-16/1935-11-16">1935 November 16</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="562c812a13ff1984b5f04b2aa21c0ac8" label="mixed materials [A0000000118236]" type="box">1</container><container id="1c45af7b621cdf817282d1807a7d9e80" parent="562c812a13ff1984b5f04b2aa21c0ac8" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="8dda97b66a2b7115b354de88f1f3c7e8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Note from Kerr from April 7, 1972: This was a pinoneer project because mice had not previously been used to isolate yellow fever virus. With the collaboration of Dr. L? Whitman, if I can recall correctly.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="470732a0538d06d38b0e77e76a581c90" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Concept of Selective Measures in Malaria Eradication by J. Austin Kerr, M.D.</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce">undated</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="bae9e1913472fb61b82df86864ad4304" label="mixed materials [A0000000118236]" type="box">1</container><container id="3092af00cccd8b901734542fc2d79670" parent="bae9e1913472fb61b82df86864ad4304" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="5106b2cc7bfa7a32edca40bf0d160efa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Copy - RFA, VII Congresses, Rio de Janeiro</p></scopecontent></c><c id="ca2e0083fcb89a7acb20b9e91ee32ffa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Yellow Fever Research Service - Brazil, Special Report for the Period July 1, 1941 to June 30, 1942</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="2c1f5039c1320311a5c52592a726577a" label="mixed materials [A0000000118236]" type="box">1</container><container id="4487ad4209601321dd002e9ac7ed8bd7" parent="2c1f5039c1320311a5c52592a726577a" type="folder">4</container></did></c><c id="edf18c7f71f28a1cfab6691859e7b506" level="file"><did><unittitle>What to Bring to Brazil by Janet M. Kerr</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="160ef7206e1f996eca6221c242edfbfc" label="mixed materials [A0000000118236]" type="box">1</container><container id="3f68387d745ed8189cc746f1ee98cb28" parent="160ef7206e1f996eca6221c242edfbfc" type="folder">5</container></did></c><c id="5732f5ad8f6fbb4e95a4123425a3b057" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ente Regional per la Lotta Anti-Anofelica in Sardinia Papers and Photographs</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1947/1976" type="inclusive">1947-1976</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="159fc58840c8367639f479a40f0e672c" label="mixed materials [A0000000118236]" type="box">1</container><container id="50e8ac60e67703b3100e978934677616" parent="159fc58840c8367639f479a40f0e672c" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="f333c54cb31094a3cb24a2046b99da4f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes Dr. Kerr's notes about the documents from 1976 when he donated his materials to the Rockefeller Archive Center.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="ca0160a31eb2bef61b3fb59972d1e555" level="file"><did><unittitle>Souvenir Portfolio from Cagliari, Sardinia</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1947-10/1947-10">1947 October</unitdate><physdesc id="5aebf0d26cf2164b10aafc0f06ff8280">Leather portfolio 12" x 8.5"</physdesc><container altrender="Half Legal Document Box" id="0ce40e92b1c83e8104b9ab084cfe6520" label="mixed materials [A0000000118259]" type="box">10</container><container id="36b181c1058e758cf51eedc2f9ab4f05" parent="0ce40e92b1c83e8104b9ab084cfe6520" type="folder">61</container></did><scopecontent id="6ae6d5880e6eb7ded164152cc311b829"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Received at ceremony when he left his role as Director of Ente Regionale per la Lotta Ani-Anofelica en Sargegna (ERLAAS)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="81482a1c53270dffecd72f2d784014a3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Illuminated Parchment Commending Work in Sardinia</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1947-10/1947-10">1947 October</unitdate><container altrender="Legal Document Box" id="94c4039aaa5108f45f13243f105f8968" label="mixed materials [A0000000118239]" type="box">3</container><container id="f312f02c5c6925e8b782affd1b82543e" parent="94c4039aaa5108f45f13243f105f8968" type="folder">31</container></did><scopecontent id="4b916fb4bafb960c2f9f5ed2a40111ed"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes Italian transcription and English translation.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="7ced23e39ffa280e3dc48dc120ae4f31" level="file"><did><unittitle>Yellow Fever Conference at the Institute for Medical Research, Kuala Lumpur</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1954-01/1954-01">1954 January</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="96dcacad55623bf6f4dd55a69e0d502e" label="Still Image [A0000000118236]" type="box">1</container><container id="7b53d5a2a03464de952caf5606be3c98" parent="96dcacad55623bf6f4dd55a69e0d502e" type="folder">7</container></did></c><c id="6229cb2ab46161ee68869a7186ce53a9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Poona, India</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1954/1955" type="inclusive">1954-1955</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="de0a71c456573215a7d4d617b10bf4c3" label="mixed materials [A0000000118236]" type="box">1</container><container id="f55bd119203b6a15c850122a7171220d" parent="de0a71c456573215a7d4d617b10bf4c3" type="folder">8</container></did></c><c id="5402f63c2c522f876a924f6be859ebb5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Speeches, Lectures, and Papers by J. Austin Kerr with Commentary from Kerr</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1933/1971" type="inclusive">1933-1971</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="34ef37430f410721130bb0c771fa7dba" label="mixed materials [A0000000118236]" type="box">1</container><container id="39f6dc2e20e3417919281d1941759572" parent="34ef37430f410721130bb0c771fa7dba" type="folder">9</container></did></c><c id="90afb5714d75a5ca713373139364592e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Laboratory Technics - Brazil</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1933-10/1933-10" type="inclusive">1933-1935</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="d829bd7b3ca1ae9ad1abb84b71b58ee8" label="mixed materials [A0000000118236]" type="box">1</container><container id="78823cfc4c34a8254cbe2287531aca7a" parent="d829bd7b3ca1ae9ad1abb84b71b58ee8" type="folder">10</container></did></c><c id="53a085b7dcee0414ede2a8ee97c65b10" level="file"><did><unittitle>A Neutralization Test for Yellow Fever Virus Antibodies Using Three-Day Old Mice Inoculated Subcutaneously - Unpublished Experiment</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1942/1970" type="inclusive">1942-1970</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="1560b66424cab4d33f7f3b4b1b16df22" label="mixed materials [A0000000118236]" type="box">1</container><container id="ba43efd249245f4d1153cd2ab4f898be" parent="1560b66424cab4d33f7f3b4b1b16df22" type="folder">11-13</container></did></c><c id="34bd2f1878cc373c9dd4cbc9324f4c3d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letter to Mother Regarding Trip to Northern Nigeria</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1931-02-02/1931-02-02">1931 February 2</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="c213cf55d945670bb6fc1172ac15135e" label="mixed materials [A0000000118236]" type="box">1</container><container id="51a3815cc858cdf259b9c1fbef96bf38" parent="c213cf55d945670bb6fc1172ac15135e" type="folder">14</container></did></c><c id="4333c016b24fcea88098676a87467523" level="file"><did><unittitle>Malaria, Yellow Fever, and Mosquito Research Notes, Reprints, and Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1933/1971" type="inclusive">1933-1971</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="f9b4dd4db5d18a8bf66faf18bd78ebcf" label="mixed materials [A0000000118237]" type="box">2</container><container id="f92016b2345a629f5357319f5b30b25e" parent="f9b4dd4db5d18a8bf66faf18bd78ebcf" type="folder">15</container></did></c><c id="e7f9cee722b1d8f71f7ad13157f9d8ef" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence - J. Austin Kerr and Fred L. Soper, Manila, Philippines</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1965-07/1966-08" type="inclusive">1965 July-1966 August</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="d64b8dcc37d814d9a16b98c8c72c1947" label="mixed materials [A0000000118237]" type="box">2</container><container id="aa22bba4d82ff8158ff869c3efa76a21" parent="d64b8dcc37d814d9a16b98c8c72c1947" type="folder">16</container></did></c><c id="a0ece5d31af37a8f1be31f1d48bdaa55" level="file"><did><unittitle>Revista Brasileira de Malariologia e Doenças Tropicais, Vol. XXV, N. 1/4</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1973/1974" type="inclusive">1973-1974</unitdate><langmaterial id="72acf430c28ea3dd0cde93728443258e">The paper is in English</langmaterial><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="520afed832ebcf851190375fcfd4bdfb" label="mixed materials [A0000000118237]" type="box">2</container><container id="ee8c941e9e8de561bde6be38ddab130e" parent="520afed832ebcf851190375fcfd4bdfb" type="folder">17-18</container></did><scopecontent id="b2eae667a0798aa38ddb10f645d3d8eb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes note from Kerr explaining his contributions to the paper - edited the text and prepared the tables</p></scopecontent></c><c id="cfc13296775f51b13a79fb006431958f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Working Papers, Drafts, and Notes</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1942/1965" type="inclusive">1942-1965</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="1170ead9967df4f2730e801bcf418b04" label="mixed materials [A0000000118237]" type="box">2</container><container id="5630a262473b3f3e00a435f47c85d66d" parent="1170ead9967df4f2730e801bcf418b04" type="folder">19</container></did></c><c id="433ada0d7ad6288814329c8dfe168331" level="file"><did><unittitle>Headshots</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1942/1971" type="inclusive">1942-1971</unitdate><physdesc id="90334ed437638702d3d178f80a653eb9">2 photographs</physdesc><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="fbb4ebb57a11b2d1ca556f46245ccd4b" label="Still Image [A0000000118237]" type="box">2</container><container id="da15b6585e328dab0a7f4b055bb68c7f" parent="fbb4ebb57a11b2d1ca556f46245ccd4b" type="folder">20</container></did><scopecontent id="585ab306c6dcb87ed1f6cf4f8bbed853"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>July 1971, age 71</p><p>1942, Rio de Janeiro</p></scopecontent></c><c id="51301b658fa475c5b6e34713fd20ba8c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rockefeller Foundation Staff Newsletter - J. A. Kerr Retires</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1965-04/1965-04">1965 April</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="97c58017fc9b733088de903313d36b9c" label="mixed materials [A0000000118237]" type="box">2</container><container id="7e5a5753ef56053d19503a51130f1d16" parent="97c58017fc9b733088de903313d36b9c" type="folder">21</container></did></c><c id="83b6dfcfd527a62594759d2a47daf84e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manuscript of Yellow Fever by J. Austin Kerr</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1960/1960">circa 1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="b5e2ed9c4654fd83035cd4d4c9c3623b" label="mixed materials [A0000000118237]" type="box">2</container><container id="6308db9d83c25470ef5a6082c183ab2a" parent="b5e2ed9c4654fd83035cd4d4c9c3623b" type="folder">22</container></did><scopecontent id="04ac1c9b0de69906d47d56fdd97f75df"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Original typescript submitted to Dr. LeRoy Sloan (editor of Tice-Sloan) Practice of Medicine Vol. IV - Infectious Diseases, pp. 1-31, Revision of 1960</p></scopecontent></c><c id="d9579ab855a7272bdd682529effa1577" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reports and Memos</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1956/1967" type="inclusive">1956-1967</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="858162fc4f59aaef5e5d1e652e6523fc" label="mixed materials [A0000000118237]" type="box">2</container><container id="b9e0889f9b9d99fd348cb6766cc64887" parent="858162fc4f59aaef5e5d1e652e6523fc" type="folder">23</container></did></c><c id="dded52ebe238b81774d6fa851579d1ce" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Eradication of Anopheles gambiae from Egypt by J. Austin Kerr</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="3f5762a632565e52bf44765941458cf3" label="mixed materials [A0000000118237]" type="box">2</container><container id="9eb57d80f7b488617cc1315a82f3bf63" parent="3f5762a632565e52bf44765941458cf3" type="folder">24</container></did></c><c id="efc7cfe2b85196a2a34ec93d3964757d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sylvan, or Jungle, Yellow Fever in Southern Brazil by J. Austin Kerr (manuscript)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1944-02-01/1944-02-01">1944 February 1</unitdate><container altrender="Legal Document Box" id="29735f38e6c3274ecb26326ff14e2016" label="mixed materials [A0000000118239]" type="box">3</container><container id="193718c398f396408d6194c9da134c21" parent="29735f38e6c3274ecb26326ff14e2016" type="folder">25-26</container></did></c><c id="ac34b7248f316cda3271febe095c807a" level="file"><did><unittitle>17D Vaccine Memos - Brazil</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1943/1943">1943</unitdate><container altrender="Legal Document Box" id="9de9b4d6eba9c32b49df7309f9abcce3" label="mixed materials [A0000000118239]" type="box">3</container><container id="60fbb6032ea7106426cc760da8ef85da" parent="9de9b4d6eba9c32b49df7309f9abcce3" type="folder">27</container></did><scopecontent id="15395ae1d92e75d04930a66fd02f6ef8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Memos:</p><p>1. A Review of the Efficacy of Vaccination Against Yellow Fever as Applied in 1938 and 1939 in Brazil</p><p>2. Further observations on the results obtained following the use of the "17DD high" substrain of 17D virus as vaccine</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="9f0dd4eb6b3662f187f4d5cc82b0d63b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Manuscripts</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.21 Cubic Feet</extent><extent altrender="carrier">3 letter document boxes, 4 legal document boxes, and 1 flat file folder</extent></physdesc><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927/1974" type="inclusive">1927-1974</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="9ffc9ac57161048b275152c0418dd41a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains 159 documents that Dr. John Austin Kerr referred to as his manuscript collection. The documents are numbered in order by date and primarily comprise his published works, memos, personal and professional correspondence, notes, writings from his wife Janet Kerr, and unpublished drafts. The manuscripts span from 1925-1970. Kerr sent the manuscripts in several shipments to the Rockefeller Archive Center in 1974. He included annotations and cataloging notes from that time. There is an index and table of contents in this series and the titles of individual numbered manuscripts are further described at the folder level.</p></scopecontent><acqinfo id="f276157b619272478ba6c610c8536fb4"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>The manuscripts were received in five packages in September and October 1974 by the Rockefeller Archive Center.</p></acqinfo><arrangement id="f6700ae9c1d0fa2d11c7449fe863763d"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged "as received" by the Rockefeller Archive Center. Kerr arranged many documents by folder size and that has contributed to the order of the documents in this series. Kerr created the manuscript numbering system in his retirement.</p></arrangement><c id="b3a542df8e55bc6ac5b4d19b7d85a87c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Prospect for Malaria Eradication in Thailand in 1965, Number 133</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1959/1967" type="inclusive">1959-1967</unitdate><container altrender="Legal Document Box" id="fc7c88fccdb49fe73d900276f5e57815" label="mixed materials [A0000000118239]" type="box">3</container><container id="ebfbeaffe377a5dd1637676b8b03f442" parent="fc7c88fccdb49fe73d900276f5e57815" type="folder">28-29</container></did></c><c id="dc0e7c27113a18be8774f635d8ef8dc0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manuscripts by J. Austin Kerr, Numbers 134-158</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1958/1974" type="inclusive">1958-1974</unitdate><container altrender="Legal Document Box" id="af561fcb7ee8d3464401e7abd034d0b3" label="mixed materials [A0000000118239]" type="box">3</container><container id="6c836a585f6874d6a4a216d81cad3082" parent="af561fcb7ee8d3464401e7abd034d0b3" type="folder">30, 32</container><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="0411e09463969f93444def9ed72af189" label="mixed materials [A0000000118240]" type="box">4</container><container id="c47c5356bc05a8cf6a7ed457903f2c12" parent="0411e09463969f93444def9ed72af189" type="folder">33-34</container></did><scopecontent id="3d80ba3a87dd4f0ec22e60248122f3ff"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Folder 30:</p><p>134 - Informe Mensal Statistico - Preliminar (Monthly Statistical Report - Preliminary) from the Campanha da Erradicação de Malaria (C.E.M.) to AID/Brazil, Devised and proposed by JAK, but probably never implemented</p><p>135 - Procedure for making the Definitive Quarterly Evaluation of the Status of the Malaria Eradication Operations of the Campanha de Erradicação de Malaria (CEM) of Brazil</p><p>Folder 32:</p><p>136 - Summary of the Aerial Reconnaissance of the Philippines, December 1965</p><p>137 - Trip to Kertessia problem area in Santa Catarina and Parana States, March 1966</p><p>138 - Kerring on Project Coordinator for the Malaria Eradication Program for USAID/Brazil, March 1966</p><p>140 - Comments by J. A. Kerr on Memo From John W. McDowell to Dr. Horace Delien, Dated July 8, 1958</p><p>142 - Epidemiological Evaluation of the Results of Malaria Eradication Operations in the Attack Phase, J. Austin Kerr, July 1, 1966</p><p>Folder 33:</p><p>143 - Instructions for Making Preliminary Investigation of a Malaria Case, July 1965</p><p>144 - End-of-Tour Report, Regional Malaria Advisor, Far East, April 20, 1965-August 15, 1966, August 3, 1966</p><p>145 - The Delimitation of the Malarious Areas of a South East Asian Country, August 4, 1966</p><p>146 - An Exercise in Planning, Programming, and Budgeting a National Malaria Eradication Program, August 11, 1966</p><p>147 - Ecology in Malaria Eradication, CDC Atlanta Lecture</p><p>148 - Trip Report of my Visit to the Area of the HCH Pilot Project in Guerrero State, Mexico, 1967 February</p><p>Folder 34:</p><p>149 - Report of Visit to the Plan Piloto De Ataque Integral (PPAI) of the CNEP, February 1-8, 1967</p><p>150 - The age and sex distribution of diagnosed malaria cases in relation to the age and sex distribution of the blood slides collected - Mexico, 1966-1967</p><p>151 (also labelled 143?) - Age and Sex Distribution in a one-week Sample of Blood Slides from the PRIAL (sp? Plan de Responsabilidad Individual en Areas and Limitadas), 1967 February</p><p>152 - Some Thoughts about the Global Malaria Eradication Campaign, August 27, 1967</p><p>153 - Travel Report on Visit to Malaria Eradication Pilot Projects in Mexico (October 1-13, 1967)</p><p>154 - Evaluation of Case Detection in the PRIAL (sp? Plan de Responsabilidad Individual en Areas and Limitadas) Area (Morelos State, Mexico) in 1966 and 1967, December 1967</p><p>155 - Public Health in Latin America, PSI, March 12, 1968</p><p>156 - The Eradication of Aedes Aegypti, December 14, 1968</p><p>157 - Mosquito-Borne Disease Around the World: Remarks at a Seminar of Mosquito Biology Training Program, Vector Biology Laboratory, University of Notre Dame, April 15, 1970</p><p>158 - Comments by JAK on The Place of Persistent Insecticides in the Control of Anthropod Vectors of Disease, Vector and Biological Control Division of WHO/Geneva, November 27, 1970</p></scopecontent></c><c id="1550f3956fa437e0087e281e9fe3a463" level="file"><did><unittitle>Topographic Maps to Accompany Ecology in Malaria Eradication, Lecture by J. Austin Kerr at Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1966-09-30/1966-09-30">1966 September 30</unitdate><container altrender="Medium Flat File Folder" id="a8d4e7f554c736c109de55791d78f1a6" label="mixed materials [A0000000118262]" type="folder">62</container></did><scopecontent id="430c26054c5b286229ff0867095e6ce9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Accompanied manuscript number 147 - Ecology in Malaria Eradication, CDC Atlanta Lecture</p></scopecontent></c><c id="4f17f9f54ff24b933b1969ea37c8c6f8" level="file"><did><unittitle>A Plan for Visualizing Case Detection Data in Order to Facilitate Analysis and Improve Reporting, Number 74</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1961-01-11/1961-01-11">1961 January 11</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="2a646e27b27ae634f6ba00d139064938" label="mixed materials [A0000000118240]" type="box">4</container><container id="ff15bf46a6803d047e688b2074ea256c" parent="2a646e27b27ae634f6ba00d139064938" type="folder">35</container></did><scopecontent id="1b9cd7be15a4b8fba08e8b6872f131bb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Written by JAK, but never formally approved by PASB/ME for general use by national malaria eradication services</p></scopecontent></c><c id="4c9e15b7f94654ad485b1394a629449c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manuscripts by J. Austin Kerr, Numbers 70-97</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1947/1966" type="inclusive">1947-1966</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="4ab4870be38fc22db9177da28ce4fb44" label="mixed materials [A0000000118240]" type="box">4</container><container id="fa61da97bcd55ce3b242ef6847d36dec" parent="4ab4870be38fc22db9177da28ce4fb44" type="folder">36-37</container></did><scopecontent id="56c5ca62842f6398c7431e25e28af898"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Folder 36:</p><p>70 - J. Austin Kerr's corrections to Yellow Fever in the Merck Manual of Diagnosis and Therapy, 1966</p><p>71 - Entomological Studies in Panama, May 22-July 22, 1960</p><p>72 - Some Thoughts About Malaria Eradication, March 1, 1960</p><p>73 - Shannon Trap, July 6, 1960</p><p>75 - Determination of local mean times of sunrise and sunset at any place in the world between latitudes 0 and 30N, 1961</p><p>76 - Outline for the Field Study of Suspect Chloroquine-Resistance in a P. falciparum Infection in Brazil, January 1962</p><p>77 - Malaria - Research Needs and Opportunities in Latin America, Some Background Information, 1962</p><p>78 - PAHO/ME Guide Lines for Entomological Studies, June 28, 1962</p><p>79 - Yellow Fever Studies, 1962?</p><p>80 - Plan Piloto de Larvicidas, or Pilot Project of Larviciding, 1962</p><p>81 - Bio-assay with Anopheles albimanus of DDT and Malathion Residues in Houses in El Salvador, Central America, Read on December 4, 1962 at the Annual Meeting of the Entomological Society of America, Phoenix, Arizona</p><p>82 - Mexico, 1947</p><p>83 - A note about the NET ANNUAL MALARIA REPRODUCTION (NAMR) RATE, March 21, 1963</p><p>84 - Some Thoughts About the Possibility That Mass Drug Administration May Be of Major Importance in the Area of Malaria Eradication in El Salvador, March 29, 1963</p><p>85 - Pruebas de Excito Repelencia, Instructivo para su ejecución utilizando las cajas de excito-repelencia, Modelo OPS, April 1963</p><p>Folder 37:</p><p>86 - A Sophisticated Malaria Eradication Program for Central America, July 2, 1963</p><p>87 - Primer Plan Decenal de Salud de El Salvador - Lucha Antipalúdica, May 31, 1963</p><p>88 - The Recognition and Delineation of Areas of Stable Malaria: An Operational Research Program, June 3, 1963</p><p>89 - On the Diagnosis and Treatment of the Malaria Eradication Problem Areas in El Salvador, Central America, August 3, 1963</p><p>90 - Fifth Annual Course in Military Entomology, Malaria Eradication Problems in Tropical America, August 8, 1963</p><p>91 - Preliminary Note on the Epidemiological Studies Made in El Salvador to Determine the Causes of the Failure of Residual Spraying to Interrupt the Transmission of Malaria, 1963</p><p>92 - Analysis of Malaria Parasite Densities, Falla, El Salvador, July 1961-September 1962, September 1963</p><p>93 - Procedure for Making the Epidemiological Evaluation of the Results of the Larviciding Demonstration in El Salvador, C. A., October 28, 1963</p><p>94 - Results of Recent Malariological Field Research in El Salvador, Central America, November 8, 1963</p><p>95 - Procedure for Making an Epidemiological Evaluation of any specific field operation intended to interrupt the transmission of malaria in a problem area, November 1963</p><p>96 - Malaria Eradication Studies in El Salvador I. Evaluation of Larviciding Procedures in Interruption of Transmission, December 4, 1963</p><p>97 - Malaria Eradication Studies in El Salvador II. Evaluation of the Excito-Repellency of Selected Insecticides Alone and Applied Over DDT Residues</p></scopecontent></c><c id="9e82dc0f1090872a8bea5301528df834" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proposed Trial in Mexico of the new Pan American Health Organization (PAHO)/Malaria Eradication (ME) Form 22: Resumen de Operaciones de Erradicacion en Mexico - Contained in Memo ME 2021-64 from JAK to Dr. da Silva, Chief of the Malaria Eradication Branch of PAHO, Number 109</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1964-11/1964-11">1964 November</unitdate><container altrender="Legal Document Box" id="669de6b263655d07fd0df32d09976a23" label="mixed materials [A0000000118254]" type="box">5</container><container id="86dfa046f964974c4e0dcb397b112141" parent="669de6b263655d07fd0df32d09976a23" type="folder">38</container></did></c><c id="20625eb4ce2d9b773f74095581c0313c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manuscripts by J. Austin Kerr, Number 98-108</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1964/1964">1964</unitdate><container altrender="Legal Document Box" id="76d0bec125b65ce48f1b351f0466c77a" label="mixed materials [A0000000118254]" type="box">5</container><container id="e54a145b66f0b5e4101b83435da0e360" parent="76d0bec125b65ce48f1b351f0466c77a" type="folder">39</container></did><scopecontent id="961f51321ce8439392d1f2e55a0a581a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>98 - Malaria Eradication Studies in El Salvador, III. Bio-Assay Studies of the Duration of Activity of Six Insecticides After Application to Mud Walls</p><p>99 - Notes on a meeting of AID personnel and the Assessment Team with Pacific Health Organization staff personnel to discuss the report of the: Central America Malaria Eradication Assessment Team, May 7, 1964</p><p>100 - Malaria case detection ratio charts</p><p>101 - Conference on Military Entomologists, Excito-Repellency of Anopheles Mosquitoes - A Phenomenon of Newly-Recognized Importance in Malaria Control and Eradication</p><p>102 - Lo Que Es Nuevo En La Erradicación de la Malaria, Trabajo presentado en el XV Congreso de Medicina - Guatemala City, 1964 November</p><p>103 - Field Trial of an Integrated Attack on Malaria in the Costa Chica of Guerrerp and Oaxaca, Mexico, July 28, 1964</p><p>104 - Memo to Dr. Wilbur Downs about trip to Mexico, December 7-14, January 2, 1964</p><p>105 - Aide Memoire, Objective of the Epidemiological Studies in Mexico, January 1964</p><p>106 - CNEP program of Estudios Especiales, January 22, 1964</p><p>107 - On the Use of Ratio Paper for Charting Malaria Case Detection Data, October 28, 1964</p><p>108 - Annual Meeting at CNEP Headquarters in Mexico City, November 19-21, 1964</p></scopecontent></c><c id="6999ea963cb7f06bc5d4446dcbddc8da" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sylvan, or Jungle, Yellow Fever in Southern Brazil - 1932-1942 by J. Austin Kerr (Incomplete Copy, Original Typescript sent to Archives), Number 40</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1943/1943">1943</unitdate><container altrender="Legal Document Box" id="b129a15ff0546b8019ef18f9a97a7255" label="mixed materials [A0000000118254]" type="box">5</container><container id="54bc72a2158a1d0900c81a0c1486c5f1" parent="b129a15ff0546b8019ef18f9a97a7255" type="folder">40</container></did></c><c id="a669435915ff0c1bfa6d81a090edce45" level="file"><did><unittitle>Yellow Fever Research Service Ministry of Education and Health Brazil, Annual Report for 1942 - Draft, Number 41</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1942/1974" type="inclusive">1942-1974</unitdate><container altrender="Legal Document Box" id="1fdba2788cd8ef4fb582af5e2af3b4d1" label="mixed materials [A0000000118254]" type="box">5</container><container id="e4835dab941144f25cafd6a7d82a5559" parent="1fdba2788cd8ef4fb582af5e2af3b4d1" type="folder">41</container><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="608381275e5d3237c3c2141e7b5868f9" label="mixed materials [A0000000118255]" type="box">6</container><container id="19a8d180361e42efd5550f7a3f03d799" parent="608381275e5d3237c3c2141e7b5868f9" type="folder">42</container></did></c><c id="acf3763df3e615a5cbf68d37100bc347" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manuscripts by J. Austin Kerr, Numbers 1-39</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1927/1970" type="inclusive">1927-1970</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="6e86830fc67695bfc0bd5b9a6df56488" label="mixed materials [A0000000118255]" type="box">6</container><container id="d48222e0147ba7d9ed5d213fe02e205b" parent="6e86830fc67695bfc0bd5b9a6df56488" type="folder">43-45</container></did><scopecontent id="d8eb729e012b560e5707fbd0777eef6e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Folder 43:</p><p>1 - Malaria Survey of Byne's Plantation, Lee County, Georgia, September 1925</p><p>2 - On the epidemiology of aegypti-transmitted yellow fever in rural Northeast Brazil, Parahyba, September 26, 1927</p><p>3 - Report of the Comissão de Febre Amarella, 1970</p><p>4 - Report of Inspection of aedes aegypti control work in Natal, March 3-13, 1928</p><p>5 - Notes on my Trip to the Paraguayan Chaco, September 17-27, 1928</p><p>6 - Comunicado Para la Prensa de la Campafia Sanitaria, November 1928</p><p>7 - Campana Sanitaria - Departamento Nacional De Higiene Y Asistencia Publica Resumen De Los Informes Del Quinquenio, 1924-1928, 1929</p><p>8 - Inspection of Macahe, Yellow Fever, May 12th to 14th, 1929</p><p>9 - Memorandum Regarding the Occurrence of Yellow Fever in Sao Salvador, Bahia, 1901 to 1909, August 1929</p><p>10 - History of illness of J. Austin Kerr (yellow fever), Resident at Pensao Edith, Working at Yellow Fever Lab, Montserrat, Bahia, Brazil, August-September 1929</p><p>11 - Yellow Fever in North Brasil, 1922-1929, 1930</p><p>12 - Preservation of Yellow Fever Virus in Monkey Blood Dried in the Frozen State, undated</p><p>13 - Annual Report 1930, West African Yellow Fever Commission (Portion Written by J. Austin Kerr)</p><p>14 - Letter to J. Austin Kerr's mother about trip to Northern Nigeria, Lagos, February 2, 1931</p><p>15 - Sketches from My Andian Notebook by J. Austin Kerr, 1932</p><p>Folder 44:</p><p>16 - Recent Research in Yellow Fever (Notes for lecture at U. of C. Dept. Bacteriology (N. P. Hudson), January 21, 1932</p><p>17 - The Epidemiological Importance of the Experimental Vectors of Yellow Fever in West Africa, Henry Beeuwkes and J. Austin Kerr, From the Laboratory of the West African, Yellow Fever Commission of the Rockefeller Foundation at Lagos, Nigeria, 1933</p><p>18 - Memorandum to Doctor Soper, Recommendations regarding larvicidal oil, May 23, 1933</p><p>19 - Memorandum to Dr. Sawyer on the Possibility of Substituting Groups of Six Mice by Groups of Five Mice in the Routine Testing of SERA by the Protection Test, Rio de Janeiro, April 15, 1935</p><p>20 - Proposed Field Investigation looking toward the discovery of an animal reservoir of yellow fever virus, Rio, August 12, 1935</p><p>21 - Draft - Instructions for Numbering and Documenting Native Monkeys, Rio, November 16, 1935</p><p>22 - PanAmerican Medical Society Meeting, Viscerotomy Discussion by J. A. Kerr, Rio, Nov (?) 1935</p><p>23 - Criação de Camundongos Laboratório da Bahia, January 1936</p><p>24 - Memorandum Regarding Mass Vaccination Against Jungle Yellow Fever, Londrina, Parana, March 7, 1936</p><p>25 - Examination by JAk at Johns Hopkins of sections from 15 human livers, originally diagnoses as having Midzonal Necrosis, seeking for lesions that could be confused with those of yellow fever, May 1936</p><p>26 - Instrucciones Para La Vacunación Contra La Fiebre Amarilla, June 8, 1938</p><p>27 - What to Bring to Brazil, Janet Kerr, 1940</p><p>28 - Memorandum - Dr. J. A. Kerr and Dr. F. L. Soper - A Hypothetical Explanation of the Epidemiology of Jungle Yellow Fever, June 9, 1940</p><p>29 - Yellow Fever and its Control, March 1941</p><p>30 - Suggestions - Memorandum from Miss Louise Kieninger to the Hospitalization Sub-Committee of the American Society of Rio de Janeiro regarding nursing in the Federal District, March 1942</p><p>
Folder 45:</p><p>31 - Memorandum Re: Nursing in Brazil, July 18, 1942</p><p>32 - Yellow Fever Research Service Special Report for the Period July 1, 1941-June 30, 1942 - Copy</p><p>33 - On "Field Investigations" - Draft, Rio, 1942</p><p>34 - Nursing in Brazil, Rio, 1942</p><p>35 - A Theoretical Discussion of How Mice are Immunized, March 1943</p><p>36 - Yellow Fever "B" Thoughts on March 28, 1943</p><p>37 - Narrative Report for January to June 1943</p><p>38 - Memorandum - Further Observations on the Results Obtained Following the Use of the "17DD High" Substrain of 17D Virus as Vaccine, December 1, 1943</p><p>39 - A Review of the Efficacy of Vaccination Against Yellow Fever as Applied in 1938 and 1939 in Brazil, December 1, 1943</p></scopecontent></c><c id="4b22db8c864d0040d2c3e8887eea7df2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manuscripts of J. Austin Kerr, Table of Contents and Index</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="07af9432855fc0274abe45e6c7301541" label="mixed materials [A0000000118255]" type="box">6</container><container id="b57f8b74544a5f24b1cb8fe429ea4261" parent="07af9432855fc0274abe45e6c7301541" type="folder">46</container></did></c><c id="2e7e9ea929477c88c54bef0006b435af" level="file"><did><unittitle>J. Austin Kerr Manuscript Number 159 Entitled The Rise and Fall of Global Malaria Eradication</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1955/1974" type="inclusive">1955-1974</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="d0cc3aba9e3694322afeea7f31667497" label="mixed materials [A0000000118255]" type="box">6</container><container id="1f8de3b8463b1e6dc801a297f6790f3d" parent="d0cc3aba9e3694322afeea7f31667497" type="folder">47</container><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="7f17734eeb33f2e163b6db120fa7f0a6" label="mixed materials [A0000000118256]" type="box">7</container><container id="bbe80d1d30b062ca833b05f9b1199883" parent="7f17734eeb33f2e163b6db120fa7f0a6" type="folder">48</container></did></c><c id="b583bab80cb9c29c228aa7bf2d60fe53" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manuscripts by J. Austin Kerr, Numbers 42-68</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1944/1959" type="inclusive">1944-1959</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="5a82cf51a50cad26e3df8496ff5df96c" label="mixed materials [A0000000118256]" type="box">7</container><container id="6084ed20a2cb4dd72f316a9b69c3fd8e" parent="5a82cf51a50cad26e3df8496ff5df96c" type="folder">49</container></did><scopecontent id="3dd319e0a9404ebfa2e8efd77f1ad435"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>42 - "Jaundice" at Lemoore Army Air Field, May 3, 1944</p><p>43 - A Working Hypothesis Regarding Infective Hepatitis, Or So-Called "Acute Catarrhal Jaundice," as a Virus Disease of World-Wide Distribution and Almost Universal Incidence, J. Austin Kerr, May 6, 1944</p><p>44 - Research Laboratory, Berkeley - Infective Hepatitis in Vacaville, Solano County (California), J.A. Kerr and H. L Wynns, May 8, 1944</p><p>45 - The Working Methods of the Gambiae Eradication Service by J. A. Kerr (Speech read by JAK celebrating the eradication of Anopheles gambiae from Egypt broadcast on Cairo radio), January 4, 1946</p><p>48 - Standard Technic for the Quantitative Hemagglutinin Inhibition Tests with Influenza Virus Pattern Test of Salk - with Chicken Red Cells, February 17, 1949</p><p>49 - Memo to RMT (?) - Subject: Studies on Mengo Virus, May 6, 1951</p><p>50 - Thoughts on a Polio Vaccine, May 5, 1951</p><p>51 - A hypothesis regarding an extra-human reservoir of poliomyelitis virus, May 31, 1951</p><p>52 - Vote of Thanks (Inauguration of Virus Research Centre), February 4, 1953</p><p>53 - Zoology in Medical Research, August 20, 1953</p><p>54 - Virus Research Rotary Club, Poona, September 21, 1953</p><p>55 - Filterable Viruses - Lecture Given at the College of Military Engineering, Kirkee, March 16. 1954</p><p>56 - Status Report on Yellow Fever in Middle America, Pan American Sanitary Bureau, March 1956?</p><p>57 - World Health Day "Destroy Disease-Carrying Insects" - The Last Refuge of Yellow Fever by J. Austin Kerr, April 7, 1956</p><p>58 - Seminario Sobre Cuarentena Internacional, Veracruz, Ver. July 26-28, 1956 - La Fiebre Amarilla Como Problema Sanitario Internacional</p><p>59 - Status of Yellow Fever in Middle America by J. Austin Kerr, 1956</p><p>60 - Manual of Operations for an Aedes Aegypti Eradication Service, Part Two Manuals of Instruction, Edition of March 1957, Pan American Sanitary Bureau (Part I was never prepared)</p><p>61 - Jungle Yellow Fever and Related Virus Diseases by J. Austin Kerr, Staff Member of the Rockefeller Foundation on loan to the Pan American Sanitary Bureau, October 1, 1957</p><p>62 - AMRO-57 - Studies of Jungle Yellow Fever and Other Virus Infections, Highlights of Seven Weeks in South America, May 1958</p><p>63 - Note on the Use of Complement-Fixation to Identify the Antigen of Yellow Fever Virus in the Blood Serum of Acutely Ill Patients -- A Proposed New Diagnostic Method for Yellow Fever in Man, February 9, 1959</p><p>64 - The Dilemma of Insecticide-Resistance, February 1958</p><p>65 - A Discussion of the Problem Arising When a Species of Anopheles is Found to be Resistant to a Given Insecticide, February 13, 1959</p><p>66 - Resistance of Anopheles Mosquitoes to Insecticides, Summary of remarks by J. Austin Ker, MD at the Third Public Health ICA Technical Conference, Lima, Peru, March 3, 1959</p><p>67 - Instrucciones Suplementaria para determinar la Susceptibilidad o Resistencia de los mosquitos Anopheles Adultos a los Insecticidas por medio del Equipo de Prueba de la Organización Mundial de la Salud para mosquitos adultos, March 1958</p><p>68 - Visualization of the Results of Evaluation Operations, Guatemala City, August 25, 1959</p></scopecontent></c><c id="d8fd733ef976eaa712a9885e09f03894" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Eradication of Anopheles Gambiae from Egypt by J. Austin Kerr, M.D., Number 46</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1946/1970" type="inclusive">1946-1970</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="7701a2d2374937e42be631ef200b8de0" label="mixed materials [A0000000118256]" type="box">7</container><container id="006ba0c442aeebc174c82f706d25a41f" parent="7701a2d2374937e42be631ef200b8de0" type="folder">50</container></did></c><c id="c074ae4f368c89616588576ec6faa3cf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reports - Gambiae Eradication Service Egypt, Number 47</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1944/1945" type="inclusive">1944-1945</unitdate><container altrender="Legal Document Box" id="144792fabd029231db443e0ac9fd124c" label="mixed materials [A0000000118257]" type="box">8</container><container id="80219b9ece169b9b5607ff9c68f75192" parent="144792fabd029231db443e0ac9fd124c" type="folder">51-53</container></did><scopecontent id="47d3597ece46b620bb1e98cbfc80aebd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>J. Austin Kerr was director July 15, 1944-December 31, 1945, Quarterly Reports, Annual Reports, Appendix</p></scopecontent></c><c id="c188f6bbf2f20b33c94518fd050dceb0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Global Medicine Lectures, Number 69</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1960/1965" type="inclusive">1960-1965</unitdate><container altrender="Legal Document Box" id="bb62ed318f43e3fa1f4c27969936434b" label="mixed materials [A0000000118257]" type="box">8</container><container id="1ba3e3ea30d15e948614a90e5b1c47c8" parent="bb62ed318f43e3fa1f4c27969936434b" type="folder">54</container></did><scopecontent id="33ecb77b67a35e42a094df5d4f33b535"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Global Medicine Lectures by JAK on: A-Malaria; B-Yellow Fever Epidemiology; and C-Yellow Fever Control, given annually 1960-1965 at the Walter Reed Army Institute of Research, Washington, D.C., with pertinent correspondence and some supporting documentation</p></scopecontent></c><c id="9b26cfef5a9387486999062a6606f8cd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Manuscripts by J. Austin Kerr, Numbers 110-132</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate><container altrender="Legal Document Box" id="2a39908e20815a35412e1af256208678" label="mixed materials [A0000000118257]" type="box">8</container><container id="b99ef8f637adac8be7f1b6250e107c1e" parent="2a39908e20815a35412e1af256208678" type="folder">55-56</container><container altrender="Legal Document Box" id="da8d30d5ef8d5fe8a7fc0ee6383b1f8f" label="mixed materials [A0000000118258]" type="box">9</container><container id="b0f20154908f8c8bcc72e92035f37bd3" parent="da8d30d5ef8d5fe8a7fc0ee6383b1f8f" type="folder">57-59</container></did><scopecontent id="3c864271ab7a5967c3ed7c6e95128d5f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Folder 55:</p><p>110 - Two master tracings for summarizing field data collected during the "Synoptic Studies" and "ozalid sepia" tracings on which the data for each of the study areas were recorded as they were obtained, 1965</p><p>111 - Spanish translation of "Synoptic studies of Malaria in El Salvador" by Rachou, Lyons, Moura-Lima, and JAK, January 1965</p><p>112 - Memo - Graphic Representation and Visualization of Results of Malaria Case Detection Operations PAHO/ME XYZ, circa February 1965</p><p>113 - Observaciones sobre la vacuna de virus 17D para fiebre amarilla aplicada por escarificación cutánea, Hernando Groot y Augusto Gast-Galvis, February 1965 with comments from January 21, 1971</p><p>114 - A Hard Look at Malaria Eradication Operations by J. Austin Kerr, March 16, 1965</p><p>Folder 56:</p><p>115 - Rejected Manuscript entitled Bio-Assays with Anopheles Albimanus of DDT and Malathion Residues on the Interior Wall Surfaces of Houses in El Salvador, Central America by J. Austin Kerr et al, February 5, 1965</p><p>116 - Malaria prevalence in the Philippines 1961-1964, by quarters, separately for the Attack and Consolidation Phase areas, May 3, 1965 (reflective comments from August 16, 1974)</p><p>Folder 57:</p><p>117 - Evaluation of the results of the operations of the Philippine Malaria Eradication Program (N.M.E.S.) in the nine years 1955-1963. By J. Austin Kerr, dated May 28, 1965</p><p>Folder 58:</p><p>118 - The Philosophy of Malaria Eradication by J. Austin Kerr, 1965</p><p>119 - Malaria Eradication Training Center - Manila, Philippines Special Course in Malaria Entomology, Review of Entomological Problems in the Americas Remarks by J. Austin Kerr on June 9, 1965</p><p>120 - For Use at Session B, June 18, 1965(?), Research - Outline, Four Resurrections of Research by J. Austin Kerr</p><p>121 - A New Procedure for Visualizing the Results of Malaria Case Detection Operations by J. Austin Kerr, June 28, 1965</p><p>121A - Sequential Changes in Norms for Malaria Case Detection in a Malaria Eradication Operation by J. Austin Kerr, July 13, 1965</p><p>122 - The Seven Deadliest Sins of a National Malaria Eradication Service, July 29, 1965</p><p>123 - Paper on the Use of the Ratio Scale to Visualize the Results of Malaria Eradication Operations, June 11, 1965</p><p>Folder 59:</p><p>124 - Appraisal of the Malaria Eradication Training Center, Manila by J. Austin Kerr, November 1965, supporting documents attached</p><p>125 - A "Working Paper" on The Need for a Field Demonstration Area of the METC, Manila by J. Austin Kerr - November 10, 1965</p><p>126 - Memo - Recommendations regarding the Field Training Area of the Malaria Eradication Training Center/Manila, November 17, 1965</p><p>127 - Comments on the Report of the Malaria Eradication Services/Philippines, FY 1965, December 1, 1965</p><p>128 - Christmas message from the Janet and J. Austin Kerr, 1965, Manila, Philippines</p><p>129 - Comments on the 1964 Evaluation on the Viet Nam Eradication Project, J. Austin Kerr, April 26, 1965, Manila</p><p>130 - Graphic Summary of Malaria Prevalence in Seven Provinces of Viet Nam, 1962-1965, August 1965</p><p>131 - Suggestions for a Malaria Control Program by the Government of Viet Nam - First Draft, dated October 24, 1965</p><p>132 - Memo - Re-evaluation of the malaria situation in Laos as per AID to 78 to Manila, dated July 24, 1965</p></scopecontent></c><c id="8e4f3690ab81b193156daf3ede180b0f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Appendix Z to Manuscript #117</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate><container altrender="Legal Document Box" id="842aa3ec6064604a97996b57a6a13fa9" label="mixed materials [A0000000118258]" type="box">9</container><container id="e4891543fed1b0f6a9b94b28343708b1" parent="842aa3ec6064604a97996b57a6a13fa9" type="folder">60</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
