<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA1433.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Population Council records, International Programs, Accession 2, RG 2, Series 13</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Population Council records, International Programs, Accession 2, RG 2, Series 13 <num>FA1433</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-09-02 20:05:15 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="series">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Population Council records, International Programs, Accession 2, RG 2, Series 13</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" source="naf">Population Council</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA1433</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">17.05 Cubic Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">29 legal-size document boxes and 9 letter-size document boxes.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1963/1986" type="inclusive">1963-1986</unitdate>
    <langmaterial id="cc1add12153df0720b77eeb070d54885">English</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="35ae6aed05c7ca102d1467f5366c95b1">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Series 13: International Programs is arranged in the following subseries:</p>
<p>
Subseries 1: Infant Feeding Study
</p>
<p>
Subseries 2: Field Staff File
</p>
<p>
Subseries 3: Routine Administration and Lippes Loops Files
</p>
<p>
Within each subseries the records remain in original order.
</p>  </arrangement>
  <accessrestrict id="c20afc3ba1d490ac1b44ea29ed9c5b83">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Personnel files are restricted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="212a257f24c567c27341c5476b099631">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Records document the Population Council's International Programs (IP), and an earlier incarnation - the Technical Assistance Division, primarily focusing in the areas of the Infant Feeding Study and Lippes Loops. Records include but are not limited to: program files and reviews, proposals, reports, surveys, site visits, field reports, articles, field staff correspondence, general administrative records, and a small selection of donor files.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="8db354a93ee7f68c3363dd30a320ab1f">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The Population Council retains title, copyright and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them.</p><p>The Rockefeller Archive Center has authority to grant permission to cite and publish material from the collection. The Population Council retains the right to prior consent with respect to any reproduction or extensive quotation of the records for publication.</p><p>Reproduction/duplication of archival items is routinely provided in accordance with "fair use". If the RAC does not hold copyright for an archival collection, or items within a collection, it is the users responsibility to contact the copyright holder, or make a fair effort to do so, prior to publication.</p>  </userestrict>
  <bioghist id="82c9a20dff944bbd0909ed47541e699e">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The Population Council was founded by John D. Rockefeller 3rd in 1952 to undertake "significant activities in the broad field of population." Its goal has been to bring about a reduction in the number of births that occur in the world. In its early years, the business of the Population Council was conducted by a Demographic Division and a Biomedical Division. Through its Demographic Division, the Council sought to document what it conceived to be an overpopulation problem threatening many areas of the world. To accomplish this purpose, the Division facilitated research on the economic, social, and psychological factors which affect the growth and decline of human population. This Council-assisted research effort was conducted not only by staff of the Demographic Division but also by other institutions and scholars, some of whom received Council grants and fellowships and some of whom received informal advice and consultation on how to design and execute studies.</p>

<p>The Biomedical Division, which, beginning in 1959, occupied a laboratory at The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (now The Rockefeller University), has conducted pure and applied research on plant, animal, and human reproductive physiology and on the development, the physiological action, and the safety and effectiveness of contraceptive methods. The Council facilitated similar types of medical research by non-Council scientists at other institutions by giving grants and fellowships for such research. The Council's biomedical research and its support for research by non-Council scientists were instrumental in the development of the modern intrauterine coil and the birth control pill.</p>

<p>In about 1960, the scope of Population Council activities expanded. The Council began to render practical and technical aid to foreign nations. Beginning in that year, the Demographic Division, in addition to supervising research, became involved in Pakistan's family planning program, extending practical and technical aid in organizing and running a national family planning program. By 1964 the Council's Demographic Division had assisted in organizing family planning programs in South Korea, Taiwan, Thailand, Tunisia, and Turkey. In that year, the Council created the Technical Assistance Division. This division, in ensuing years, continued the assistance of the Council in the countries where it had already become involved and also helped start and run programs in India, Morocco, the Philippines, and Puerto Rico.</p>

<p>An underlying aim of the Council's grant programs has been to encourage the development and growth of institutions that would promote family planning programs. To this end, the Council has given grants and advice to various universities and research centers for starting and upgrading programs for demographic and biomedical training and research programs; has assisted the United Nations to set up and expand regional Demographic Training and Research Centres in Bombay, India, Santiago, Chile, and Cairo, Egypt; has worked with the Ford Foundation on family planning programs in Pakistan, India, and North Africa.</p>

<p>In addition to rendering technical aid and sponsoring research, the Council has undertaken several complementary public relations efforts. To reach the general populations of the United States and of foreign nations, Council officers have worked to inform the mass media about population issues and to encourage magazine articles, movies, and books dealing with population matters. Council officers and representatives have also made trips and prepared reports to convince various foreign government leaders of the importance and the desirability of promulgating family planning programs. In addition, Council officers participated in and helped organize and finance conferences for demographers and medical scientists active in population work.</p>

<p>The Population Council has obtained its financial support through large contributions. The Ford and Rockefeller Foundations and the Rockefeller Brothers Fund have been the principal institutional supporters of the Council. John D. Rockefeller 3rd has been the single most significant individual backer of the Council.</p>  </bioghist>
  <userestrict id="bfa0405196a8a20121dc8f0ecb4f4e23">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Collection is open for research. If accessing the records of the Population Council, I understand that I am given access to these records on condition that I will not identify by name, either in my research notes or in publication or recording, the names of individuals who received or apparently received medical diagnoses and/or treatments, whose case(s), may be documented or mentioned by personal name in the Population Council records.</p>  </userestrict>
  <dsc>