<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="https://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>1501.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">William and Flora Hewlett Foundation records</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the William and Flora Hewlett Foundation records <num>FA1501</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>Telephone: 914-631-4505</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 914-631-6017</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-01-01 05:03:40 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>William and Flora Hewlett Foundation records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" source="naf">William &amp; Flora Hewlett Foundation</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA1501</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/resources/12867</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">32.42 Cubic Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">66 containers</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/2014" type="inclusive">1966-2014</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <acqinfo id="197f4156d4191394323ac1a3a8a1cf7c">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated by the William and Flora Hewlett Foundation in 2019.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="2b523c5897a7550a4dae3d2b19acd40f">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. </p><p>Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.</p><p>When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="4eed411157c838a9c1a949de945e7e93">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The William and Flora Hewlett Foundation retains legal title, copyright and literary property rights. The Rockefeller Archive Center has authority to grant permission to cite and publish material from the collection. Permission to publish extensive excerpts, or material in its entirety, will be referred to the Hewlett Foundation.</p>  </userestrict>
  <arrangement id="403619e7797dd55c5b1b1d4a898d3515">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The William and Flora Hewlett Foundation records are arranged as received, represented by following series: </p><p>Series 1: President's Office, 1967-2014</p><p>Series 2: Photographs, 1980-2005</p><p>Series 3: Published Material, 1966-2016</p><p>Series 4: Conflict Resolution Program, 1984-2004</p><p>Series 5: Oral History Project, 1995-2004</p><p>Series 6: Annual Reports, 1966-2008</p><p>Series 7: Board of Directors Meeting Dockets, 2000-2014</p><p>Series 8: Grant Products, 1999-2012</p><p>Series 9: San Diego School Reform, 1998-2004</p><p>Series 10: Bay Area School Reform Collaborative (BASRC), 1994-2004</p><p>Series 11: San Francisco Bay Area Performance Space, 1986-2012</p><p>Series 12: Audio Visual Material, 1998-2012</p><p>Series 13: Oversize Material, 2005-2012</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="e4e8ddad5b38a5bc5f33fec5c0f094dd">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>William (Bill) Hewlett was a founding partner of the Hewlett-Packard Company, which was started in 1939. Longtime supporters of environmental and social-issue non-profit groups as well as the performing arts, he and his wife, Flora, formed the Hewlett Foundation on November 27, 1966. The Foundation began with only three trustees: Bill and Flora Hewlett along with their son, Walter. In the early days, it was very much a small family foundation, with many of the giving considerations reflecting the Hewletts' personal philanthropic giving and decisions being made during meetings in the family living room.</p><p>The Hewlett Foundation hired its first executive director, John May, in 1974. May had formerly been the director of the San Francisco Foundation in which Bill Hewlett had long been involved. Under May's leadership the Foundation formalized the application review procedure and expanded its board leadership outside of the Hewlett family. He also increased the hiring of a variety of consultants to assist the Foundation in its different program areas. One of these consultants, Ted Lobman, became the Foundation's first full-time program officer, with a focus on education. One of the key tenets, both of the Hewlett-Packard Company and the Hewlett Foundation, was a management style that became known as the "HP Way." This management style emphasized an informal work environment in which the working groups were given independence and latitude in decision making as well as a focus on the interpersonal connections, stressing that coworkers should care for one another and their communities. Though there was no formal system of programs, under the leadership of Bill and Flora Hewlett, the Foundation focused on five main issues: healthcare, environment, population, education, and quality of life in the San Francisco Bay Area.</p><p>Flora Hewlett died in 1977 and upon her death, almost the entirety of her estate went to the Foundation, increasing its endowment exponentially. At the same time, Bill Hewlett stepped away from day-to-day management at Hewlett-Packard and stepped into the role of board chair at the Foundation while Roger Heyns took over the role of president of the Foundation from John May. During his tenure at the Foundation, he reshaped it from the small family foundation that made decisions based on organizations known to the president and board members to a large foundation that used a formal procedure and professional staff to seek out programs that were most deserving in the targeted areas that the Foundation chose to support. Under Heyns the Foundation ended their program support for healthcare (he felt the field was too amorphous and already being well funded by other foundations) and expanded into funding in the area of conflict resolution and began a program on US-Mexico relations.</p><p>In 1993, David Gardner took over as president of the Foundation upon Roger Heyns' retirement. As HP stock increased in price, Gardner developed an investment strategy that proved highly successful for the Foundation and led to rapid growth in the Foundation's assets. Under Gardner's leadership, term limits by program staff were also formalized. The Foundation had long encouraged term limits for the Foundation to increase new ideas among staff while trying to avoid having program officers be too overly connected to grantees. This process was formalized under Gardner, limiting program officer's terms to six years (with a possible three years extension given by the board). This was extended to eight years in 2005.</p><p>Paul Brest took over leadership in the Foundation in 2000, and the following year Bill Hewlett passed away. Upon Hewlett's death, the assets of the Foundation almost tripled, making it the fifth largest private foundation in the country. Paul Brest remained as Foundation president until 2012. Under his leadership the Foundation continued its existing grant making while expanding its initiatives to include work in the areas of climate change and the use of open education resources. The Foundation also merged its programs on global development and population (approximately 2008) and moved into new headquarters in Menlo Park, California.</p><p>Larry Kramer, a former dean at Stanford Law School, took over as Foundation president in 2012. Under his leadership, the Foundation has added to new time-bound initiatives examining the challenges of cybersecurity and addressing the problem of the increasing polarization in politics and its role on the effectiveness of the U.S. government. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="39056b4ae45d69df7e039c00eb7c390e">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The William and Flora Hewlett Foundation records documents the foundation's early history and programs. The majority of the material is biographical in nature, with only a small amount of grant-related records which can be found in the Grant Products series.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Teachers--Training of</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Educational evaluation -- California -- San Diego (Calif.)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">English language -- Study and teaching</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Equality -- Education -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education -- Standards</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Economic development</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Economic policy</subject>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Global Development</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">United States -- Relations -- Latin America</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Performing arts</subject>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Population</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">San Diego (Calif.)</geogname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc>