<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA1572.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Population Council records, Accession 2, RG 2</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Population Council records, Accession 2, RG 2 <num>FA1572</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>Telephone: 914-631-4505</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 914-631-6017</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-01-01 03:55:12 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="recordgrp">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Population Council records, Accession 2, RG 2</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" source="naf">Population Council</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA1572</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">386 Cubic Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1989" type="inclusive">1952-1989</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="fa6688e658e4cf2a3fdb3f6f8617cb7c">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p><p>If accessing the records of the Population Council, I understand that I am given access to these records on condition that I will not identify by name, either in my research notes or in publication or recording, the names of individuals who received or apparently received medical diagnoses and/or treatments, whose case(s), may be documented or mentioned by personal name in the Population Council records.</p><p>Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <arrangement id="be1a3cd007f712b7008c734672cebffd">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Record Group 2 consists of 16 open series of records (Series 1-4, and Series 5-17).</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="edeec6d9f6b7cec6d667191936256ce2">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The records of the Population Council document its day-to-day operation as an organization that, among other activities, evaluated and administered grants, sponsored conferences of scholars in the field of family planning and demography, and provided advice to individuals, private institutions, and governments concerned with population. There is some material relating to major policy decisions of the Council. There are also letters and reports from scientists involved in medical research and from Council staff members and representatives involved in family planning activities abroad.</p><p>Accession 2, most of which is dated after 1966, consists primarily of material received by the Center in April 1977 and later.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
