<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA1565.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Institute of International Education records</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Institute of International Education records <num>FA1565</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>Telephone: 914-631-4505</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 914-631-6017</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-03-13 17:58:11 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Institute of International Education records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" source="naf">Institute of International Education (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA1565</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">115.94 Cubic Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">115.94 cu. ft. including 650+ reels of unique microforms</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1919/2017" type="inclusive">1919-2017</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="77dd1de7082464e36feb4edccc3eb808">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Arranged in 4 record groups, by record type.  The record groups and associated numbers are representative solely of when the materials were processed by RAC, and do not imply an original order of the records. Additional finding aids are created as records are processed and open for research.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="987e6e61ab0cd0db73479dbe341dbd75">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The Institute of International Education (IIE) was established in 1919 by Nobel Prize winners Nicholas Murray Butler, Elihu Root and Stephen Duggan, Sr. The founders sought greater understanding among nations, primarily through the establishment of international educational exchange between United States institutes of higher education and foreign actors interested in formulating and developing active and ongoing educational understanding. As the Institute grew, developed and matured, it has continued to focus in the area of scholars exchange, as well as education services, international development and leadership training.</p><p>IIE initially focused on facilitating student, faculty, and teacher exchanges with European countries. In the 1930s their scope expanded beyond Europe to include exchanges between the Soviet Union and Latin America. During this period the Institute also established the Emergency Committee to Aid Displaced German Scholars which later expanded to include scholars fleeing facist Spain and Italy as well. In the 1950s this program was utilized to support Hungarian refugees. In the early 2000s IIE Trustees together with other donors endowed the Scholar Rescue Fund (SRF).</p><p>Following WWII, the Institute helped establish the Association of International Educators (NAFSA) and the Council on International Education Exchange (CIEE) for which they serve to administer the CIEE faculty component and the graduate student component of the Fulbright program, which continues to today as the Institute's largest program.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="2e1f046535f1e51206b62f895a2fbf45">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged materials are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="b3bb26a12ae33582db61a08b2812c8c4">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection includes documentation of grants, fellowships, administration, historical files, photographic files and publications.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="8e686c1c3b75b1941011c1f774eb2c0f">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>The Council for International Exchange of Scholars (CIES) collection is available at the University of Arkansas.</p><p>The Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Scholars records are available at the New York Public Library.</p><p>The International Fellowship Fund (IFF) Archives are available at Columbia University.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="a2f7ed09486a4667344dcce4662b525a">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>The Institute of International Education archives were deposited at the RAC by IIE in June 2016. Records were transferred to RAC by the Institute of International Education through several accessions in 2017.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
