<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA1561.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Ehrlich (Paul) papers</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Paul Ehrlich papers <num>FA1561</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>Telephone: 914-631-4505</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 914-631-6017</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-07-01 02:37:44 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Paul Ehrlich papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="naf">Ehrlich, Paul (1854-1915)</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" source="naf">Rockefeller University</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="naf">Pinkus, Max (1857-1934)</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" rules="dacs">Pinkus, Felix (1868-1947)</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="naf">Pinkus, Hermann</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="naf">Marquardt, Martha</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA1561</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">70.91 Cubic Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1863/1971" type="inclusive">1863-1971</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="b953ed06ad8cc289608eb4fe4bbf3c5b">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Paul Ehrlich, 1854-1915, physician and scientist, Berlin and Frankfurt, Germany. Founder of hematology, pioneer and major contributor to the fields of histochemistry and immunology. Famous for his development of chemotherapy (arsphenamine - 606) for syphilis. Nobel Laureate in physiology or medicine in 1908, jointly with Elie Metchnikoff for their studies in immunity.</p><p>
Biographical Information:
1854 - Born March 14 in Strehlen, Silesia.</p><p>1872 - Graduated from St. Maria Magdalena Gymnasium in Breslau.</p><p>1878 - M.D. from the University of Leipzig, after studies at the Universities of Breslau, Strassburg and Freiburg.</p><p>1878-1888 - Assistant physician, later senior physician at the Charité Hospital in Berlin, director Professor von Frerichs.</p><p>1888/1889 - After contracting tuberculosis cured in Italy and Egypt.</p><p>1889 - Established a small private research laboratory in Berlin.</p><p>1890 - Appointment in the Robert Koch Institute for Infectious Diseases in Berlin.</p><p>1896 - Appointed director of the new State Institute for Serum Research and Serum Control in Steglitz, a suburb of Berlin.</p><p>1898 - This institute moved to Frankfurt and was expanded and renamed: The Institute for Experimental Therapy.</p><p>1906 - The Georg-Speyer wing for chemotherapeutical research was added with the private financial help of Mrs. Franzisca.</p><p>1908 - Nobel Prize in physiology and medicine.</p><p>1911 - Received the state rank of "Wirklicher Geheimer Rath" with the title of Excellency.</p><p>1914 - Named "Ordentlicher Professor" at the newly founded University of Frankfurt.</p><p>1915 - August 20, died in Bad Homburg and is buried in the Jewish Cemetery in Frankfurt.</p><p>
Honorary Degrees:
1904 - University of Chicago, LL.D. 
1907 - University of Oxford, D.C.L.
1911 - University of Athens, Dr. phil. h.c.
1911 - University of Breslau, Dr. med. h.c.</p><p>
Awards:
1887 - Senckenberg Naturforschende Gesellschaft, Frankfurt a.M. Tiedemann Prize.
1903 - The Prussian Great-Golden Medal of Science. 
1906 - Prize of Honor at the XVth International Congress of Medicine at Lisbon.
1908 - Nobel Prize.
1911 - Liebig Medal, Society of German Chemists.
1914 - Cameron Prize of Edinburgh.</p><p>
Orders:
Bavaria: Member of the Bavarian Maximilian Order.</p><p>Denmark: Commander Cross of the Dannebrog Order, Second Class.</p><p>Japan: Order of the Rising Sun, Third Degree.</p><p>Norway: Commander Cross of the Royal Norwegian St. Olaf Order, Second Degree.</p><p>Palatinate: Cavalier Cross of the order of Berthold I of Zähringen.</p><p>Prussia: Order of the Crown, Second Degree; Order of the Red Eagle, Second Degree.</p><p>Rumania: Cross for Sanitary Merits, First Degree.</p><p>Russia: Order of St. Anne, First Degree, with Diamonds, Star and Cross.</p><p>Serbia: Great Cross of the Order of St. Sava. </p><p>Spain: Great Cross of the Order of Alfonso XII, with Star and Cross.</p><p>Venezuela: Order of the Bust of Bolivar, Second Degree, with Precious Stones</p><p>
Membership in Scientific Societies:
1887 - Senckenbergische Naturforschende Gesellachaft, Frankfurt a.M., Corresponding Member.</p><p>1899 - Senckenbergische Naturforschende Gesellechaft, Frankfurt a.M., Ordinary Member.</p><p>1900 - Balneologische Gesellschaft, Berlin, Honorary Member.</p><p>1900 - Royal Danish Society of Sciences, Copenhagen, Foreign Member.</p><p>1902 - International Society for the Fight against Tuberculosis, Berlin, Honorary Member.</p><p>1902 - German Chemical Society, Berlin, Member of the Committee.</p><p>1903 - Silesian Society for Home Culture, Corresponding Member.</p><p>1903 - Royal Academy of Medicine, Turin, Corresponding Member.</p><p>1904 - Royal Academy of Sciences, Bologna, Corresponding Member.</p><p>1904 - Society for Internal Medicine, Vienna, Honorary Member.</p><p>1904 - Imperial and Royal Society of Physicians, Vienna, Honorary Member.</p><p>1904 - The New York Academy of Medicine, Honorary Member.</p><p>1904 - Royal Society of Sciences, Göttingen, Foreign Member of the mathematical and physical class.</p><p>1904 - Royal Society of Medicine and Natural Science, Brussels, Corresponding Member.</p><p>1904 - Academy of Sciences, Washington, Foreign Member.</p><p>1904 - Societas therapeutical Mosquana, Moscow, Honorary Member.</p><p>1905 - Académie de Médecine, Paris, Foreign Member.</p><p>1905 - Medical Society, Budapest, Honorary Member.</p><p>1906 - Medical Society of Finland, Helsingfors, Honorary Member.</p><p>1906 - Society, of Physicians, Munich, Honorary Member.</p><p>1906 - Société de Biologie, Paris, Ordinary Member.</p><p>1907 - Pathological Society of Great Britain and Ireland, Honorary Member.</p><p>1907 - Society of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, London, Honorary Member.</p><p>1907 - Royal Academy dei Lincei, Rome, Foreign Member.</p><p>1907 - Royal Institute of Public Health, London, Honorary Member. </p><p>1907 - Medical Society of Berlin, Honorary Member.</p><p>1908 - Société de Pathologie Exotique (Institut Pasteur), Paris, Honorary Member.</p><p>1908 - Physical-Medical Society, Erlangen, Honorary Member.</p><p>1908 - Society for the Knowledge of Nature and Medical Treatment, Dresden, Honorary Member.</p><p>1908 - Swedish Medical Society, Stockholm, Honorary Member.</p><p>1908 - Physical Society, Frankfurt, Honorary Member.</p><p>1909 - Medical Society, St. Petersburg, Honorary Member.</p><p>1910 - Microbiological Society, St. Petersburg, Honorary Member.</p><p>1910 - Royal Academy of Medicine, Turin, Honorary Member.</p><p>1910 - Royal Society, London, Honorary Member.</p><p>1910 - Société Médicale Impériale du Caucase, Honorary Member.</p><p>1910 - International Commission for the Study of the Causes of Mental Diseases and their Prophylaxis, Berlin, Honorary Member.</p><p>1910 - Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences, Stockholm, Foreign Member.</p><p>1910 - German Society for Tropical Medicine, Hamburg, Honorary Member. </p><p>1910 - Society of Physicians, Odessa, Honorary Member.</p><p>1910 - Société Khediviale de Médecine, Cairo, Honorary Member.</p><p>1910 - International Commission for the Study of the Causes of Mental Diseases and their Prophylaxis, Rome, Honorary Member.</p><p>1910 - Medical Society of Jekaterinoslaw, Honorary Member.</p><p>1910 - Vienna Dermatological Society, Honorary Member.</p><p>1910 - Medical Society of Serbia, Belgrade, Honorary Member.</p><p>1910 - Physico-Medical Society, Saratow, Honorary Member.</p><p>1911 - Union of the St. Petersbuerg Pediatricians, Honorary Member.</p><p>1911 - Société Imperiale de Médecine, Constantinople, Honorary Member.</p><p>1911 - Royal Society of Sciences, Upsala, Ordinary Member.</p><p>1911 - Academia Romana, Bucharest, Honorary Member.</p><p>1911 - Union of Physicians, Smolensk, Honorary Member.</p><p>1911 - Microbiological Society, Delft, Corresponding Member.</p><p>1911 - Royal Medical Society, Edinburgh, Honorary Member.</p><p>1911 - Academie Royal de Médecine, Brussels, Honorary Member.</p><p>1911 - Imperial Institute for Experimental Therapy, St. Petersburg, Honorary Member.</p><p>1912 - Physiological Society of London, Honorary Member.</p><p>1912 - Society of Internal Medicine, Berlin, Honorary Member.</p><p>1912 - Society of Cancer Research of the Palatinate, Heidelberg, Honorary Member.</p><p>1912 - Charkow Veterinary Institute, Honorary Member.</p><p>1912 - Society of Brazilian Dermatologists, Honorary President.</p><p>1912 - National Academy of Caracas, Corresponding Member.</p><p>1912 - City of Strehlen, Honorary Citizen.</p><p>1912 - Société Royale des Sciences médicales et naturelles, Brussels, Hon. Member.</p><p>1912 - German Society of Recreation Homes for Merchants, Member of Committee.</p><p>1912 - Dermatological Society, Odessa, Honorary Member.</p><p>1912 - Sommering-Prize Commission, Member.</p><p>1912 - Medical Society of Athens, Honorary Member.</p><p>1913 - Society for Natural Sciences, Braunschweig, Honorary Member.</p><p>1913 - German Chemical Society, Berlin, Honorary Member.</p><p>1913 - Union of Physicians, Archangel, Honorary Member.</p><p>1913 - Society of Physicians, Odessa, Honorary Member.</p><p>1913 - Society of German Physicians of Mental Diseases, Berlin, Honorary Member.</p><p>1913 - Medical Society of Orel.</p><p>1913 - Society of Veterinary Doctors of the Veterinary Institute of Kazan Hon. Member.</p><p>1913 - Harveian Society of London, Foreign Member.</p><p>1913 - Société de Biologie, Paris, Honorary Member.</p><p>1913 - Italian Society of Dermatologists and Physicians for Sexual Diseases, Rome, Honorary Member.</p><p>1914 - Medical-Surgical Society of Bologna, Corresponding Member.</p><p>1914 - Society of Specialists for Children, Moscow, Honorary Member.</p><p>1914 - Norwegian Society of Natural Sciences, Christiana, Foreign Member. </p><p>1914 - Society of Jewish Physicians of the Ottoman Empire, Constantinople, Honorary Member.</p><p>1915 - Pharmaceutical Society, Berlin, Honorary Member.</p><p>
The above information was copied from the book Paul Ehrlich, by Martha Marquardt. Henry Schuman, 951, pp 252-255.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="ae4771730a4cf6668085eac7da6daad8">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of the RAC.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="cfc3df665e597e4d9dab33aa764c292a">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Ehrlich papers is a special collection of the Rockefeller University comprising the contents of 3 unique collections.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="1553d3fee518943cf14aba804a225d0a">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The Paul Ehrlich papers consists of three collections --</p><p>Paul Ehrlich papers (FA135)
Paul Ehrlich and Martha Marquardt papers (Wellcome collection) (FA136)
Pinkus family collection of Paul Ehrlich papers (FA072)</p>  </arrangement>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
