<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA1590.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Rockefeller Brothers Fund records</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Rockefeller Brothers Fund records <num>FA1590</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-17 11:15:17 -0500</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Rockefeller Brothers Fund records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" source="naf">Rockefeller Brothers Fund</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA1590</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">843.93 Cubic Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1941/2012" type="inclusive">1941-2012</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="cc37b5e111b8e244fba38e9acaf8f978">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The Rockefeller Brothers Fund (RBF) was established in 1940 by the five sons of John D. Rockefeller Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller: John D. 3rd, Nelson A., Laurance S., Winthrop, and David Rockefeller, as a vehicle for the members of the Brothers generation to systematically coordinate their philanthropic giving as well as share consultants, advice, and resources. Its endowment was created through a gift from JDR Jr. in 1951, and a subsequent bequest from his estate in 1960. Abby Rockefeller Mauzé, the eldest sibling and the only daughter of John D. Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, joined the RBF Board in 1954.</p><p>John D. Rockefeller 3rd served as president of the Fund from its inception until 1956. Other past presidents have included: Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1956-1958; Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1958-1968; Dana S. Creel, 1968-1975; William M. Dietel, 1975-1987; and Colin G. Campbell, 1998-2000.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="a08c47f02dd90b90b7437c5788e97833">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="b7600ae3a830b13bd54e9bfea970939b">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection includes correspondence, reports, memorabilia, program files, grant actions and grant administration files, Board of Trustees records, officers' files, photographs, and other material that document the philanthropic work of the Rockefeller Brothers Fund.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="b827ac3795c32dcd8cba8b5074a78ae7">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Arranged in eight record groups by record type. Each record group is comprised of multiple series, subseries or subgroups. Within records groups or series the material remains in original order. Additional finding aids are created as records are processed and open for research.</p><p>RG 1 Administative and Accounting records</p><p>RG 2 Office of the President</p><p>RG 3 Project Files</p><p>RG 4 Special Studies Project</p><p>RG 5 West Africa Program</p><p>RG 6 Ramon Magsaysay Awards Foundation</p><p>RG 7 Awards in Arts Education</p><p>RG 1044 Photographs</p>  </arrangement>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
