<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA1555.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Agricultural Development Council records</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Agricultural Development Council records <num>FA1555</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>Telephone: 914-631-4505</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 914-631-6017</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-01-01 03:53:04 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Agricultural Development Council records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" source="naf">Agricultural Development Council</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA1555</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">201.5 Cubic Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1983" type="inclusive">1950-1983</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="06d9f24152fa7af9a7964519981ad310">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Arranged in 2 record groups, each comprised of multiple series. The record groups are representative solely of when the materials were processed by RAC, and do not imply an original order of the records. Additional finding aids are created as records are processed and open for research.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="cc1e6c4ed2299a0b0d02984386ce0dd1">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The Agricultural Development Council, known as the Council on Economic and Cultural Affairs, Inc. during its first ten years, was established in 1953 by John D. Rockefeller 3rd as a "charitable, scientific and educational" organization that aimed "to stimulate and support economic and related activities important to human welfare." Its focus was Asia. From its beginning, the Council committed a major part of its resources to training and research activities in the social sciences, with the central aim of strengthening professional capacity to deal with the economic and human problems of agriculture and rural development in Asia. In 1985 it merged with two other Rockefeller-related agricultural programs, the Winrock International Livestock Research and Training Center and the Rockefeller Foundation's International Agricultural Development Service to create the Winrock International Institute for Agricultural Development.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="d5659121c38de3da93734bc9afd570d5">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Contains minutes of Board of Trustees meetings, general correspondence, grant files, fellowship files, training program records, workshop and seminar files, and publications. Subjects include agricultural development, agricultural economics, agriculture and politics, archaeology in Burma, farm mechanization, the education of farmers, land use, and rural development.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
