<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA1574.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Rockefeller Archive Center records</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Rockefeller Archive Center records <num>FA1574</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-17 11:15:08 -0500</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Rockefeller Archive Center records</unittitle>
    <unitid>FA1574</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4.66 Cubic Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1973/1995" type="inclusive">1973-1995</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="e9f1c6ef5692491b7e85eb8f6043743f">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. If accessing the records of the Population Council, I understand that I am given access to these records on condition that I will not identify by name, either in my research notes or in publication or recording, the names of individuals who received or apparently received medical diagnoses and/or treatments, whose case(s), may be documented or mentioned by personal name in the Population Council records. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <arrangement id="51a3de4740e00bd7ea5ec6f866676d40">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The Rockefeller Archive Center records currently consists of five collections. Additional finding aids are created as records are processed and open for research.</p><p>Rockefeller Archive Center photographs (FA095).
Rockefeller Archive Center Oral History and Audio Recordings Collection (FA1444).
Rockefeller Archive Center records, Related Publications (FA1497).
Rockefeller Archive Center records, Brochures, Pamphlets, and Clippings (FA1498).
Rockefeller Archive Center records, Topical Surveys (FA1499).</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="71d2aa8f265f8b2e55871e5a41a79563">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Materials include: brochures, pamphlets, publications, oral history recordings and transcripts, surveys and photographs.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
