<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA1567.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">International Education Board records</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the International Education Board records <num>FA1567</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-17 11:15:04 -0500</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>International Education Board records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" source="naf">International Education Board</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA1567</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">39.05 Cubic Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1923/1960" type="inclusive">1923-1960</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <arrangement id="f2fc2f79b7bec92460eed71d7c88f0a4">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The International Education Board materials consist of two collections.
International Education Board records (FA062)
International Education Board records, Albert R. Mann and Harry Luman Russell logs index (FA769)</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="8f1bffa4566cdeaa8f825cb48a659222">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The International Education Board was incorporated January 12, 1923, in the state of Virginia. Its purpose was to promote education, institutional or otherwise, throughout the world and as such was a complement to the General Education Board which functioned in the United States. Wickliffe Rose resigned from the International Health Board in 1923 to become director of both boards. At his retirement in 1928, the International Education Board discontinued its active program.</p><p>The International Education Board promoted the advancement of education through grants to universities and through a multitude of fellowships to individuals. It sponsored the strengthening of disciplines with such grants as those to develop Mount Palomar and traveling professorships and fellowships. While the main fields of the board were the physical and natural sciences and agriculture, some appropriations were made in the humanities and social sciences as to the American Academy in Rome, the Oriental Institute in Chicago and the New York State Colonization Society for the Booker Washington Agricultural and Industrial Institute of Liberia.</p><p>The Board terminated its activities on December 31, 1938.</p><p>A history, "Education on an International Scale," was written by George Gray.</p><p>The International Education Board records cover the period from 1923 to 1960.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="f8a8e43da2fe06bebbe0e395a3dee9c4">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for researchd. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="504b9b629676364530b687531b4eb66f">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Important subjects in this collection are astronomy, agriculture, rural clubs, physics, chemistry, dairying, biology, marine biology, mathematics, Mount Palomar, Oriental Institute, veterinary medicine, home economics, scientific publications, agricultural education, geology, forestry, Negro education, international education, and the National Research Council.</p><p>Among the correspondents are R. A. Millikan, W. W. Bierly, W. S. Richardson, Anson Phelps Stokes, Jackson Davis, W. H. Shepardson, Wickliffe Rose, H. L. Russell, George Foster Peabody, Ray Lyman Wilbur, Frank R. Lillie, Oswald Veblen, Augustus Trowbridge, Abraham Flexner, Simon Flexner, Louise Stanley, H. C. Taylor, Frants P. Lund, Vernon Kellog, W. E. Tisdale, C. B. Hutchison, A. R. Mann, Arthur A. Noyes, A. O. Leuschner, E. G. Nourse, George Asher Hobson, S. T. Dana, Martha van Rensselaer, Florence M. Read, Charles T. Loram, Harlow Shapley, Frank Schlesinger, Charles Breasted, James Breasted, John A. Wilson, Paul Monroe, Thomas H. Morgan, Frank Heath, Albert Einstein, Ernest Rutherford, Nils Bohr, Enrico Fermi, H. von Euler, Marie Curie, and Emil Godlewski.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
