<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA1710.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Ford Foundation records, Urban Poverty Program</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Urban Poverty Program <num>FA1710</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>Telephone: 914-631-4505</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 914-631-6017</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-03-13 18:07:55 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Ford Foundation records, Urban Poverty Program</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" rules="dacs" source="nad">Ford Foundation</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA1710</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">32.8 Cubic Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1996" type="inclusive">1973-1996</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="188c386ae2ff03073eb95ad111ead373">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Records more than 10 years old are open for research, unless otherwise noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="bbed84750f6b097cc2489bfaf2528cd1">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Consists primarily of office files, program files and administrative records.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="1ff01017bd8e1ec363ad4208c7f9f290">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Arranged in collections by file type or originating officer. Additional finding aids are created as records are processed and open for research.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="f2b89a2103825414fc19120e0488b3f2">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The work of what became the Urban Poverty Program began when the Public Affairs Program was formally established in 1952. One of the goals of the new program was to work toward greater equality of opportunity for minority groups. In 1965, Public Affairs was succeeded by the National Affairs Division, created to focus on deep-rooted problems facing American society. Program areas under the National Affairs Division included Social Development and Urban and Metropolitan Development. In 1981, a reorganization of the Foundation replaced National Affairs with the United States and International Affairs Program (USIAP).</p><p>The Urban Poverty Program was established in October 1981 as a subdivision of USIAP, taking over programs formerly administered by the divisions of National Affairs and Education and Public Policy. It administered programs benefiting the poor and inner-city residents in areas that included community development, employment and training, welfare, teen pregnancy, poverty, crime, and precollege education. It also assumed oversight of the programs in Population and of new programs to combat infant and child mortality. The Urban Poverty Program became a program area within a newly organized Program Division in 1988 and was merged into the Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS) in 1996.</p>  </bioghist>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
