<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA1767.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Rockefeller Brothers Fund records, Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, RG 6</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Rockefeller Brothers Fund records, Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, RG 6 <num>FA1767</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>Telephone: 914-631-4505</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 914-631-6017</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-01-01 04:08:50 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="recordgrp">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Rockefeller Brothers Fund records, Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, RG 6</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" source="naf">Rockefeller Brothers Fund</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA1767</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">36 box(es)</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">38 scrapbooks</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1998" type="inclusive">1957-1998</unitdate>
    <physdesc id="f4ee4a77011d711f48379cf2ea66a25d">38 scrapbooks</physdesc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="ac30ce4b4b5f74358a0fe00e16a3ced1">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Biography of President Ramon Magsaysay</p><p>Ramón del Fierro Magsaysay (b.August 31, 1907 – d.March 17, 1957) served as president of the Republic of the Philippines from December 30, 1953 until his death in a plane crash in 1957. President Magsaysay was best known for successfully defeating the communist-led Hukbalahap (Huk) movement, and for introducing reform to various aspects of Filipino life.(1)   He was extremely popular with the Filipino people and was universally respected for his integrity and his dedication to the betterment of all humankind.</p><p>Magsaysay Credo</p><p>I believe that government starts at the bottom and moves upward, for government exists for the welfare of the masses of the nation. 
I believe that he who has less in life should have more in law. 
I believe that the little man is fundamentally entitled to a little bit more food in his stomach, a little more cloth in his back and a little more roof over his head. 
I believe that this nation is endowed with a vibrant and stout heart, and possesses untapped capabilities and incredible resiliency. 
I believe that a high and unwavering sense of morality should pervade all spheres of governmental activity. 
I believe that the pulse of government should be strong and steady, and the men at the helm imbued with missionary zeal. 
I believe in the majesty of constitutional and legal processes, in the inviolability of human rights. 
I believe that the free world is collectively strong, and that there is neither need or reason to compromise the dignity of man. 
I believe that communism is iniquity, as is the violence it does to the principles of Christianity. 
I believe that the President should set the example of a big heart, an honest mind, sound instincts, the virtue of healthy impatience and an abiding love for the common man.</p><p>Organizational History of the Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation</p><p>The Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation (RMAF) was established in 1957 in memory of the late President Magsaysay who died in a place crash that same year. President Magsaysay was well-known for his good nature and commitment to justice for all people. Consequently, his death devastated not just the people of the Philippines, but the global community which included the Rockefeller brothers. Just six weeks after learning of the death of Ramon Magsaysay, John D. Rockefeller 3rd wrote to President Carlos P. Garcia, who succeeded President Magsaysay, and proposed that an award be given in honor of President Magsaysay. He wrote:</p><p>"My brothers and I have followed closely President Magsaysay's life and work. We believe deeply in that for which he stood… The trustees of the Rockefeller Brothers Fund would consider it a privilege to have a part in establishing a living memorial to the late President. They have authorized me to suggest the creation of the Ramon Magsaysay Award to be given annually to one or more persons in Asia whose demonstrated leadership is motive by a concern for the welfare of people comparable to that which characterized the life of Ramon Magsaysay."(2)</p><p>President Garcia accepted the Rockefeller Brothers Fund's proposal. As described on the Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation's website, "[w]ith the concurrence of the Philippine government, the trustees of the Rockefeller Brothers Fund (RBF) established the Award to honor his memory and perpetuate his example of integrity in public service and pragmatic idealism within a democratic society".(3)  The RBF supplied the initial endowment and the RMAF was formally organized in May 1957.</p><p>The RMAF is a non-profit corporation run by a seven person, all-Filipino, Board of Trustees. The RMAF is based in Manila, Philippines, and has operated out of the Ramon Magsaysay Center since 1968, when the building opened. Income earned from the Ramon Magsaysay Center has helps to support and sustain the RMAF.</p><p>The first awards were given in 1958. Since then, each year one award was given in each of the following five categories: Government Service (GS), Public Service (PS), Community Leadership (CL), Journalism and Literature (JL) and International Understanding (IU, later PIU). In 1964, the Journalism and Literature category was amended to include Creative Communication Arts (JLCCA). Then, in 2000, thanks to a grant from the Ford Foundation, a sixth category for Emergent Leadership (EL) was added. After 2008, the awards were no longer given according to category, except for Emergent Leadership. As described on the RMAF website, "[t]he Ramon Magsaysay Award is given to persons – regardless of race, nationality, creed or gender – who address issues of human development in Asia with courage and creativity, and in doing so have made contributions which have transformed their societies".(4)  Since, 1958, the award has been given to a diverse group of individuals and organizations.
 
The award ceremonies are held every year on August 31st, the anniversary of the birth of President Magsaysay. During the days surrounding the award ceremony, awardees and guests attend a series of events given in their honor. These events include the laying of wreaths at the Rizal Monument and in front of Ramon Magsaysay's tomb, luncheons for the awardees, and calls on the current President of the Philippines and on Mrs. Luz Magsaysay, the wife of President Magsaysay. Additionally, the awardees are asked to lead a discussion or give a presentation on a subject related to the work for which they were acknowledged.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="adcb1904da972731aecca1d9b222176a">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>All archival material 10 years old or older is open for research.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="716cb1ea8cd81f88ef6dc5ab960906a9">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Contains a scrapbook for each year that the Ramon Magsaysay Award was given from 1958-1998, with the exception of 1996 and 1997. In each given year, a scrapbook was completed shortly after the award ceremonies had ended. The scrapbooks were then sent to the Rockefeller Brothers Fund (RBF).</p><p>The material within each scrapbook includes media coverage leading up to the award ceremony, documentation of the ceremony itself, and the post-event departures of the awardees. Most scrapbooks feature newspaper clippings, responses given by the awardees at the ceremonies, photographs of the various events related to the awards, and copies of materials handed out during informal group discussions given by the awardees.</p><p>There were no awards given in 1970 because the government of the Philippines asked that institutions conserve all foreign currency. No awards given in 1990 out of respect for the people of the Philippines who had just experienced a terrible earthquake on July 16th, 1990.</p><p>In this series, categories of awards will be abreviated in the following fashion:</p><p>Award Category	Abbreviations are as follows:
Government Service	(GS)
Public Service	(PS)
Community Leadership	(CL)
Journalism and Literature	(JL)
International Understanding	(IU)
Peace and International Understanding	(PIU)
Journalism, Literature and Creative Communication Arts	(JLCCA)
Emergent Leadership	(EL)</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="9f7078fe17e57577c5e48f729e64c86c">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The Rockefeller Archive Center has title to the collection and has authority to grant permission to cite and publish archival material from the collection. Rockefeller Brothers Fund retains copyright and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them.</p>  </userestrict>
  <dsc><c id="0fdb484e5e3743e481d3977f7bfc876a" level="recordgrp"><did><unittitle>Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation</unittitle><unitid>6</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1998" type="inclusive">1957-1998</unitdate></did><c id="78bb5f76a3d1466089dea32be98efa33" level="series"><did><unittitle>Scrapbooks</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1998" type="inclusive">1957-1998</unitdate><physdesc id="2d609827e6fc5e8ce374a8474e52a0fd" label="Container Summary">38 scrapbooks</physdesc></did><scopecontent id="91ece73b6655b3487a2ebf89277a94a3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains a scrapbook for each year that the Ramon Magsaysay Award was given from 1958-1998, with the exception of 1996 and 1997. In each given year, a scrapbook was completed shortly after the award ceremonies had ended. The scrapbooks were then sent to the Rockefeller Brothers Fund (RBF).</p><p>The material within each scrapbook includes media coverage leading up to the award ceremony, documentation of the ceremony itself, and the post-event departures of the awardees. Most scrapbooks feature newspaper clippings, responses given by the awardees at the ceremonies, photographs of the various events related to the awards, and copies of materials handed out during informal group discussions given by the awardees.</p><p>There were no awards given in 1970 because the government of the Philippines asked that institutions conserve all foreign currency. No awards given in 1990 out of respect for the people of the Philippines who had just experienced a terrible earthquake on July 16th, 1990.</p><p>In this series, categories of awards will be abreviated in the following fashion:</p><p>Award Category	Abbreviations are as follows:
Government Service	(GS)
Public Service	(PS)
Community Leadership	(CL)
Journalism and Literature	(JL)
International Understanding	(IU)
Peace &amp; International Understanding	(PIU)
Journalism, Literature and Creative Communication Arts	(JLCCA)
Emergent Leadership	(EL)</p></scopecontent><acqinfo id="1a7c3617fa9927327a67b0bb1c23ca33"><head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head><p>Rockefeller Brothers Fund has donated this collection to the Rockefeller Archive Center. The Archive Center received the scrapbooks in multiple accessions beginning in 1979 and continuing periodically through 2006.</p></acqinfo><processinfo id="4ea0e481337cbff9a31702e4d1ddfd89"><head>Processing Information</head><p>The scrapbooks were originally housed in maroon covers inscribed with the year. Archival photocopies of each cover can be found in the collection. To enable long-term preservation of the original materials, the support pages of the scrapbooks were removed from their bindings and re-housed in polypropylene sleeves.</p></processinfo><arrangement id="a794a551da5ad9948ff11a2958bcf3c4"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged chronological by the year the award was given. Original order was maintained within each scrapbook, and pages numbers were assigned, found in the upper right-hand corner of each sleeve.</p></arrangement><accessrestrict id="d66451136470e533f1eda664dc11e07e"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>All archival material 10 years old or older is open for research.</p></accessrestrict><userestrict id="f1ce4a5ad27b64a33d5b69e7ca5a162c"><head>Conditions Governing Use</head><p>The Rockefeller Archive Center has title to the collection and has authority to grant permission to cite and publish archival material from the collection. Rockefeller Brothers Fund retains copyright and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them.</p></userestrict><c id="c096b4e939f5444c9ba791134cb0808d" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1958" type="inclusive">1958</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="06870ec0cda5e01824bbbcb9180ba93e" label="mixed materials [A0000000008441]" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="83d287f19f775578c4a1731094521b42"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Vinoba Bhave (CL); Chian Mon Lin (GS); Robert Dick and Mochtar Lubis (JLCCA); Operation Brotherhood (PIU); Mary Rutnam (PS)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="20401f70d8ec424a8ae0cbfcd27f748d" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959" type="inclusive">1959</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="9761ea6c683e5d6773f991c0d5ccd369" label="mixed materials [A0000000008442]" type="box">2</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="63e92e40eefcfbe1aba248da277d1b1f" label="mixed materials [A0000000008441]" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="f798d58e32febfc7245cd6d74ffc7044"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Jose Aguilar (GS); Dalai Lama (CL); Chintaman Deshmukh (GS); Edward Law Yone (JLCCA); Tee Tee Luce and Joaquin Vilallonga (PS); Tarzie Vittachi (JLCCA)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="ad106dfb45284d1490a741e1e59ecd99" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1960" type="inclusive">1960</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="f8f44e5459d77d5b27d31f435953cd1a" label="mixed materials [A0000000008442]" type="box">2</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="30514cd0f808bedfe6824cf5e8ab4e41" label="mixed materials [A0000000008443]" type="box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="9cf47c1df32c9aae4f1ae1e4801b2621"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Rahman Abdul (CL); Henry Holland and Ronald Holland (PS); Y.C. James Yen (PIU)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="fcbae10bd4e44fb283e6e063344cac8f" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961" type="inclusive">1961</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="d0f7d1a33d2fe54d473db326f2686e96" label="mixed materials [A0000000008444]" type="box">4</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="0779ec7b589793b264ac852ac05f4689" label="mixed materials [A0000000008443]" type="box">3</container></did><scopecontent id="9aac353566549abe4d591d085573cea3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Gus Borgeest (CL); Genevieve Caulfield (PIU); Amitabha Chowdhury (JLCCA); Raden Kodijat (GS); Nilawan Pintong (PS)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="cb025f085fc8478d81a6ef3587f2cede" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962" type="inclusive">1962</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="cc9345032fecb8f3489b1e47237b67b0" label="mixed materials [A0000000008444]" type="box">4</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="d136b4ffea3d8cfb5c8394c262170ff2" label="mixed materials [A0000000008445]" type="box">5</container></did><scopecontent id="0d234e33574165f05df72215ca4c0057"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Francisca Aquinto (GS); Chang Chun-ha (JLCCA); Horace Kadoorie and Lawrence Kadoorie (PS);
Mother Teresa (PIU); Palayil Narayanan and Koesna Poeradiredja (CL)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="c5d1a439298d48889d671f7d0175eaf7" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963" type="inclusive">1963</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="3b0b636e899ef5b5df91c6135af6f010" label="mixed materials [A0000000008446]" type="box">6</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="1fd73af26827e2357ab544683a2a669a" label="mixed materials [A0000000008445]" type="box">5</container></did><scopecontent id="f4811f8e12bcfd20fca6ea6d55225807"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Akhter Khan (GS); Dara Khurody, Verghese Kurien and Tribhuvandas Patel (CL); Helen Kim (PS); US Peace Corps in Asia (PIU)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="003081fecd954cc5baea8fcf9b0b525a" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1964" type="inclusive">1964</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="5fcd5037f0c776eecfd4f29dd475d60f" label="mixed materials [A0000000008446]" type="box">6</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="b15cd3d45d80bffced70172b0b77e789" label="mixed materials [A0000000008447]" type="box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="7bee8d356e86f53b69af7a6d722988bd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Welthy Fisher (PIU); Augustine Hoa (PS); Yukiharu Miki (GS); Kayser Sung and Richard Wilson (JLCCA); Pablo Tapia (CL)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="38a8b08af99c409998e72404231905aa" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1965" type="inclusive">1965</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="f544373de20b817c405fb22040b53333" label="mixed materials [A0000000008449]" type="box">9</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="acb9f6572e31d194d804e86a16d094f0" label="mixed materials [A0000000008448]" type="box">8</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="4958ec5d2a3c71c25a20656434716a64" label="mixed materials [A0000000008447]" type="box">7</container></did><scopecontent id="341f07fd9f1850881be933c599ee5beb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Bayanihan Folk Arts Center (PIU); Akira Kurosawa (JLCCA); Lim Kim San (CL); Jayaprakash Narayan (PS); Puey Ungphakorn (GS)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="7c69aa6fa4f64d968620e54ef2e73f4a" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1966" type="inclusive">1966</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="806bbb57bd10a1b93f691a36c75c2cdc" label="mixed materials [A0000000008449]" type="box">9</container></did><scopecontent id="48ca73f64eeb7619781720cec17856f3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Kamaladevi Chattopadhyay (CL); Committee for Coordination of Investigations of the Lower Mekong Basin and Cooperating Entities (PIU); Kim Yong-ki (PS); Phon Sangsingkeo (GS)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="acfc2be4d452404ebad890b7ddd4dd73" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1967" type="inclusive">1967</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="d765b0a9c5be53c3eb1e03bd87456280" label="mixed materials [A0000000008450]" type="box">10</container></did><scopecontent id="eef0526d8b7e3146be517d27004f9aa0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Abdul Razak (CL); Sithiporn Kridakara (PS); Shiroshi Nasu (PIU); Satyajit Ray (JLCCA); Keo Viphakone (GS)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="ed7637b0208e4c7e8074c32b5694cb22" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1968" type="inclusive">1968</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="f47f62601a50c1619532f49afbb7a671" label="mixed materials [A0000000008451]" type="box">11</container></did><scopecontent id="a03040e8acdd3dd16b52c5935a932ec5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Cooperative for American Relief Everywhere (PIU); Rosario Encarnation and Silvino Encarnation (CL); Li Kwoh-ting (GS); Ton That Thien (JLCCA); Seiichi Tobata (PS)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="f4dae623a398428591cc94ff5837d05e" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1969" type="inclusive">1969</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="49acb6707534b71cffad447e9d549bc6" label="mixed materials [A0000000008452]" type="box">12</container></did><scopecontent id="002c039e32fbc940e19162aadd1f629f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Ahangamage Ariyaratne (CL); Hsu Shih-Chu (GS); International Rice Research Institute (PIU); Kim Hyung-Seo (PS); Mitoji Nishimoto (JLCCA)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="0a566a519fe7498d91b5d44dcdf0f6c8" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1971" type="inclusive">1971</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="0f4fa32be2d4107a2cf9443c59e6a7e1" label="mixed materials [A0000000008453]" type="box">13</container></did><scopecontent id="bf8e243f866fd93b2e0a0d6ce603c311"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Prayoon Chanyavongs (JLCCA); Saburo Okita (PIU); Pedro Orata (PS); Ali Sadikin (GS); Moncompu Sambasivan Swaminathan (CL)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="a2adf4bad88b4600806f779eae3ac908" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">1972</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="b3b992d2f1dc71f832658702f5cce2af" label="mixed materials [A0000000008453]" type="box">13</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="71cbb1b2522f6d8cb4cb5c3493d3b8f5" label="mixed materials [A0000000008454]" type="box">14</container></did><scopecontent id="cc9d377171f86c45ecd43080ba73bbc4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Goh Keng-Swee (GS); Cecile Guidote and Gilopez Kabayao (PS); Yasuji Hanamori (JLCCA); Hans Westernberg (CL)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="c4519997dd4c4a8893ca69f7b0758db2" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">1973</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="749edc04c8f0dae331c0ed8bec2789bb" label="mixed materials [A0000000008454]" type="box">14</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="b58a5a5b261cd43533457c1874abedfa" label="mixed materials [A0000000008455]" type="box">15</container></did><scopecontent id="cc5d7bb4fc92997475e17dbe4e50f545"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Krasae Chanawongse (CL); Antonio Fortich and Benjamin Gaston (PS); Michiko Ishimure (JLCCA); Balachandra Sekhar (GS); Summer Institute of Linguistics (PIU)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="287e58626cf448ceaf01983307f99958" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">1974</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="dc5b1f1f3bb79b7a6a1a1d59db7853ae" label="mixed materials [A0000000008455]" type="box">15</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="fdbf0f48bcadbe1c1f7bb2e8bc9b1348" label="mixed materials [A0000000008456]" type="box">16</container></did><scopecontent id="8dd50df74cbee9d4d6d504ab4bc44257"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Fusaye Ichikawa (CL); Hiroshi Kuroki (GS); William Materson (PIU); Zacarias Sarian (JLCCA); M.S. Subbulakshmi (PS)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="ed0773bfd633461db04c2e9b78672538" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1975" type="inclusive">1975</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="9759686ca39545ab56a7ecf4ee2dc6dc" label="mixed materials [A0000000008456]" type="box">16</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="0faf23c2d5899a6756f074543c08285a" label="mixed materials [A0000000008457]" type="box">17</container></did><scopecontent id="ad53f638a15df8a545e98ca6236c6dec"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Lee Tai-Young (CL); Patrick James McGlinchey (PIU); Phra Parnchand (PS); Mohammed Suffian (GS); Boobli George Verghese (JLCCA)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="4e7aecde36014870bffd60f921ea481a" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976" type="inclusive">1976</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="30358e5faef17110fad187bc289535b2" label="mixed materials [A0000000008457]" type="box">17</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="39d71193b93bb99ccffcf446affbb8c8" label="mixed materials [A0000000008458]" type="box">18</container></did><scopecontent id="9dd0a796c5273bf7403fc2318a840efb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Hermenegild Fernandez (PS); Henning Holck-Larson (PIU); Sombhu Mitra (JLCCA); Elsie Tu (GS); Toshikazu Wakatsuki (CL)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="19664b6355d14783add1215f0d4955ac" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1977/1977" type="inclusive">1977</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="ee01b5ec9109b6db3c0e913d3efa16cc" label="mixed materials [A0000000008458]" type="box">18</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="534c09f19d9344efbd2c96d2c6ff5249" label="mixed materials [A0000000008459]" type="box">19</container></did><scopecontent id="99aa606a00b0651d3997b3be4c58b534"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Ela Ramesh Bhatt (CL); College of Agriculture at the University of the Philippines at Los Banos (PIU); Fe Del Mundo (PS); Benjamin Galstaun (GS); Mahesh Regmi (JLCCA)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="0e9b7a9d50c7490eb2baa063e76535d1" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1978" type="inclusive">1978</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="518dcb9096139060883468ee654a5850" label="mixed materials [A0000000008459]" type="box">19</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="4c6bb6323daf9fb17373d5d3e8baa9f5" label="mixed materials [A0000000008460]" type="box">20</container></did><scopecontent id="2309ba81a8a63461e29e0c6ea2303287"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Tahrunnesa Abdullah (CL); Shahrum bin Yub (GS); Soedjatmoko (PIU); Prateep Ungsongtham-Hata (PS); Yoon Suk-joong (JLCCA)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="54d75ad5a9ee41178e5f177e4e0660bd" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1979/1979" type="inclusive">1979</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="0b204d6f71f1c1d17706e6c60001ff1f" label="mixed materials [A0000000008461]" type="box">21</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="ffec55ffb5da133dc356fcabce18e57b" label="mixed materials [A0000000008460]" type="box">20</container></did><scopecontent id="30e500101b44edee34bcb2a85607281b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Mabelle Arole and Rajanikant Arole (CL); Association of Southeast Asian Nations (PIU); Chang Kee-ryo (PS); Lokukamkanamge Manjusri (JLCCA); Raden Wasito (GS)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="d48d10f3f4c348dabfbf4cd77bb46726" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1980" type="inclusive">1980</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="1ff22466ff08e695d457db0d9b9439ca" label="mixed materials [A0000000008461]" type="box">21</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="3ea7642c9da2364c1814a0993100ff77" label="mixed materials [A0000000008462]" type="box">22</container></did><scopecontent id="8f9cf6227a4b9d2d6dad029c79a63d6d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Fazle Hazan Abed (CL); Muhammed Alias (GS); Francisco Sionil Jose (JLCCA); Shigeharu Matsumoto (PIU); Ohm Dae-sup (PS)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="5bb0c6e4e8964ba69a64fa9a6bb8199d" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1981" type="inclusive">1981</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="64127c7b7b1ae52b1b1aa1881071cb8b" label="mixed materials [A0000000008462]" type="box">22</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="39d09a9591b0308e5e7151ec90c9c630" label="mixed materials [A0000000008463]" type="box">23</container></did><scopecontent id="6403fb2890b52e195067b716f2dbdf4e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Gour Kishore Ghosh (JLCCA); Augustine Joung Kang (PIU); Johanna Nasution (PS); Pramod Karan Sethi (CL); Prawase Wasi (GS)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="e31c1d45d0af49429dd0199c8646e104" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1982/1982" type="inclusive">1982</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="8eac4f31247c3f076c54f30028ca1647" label="mixed materials [A0000000008463]" type="box">23</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="b34242f347ca83202653f93425a540d3" label="mixed materials [A0000000008464]" type="box">24</container></did><scopecontent id="3511410be286c0ad032091bf27e63b90"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Arturo Alcaraz (GS); Chandi Prasad Bhatt (CL); Manibhai Desai (PS); Arun Shourie (JLCCA)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="d5c47455fc7542e1b833436f18a60f49" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1983/1983" type="inclusive">1983</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="fcdc3300dbadc25a935dd2ef267baf58" label="mixed materials [A0000000008465]" type="box">25</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="00e37ece58c2ba5dd198e2e7747c32f0" label="mixed materials [A0000000008464]" type="box">24</container></did><scopecontent id="82b6e6fe4851c6ed37ddd5fa8b899baa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Fua Hariphitak (PS); Marcelline Jayakody (JLCCA); Aloysius Schwartz (PIU); ANton Soedjarwo (CL); SU Nan-cheng (GS)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="64bc143830bf40c5a7682cad30cc420b" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1984/1984" type="inclusive">1984</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="4e606d1bbd939ff5e57ff08e98e94140" label="mixed materials [A0000000008465]" type="box">25</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="ea4fa7c79fdcee4c250e338c514cbf4f" label="mixed materials [A0000000008466]" type="box">26</container></did><scopecontent id="9f6d3ee4a06975e3fc40933ff1bdf419"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Jiro Kawakita (PIU); Rasipuram Laxman (JLCCA); Thongbai Thongpao (PS); Wu Ta-you (GS); Muhammad Yunus (CL)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="cc68a0c35dd442de91e6d801fe88963f" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1985/1985" type="inclusive">1985</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="1084398ae5327ed2f369ccfcb9973712" label="mixed materials [A0000000008466]" type="box">26</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="e77e7937929b0cfad8cc596fb8b69217" label="mixed materials [A0000000008467]" type="box">27</container></did><scopecontent id="c68400ef5357a879f0bd3659251c0b5b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Murlidhar Amte (PS); Lino Brocka (JLCCA); Zafrullah Chowdhury (CL); Tan Sri Noordin (GS); Harold Ray Watson (PIU)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="f8fefe2a81af46348d9ec9542c61bc00" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1986/1986" type="inclusive">1986</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="23a82aa804518bb624ec773ca625c7cd" label="mixed materials [A0000000008467]" type="box">27</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="b55769ee8de1f128aadd546acaf6cd60" label="mixed materials [A0000000008468]" type="box">28</container></did><scopecontent id="fd7570873dd3f67df5345fb29a94f3c3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: John Vincent Daly and Paul Jei (CL); Abdul Sattar Edhi and Bilqis Edhi (PS); International Institute of Rural Reconstruction (PIU); Aloysius Mboi and Nafsiah Mboi (GS); Radio Veritas (JLCCA)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="19a9fc9b98ec43b29ca1c3fdb97d940b" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1987/1987" type="inclusive">1987</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="571a2e9055b96ce83e08b710de69ace1" label="mixed materials [A0000000008468]" type="box">28</container></did><scopecontent id="c29d25d29a06bc633b1a2138b5eeab26"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Haji Hanafiah (GS); Hans Bague Jassin (PS); RIchard William Timm (PIU); Aree Valyasevi (CL); Diane (Yun-Peng) Ying (JLCCA)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="fb6c5c20cf5644da8708effbcfa0f8d5" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1988/1988" type="inclusive">1988</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="dbfeac9d37db16d18794818b854cc9d6" label="mixed materials [A0000000008469]" type="box">29</container></did><scopecontent id="d9ea563a3ac901fa392c1ba0df09c1ae"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Masanobu Fukuoka (PS); Miriam Santiago (GS); Veditantirige Sarachchandra (JLCCA); The Royal Project (PIU); Mohammad Yeasin (CL)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="ca9ac31605e2476d9fd92b71b068f7dd" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1989/1989" type="inclusive">1989</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="d24caaa121b6eeb1836b1025c8856c61" label="mixed materials [A0000000008470]" type="box">30</container></did><scopecontent id="509f79d4a463174dcb25602a99a02b70"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Asian Institute of Technology (PIU); Zakiah Hanum (GS); Lakshimi Chand Jain (PS); Kim Im-Soon (CL); James Reuter (JLCCA)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="b3ae063fb53a467e97ca4a2335f1240a" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1991/1991" type="inclusive">1991</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="cc04179410ef8d1d0c89abec3d82702b" label="mixed materials [A0000000008472]" type="box">32</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="7260a28c1836c4386f2f57ee80f93de6" label="mixed materials [A0000000008471]" type="box">31</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="2bde4ac4fd11f658c37ec6977cf3bbdb" label="mixed materials [A0000000008470]" type="box">30</container></did><scopecontent id="0cb42c70da305c4affa5293b32e4c326"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Alfredo Bengzon (GS); Shih Cheng-Yen (CL); Press Foundation of Asia (PIU); Princess Maha Sirindhorn (PS); K.V. Subbanna (JLCCA)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="927b5b4ee47641b0b6f9bf89825281a7" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1992/1992" type="inclusive">1992</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="ba75d444d52ed067dd867b18cfd87395" label="mixed materials [A0000000008472]" type="box">32</container></did><scopecontent id="690e60e7790b7ba3322439ca12116e5a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Angel Alcala (PS); Shoaib Khan (CL); Ravi Shankar (JLCCA); Chamlong Srimuang (GS); Washington Sycip (PIU)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="0695e489f416416787b5db13ec67ca75" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1993/1993" type="inclusive">1993</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="05c0b394561adf56c64ba98e39875652" label="mixed materials [A0000000008473]" type="box">33</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="691a5790d32b7c6b27b32b49dc969128" label="mixed materials [A0000000008472]" type="box">32</container></did><scopecontent id="75acde2855cf59ca59d8651c851aa89e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Banoo Jehangir Coyaji (PS); Noboru Iwamura (PIU); Bienvenido Lumbera (JLCCA); Abdurrahman Wahid (CL); Vo-Tong Xuan (GS)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="5a4b1bcbbf31489fb0944965817e7093" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1994/1994" type="inclusive">1994</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="a4be6685d759ba31584b367d40211da9" label="mixed materials [A0000000008473]" type="box">33</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="4a8dd6ba01f5544ee0517ef5a86ae0af" label="mixed materials [A0000000008474]" type="box">34</container></did><scopecontent id="cbdc6450e79bdfeeeeb82b94a5d8b4e9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Eduardo Jorge Anzorena (PIU); Kiran Bedi (GS); Fei Xiaotong and Sima Samar (CL); Abdul Samad Ismail (JLCCA); Mechai Viravaidya (PS)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="8c496c202479494d939d44c8d32c48f7" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995" type="inclusive">1995</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="68a7c2da9fc58c913f3bd8e3daeb6c9b" label="mixed materials [A0000000008475]" type="box">35</container><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="9780a49f3f4474bda460475a364f7cab" label="mixed materials [A0000000008474]" type="box">34</container></did><scopecontent id="4c10639ac91355c23ec140dcbc1ff598"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Award Winners: Asian Institute of Management (PIU); Morihiko Hiramatsu (GS); Teh Ho Ming (CL); Asma Jahangir (PS); Pramoedya Ananta Toer (JLCCA)</p></scopecontent></c><c id="1c53898e93614f6bbff2de9431133ae3" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1998/1998" type="inclusive">1998</unitdate><container altrender="Phonograph Record Box (Tall)" id="9b9b151b8b980c0e6f7ec868d0dd736f" label="mixed materials [A0000000008476]" type="box">36</container></did><scopecontent id="0c9cd7b0e08d092d88fd29e7889784a7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Corazon Aquino (IU); Nuon Phaly (CL); Syed Adibul Rizvi (GS); Sophon Suphapong (PS); Ying Ruocheng (JLCCA)</p></scopecontent></c></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
