<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="https://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA1846.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Ford Foundation records, Civic Engagement and Government Program, Office Files of Amy Brown</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Civic Engagement and Government Program, Office Files of Amy Brown <num>FA1846</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>Telephone: 914-631-4505</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 914-631-6017</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-01-01 05:04:56 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Ford Foundation records, Civic Engagement and Government Program, Office Files of Amy Brown</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" rules="dacs" source="nad">Ford Foundation</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut">Brown, Amy</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA1846</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/resources/13406</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.84 Cubic Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">18 document boxes: 18 letter size boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="2007/2016" type="inclusive">2007-2016</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <acqinfo id="64063cfa312a86febd327adb86c085fc">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Ford Foundation archive was deposited at the RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files, and officers' papers were transferred to and accessioned by the RAC beginning in 2011.   </p><p>This material was transferred to the RAC in 2021 in two different sets of records and was ingested by the RAC as Accession 2021:016 and Accession 2021:120.   </p><p>Accessions continue as necessary.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="0a919d735715085a0ae040bef94228b9">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Ford Foundation has title, copyright and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them. The Rockefeller Archive Center has authority to grant permission to cite and publish material from the collection. Permission to publish extensive excerpts, or material in its entirety, will be referred to the Ford Foundation.</p>  </userestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="b901742dd53948e9d0a96d0e7513762f">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <arrangement id="82caea1e46b2bf4cd4337b62e65cd304">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection consists of two series.     </p><p>Collection arrangement is as follows:    </p><p>Series 1. General files, 2007-2015 
Series 2. Grant files, 2008-2016</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="991d759b6e6b1a4898dffd484e40b8d0">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains the files Amy Brown created when she worked as a Program Officer at the Ford Foundation, focusing on programming for financial justice and for providing financial opportunities and protections to low and moderate-income and marginalized communities. Most of the records in the collection originate from Brown's position as a Program Officer in the Economic Opportunity and Assets Program, Financial Assets Unit. There are also some documents created by Brown when she was a Senior Program Officer in the Civic Engagement and Government Program which was her last position at the Foundation. </p><p>The collection is comprised of two series with the bulk of the collection's contents contained in the second series. The first series contains general files mostly concerning convenings and program strategy, and the second series contains grant files documenting grant approvals, related communications and support, and reporting. Grantees focused on issues regarding affordable financial services and products, debt, credit unions, predatory lending, financial savings, financial reform and regulation advocacy, and the impact of new technology on the financial marketplace among other topics. </p><p>In addition to the grant status reports (GSR), grant communication summaries, and Recommended Grant Actions records (RGA) in the grant files, there are also materials like correspondence, reports, meeting materials, notes, drafts, and articles found throughout the collection.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Ford Foundation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Consumer credit -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Consumer protection</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Credit unions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Financial services industry</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Financial security</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Immigrants</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Saving and investment</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc>