<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="https://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA1837.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Ford Foundation records, Economic Opportunity and Assets Program, Quality Employment Unit, Office Files of Helen Neuborne</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Economic Opportunity and Assets Program, Quality Employment Unit, Office Files of Helen Neuborne <num>FA1837</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>Telephone: 914-631-4505</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 914-631-6017</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-01-01 05:04:44 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Ford Foundation records, Economic Opportunity and Assets Program, Quality Employment Unit, Office Files of Helen Neuborne</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" rules="dacs" source="nad">Ford Foundation</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut">Neuborne, Helen</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA1837</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/resources/13395</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">15.19 Cubic Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">40 letter size document boxes.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1974/2015" type="inclusive">1974-2015</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <acqinfo id="d79b100788da0ea6b15d3bc4bf188ef3">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Ford Foundation archive was deposited at the RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files, and officers' papers were transferred to and accessioned by the RAC beginning in 2011.   </p><p>This material was transferred to the RAC in 2021 and was ingested by the RAC as Accession 2021:015.   </p><p>Accessions continue as necessary. </p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="1770daa1c77289faaabca50eac07aaac">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Ford Foundation has title, copyright and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them.   
The Rockefeller Archive Center has authority to grant permission to cite and publish material from the collection. Permission to publish extensive excerpts, or material in its entirety, will be referred to the Ford Foundation.</p>  </userestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="f1d8a5528f7d3aaa5f04bfa8e52f4cdd">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <arrangement id="f0a6d3dc0b676c7aebb5c9125fef7814">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection consists of one series.   </p><p>Collection arrangement is as follows:  </p><p>Series 1. Subject files, 1974-2015</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="77786f1372daf8165c078cf587120fcd">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Collection contains the files Helen Neuborne created during her support and leadership of the Ford Foundation's programming for expanding economic opportunity and assets building. Most of the collection's contents originate from Neuborne's career at the Ford Foundation between 2003 and 2016 when she served as Senior Program Officer in the Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS) Economic Development unit and then as Director of the Quality Employment unit in the later Economic Opportunity and Assets Program. Neuborne had previous positions in the Foundation's programs for human rights and reproductive health, but there is only a small number of materials documenting that work included within the collection. </p><p>The collection is comprised of one series of subject files. These files document Neuborne's responsibilities for grants management and program strategy. Neuborne and her respective program units oversaw grants in support of low-wage workers in relation to access to public benefits, workforce development, state and Federal labor market policy, fair wages, the balance between work and family, and the intersection of employment and economic status with gender, race, disability, and immigration status. In regards to program strategy, several files in the collection pertain to the Ford Foundation's program restructuring when Luis Ubinas became President. There are materials documenting the development of Lines of Work statements. </p><p>Common material formats found throughout the collection include correspondence, notes, notebooks, drafts, grant proposals, grant recommendations, reports, graphs and tables, meeting materials, news articles, and publications. There are also digital media items in the collection and one photograph which shows Neuborne.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Ford Foundation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Economic policy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Employment -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Foreign workers--United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Labor policy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Minimum wage</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Parental leave</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public welfare</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Sick leave</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Tax Credits--United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">UnEmployment insurance--United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women -- Employment</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Women's rights</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Work and family</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Working class families--United States--Economic conditions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Working poor</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc>