<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="under_revision" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA316.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Educational Interests, Series G</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Educational Interests, Series G
 <num>FA316</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><p><date>2009</date></p><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-09-02 11:18:13 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="series">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Educational Interests, Series G</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="ctb" source="naf">Rockefeller, Winthrop</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="ctb" source="naf">Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="naf">Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison), 1839-1937</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="ctb" source="naf">Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="ctb" source="naf">Rockefeller, David</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="ctb" source="naf">Rockefeller, John D., III (John Davison), 1906-1978</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="naf">Rockefeller, John D., Jr. (John Davison), 1874-1960</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA316</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">52.35 Cubic Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1896/1961" type="inclusive">1896-1961</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="74a79af3bcb25d9e2cb21897deef0bac">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
<p>Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Material in the Rockefeller family collections that provides the names, correspondence, or activities of living members of the Rockefeller family, and/or documents the net wealth of any Rockefeller family members, is restricted. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="08f219c56e4776b9222e025bb0414fcf">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
<p>Reproduction/duplication of archival items is routinely provided in accordance with "fair use." If the RAC does not hold copyright for an archival collection, or items within a collection, it is the user's responsibility to contact the copyright holder, or make a fair effort to do so, prior to publication.</p>  </userestrict>
  <arrangement id="9d3570886b7b29bd35d260470dedc763">
    <head>Arrangement note</head>
<p>The Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records are arranged by subject matter in 27 series. Most of these series are wholly or partially open for research. The series are:</p><p>A John D. Rockefeller, Sr.; C Business Interests; D Civic Interests; E Cultural Interests; F Economic Reform Interests; G Educational Interests; H Friends and Services; I Homes; J Housing Interests; K Medical Interests; L Real Estate; M Maps and Memorabilia; N Religious Interests; O Rockefeller Boards; P Welfare - General Files; Q World Affairs; R Welfare - Youth Files; S Documents; T Public Relations; U Public Land Law Review Commission; V Greenrock; W Properties; X Costume Collection; Y Media; Z John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Personal; AA Abby Aldrich Rockefeller; AC Abby Rockefeller Mauzé</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="37ff080f5c63b26477281e98cfe1b9ca">
    <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
<p>The central figure in the creation and operation of the Standard Oil Company during its rise to the top of the petroleum industry, John D. Rockefeller (JDR) established for the family a leading role in business and philanthropy. From the days of his earliest employment, Rockefeller, a devout Baptist, was generous in his giving to worthy causes, especially those of a religious nature. During the 1890s he developed an orderly system of philanthropic giving through an office staff that included his close advisor, Frederick T. Gates (1853-1929) and his son, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. (1874-1960). With the advise of these and other associates, Rockefeller established the University of Chicago, The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (now The Rockefeller University), the Rockefeller Foundation, and other philanthropic organizations working nationally and internationally in the fields of education, religion, and health. Rockefeller's total donations to philanthropic endeavors are estimated to have been $540 million.</p><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr. (JDR Jr.) joined his father's office on October 1, 1897. He oversaw the expansion and diversification of the philanthropic work begun by his father. During his lifetime, the younger Rockefeller gave more than $537 million to educational, religious, cultural, medical, and other charitable projects.</p><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and his wife, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller (1874-1948), passed the Rockefeller philanthropic impulse on to their children. Abby (1903-1976), John D. 3rd (1906-1978), Nelson A. (1908-1979), Laurance S. (1910-2004), Winthrop (1912-1973), and David (1915-2017) further expanded and diversified Rockefeller influence and interests, establishing their own philanthropic organizations, most notably the Rockefeller Brothers Fund (1940), and becoming more active politically.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="bb5d337f27a1deced97c3a96677eaf36">
    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
<p>The Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller (OMR) materials document the increasing role assumed by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in the management of Rockefeller affairs and amply document his business and philanthropic affairs. They also chronicle the entrance of JDR Jr.'s sons, John D. 3rd, Nelson A., Laurance S., Winthrop, and David, into the world of business, philanthropy, civic leadership, and politics as they joined the office.</p><p>This material contains correspondence, reports, pamphlets, memoranda, deeds, maps, contracts, reports, minutes, charters, certificates of incorporation, clippings, diaries, notebooks, calendars, and memorabilia.</p><p>There is a microfilm card index of personal and institutional names.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <fileplan id="461f515a6dc5bc2ebe5b684bc12d0bfe">
    <head>File Plan note</head>
<p>Former Classification: III 02</p>  </fileplan>
  <scopecontent id="31d9216323daa31e58c332e917cb28ca">
    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
<p>The files found in this series include correspondence by members of the Rockefeller family and their representatives and the officials of various institutions. Most of the material is unsolicited requests for aid. The material on institutions in which the family took an active interest, such as the International Houses, includes analysis, reports, general correspondence, contributions, and administration.</p><p>The Schools section and the Colleges section both include information on the schools attended by the Rockefeller brothers and cousins. There is a significant amount of information about the University of Chicago. The Foreign Colleges section includes a substantial amount of information on the University of Paris.</p><p>The family member who appears most prominently in this series is John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Other family members are John D. Rockefeller, Sr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, and Winthrop Rockefeller.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War I</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War II</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Religious institutions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Restoration and conservation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Rockefeller family -- Art collections</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">State governments -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Travel</subject>
    <subject source="local">Philanthropy -- New York (N.Y.)</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">United States</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Urban policy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Urban renewal</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Health insurance</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1958</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Government policy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Folk art</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Religion</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public welfare</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public relations</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Housing rehabilitation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Economics</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Economic policy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Economic development</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Federal government -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Family planning</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Capital investments</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises, Foreign</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charitable contributions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art -- Collectors and collecting</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art, Modern</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Business</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Arts</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International economic relations</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International cooperation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International relations</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charities -- Investments</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charities</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Civic improvement</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Child welfare</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical sciences</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical research</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Maternal health services</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical care</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International relations -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Juvenile delinquency</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Political campaigns -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Political science</subject>
    <subject source="local">Philanthropy -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Performing arts</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Parks -- New York (State)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public policy</subject>
    <subject source="local">Philanthropy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public health administration</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public health</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Prohibition</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc>