<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="under_revision" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA317.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Friends and Services, Series H</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Friends and Services, Series H
 <num>FA317</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><p><date>2009</date></p><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-09-02 11:18:19 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="series">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Friends and Services, Series H</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="ctb" source="naf">Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="naf">Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison), 1839-1937</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="ctb" source="naf">Rockefeller, David</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="ctb" source="naf">Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="naf">Rockefeller, John D., Jr. (John Davison), 1874-1960</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="ctb" source="naf">Rockefeller, John D., III (John Davison), 1906-1978</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="ctb" source="naf">McCormick, Edith Rockefeller</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="ctb" rules="dacs">Prentice, Alta Rockefeller</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="ctb" rules="dacs">Aldrich, Lucy Truman</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="ctb" rules="dacs">Mackenzie King, William Lyon</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="ctb" source="naf">Lee, Ivy L. (Ivy Ledbetter)</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA317</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">71.39 Cubic Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">186 document boxes, 1 oversize box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1886/1961" type="inclusive">1886-1961</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="33c31ae40b2bf9d8f40ea7eecfe0ff53">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
<p>Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Material in the Rockefeller family collections that provides the names, correspondence, or activities of living members of the Rockefeller family, and/or documents the net wealth of any Rockefeller family members, is restricted. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="c483bb21dadeac9a560ecb4417d18948">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
<p>Reproduction/duplication of archival items is routinely provided in accordance with "fair use." If the RAC does not hold copyright for an archival collection, or items within a collection, it is the user's responsibility to contact the copyright holder, or make a fair effort to do so, prior to publication.</p>  </userestrict>
  <arrangement id="40bb8352c43c2de34e090dc1e4ee1476">
    <head>Arrangement note</head>
<p>The Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records are arranged by subject matter in 27 series. Most of these series are wholly or partially open for research. The series are:</p><p>A John D. Rockefeller, Sr.; C Business Interests; D Civic Interests; E Cultural Interests; F Economic Reform Interests; G Educational Interests; H Friends and Services; I Homes; J Housing Interests; K Medical Interests; L Real Estate; M Maps and Memorabilia; N Religious Interests; O Rockefeller Boards; P Welfare - General Files; Q World Affairs; R Welfare - Youth Files; S Documents; T Public Relations; U Public Land Law Review Commission; V Greenrock; W Properties; X Costume Collection; Y Media; Z John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Personal; AA Abby Aldrich Rockefeller; AC Abby Rockefeller Mauzé</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="7737b517d9c1452ed3e7544e4a6dfbd7">
    <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
<p>The central figure in the creation and operation of the Standard Oil Company during its rise to the top of the petroleum industry, John D. Rockefeller (JDR) established for the family a leading role in business and philanthropy. From the days of his earliest employment, Rockefeller, a devout Baptist, was generous in his giving to worthy causes, especially those of a religious nature. During the 1890s he developed an orderly system of philanthropic giving through an office staff that included his close advisor, Frederick T. Gates (1853-1929) and his son, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. (1874-1960). With the advise of these and other associates, Rockefeller established the University of Chicago, The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (now The Rockefeller University), the Rockefeller Foundation, and other philanthropic organizations working nationally and internationally in the fields of education, religion, and health. Rockefeller's total donations to philanthropic endeavors are estimated to have been $540 million.</p><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr. (JDR Jr.) joined his father's office on October 1, 1897. He oversaw the expansion and diversification of the philanthropic work begun by his father. During his lifetime, the younger Rockefeller gave more than $537 million to educational, religious, cultural, medical, and other charitable projects.</p><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and his wife, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller (1874-1948), passed the Rockefeller philanthropic impulse on to their children. Abby (1903-1976), John D. 3rd (1906-1978), Nelson A. (1908-1979), Laurance S. (1910-2004), Winthrop (1912-1973), and David (1915-2017) further expanded and diversified Rockefeller influence and interests, establishing their own philanthropic organizations, most notably the Rockefeller Brothers Fund (1940), and becoming more active politically.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="3aa30b9fd7cbee7ddb8f0fc497dbe119">
    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
<p>The Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller (OMR) materials document the increasing role assumed by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in the management of Rockefeller affairs and amply document his business and philanthropic affairs. They also chronicle the entrance of JDR Jr.'s sons, John D. 3rd, Nelson A., Laurance S., Winthrop, and David, into the world of business, philanthropy, civic leadership, and politics as they joined the office.</p><p>This material contains correspondence, reports, pamphlets, memoranda, deeds, maps, contracts, reports, minutes, charters, certificates of incorporation, clippings, diaries, notebooks, calendars, and memorabilia.</p><p>There is a microfilm card index of personal and institutional names.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <fileplan id="e361f33a0275c7b9d4bfe005d84cee8f">
    <head>File Plan note</head>
<p>Former Classification: III 02</p>  </fileplan>
  <arrangement id="106183f683cf4d66f5e912429db1c7bb">
    <head>Arrangement note</head>
<p>This series is arranged in twenty subseries, as follows:</p><p>Biography; Cemeteries; Chandler and Rudd; Clubs; Dancing; Detectives; Doctors; Donations; Friends and Relations; Horses, Stables, Garages; Office; Portraits; Publicity; Taxes; Requests for Photos of Art Objects; Washington Appeals; Form Letters; Foreign Mail; Family of Alta Rockefeller Prentice; Miscellaneous.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="9a3fada56aa0c782b3d59a0464da95f8">
    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
<p>The Friends and Services series is primarily John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s personal correspondence with his friends and relations. Other files deal with a variety of support, service, and administrative activities such as the operation of the Family Office, family membership in social clubs, family doctors, management of family garages and stables, and arrangement for the biographies of John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p><p>The series contains correspondence between members of the Rockefeller family and the Family Office and friends, relatives, employees, and associates. The correspondence deals with a wide variety of topics. The family members who figure most prominently in the papers are John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Sr., Martha Baird Rockefeller, Edith Rockefeller McCormick and members of her family, and Alta Rockefeller Prentice and members of her family.</p><p>There are twenty sections within the Friends and Services series. Each section is described individually here.</p><p>The Biography section covers the years 1894-1960. Materials in this section discuss the selection of an author and other arrangements for biographies of John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p><p>The Cemeteries section spans the years 1879-1954 and discusses the purchase of burial plots and the upkeep of grave sites.</p><p>The Chandler &amp; Rudd section covers the years 1902-1958. Chandler &amp; Rudd were grocers; W. C. Rudd was John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s brother-in-law. Topics covered in this section of the Friends and Services series include family loans to the firm.</p><p>The Clubs section, with documents dating from 1910 to 1961, includes materials on the family's memberships in and their support of social clubs.</p><p>The Dancing section covers the years 1914-1952; documents in this section include invitations received to dances and arrangements for orchestras for dances at 10 West 54th Street.</p><p>The Detectives section spans the years 1914-1940. Items in this section include requests for positions as private detectives, information about detectives hired to investigate impersonation of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and John D. Rockefeller 3rd (2 cases), and extortion letters (2 cases).</p><p>The Doctors section covers the years 1905-1960. This section consists of files on individual family physicians, mostly correspondence reflecting friendship between John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and family doctors. It also includes information on gifts of appreciation from John D. Rockefeller, Jr., some medical records on John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and the brothers as boys, and some bills. The entire Doctors section is closed to research.</p><p>The Donations section dates from 1894 to 1961 and includes information about small John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. donations and gifts of money, mostly to individuals.</p><p>The Friends and Relations section, which spans the years 1886-1961, is primarily composed of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s correspondence with a multitude of friends, associates, relatives, and acquaintances.</p><p>The Horses, Stables, and Garages section covers the years 1914-1961. Information in this section details the construction, management, and disposal of New York City garages, and the purchase of horses and automobiles.</p><p>The Office section, dated 1919-1961, contains information on the management of the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller. Also included in this section are some employee pension files.</p><p>The Portraits section, which spans the years 1904-1962, discusses the arrangements for portraits of 1st, 2nd, and 3rd generations.</p><p>The Publicity section dates from 1907 to 1961. Materials in this section include clipped articles, correspondence with a variety of magazines and publishing companies regarding requests for interviews, financial assistance, and appreciation for friendly editorials.</p><p>The Taxes section covers the years 1886-1961 and consists of information on real estate and income tax records for John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr., appeals from and contributions to tax reform organizations, and payment of federal and state unemployment tax for family employees.</p><p>The Requests for Photos of Art Objects section consists of one folder and discusses Martha Baird Rockefeller's policy against allowing photographs of her art objects to be used publicly.</p><p>The Washington Appeals section, dated from 1944-1961, contains information about small gifts made to private Washington, DC organizations.</p><p>The Form Letters section, consisting of one folder, contains samples of commonly written letters and legal documents in the Family Office.</p><p>The Foreign Mail section spans the years 1907-1961 and contains financial appeals from foreign organizations and individuals.</p><p>The Family of Alta Rockefeller Prentice section, dated from 1901-1961, pertains to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s sister, the management of her and her heirs' financial affairs by John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr., and the establishment and maintenance of trusts for members of the Prentice family.</p><p>The final section of this series, the Miscellaneous File, contains "a truly kaleidoscopic potpourri of odds and ends."</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical research</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Maternal health services</subject>
    <subject source="local">Philanthropy -- New York (N.Y.)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical care</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Parks -- New York (State)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical sciences</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Performing arts</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Prohibition</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public health</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Political campaigns -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Political science</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public policy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public health administration</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Urban policy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Urban renewal</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War I</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War II</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public welfare</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Religion</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Religious institutions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Restoration and conservation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Rockefeller family -- Art collections</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">State governments -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Travel</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">United States</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Government policy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Folk art</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Federal government -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Family planning</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public relations</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Housing rehabilitation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Health insurance</subject>
    <subject source="local">Philanthropy -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1958</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Economic development</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art, Modern</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art -- Collectors and collecting</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Economics</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Economic policy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charitable contributions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charities -- Investments</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charities</subject>
    <subject source="local">Philanthropy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Business</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Arts</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Capital investments</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises, Foreign</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International relations</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Juvenile delinquency</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International relations -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Civic improvement</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Child welfare</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International economic relations</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International cooperation</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc>