<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="under_revision" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA319.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Housing Interests, Series J</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Housing Interests, Series J
 <num>FA319</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><p><date>2009</date></p><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-09-02 11:18:36 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="series">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Housing Interests, Series J</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="naf">Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison), 1839-1937</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="naf">Rockefeller, David</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="naf">Rockefeller, John D., Jr. (John Davison), 1874-1960</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA319</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10.02 Cubic Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">26 boxes.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1896/1962" type="inclusive">1896-1962</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="5f04fc5a09a6c7e79359619e0ffe305a">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
<p>Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Material in the Rockefeller family collections that provides the names, correspondence, or activities of living members of the Rockefeller family, and/or documents the net wealth of any Rockefeller family members, is restricted. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="c807abb88b8df6f00ebec2613a39ef76">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
<p>Reproduction/duplication of archival items is routinely provided in accordance with "fair use." If the RAC does not hold copyright for an archival collection, or items within a collection, it is the user's responsibility to contact the copyright holder, or make a fair effort to do so, prior to publication.</p>  </userestrict>
  <arrangement id="f18faca03ac42dcd9db69db50570c50e">
    <head>Arrangement note</head>
<p>The Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records are arranged by subject matter in 27 series. Most of these series are wholly or partially open for research. The series are:</p><p>A John D. Rockefeller, Sr.  C Business Interests D Civic Interests E Cultural Interests F Economic Reform Interests G Educational Interests H Friends and Services I Homes J Housing Interests K Medical Interests L Real Estate M Maps and Memorabilia N Religious Interests O Rockefeller Boards P Welfare - General Files Q World Affairs R Welfare - Youth Files S Documents T Public Relations U Public Land Law Review Commission V Greenrock W Properties X Costume Collection Y Media Z John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Personal AA Abby Aldrich Rockefeller AC Abby Rockefeller Mauzé</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="157a1ddefe68f2ba9e8ab900aaf01a9d">
    <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
<p>The central figure in the creation and operation of the Standard Oil Company during its rise to the top of the petroleum industry, John D. Rockefeller (JDR) established for the family a leading role in business and philanthropy. From the days of his earliest employment, Rockefeller, a devout Baptist, was generous in his giving to worthy causes, especially those of a religious nature. During the 1890s he developed an orderly system of philanthropic giving through an office staff that included his close advisor, Frederick T. Gates (1853-1929) and his son, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. (1874-1960). With the advise of these and other associates, Rockefeller established the University of Chicago, The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (now The Rockefeller University), the Rockefeller Foundation, and other philanthropic organizations working nationally and internationally in the fields of education, religion, and health. Rockefeller's total donations to philanthropic endeavors are estimated to have been $540 million.</p><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr. (JDR Jr.) joined his father's office on October 1, 1897. He oversaw the expansion and diversification of the philanthropic work begun by his father. During his lifetime, the younger Rockefeller gave more than $537 million to educational, religious, cultural, medical, and other charitable projects.</p><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and his wife, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller (1874-1948), passed the Rockefeller philanthropic impulse on to their children. Abby (1903-1976), John D. 3rd (1906-1978), Nelson A. (1908-1979), Laurance S. (1910-2004), Winthrop (1912-1973), and David (1915-2017) further expanded and diversified Rockefeller influence and interests, establishing their own philanthropic organizations, most notably the Rockefeller Brothers Fund (1940), and becoming more active politically.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="9a6b9d5ecded1b5de791b19b97588462">
    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
<p>The Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller (OMR) materials document the increasing role assumed by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in the management of Rockefeller affairs and amply document his business and philanthropic affairs. They also chronicle the entrance of JDR Jr.'s sons, John D. 3rd, Nelson A., Laurance S., Winthrop, and David, into the world of business, philanthropy, civic leadership, and politics as they joined the office.</p><p>This material contains correspondence, reports, pamphlets, memoranda, deeds, maps, contracts, reports, minutes, charters, certificates of incorporation, clippings, diaries, notebooks, calendars, and memorabilia.</p><p>There is a microfilm card index of personal and institutional names.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <fileplan id="17264a44fc3e2e482f59c4ae180a4f32">
    <head>File Plan note</head>
<p>Former Classification: III 02</p>  </fileplan>
  <scopecontent id="fc58f40466298f12c5bf1cead4dfa0c4">
    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
<p>The Housing Files comprise 8 cubic feet of material covering the years 1896-1962. The bulk of the material relates to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s activities in the housing field during the 1920s and 1930s. However, there are significant sections which detail the interests of Mr. Rockefeller, Sr. in Cleveland and New York City, and David Rockefeller in the Morningside Heights project. A few scattered files cover the activities of Messrs. John, Nelson, and Laurance Rockefeller in this field. Substantively, these files deal with Mr. Rockefeller, Jr.'s involvement with housing reform and housing projects during two distinct time periods: the period of great optimism and activity during the 1920s, and the period of destabilization and disengagement from the field after the coming of the New Deal and into the 1940s.</p><p>These files focus on eight major housing developments: Forest Hill Estates in Cleveland; the City Housing Corporation's efforts at Sunnyside Gardens in Queens; Thomas Garden Apartments in the Bronx; Paul Laurance Dunbar Housing in Harlem; Lavoisier Apartments in Manhattan; Van Tassel Apartments in Tarrytown; and Radburn in New Jersey. For each of these developments, the files contain comprehensive information on the origin of the project, financing, construction, architecture, relations with government officials, taxation, and problems in operation after completion. Memoranda and other correspondence, including copies of deeds, indentures, and contracts, dealing with both purchase and sale, are also included. Interspersed throughout the specific project folders is correspondence with prominent individuals in the housing field, politicians, and businessmen. The most significant among these are Richard T. Ely, Alexander Bing of the City Housing Corporation, Lawrence Veiller and Robert DeForest of the New York City Housing Commission, Harold Ickes, Governor Alfred E. Smith, Jesse Jones of the Reconstruction Finance Corporation and Mayors Walker, Hyland, and LaGuardia.</p><p>Each of these projects was an innovative effort to solve the serious housing problems of the period. Moreover, they reflected Mr. Rockefeller's abiding commitment to meaningful reform. He viewed his own efforts in the housing field as business rather than philanthropy. He believed that governmental housing in the form of either direct construction or subsidies would be ineffective and, in the long run, self-defeating. He proposed an alternative, one of "cooperation", which would allow capital a modest profit while providing the working and middle classes with modern, affordable housing, which they would eventually own. In this sense, Mr. Rockefeller's housing efforts were a subset of his more comprehensive belief that a rational and compassionate social order could be built through partnership and cooperation rather than through class conflict and governmental intervention.</p><p>Material on the Morningside Heights development constitutes the second largest bloc of documents in this series; there are four boxes covering the period 1946-1961. Unlike the other project files, the Morningside Heights folders are very fragmentary and superficial. Occasional memoranda on tenant relocation and construction questions are submerged within a sea of press releases, brochures, speeches, and technical reports. The story of Morningside Heights cannot be traced through these papers. What is included reflects Mr. David Rockefeller's involvement with the Morningside Heights Development Council and the concern for better public schools. The subsequent arguments over tenant dislocation, Columbia's role as a landlord, and the other issues which came to the fore after 1961 are simply not present in these files.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public health</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Prohibition</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Political science</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Political campaigns -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public policy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public health administration</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Parks -- New York (State)</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State)</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical sciences</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Performing arts</subject>
    <subject source="local">Philanthropy -- New York (N.Y.)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Health insurance</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1958</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public relations</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Housing rehabilitation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Religion</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public welfare</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Restoration and conservation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Religious institutions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">State governments -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Rockefeller family -- Art collections</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">United States</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Travel</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Urban renewal</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Urban policy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War II</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War I</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Business</subject>
    <subject source="local">Philanthropy -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Arts</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Capital investments</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises, Foreign</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Economic development</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art -- Collectors and collecting</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art, Modern</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Economic policy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Economics</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Folk art</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Government policy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Family planning</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Federal government -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Maternal health services</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical care</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical research</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International relations</subject>
    <subject source="local">Philanthropy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International relations -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Juvenile delinquency</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Child welfare</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Civic improvement</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International cooperation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International economic relations</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charitable contributions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charities</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charities -- Investments</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc>