<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="https://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 https://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA406.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Near East Foundation records, Accession 2009:104, RG 1</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Near East Foundation records, Accession 2009:104, RG 1 <num>FA406</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>Telephone: 914-631-4505</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 914-631-6017</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2025-01-01 05:01:34 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="recordgrp">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Near East Foundation records, Accessions 2009:104, RG 1</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" source="naf">Near East Foundation</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="ctb" source="naf">Near East Relief (Organization)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA406</unitid>
    <unitid type="aspace_uri">/repositories/2/resources/605</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">227.14 Cubic Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">161 boxes, including but not limited to 150 standard record storage boxes, </extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1915/2003" type="inclusive">1915-2003</unitdate>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1980" type="bulk">1940-1980</unitdate>
    <physdesc id="528f8698e085661015afd7b95e57b728">The Near East Foundation records consist of approximately 173 storage boxes of archival material</physdesc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="b48305c721c16414c8de05d4535acaee">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Cleveland H. Dodge and a group of New York philanthropists formed the Committee for Armenian and Syrian Relief in 1915 (as a response to American Ambassador to the Ottoman Empire Henry Morgenthau's plea for assistance). The Committee was chartered by the U.S. Congress as "Near East Relief" (NER) in 1919.</p><p>John D. Rockefeller Sr. was one of the first major contributors to the NER. During World War I, the NER is credited with saving 1 million lives of Armenians, Assyrians, Arabs and Persians. From 1915-1930, the NER raised $110 million for refugees. Among its accomplishments, the NER: fed 12 million people; built 40 hospitals; and housed, fed and educated 132,000 children in orphanages and provided them with medical care.</p><p>In 1930, Near East Relief officially changed its name to the Near East Foundation and refocused its activities, beyond refugee relief, to become the first international development organization with the objective of catalyzing long-term sustainability through vocational education, training and agricultural programs including experimental projects and instruction.  </p><p>NEF identifies local communities in need of development assistance, and mobilizes them into grassroots civil society organizations that work to create homegrown solutions to the community's problems. </p><p>NEF staff is native members of the communities that they work in. They help guide the people of the community through stages of problem-solving, effective collaboration, and the formation of responsive civil society organizations to develop self-sustaining activities, programs and long-term societies. NEF commonly operates in active yet unstable settlements. These communities are generally beyond the emergency relief stage, yet they need systemic development assistance to build stability and facilitate their long-term survival. NEF operates in Albania, Bulgaria, Greece, Egypt, Lebanon, Mali, Morocco, Sudan, Syria, and throughout the Middle East and Africa.</p><p>The NEF's "self-help" approach created the models for the Marshall Plan, Truman's Point-4 Program, the Peace Corp, the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) and the United Nations Development Program (UNDP).</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="5e5e389f6170d7ad62b71acc4de3f14e">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection documents the Near East Foundation (1930-2003, bulk 1940s-1980s), focusing on its international development and technical assistance programs at the country and local community levels. Its focus on developing problem-solving civil society organizations, international relations, vocational training and sustainable international development, compliments many of the RAC collections, and tells an important philanthropic story of a region of the world not particularly well represented by other RAC holdings.    </p><p>Materials include but are not limited to: project files, USAID task orders and reports, Administration files, donor files and donor cards, financial statements, personnel files and contracts, publications, and documentation of special events. 
There are extensive, rich, and historically significant files documenting NEF projects and activities throughout the Near East, Middle East and Africa. </p><p>The files, reports and task orders documenting the NEF work with the Agency for International Development (AID) are also extremely rich and highly significant for research purposes. </p><p>Documentation of the Near East Relief period (1915-1930), and those records related to the Armenian genocide, is limited and sporadic.</p><p>The collection also contains a high volume of special format holdings including: photographs, slides, albums, scrapbooks, audio cassettes, film strips, and various items used in the 2003 exhibition at the Museum of the City of New York.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="0d60476c5dcddaf4d8dba77cae321cc7">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>NEF records are intellectually arranged loosely into series to facilitate access. The collection remains physicallly arranged as received by Rockefeller Archive Center.</p><p>All users of this collection guide are encouraged to refer to the entire guide when considering materials that may be pertinent or otherwise relevant to their research.   </p>  </arrangement>
  <processinfo id="45059f0bc1ee5355feed20cd1478ba03">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The NEF held a historical exhibition at the Museum of the City of New York in 2003 entitled: "Near East/New York: The Near East Foundation and American Philanthropy". The collection contains several files documenting the exhibition and its preparation. Some items with significant research value were removed from their original files during exhibition preparation and were subsequently transferred to RAC as components of the exhibition. These items will be returned to their original files during further processing (if such identification and arrangement is feasible).</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="588480625a39ecbb9bce92d178fb96af">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="435e3557c018674f2ea3c581edf17d86">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>The Rockefeller Archive Center has title, copyright, and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them, and has authority to grant permission to cite and publish archival material from the collection.</p>  </userestrict>
  <processinfo id="3892b9fade9643a3ce78dfa7906f886b">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Preliminary archival processing of the Near East Foundation records has been conducted by the Rockefeller Archive Center staff to establish intellectual and physical control of the material and assess its immediate preservation and conservation needs. Further archival processing, primarily to arrange the records to facilitate more efficient access to the collection and address its long-term preservation, will be conducted at a later date, as necessary.</p><p>A folder-level descriptive inventory was prepared by Mary Robbins (RAC Administrative Assistant) in 2006. This inventory was revised and enhanced by NEF sponsored summer interns in 2010. Front matter was compiled in 2011, and the finding aid was entered into the RAC collection management system by Diane April in 2012.</p><p>The Rockefeller Archive Center recognizes that our archival collections may contain problematic language and/or content.</p><p>Accompanying description, most often with creator or donor-generated language and terminology, has to this point been retained and maintained "as received" by RAC with minimal archivist intervention or augmentation.</p><p>We acknowledge these problems and aim to cultivate inclusive representation and equity by reconsidering and enhancing our description of this material with current sensibilities.</p>  </processinfo>
  <separatedmaterial id="275a3fd22541d8b80e09e8ad25bc10ee">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>Various photographs and special formats have been separated from the body of the collection to address their specific storage and preservation needs.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <dsc>