<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA787.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Rockefeller, Laurance S. papers, Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission, RG 6</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission, RG 6 <num>FA787</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-09-02 19:52:20 -0400</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="recordgrp">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission, RG 6</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="naf">Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" source="naf">United States. Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA787</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">15.66 Cubic Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">37 standard document boxes, 3 legal document boxes, 1 standard half document box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1949/1964" type="inclusive">1949-1964</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1958/1963" type="bulk">1958-1963</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="86f360c78185453ccd5090d016a83c9b">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>In 1958 President Dwight D. Eisenhower selected Laurance Rockefeller to head the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission, a fact-finding and advisory group created by Congress. Eight of ORRRC's fifteen members came from Congress and seven were presidential appointees. Their assignment was to determine the outdoor recreation needs of the American people to the year 2000 and recommend policies and programs necessary to assure that the needs will be met. A year later funds were appropriated and the commission set to work. </p><p>ORRRC conducted the most comprehensive fact-finding study ever made in this field and the results were published in 27 volumes. The major findings and more than 50 recommendations were contained in ORRRC's own report, Outdoor Recreation for America, submitted to President John F. Kennedy and Congress in 1962. This report presented a five-point program designed to improve and increase recreation use of both public and private land and water resources, to make more effective use of existing recreation areas and to acquire new ones, particularly shoreline. This program spelled out proposals for a national recreation policy; a classification system for outdoor recreation resources; expansion, modification and intensification of existing programs; a Federal Bureau of Outdoor Recreation and a program of grants-in-aid to the states. </p><p>The ORRRC Report envisioned a "long-range sustained effort -- both public and private" to achieve the goals fixed for the nation in the outdoors. While recognizing the need for acquiring additional parklands, ORRRC stressed making more effective use of resources already available but overly restricted or not used at all for recreation. The commission also presented a strong case for providing natural, or open, areas in the first- step planning of the new communities that the expanding population would require. </p><p>The acceptance of the ORRRC recommendations was extraordinary. In the months following their presentation a number were put into effect by legislative action or administrative ruling. A new Bureau of Outdoor Recreation and a cabinet-level Federal Recreation Council was established, with the Bureau carrying forward many of the specific program recommendations. </p><p>Most significant, perhaps, was that the ORRRC Report engendered a new enthusiasm and awareness for conservation and outdoor recreation. Citing the commission's recommendations, state and local governments initiated new programs.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="98ecc3608c14faca4779764295677cbc">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection documents the creation, implementation, and general activities of the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission from 1949-1964 with the bulk of the material dated between 1958 and 1963. The collection consists primarily of background material relating to members of the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission, as well as correspondence between Laurance Rockefeller and his advisors, reports, studies, and speeches given by Laurance Rockefeller and others.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="4da94d00fe1a7e0c5af4acc6d1891d41">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission papers have been arranged into ten series to represent a simplified version of its original organization structure:</p><p>Series 1: Administrative Records; 
Series 2: Advisors, Representatives, and Staff Members; 
Series 3: Contracts and Financial Materials; 
Series 4: Geographical Areas; 
Series 5: Government Relations
Series 6: Reports and Studies; 
Series 7: Laurance S. Rockefeller; 
Series 8: General Files; 
Series 9: Meetings; 
Series 10: Clippings</p>  </arrangement>
  <separatedmaterial id="4ceb3231bac233c4e9ebde98284943fd">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>Special format items have been separated from the body of the collection and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <accessrestrict id="462ecb44dae032b97e79964be90c50f1">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Collection is open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="0d223a3004d1d811cc7c0c6096f886e0">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>RAC has title, copyright and literary rights to the papers in so far as it holds them.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="5b2c5eeef41bdf08501913daa7bd4468">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Donated to RAC by the estate of Laurance S. Rockefeller, January 2009.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Outdoor recreation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">National parks and reserves -- Planning</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Wilderness areas -- Recreational use</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Federal aid to outdoor recreation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Recreation and state</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc>