<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA089.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Pearce (Richard M.) papers</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Richard M. Pearce papers
 <num>FA089</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><p><date>2009</date></p><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-06-10 00:01:29 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Richard M. Pearce papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="naf">Pearce, Richard Mills</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA089</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.1 Cubic Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">1 folder</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1901/1921" type="inclusive">1901-1921</unitdate>
  </did>
  <fileplan id="0f74095fb441c5411d8850a988a6c16d">
    <head>File Plan</head>
<p>Former Classification: IV 2A 04</p>  </fileplan>
  <prefercite id="3b08eaed03b1473c1b3d120300a6b65d">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="3815c543b005eefe1e7953319c2665af">
    <head>Processing Information note</head>
<p>Processing was completed as of September 12, 1969, and August 19, 1974. Inventory and processing of paper records at a later date.</p>  </processinfo>
  <userestrict id="b01ca57bb0485c0428a8944a745f5bcf">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Reproduction/duplication of archival items is routinely provided in accordance with "fair use."  If the RAC does not hold copyright for an archival collection, or items within a collection, it is the user's responsibility to contact the copyright holder, or make a fair effort to do so, prior to publication.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="ee1061155ad47949ec5311002cde90ab">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
<p>(Accession 7) The photographs of Richard M. Pearce were deposited with The Rockefeller Foundation Archives in June 1967 by Mrs. Richard M. Pearce.</p><p>(Accession 49) The Richard M. Pearce Collection was given to The Rockefeller Foundation Archives on August 15, 1974 by Miss Agnes Pearce of Dorset, Vemont. There are no restrictions.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="caa96fb3e7b44731ca0229f28bc9cc86">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Richard M. Pearce was born in Montreal in March 1874. He received his early education at the Boston Latin School and then entered Harvard University where he received a degree in medicine in 1897.</p><p>From 1897-1899, Dr. Pearce was a resident pathologist at the Boston City Hospital and the following year became an instructor in pathology at Harvard. In 1900 he went to the University of Pennsylvania where he was demonstrator and assistant professor of pathology. Dr. Pearce was called to become Director of the Bender Hygienic Laboratory in 1903. The Bender Lab was affiliated with the Albany Medical School, and Dr. Pearce was professor of pathology and bacteriology at that institution. He assumed the same position at Bellevue Hospital College in 1908. He then returned to the University of Pennsylvania in 1910, where he was a professor of pathology and held the Chair of Experimental Medicine.</p><p>During World War I, Dr. Pearce joined the Army as a Major in the Medical Corps and during the war years was Secretary of the Medical Advisory Committee of the Red Cross, Director of the Bureau of Foreign Medical Service and Chairman of the National Research Council.</p><p>In 1919 Dr. Pearce joined The Rockefeller Foundation as Director of the Division of Medical Sciences. He remained in that position until his death in 1930.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="a2dfe0aa325b71822a5dce72c1977562">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="a7a1a8b47c03aab7bcede48b56a8b3b8">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>1. Richard M. Pearce, 1906. 2. Richard M. Pearce, 1906. 3. Major Richard M. Pearce, 1918. 4. Richard M. Pearce, Chile, 1919. 5. Dinner in honor of Richard M. Pearce, Sao Paulo, Brazil, 1919. 6. Dinner in honor of Richard M. Pearce, Sao Paulo, Brazil, 1922. 7. Bender Laboratory and staff, Albany New York, 1904-1909. 8. Richard M. Pearce and Dr. Urrutia, acting as interpreter, Buenos Aires, Argentina, [January 17, 1927]. 9. Richard M. Pearce, Dr. Crowell and Mrs. Crowell, Rio de Janeiro, 1919. 10. Richard M. Pearce and group, Santiago, Chile, 1919. 11. Richard M. Pearce and group, Chile, 1919. 12. Bailey K. Ashford, Richard M. Pearce, John A. Ferrell, and fourth individual, Rio de Janeiro, 1916. 13. Richard M. Pearce and the staff of Portuguese Hospital, Rio de Janeiro, 1916. 14. Richard M. Pearce visiting a coffee plantation, Sao Paulo, 1916. 15. Richard M. Pearce, mayor and health officers, Rio Grande, 1916. 16. Richard M. Pearce and group, Germany, 1901. 17. Richard M. Pearce and group, University of Pennsylvania, 1902. 18. Richard M. Pearce with group of Japanese doctors, Tokyo, Japan, 1921. 19. Lewis Hackett, Richard M. Pearce, and George K. Strode, Nictheroy, Brazil, 1917. 20. Richard M. Pearce, Bailey K. Ashford, Juan Gutierrez, Puerto Rico, 1917.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="c96442116ce620a0532029b0ef1274fc">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>As received.</p>  </arrangement>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Photographs</genreform>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="9c3203d040cc48a9a1923f9b3b703202" level="series"><did><unittitle>Richard M. Pearce photographs</unittitle><unitid>1024</unitid><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.1 Cubic Feet</extent></physdesc></did><controlaccess><genreform source="lcsh">Photographs</genreform></controlaccess><c id="26b7e76fd4354e508f786097c741de23" level="file"><did><unittitle>Richard M. Pearce</unittitle><materialspec id="5c0876d3055454d3e5d4c263469fe41a">Approximately 10 prints</materialspec><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="cfe769faed5797b03b489a0b3c7b0a64" label="Still Image [A0000000055098]" type="box">10</container><container id="7d0461f3f6fe09dd9efe05c00386b921" parent="cfe769faed5797b03b489a0b3c7b0a64" type="folder">91</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
