<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="under_revision" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA920.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Rockefeller University records, Rockefeller University Press, Journals Department, Manager, Margaret Broadbent</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Rockefeller University Press, Journals Department, Manager, Margaret Broadbent
 <num>FA920</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-04-04 00:22:21 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Rockefeller University records, Rockefeller University Press, Journals Department, Manager, Margaret Broadbent</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" rules="dacs">Rockefeller University Press</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" source="naf">Rockefeller University</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA920</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.38 Cubic Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">1 letter document box.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1971/1983" type="inclusive">1971-1975, 1979, 1983</unitdate>
    <physdesc id="53b2122b4bf05591767265fc2b182cf6" label="General Physical Description note">1 box.</physdesc>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="5d62f4c53ee3bc590ee06ab37d18453a">
    <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
<p>In order to assist in the dissemination of scientific investigations conducted at the Institute and elsewhere, publication was an early and important activity of The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research. A senior member of the scientific staff was usually the editor of a periodical. As early as 1910 the Institute had a Publication Service, which was supervised from 1910 by Editha C. Campbell until she retired in the fall of 1940. A Department of Illustration and Photography was under a part-time arrangement with De. Eduard Learning from 1906 until 1910 when Louis Schmidt undertook the direction of a full-time department. Louis Schmidt was at the head of the department until he reached the age of 70 in 1936. The work in the Department of Illustrations included hand-drawn illustrations for publications, photographs, moving pictures of experimental procedures made for the various investigators and used for a variety of purposes. Louis Schmidt served on a consultant basis until his death in 1939. Joseph Blauvelt Haulenbeek was acting in charge of Illustrations during that time and named officially in charge of illustrations in 1942, serving until he resigned September 1, 1946. Julian Alexander Carlile who was in charge of illustrations in the Department of Animal and Plant Pathology at Princeton took charge of the New York Department starting October 1, 1947 and divided his time between the two departments until they were consolidated during 1950. He directed the expanding department until his death in 1959 when he was succeeded by Richard F. Carter until 1964. In the academic year 1968/1969 Lewis William Koster became Manager of Graphic Services until 1973. March 1973 Bill Leyrer was appointed to that position.</p><p>Florence M. Stewart succeeded Editha Campbell in charge of the Publication Service in 1940 and served until she retired June 30, 1963, when she was succeeded by Margaret E. Broadbent.</p><p>Effective January 1, 1957 Charles Irvin Campbell was appointed Administrative Associate for Information Services. He had responsibility for a variety of information services among which were Secretary of the Library Committee, Librarian, ex officio, and supervision of the Publication Service and Illustration and Duplicating Services. Included were publication duties of such items as the Annual Report, Rockefeller Institute Quarterly, and the Calendar of Events. On October 20, 1958 the Board of Trustees approved a cooperative arrangement with the Oxford University Press to assist in producing, advertising and selling publications of the newly established Rockefeller Institute Press. The plan was for the Institute to continue publishing journals in accord with previously established policy and arrangements. Charles I. Campbell was appointed Director of The Rockefeller Institute Press. The Publications Service became the Journals Department without change of personnel or function. A new Books and Reports Department was created with responsibility for the production of books and the publication of bulletins and reports issued by the Institute.</p><p>January 1, 1960 Reynard F. Biemiller was appointed Assistant Director of The Rockefeller Institute Press. Effective December 5, 1960 Raymond B. Griffiths was appointed to the newly created position of Executive Editor of the Journal of Cell Biology.</p><p>Charles I. Campbell resigned May 15, 1962 and Joseph G. Sutton served as Acting Director of the Press from January 1963 until in 1964 William Arthur Bayless was named Director of the Press.</p><p>William Bayless retired as Director of The Rockefeller University Press on February 8, 1980. As of February 11, 1980, Mrs. Helene Jordan agreed to serve as acting director of the Press.</p><p>Effective July 1, 1980, Mrs. Helene Jordan was appointed Director of The Rockefeller University Press.</p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="c977d1a842e8ad0d1629340a2a9dd421">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Updated by Lee R. Hiltzik, December 2007.</p>  </processinfo>
  <arrangement id="1359cd953bb5c7bdffe737efa2756ce1">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Arranged primarily in chronological order.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="f448e86ce0720cafdcc822b3f5f05fca">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Includes memoranda, correspondence, committee drafts, and minutes of meetings of the Council of Biology Editors, Inc.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="0e119a8bbf0858db82841fc6b15145b1">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Margaret Broadbent was the chairperson of the Publication Committee in 1973. She held the position of manager of the Rockefeller University Press' Journals Department during the early 1970s. Additions to the collection relate to her retirement in 1979.</p>  </bioghist>
  <accessrestrict id="33b0983717dcc971b6554b4c16ae1c64">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Collection is open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <prefercite id="0accab592106f8ba2cbf1498dabf7d70">
    <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
<p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>  </prefercite>
  <fileplan id="cd4e00778e4d628b5a2aa084f0c2a812">
    <head>File Plan note</head>
<p>Former Classification: I 515-1</p>  </fileplan>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Biology -- Research</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Science -- Study and teaching</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medicine, Preventive</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical technology</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Cell and biomolecular sciences</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical sciences</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical research</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Life sciences</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="add3c7768d10437284dad80bf8d3f3db" level="file"><did><unittitle>Council of Biology Editors, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1971/1975" type="inclusive">1971-1975</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="91168d4a7969c1e52d8900aebe448388" label="mixed materials [A0000000092964]" type="box">1</container><container id="00355f84ae9da6f375f8f3ba87bbd3d3" parent="91168d4a7969c1e52d8900aebe448388" type="folder">1-8</container></did></c><c id="3bd336605a7f4d3f91d8ed08a17390e1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Retirement Letters</unittitle><unitdate normal="1979/1979" type="inclusive">1979</unitdate><physdesc id="ec28e50e79e4f2f0f00d73f71417c360" label="General Physical Description note">1 of 2</physdesc><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="ede525a4ecd80aa0a52f62f28324bf41" label="mixed materials [A0000000092964]" type="box">1</container><container id="60079674658831e4e62e7a2ffdc9b4b2" parent="ede525a4ecd80aa0a52f62f28324bf41" type="folder">9</container></did></c><c id="396a98153eed48e99d942bd3a915b2c4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Retirement Letters</unittitle><unitdate normal="1979/1979" type="inclusive">1979</unitdate><physdesc id="a142e43f66cd0335de902ed26bca6d9b" label="General Physical Description note">2 of 2</physdesc><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="7539c7e7f9ecdcd03b8b5cfe26192e46" label="mixed materials [A0000000092964]" type="box">1</container><container id="6ddebaa1df1cf0914228b6ff88f8e422" parent="7539c7e7f9ecdcd03b8b5cfe26192e46" type="folder">10</container></did></c><c id="510f414c3cdc4f059f86a8a9c4b3cf9f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Retirement Photographs</unittitle><unitdate normal="1979/1979" type="inclusive">1979</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="e00f229bb459d7f5b60c211e3ced5f15" label="mixed materials [A0000000092964]" type="box">1</container><container id="db642830a5151131698fd4e7b0f5bd2d" parent="e00f229bb459d7f5b60c211e3ced5f15" type="folder">11</container></did></c><c id="533ffcf4a64e4c3fae247ed112c5cbb6" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Margaret Broadbent: Meritorious Awardee 1983" in CBE Views</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1983-09-23/1983-12-22" type="inclusive">1983 Fall</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="ccd122088f86cdb8dee84041fd84db92" label="mixed materials [A0000000092964]" type="box">1</container><container id="4aa354a3516e408eb3a4f1eb792190c1" parent="ccd122088f86cdb8dee84041fd84db92" type="folder">12</container></did></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
