<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="under_revision" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA226.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Rockefeller University records, History of the University</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, History of the University
 <num>FA226</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-08-07 00:02:50 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2010 October 12</date><item>Paper finding aid converted to EAD/XML by AureXus in 2010. Imported into the Archvists’ Toolkit by Becky Robbins.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Rockefeller University records, History of the University</unittitle>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname role="aut" source="naf">Rockefeller University</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="creator">
      <corpname role="ctb" source="naf">Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA226</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.57 Cubic Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">2 boxes and 5 volumes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1901/1924" type="inclusive">1901-1924</unitdate>
    <physdesc id="8b2d88fbf6993ffa09d9e6768b74b4bf">2 boxes and 5 volumes.</physdesc>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="604760689d11c321f80cc56d886e03d3">
    <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
<p>The work of The Institute concentrated on basic research. The hope was that the discoveries might, in the long run, be applied to the public welfare, but the basic purpose was to provide an environment for exploratory original research by individuals under no compulsion to produce immediately useful results.</p><p>Scientific work of The Institute was first carried on through grants-in-aid made to researchers in scattered laboratories. This program decreased as the Institute's own laboratories developed. July 1, 1904 temporary quarters were rented at 127 East 50th Street, New York and work began there about Nov. 1, 1904. Those recruited for the first staff were Eugene L. Opie, Samuel J. Meltzer, Hideyo Noguchi and Joshua Edwin Sweet. Added to the staff very shortly were Phoebus Aaron Theodor Levene and John Auer. Alexis Carrel joined The Institute in 1906 and Jacques Loeb in 1910. On June 13, 1907 the Board of Directors voted to establish various classes of association with The Institute. The classes were: Member (for an indefinite period); Associate Member (for five year periods; amended in 1911 Rules to "a term of years); Associate of The Institute; Fellow of The Institute; Scholar of The Institute (which was dropped in the Rules amended 1928). The first Members of The Institute were Simon Flexner, S.J. Meltzer, E.L. Opie, and P.A.T. Levene.</p><p>In April 1906 the Central Laboratory with animal house and power house, located on York Avenue and 66th Street were ready for use. Simon Flexner, the first Director of the laboratories had been unanimously elected Director of The Institute on Oct. 25, 1902. However, not until a meeting on Jan. 17, 1920 did the Board make clear its sense that these were two offices, both held by Simon Flexner. The Office of Director of The Institute was clearly added in amended Rules Oct. 18, 1924. Simon Flexner was Director of The Institute and Director of the laboratories until his retirement in 1935. He was succeeded in both offices by Herbert S. Gasser, 1935-1953.</p><p>In 1910, at the York Avenue site a Hospital was opened so that the investigations of the Laboratories could be supplemented by the study of certain diseases as they actually occur in man. The Rules for the Scientific Directors as adopted on Jan. 21, 1911, provided that The Institute be comprised of two coordinate departments, Laboratories and Hospital. Rufus Cole was the first Director of the Department of the Hospital and continued in this post until his retirement in 1937 when he was succeeded by Thomas M. Rivers. The Hospital accepted only a limited number of patients, limited further to classes of diseases under study in the Hospital laboratories. The By-Laws of the Corporation provided that The Institute make no charge to persons treated at the Hospital for professional care rendered or for board and lodging. Classes of appointment to the Hospital were Physician, Assistant Physician, Resident Physician, Superintendent and Assistant Superintendent. In 1946 an amendment to the Rules provided that the titles be as follows: Physician-in-Chief to the Hospital; Physician to the Hospital; Assistant Physician to the Hospital; Resident Associate Physician; Senior Assistant Physician; Superintendent of the Hospital; Assistant Superintendent of the Hospital.</p><p>In 1914, at a location about three miles from Princeton, N.J. with Theobald Smith as Director, a new Department of Animal Pathology was established. In June 1915 the Rules were amended to make this coordinate with the Departments of Laboratories and Hospital. When Theobald Smith retired in 1930 Carl TenBroeck became Director of the Department which in 1931 was expanded by the appointment of Louis O. Kunkel who headed the new division of plant pathology into the Department of Animal and Plant Pathology.</p><p>The Director of each Department was appointed by the Board of Scientific Directors, and the Director of The Institute by the Corporation. In the different departments separate laboratories were organized under the guidance of a Member or Associate Member. The broad divisions of scientific fields varied from time to time in accordance with scientific developments and the interests of the Members, but always with consultation, approval and direction of the Board of Scientific Directors.</p><p>In 1953, after the retirement of Herbert S. Gasser, an extensive reorganization was undertaken. Thomas M. Rivers, who served for two years as Vice-President of the Corporation and at the same time, Director of the Laboratories, Director of the Department of the Hospital and Physician-in-Chief to the Hospital retired in 1955. The position of Director of The Institute was abolished and also the organization into departments.</p><p>On and after November 19, 1954 when the Charter of the Corporation was amended so that the Corporation became part of the University of the State of New York The Institute had the power to confer degrees. On June 27, 1958 by amendment to the Charter the corporate name was changed to The Rockefeller Institute and on May 27, 1965 the Charter of The Institute was amended in its entirety and the name changed to The Rockefeller University.</p><p>The University is organized into laboratories, each headed by one or two senior scientists rather than into categorical departments. The scientific work of the laboratories is under the direction of the President.</p>  </bioghist>
  <fileplan id="b436c57fe7425c8205db33b91a3c5093">
    <head>File Plan note</head>
<p>Former Classification: I 400</p>  </fileplan>
  <separatedmaterial id="fe614be7de6783091bde0c0544421b74">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>ALL VOLUMES REMOVED TO RAC LIBRARY 8/9/1988.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <prefercite id="786b08c41f4949adcacfba4ad3854fec">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>  </prefercite>
  <accessrestrict id="bb0ee6ca94e5bb6a52863b9506c41397">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
<p>Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <scopecontent id="60fbe8d3bf4081bea5ac856025799039">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Types of records include: correspondence and printed materials.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="e087d0584c35613a400ec18d0741e54c">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>As received.</p>  </arrangement>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Operations management</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical sciences</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical research</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Life sciences</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Cell and biomolecular sciences</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Biology -- Research</subject>
    <persname rules="dacs">Greene, Jerome D.</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">Rockefeller Foundation</corpname>
    <persname source="naf">Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison)</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="fb14d279417d42fb904d0bbb3f989ea7" level="series"><did><unittitle>Theophil Mitchell Prudden</unittitle><unitid>1</unitid><unitdate normal="1901/1924" type="inclusive">1901-1924</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="df30286da1d1889e666aa8593971575a"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Unfinished manuscript and drafts.</p><p>History of the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research in manuscript form as planned and written by T. Mitchell Prudden, member of the first Board of Scientific Directors and first chairman of the Executive Committee.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="82a5161f572a4200578cf23385edd952"><head>Arrangement note</head><p>Arranged by chapters and subjects.</p></arrangement><c id="a0803e3fab9e471ab84e75917942d6d2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chapter Manuscripts</unittitle><container altrender="Half Ltr Document Storage Box" id="069688c92e4871ea44fcc82121fa8be9" label="mixed materials [A0000000085494]" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="36836c0057c584c48b9da797c78126ba"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Part 1 in 15 chapters; Part 2 unfinished.</p><p>Listing of chapter headings followed in arrangement.</p><p>Also included is a 14 page exchange between Dr. Prudden and Dr. Peyton Rous on tumor cells in the form of questions and answers. Not dated and no information of the circumstances under which it took place.</p><p>5 letters from E.B. Smith to Dr. Flexner and Dr. James Murphy, 1926-1934 referring to various parts of Prudden's History.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="b5333516ae474d5c98b1456baaa3e0a2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Drafts, Notes and Clippings</unittitle><container altrender="Letter Document Storage Box" id="3d64c65041d1be9a652fcf6b2673a4f0" label="mixed materials [A0000000085495]" type="box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="a911d8fcb0305e771976d6a8b664684d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contains working copies, some originals, some revised copies, some handwritten notes of chapters as found in Box 1.</p><p>Also includes a folder of reprints, clippings and notes used in writing the history.</p><p>Also includes drafts of various reports prepared for the Scientific Directors. Early drafts of the Report with special Reference to a Permanent Endowment, including Hospital plans; plans for a farm; plans for Pension and Retiring Plans; Plans for a third section of the Institute. See Minutes of Scientific Directors, Feb. 10, 1910 for final form.</p><p>Also includes a summary accompanying the Report of Oct. 1914 on the Establishment of New Activities for the Promotion of Public Health (handwritten notations of planned changes)</p></scopecontent></c></c><c id="3de95a0d643b49cf9daa3ce75ee519b5" level="series"><did><unittitle>Books and early articles</unittitle><unitid>2</unitid></did><c id="13be852f16074e8eb72c1ac63b3d6e19" level="file"><did><unittitle>Articles by Burton J. Hendrick</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="4afe2516d17223915a4e013f430872ca"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>These are article citations are provided for reference purposes only. The individual articles are not contained in the collection.</p></scopecontent><c id="e31c9fb955514d09bfd5b13c55207b18" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Work at The Rockefeller Institute. The transplanting of animal organs" McClure's Magazine 32: 367-383</unittitle><unitdate>1909 February</unitdate></did></c><c id="13756a93006146d9a0dea0c55553df50" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Conquering spinal meningitis. What The Rockefeller Institute has done for children" McClure's Magazine 32: 594-604</unittitle><unitdate>1909 April</unitdate></did></c></c><c id="2ce243e689944fc4b2e9be0be10f8de2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Articles indexed in the Reader's Guide to Periodical Literature</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="ffb9aea3c1919cff8e6e2d4e5fe5325e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>These are article citations are provided for reference purposes only. The individual articles are not contained in the collection.</p></scopecontent><c id="ef0f9a4f37b34054ab9925312d3117f3" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Establishment" Popular Science. 62: 564</unittitle><unitdate>1903 April 5</unitdate></did></c><c id="09a5dabcbc7c4cf0b657219c4d640a77" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Plans for the Institute" Independent 55: 467</unittitle><unitdate>1903 February 26</unitdate></did></c><c id="0413662c3c164f96baef08cf5d3b0d91" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Dedication" Science n.s. 24: 12-3</unittitle><unitdate>1906 July 6</unitdate></did></c><c id="5adc99c508b741329cd6937b38eb6b09" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Home for medical research" H.T. Wade il. Sci. Am. 100: 21 2</unittitle><unitdate>1909 January 9</unitdate></did></c><c id="f6774d3500804d9fac2824adc8e3b3c8" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Sketch of development" L.E. Holt, Science n.s. 24: 1-6</unittitle><unitdate>1906 July 6</unitdate></did></c><c id="54d89e86733746e48c6e3eb210b3186d" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Temple of preventive medicine" F. Strother World's Work 13: 8324</unittitle><unitdate>1906 December 6</unitdate></did></c><c id="cf68ebfbfa594c239eeb24e7ee6b349b" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Work at the institute" B.J. Hendrick</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="c00d86898b676f298de03d8d851edf5b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>[See above]</p></scopecontent></c><c id="1db73c4a752240a38510b52f2c5f7b9e" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Work of the institute" H.T. Wade, il. Reviews of Reviews 39: 183-91</unittitle><unitdate>1909 February</unitdate></did></c></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
