<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA1780.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Rockefeller (Winthrop) papers</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Winthrop Rockefeller papers <num>FA1780</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-12-16 07:31:08 -0500</date>.</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Winthrop Rockefeller papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="naf">Rockefeller, Winthrop</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA1780</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12.57 Cubic Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1912/1976" type="inclusive">1912-1976</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="7f99e3449c753f091716f8317e76bce6">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="6e4224119f91e288a6c608e62ffcc192">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Winthrop Rockefeller, born May 1, 1912, was the fourth son of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. After attending the Lincoln School in New York City and the Loomis School in Connecticut, Winthrop enrolled at Yale University for a short period of time. After leaving Yale, Winthrop worked as a roughneck in the oilfields in Texas. </p><p>After serving in the Army during World War II, Winthrop eventually moved to Arkansas in 1953. Purchasing a 927-acre tract of land on Petit Jean Mountain, he built Winrock Farms, which would become famous for breeding Santa Gertrudis cattle.</p><p>In 1948, Winthrop Rockefeller married Barbara "Bobo" Sears, amidst a flurry of publicity. They had one son, Winthrop Paul Rockefeller, and divorced in 1954. In 1956, Winthrop remarried Jeanette Edris, who had two children from a previous marriage. The couple divorced in 1971.</p><p>In 1955, Winthrop accepted a position as Chairman of the Arkansas Industrial Development Commission, serving for eight years.</p><p>Although his bid for governor of Arkansas was unsuccessful in 1964, Winthrop ran again in 1966 and won, making him the first Republican governor in Arkansas in 94 years. He was re-elected in 1968, and served until January 1971 as governor.</p><p>Winthrop Rockefeller died of cancer on February 22, 1973 at the age of 60. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="986fe2735a4eb114a8022adb0d1472ec">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Winthrop Rockfeller papers available at the Rockefeller Archive Center is comprised of three sets of records -- papers maintained by the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller (Room 5600) pertaining primarily to Winthrop's speeches, publicity materials and personal and family correspondence; The microfilmed copy of papers available at the University of Arkansas-Little Rock consisting primarily of his Gubernatorial papers and Arkansas activities including Winrock Enterprises and Winrock Farms; and a small volume of family photographs.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
