<?xml version="1.0"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xd="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/doc/xsl" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd" version="3.4"><identifier type="local">LI01321</identifier><titleInfo><title>The resilient sector :
the state of nonprofit America</title></titleInfo><name><namePart>Salamon, Lester M.</namePart><role><roleTerm type="text" authority="naf">aut</roleTerm></role></name><name><namePart>Brookings Institution</namePart><role><roleTerm type="text" authority="naf">aut</roleTerm></role></name><originInfo><place><placeTerm type="text">Washington, D.C.</placeTerm></place><publisher>Brookings Institution Press</publisher><dateIssued>2003</dateIssued></originInfo><physicalDescription><extent>1 Bound Volumes</extent></physicalDescription><note>Includes bibliographical references (p. 89-105) and index./ "Published in collaboration with the Aspen Institute."</note><abstract>Annotation Salamon (director, Johns Hopkins Center for Civil Society Studies) presents an overview of non-profit, non-governmental organizations in the United States. He provides separate chapters on the challenges and opportunities facing "civil society," later moving on to descriptions of how those challenges and opportunities are being faced by charitable organizations. Salamon is generally positive in his assessment of the state of such organizations, but does not fail to provide his own advice on future directions. Annotation 2004 Book News, Inc., Portland, OR (booknews.com). Annotation The Resilient Sector makes available in an updated form the concise overview of the state of health of America's nonprofit organizations that Johns Hopkins scholar Lester Salamon recently completed as part of the "state of nonprofit America" project he undertook in cooperation with the Aspen Institute. Contrary to popular understanding, Salamon argues, America's nonprofit organizations have shown remarkable resilience in recent years in the face of a variety of difficult challenges, significantly re-engineering themselves in the process. But this very resilience now poses risks for the sector's continued ability to perform the tasks that we have long expected of it. The Resilient Sector offers nonprofit practitioners, policymakers, the press, and the public at large a lively assessment of this set of institutions that we have long taken for granted, but that the Frenchman Alexis de-Toqueville recognized to be "more deserving of our attention" than almost any other part of the American experiment.</abstract><subject authority="lcsh"><topic>Nonprofit organizations</topic></subject><subject authority="lcsh"><geographic>United States</geographic></subject><identifier type="isbn">0815776799</identifier><genre>volume</genre><classification>338.7 SAL CHC</classification></mods>
