<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>FA723.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper type="filing">Ford Foundation records, Overseas Development, South and Southeast Asia (SSEA), Office Files of George Gant</titleproper>
        <titleproper>A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Overseas Development, South and Southeast Asia (SSEA), Office Files of George Gant
 <num>FA723</num></titleproper>
        <author>Arranged and described  by Anneliese Ostendarp, Ford Foundation Archives</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>March 1986</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline>
          <addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline>
          <addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2016-01-06 01:15:21 -0500</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Ford Foundation records, Overseas Development, South and Southeast Asia (SSEA), Office Files of George Gant</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="aut" source="lcnaf">Ford Foundation</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>FA723</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.44 Cubic Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1962/1967" type="inclusive">1962-1967</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_6664beb748d1b873413ac79c5bcbc073">The Office Files of George Gant were transferred to the Archives in 1978 with other material from the International Division/Asia &amp; Pacific. The papers were originally described as "conference files." The correspondence, agendas, working papers and reports were actually generated in connection with various seminars, meetings and study groups that Mr. Gant either attended or helped to organize. These files may not represent all the seminars/meetings that Mr. Gant participated in between 1962 and 1967 but only those retained in his office files. 

Researchers should be aware that there is additional Gant material in the Archives. There is approximately 50' of field office records from Bangkok, Thailand. These field office records include files that were created and maintained by Mr. Gant but continued by his successors and interfiled with their papers. This material was sent to the Archives when the Bangkok office closed in 1981.</abstract>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_2c0a9a7271472d533c93f17230eaaf23">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.</p>
      <p>Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_96f296268d6283375625b3e5ad149f99">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
      <p>Completion of a use agreement is required prior to providing scholarly access. See RAC Head of Reference (or applicable designee) for details. </p>
      <p>Ford Foundation holds title, copyright and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them.</p>
      <p>The Rockefeller Archive Center has authority to grant permission to cite and publish material from the collection for scholarly purposes. Permission to publish extensive excerpts, or material in its entirety, will be referred to the Ford Foundation.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_9cbf9a959aac759e24f48716457e0a73">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
      <p>Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_b970c4b06e489a6edf69363c05ee88c1">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref>.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <phystech id="aspace_28e2613ab79b5f38c9a2648121c31aca">
      <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
      <p>Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. </p>
      <p>Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.</p>
    </phystech>
    <bioghist id="aspace_e583db8817e63b35eb379198cb0033c2">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>George Franklin Gant was a member of the Ford Foundation staff from 1955 until his retirement in 1977. Throughout his career at the Foundation Mr. Gant worked in South and Southeast Asian affairs and served as follows:</p>
      <p>July 1955, Representative, Pakistan
July 1958, Director, South and Southeast Asia Program
January 1967, Head, South &amp; Southeast Asia International Division
August 1967, Special Representatives for Southeast Asian Affairs, Bangkok, Thailand</p>
      <p>Mr. Gant also held the following positions:</p>
      <p>1935-1951, Tennessee Valley Authority, General Manager, Assistant Director &amp; Director of Personnel; Assistant Chief  &amp; Chief of Training &amp; Educational Relations; Research Asst.
1951-1954, Southern Regional Education Board, Consultant on Graduate Education
1955, Harvard Advisory Group, Consultant on Education to the Pakistan Planning Board
1965, University of Wisconsin, Visiting Professor (on leave from FF)</p>
      <p>Mr. Gant was born 26 April 1909. He received his B.A. and M.A. degrees from the University of Nebraska in 1930 and 1931 respectively. He received his Ph.D. from the University of Wisconsin in 1934. </p>
      <p>Mr. Gant also published a number of articles in professional journals on administration, education and overseas development.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_d4cd48aeb76aa475046b173e55675169">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>The Office Files of George Gant consist of a single series, Seminar/ Meeting Files. These files were generated as a result of Mr. Gant's participation as a member or organizer of various seminars, study groups, meetings and advisory groups. The seminars and meetings date from 1962 to 1967 and were sponsored by the Council on Foreign Relations, the Southeast Development Advisory Group, the United Nations and jointly, the Ford Foundation and the Comparative Administration Group (a branch of the American Society for Public Administration). The papers and reports, and measure onehalf foot.</p>
      <p>The files have two research strengths. First is the documentation of the planning process for development and public administration in developing countries: how the questions of who would be trained and how and where they would be trained were considered. The topic of  development administration is addressed in the Ford Foundation/Comparative Administration Group, Southeast Asia/ Development Advisory Group and United Nations folders. A second research strength is found in the Council on Foreign Affairs Study Group folders. These folders contain information on variety of topics (see container listing) but all have a common theme: the emerging roles of India and Pakistan in the strategic and political balance of Asia and the world. </p>
      <p>The files do not document Mr. Gant's 22-year career with the Ford Foundation. However, they do indicate his interests and professional commitment to South Asia and development administration.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_bec7d928e9dbba81be05386b92421242">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>Series I, Seminar/Meeting Files, 1962-1967, consists of one-half foot of correspondence, memoranda, agendas, working papers and reports. The folders are arranged alphabetically by conference/seminar sponsor. Most of the series consists of Council on Foreign Relations material but includes a small amount of material from other national and international organizations interested in development administration in South and Southeast Asia.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <controlaccess>
      <corpname role="aut" source="lcnaf">Ford Foundation</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="aspace_ref10_7qk" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Seminar/Meeting Files</unittitle>
          <unitid>I</unitid>
          <unitdate normal="1962/1967" type="inclusive">1962-1967</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c id="aspace_ref11_7wa" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Council on Foreign Relations - Advisory Group Sino-Indian Relationship</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1963/1963" type="inclusive">1963</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_fb43fcc89f414707011f93e2c3f99788" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_0abb840923ee0b9a6dd2b15b2d5a0a62" parent="aspace_fb43fcc89f414707011f93e2c3f99788" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref12_dd5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Council on Foreign Relations - Study Group South Asia and U.S. Policy in the 1960s</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1962/1963" type="inclusive">1962-1963</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_accac741a71d53154cd3794f3c027f9e" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_5eadc8c66042cde4f7e1f2d972096e5e" parent="aspace_accac741a71d53154cd3794f3c027f9e" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref13_9o9" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>International Flow of News</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1963/1965" type="inclusive">1963-1965</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_2bd66f2fe0c1b48f624020f87016e4de" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_7a37328f4029769c4aa0ac24b58cff0a" parent="aspace_2bd66f2fe0c1b48f624020f87016e4de" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref14_9ud" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>South Asia as a New Focus of World Politics</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1967" type="inclusive">1966-1967</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_05382bd07051f6bf734efe2814e0e3ee" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_87cc6ad613df6628f51bfb8c7e87d5a3" parent="aspace_05382bd07051f6bf734efe2814e0e3ee" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref15_ymc" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Ford Foundation/Comparative Administration Group Meeting - Development Administration</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1963/1963" type="inclusive">1963</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_1920881c4eb40a8c93140add1175d8a2" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_180c5e973c1d869ce075a89b0a502dcb" parent="aspace_1920881c4eb40a8c93140add1175d8a2" type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref16_c1d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Southeast Asia/Development Advisory Group</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1967" type="inclusive">1966-1967</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_3ef8e1bcae05775ec172e719aebdf9ae" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_1bd5f4e893c70898a458106819581eeb" parent="aspace_3ef8e1bcae05775ec172e719aebdf9ae" type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aspace_ref17_4i3" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>United Nations Public Administration Meeting</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966" type="inclusive">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_429b68c9ea1baefa49430fb7ca0301a1" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="aspace_ce551ed3dbe98f244f1c33708d11fe2d" parent="aspace_429b68c9ea1baefa49430fb7ca0301a1" type="folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
