<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="under_revision" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>FA086.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper type="filing">Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, RG 1</titleproper>
        <titleproper>A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, RG 1
 <num>FA086</num></titleproper>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline>
          <addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline>
          <addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2016-08-22 17:53:46 -0400</date>.</creation>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <date>May 2010, January 2011</date>
      <item>Migrated from Re:discovery to the Archivists' Toolkit by Becky Robbins in May, 2010; Sub RG 1.3, Series 103 added in January, 2011.</item>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="recordgrp">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, RG 1</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname source="ingest">Rockefeller Foundation.</corpname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="aut" source="lcnaf">Rockefeller Foundation</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>FA086</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Cubic Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">Actual extent is unknown.</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1910/2000" type="inclusive">1910-2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <bioghist id="aspace_3eff0e8a33bbe24b2df9733b829dd7fb">
      <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
      <p>The Rockefeller Foundation was established by act of the New York State Legislature approved by the Governor on May 14, 1913, "to promote the well-being of mankind throughout the world." Between 1913 and 1928 the China Medical Board, the International Health Board, and the Division of Medical Education functioned as divisions of the Foundation, concentrating on the administration of programs in public health and medical education. A Division of Studies was created in 1923 to handle projects outside the medical field. These early years were experimental as the new foundation studied the methods of philanthropy and explored its relationships with other Rockefeller boards.</p>
      <p>Although the Rockefeller Foundation is the largest and best known philanthropy founded by the Rockefeller family, it was neither the first nor the last to be established. The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (1901), the General Education Board (1902), the Rockefeller Sanitary Commission for the Eradication of Hookworm Disease (1909), and the Bureau of Social Hygiene (1911) all existed earlier. When the Foundation was created, the Sanitary Commission was disbanded. After the establishment of the Foundation, the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial (1918) and the International Education Board (1923) were created.</p>
      <p>The Rockefeller boards and their programs were reconsidered and reorganized in 1927-1928 in order to avoid overlapping programs. The International Health Board of the Foundation was disbanded and an International Health Division was organized. The China Medical Board, Inc., was established as a separately incorporated institution, and the China Medical Board of the Foundation ceased to exist. The Division of Studies was dropped and the Division of Medical Education was phased out. The Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial was combined with the Foundation and the Spelman Fund of New York was chartered to continue activities of the LSRM that were not absorbed by the Foundation. The International Education Board was disbanded.</p>
      <p>As a result of this reorganization, the Foundation adopted a program which included public health work (administered by the IHD), the advancement of knowledge in the medical and natural sciences (in part taken over from the IEB), the social sciences (formerly the field of the LSRM), and the humanities and arts (shared with the GEB). The Rockefeller Institute and the Bureau of Social Hygiene were not affected by the reorganization. The program adopted by the Foundation at this time remained basically the same for the next twenty years.</p>
      <p>As its files accumulated, the Foundation maintained a card index recording the names of institutional and individual grantees and correspondents. A microfilm copy of this index is available at the Archive Center.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_c34b5a5a2f7efe4229d70c216a62dd9d">
      <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
      <p>The Foundation's archives include:</p>
      <p>Projects General Correspondence Administration, Program and Policy China Medical Board International Health Board/Division Field Offices Treasurer's Office Comptroller Personnel Fellowships Information Services Diaries Oral Histories Counsel Secretary Minutes and Officers Actions Dockets Declinations (100F)</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="aspace_fba4a19ef1fd9c25e5457590ce6c582b">
      <head>Arrangement note</head>
      <p>The project files are arranged in series according to country. Each state within the United States and every country or geographical area was assigned a three-digit number by RF staff. In addition, letters signifying program areas are used: for example, "A" indicates a grant in the Medical Sciences, and "C" Nursing. Material is organized within these letter/ program subdivisions alphabetically by grant title. A grant title usually consists of a heading that includes the name of the institution or individual that received the grant. Thus each grant, or project, is filed individually in one or more folders.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <processinfo id="aspace_5554946eed6b3dad87fb7cd5e0e190da">
      <head>Processing Information note</head>
      <p>Migrated from Re:discovery to the Archivists' Toolkit by Becky Robbins in May, 2010 except for Sub RG 1.3, Series 103 which was processed by Monica Blank in January, 2011.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <phystech id="aspace_51b018dba5dc0d435c006535e1f2d3af">
      <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
      <p>Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment</p>
      <p>Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.</p>
    </phystech>
    <prefercite id="aspace_f52701893bad696cd7755aaa24d5646d">
      <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
      <p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>
    </prefercite>
    <otherfindaid id="aspace_9ab33745c3faf0b72b789313e2ad10e8">
      <head>Other Finding Aids note</head>
      <p>Detailed finding aids for the following portions of the collection are available:</p>
      <p>FA386 Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, RG 1.1</p>
      <p>FA387 Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, RG 1.2</p>
      <p>FA388 Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, RG 1.3</p>
      <p>Detailed finding aids for the following portions of this collection are available.</p>
      <list type="ordered">
        <head>Missing Title</head>
        <item>Rockefeller Foundation projects, RG 1.1 (FA386)</item>
        <item>Rockefeller Foundation projects, RG 1.2 (FA387)</item>
        <item>Rockefeller Foundation projects, RG 1.3 (FA388)</item>
      </list>
    </otherfindaid>
    <fileplan id="aspace_ff9d47eca144910e2b46d31c2432dad0">
      <head>File Plan note</head>
      <p>RG 1.1, 1.2, and part of 1.3</p>
      <p>Organization of the Rockefeller Foundation's archives:</p>
      <p>RG 1 Projects</p>
      <p>RG 2 General Correspondence</p>
      <p>RG 3 Administration, Program and Policy</p>
      <p>RG 4 China Medical Board</p>
      <p>RG 5 International Health Board/Division</p>
      <p>RG 6 Field Offices</p>
      <p>RG 7 Treasurer's Office</p>
      <p>RG 8 Comptroller</p>
      <p>RG 9 Personnel</p>
      <p>RG 10 Fellowships</p>
      <p>RG 11 Information Services</p>
      <p>RG 12 Diaries</p>
      <p>RG 13 Oral Histories</p>
      <p>RG 14 Counsel</p>
      <p>RG 15 Secretary</p>
      <p>RG 16 Minutes and Officers Actions</p>
      <p>RG 17 Dockets</p>
      <p>RG 18 Declinations (100F)</p>
      <p>RG 19 Non-textual Materials</p>
      <p>RG 20 Communications Office</p>
    </fileplan>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_c20b93891f4f8dbcc89323294639cde3">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
      <p>Material more than twenty years old is open for scholarly research.</p>
      <p>RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. In addition separated media may not yet have undergone stabilization procedures. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <phystech id="aspace_0922499daf10263c8a9fb57e93a3c42c">
      <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note</head>
      <p>Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment</p>
      <p>Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.</p>
    </phystech>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Malaria</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Medical care</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Medical sciences</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Natural history</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Yaws</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Yellow fever</subject>
      <subject source="local">Philanthropy</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Social sciences -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Scholarships</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Viruses -- Research</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Tuberculosis</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">War relief</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Agriculture</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Nursing</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Public health</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Public health administration</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Public health -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Respiratory organs -- Diseases</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Scarlatina -- Hospitals -- Administration</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Life sciences</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Humanities -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Humanities</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Hospitals</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Hookworm disease</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Epidemiology</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Diseases</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Arts</subject>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc/>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
