<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="in_progress" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA571.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Ford Foundation records, International Division, Population Program, Project Specialist in Communications, Office Files of William O. Sweeney</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Population Program, Project Specialist in Communications, Office Files of William O. Sweeney
 <num>FA571</num></titleproper><author>Finding aid prepared by Brian Bleich and Nancy Ng Tam, The Winthrop Group</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><p><date>April 2011</date></p><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-11-19 00:42:01 -0500</date>.</creation><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Ford Foundation records, International Division, Population Program, Project Specialist in Communications, Office Files of William O. Sweeney</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="naf">Sweeney, William O., 1931-</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" rules="dacs" source="naf">Ford Foundation</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA571</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.6 Cubic Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1968/1980" type="inclusive">1968-1980</unitdate>
    <abstract id="9362616bfd645ed03626ac7a3af460c2">The Office Files of William O. Sweeney document his work as a project specialist in population communications for the Foundation from 1969 to 1981. The collection is organized into two series: Project Files (1970-1980), and Reports and Writings (1968-1977). Mr. Sweeney's Project Files detail his work on the Foundation's Population Communications Project. The Reports and Writings focus on population communications. The files hold research reports, evaluations, conference papers and other writings authored by Mr. Sweeney The earliest Foundation grants for population research and family planning occurred under the aegis of the Divisions of International Affairs or Overseas Development. The Population Program was officially established in 1963, and became part of the International Division in 1966. Following a Foundation-wide reorganization in 1981, the Population program became an independent program area. In 1992 the Population Program was subsumed into Reproductive Health and Population. Following the Foundation-wide reorganization in 1997, Reproductive Health and Population became Human Development and Reproductive Health, a subset of the ASSETS Program. William O. Sweeney was retained by the Foundation as Project Specialist for the Population Communications Project when that project was initiated in 1969. Throughout his time with Ford, he travelled extensively assisting developing nations such as China, Egypt, Indonesia, Kenya, Korea, the Philippines, Thailand and Vietnam with the establishment of family planning programs.</abstract>
    <physdesc id="4bc811f3776936d686e8468113c2b460" label="General Physical Description note"><extent>(4 Hollinger document boxes)</extent></physdesc>
  </did>
  <acqinfo id="2fccb5d6a7435f43b0a1fcdc8b79cbe0">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition note</head>
<p>Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="c485d5e6b59896c7e53f6ed8726975db">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
<p>Completion of a use agreement is required prior to providing scholarly access. See RAC Head of Reference (or applicable designee) for details. Ford Foundation holds title, copyright and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them. The Rockefeller Archive Center has authority to grant permission to cite and publish material from the collection for scholarly purposes. Permission to publish extensive excerpts, or material in its entirety, will be referred to the Ford Foundation.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="575e93b63807d1d83d6ccc8fac93577e">
    <head>Preferred Citation note</head>
<p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>  </prefercite>
  <separatedmaterial id="b32b08435e83ad22488e598d65ba35ed">
    <head>Separated Materials Note</head>
<p>Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <bioghist id="2d26c1ac2366455067afad71a287544f">
    <head>Organizational History</head>
<p>The earliest Foundation grants for population research and family planning occurred under the aegis of the Divisions of International Affairs or Overseas Development. The Population Program was officially established in 1963, and became part of the International Division in 1966. Following a Foundation-wide reorganization in 1981, the Population program once again was made independent. In 1992 the Population Program was subsumed into Reproductive Health and Population. Following a second Foundation-wide reorganization in 1997, Reproductive Health and Population became Human Development and Reproductive Health, a subset of the ASSETS Program.</p>  </bioghist>
  <bioghist id="92f79de61d399dab626a10b2439f70aa">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>William O. Sweeney received a J.D. from University of Pennsylvania. Before he joined the Foundation, he worked for <emph render="italic">Newsweek</emph> magazine and the Cursillo Movement of the Roman Catholic Church. The Foundation retained Mr. Sweeney as Project Specialist its Population Communications Project in 1969. Throughout his time with Ford, he helped developing nations to establish family planning programs.</p><p>He left the Foundation in 1981. Subsequently Mr. Sweeney was Executive Director of the International Institute of Communications in London and later the International Advertising Association in New York. He died on July 4, 1987 at age 55.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="1b03d15bc7840ec058cd209ed182bc08">
    <head>Scope and Content</head>
<p>The Office Files of William O. Sweeney document his work as a project specialist for the Foundation over a span of twenty years. His records document his work in population communications as an advisor to governments in China, Egypt, Indonesia, Kenya, Korea, the Philippines, Thailand, Vietnam and elsewhere. Available in this collection are research reports that Mr. Sweeney prepared throughout his tenure at the Foundation.</p><p>One project file of note concerns the proposed establishment of Cycle Communications Associates (CCA), a non-profit agency (1978-1980). Its purpose was to advise non-profits and governments about population communications. Because of concerns that it was not needed, CCA did not receive sustaining Foundation support.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="b3403dd78fd2d0177cc67a796f057111">
    <head>Arrangement note</head>
<p>Collection is arranged in two series.</p>  </arrangement>
  <processinfo id="dea6b6d03148ad9eb2461a13a1f5be23">
    <head>Processing Information Note</head>
<p>Mr. Sweeney's files had been part of the artificially created collection of National Affairs Division Staff Files. The latter collection was accessioned into the Archives in 2004. During review 3 cubic feet of Mr. Sweeney's files were separated and re-categorized as the International Affairs Division/Population Program. Mr. Sweeney's papers were reduced to 1.3 cubic feet during processing. Duplicates, reference files, grant proposals, and files that addressed purely financial matters were not retained.</p>  </processinfo>
  <accessrestrict id="cd211d81d7e3c82adc2cf16f2e0c94b2">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <dsc><c id="2452b70a2aa345fd892239c44b7ab253" level="series"><did><unittitle>Project Files</unittitle><unitid>I</unitid><unitdate normal="1970/1980" type="inclusive">1970-1980</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="0666b10fce7d2ea760bf35ad7306fc00"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains the files Mr. Sweeney kept of his work on the Foundation's Population Communications Project and Cycle Communications Associates. The files contain proposals, research, memoranda and correspondence.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="365d7d304fa054bcfb9d1a6871a89a2f"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically.</p></arrangement><c id="c8042f149ec342a6b16de7b30f02c7f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>China -- Memoranda Re: UNFPA Communications and Family Planning Project, Project Agreement</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1980" type="inclusive">1980</unitdate><container id="0812b1cbb3d9f7b1f1859473867e4ab3" label="documents [510424.1.318]" type="box">1</container><container id="d7ebd269250d94f9bfd11249fd681b7e" parent="0812b1cbb3d9f7b1f1859473867e4ab3" type="folder">1</container></did></c><c id="23c8b9e80a544e04ad9517b196ca84b8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cycle Communications Associates (CCA) -- Memoranda and Correspondence Re: Incorporation of CCA, Research on Incorporation Process</unittitle><unitdate normal="1978/1980" type="inclusive">1978-1980</unitdate><container id="a02b228e4aaed6b96a0d8087109ac8f8" label="documents [510424.1.318]" type="box">1</container><container id="4ee8f4496303f71ac166bcab54791d43" parent="a02b228e4aaed6b96a0d8087109ac8f8" type="folder">2</container></did></c><c id="18794d26b9e54de69b11ba9ebecb2e6e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cycle Communications Associates (CCA) -- Memoranda Re: Closing Out DAP in Population and Proposal for Establishing CCA</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1980" type="inclusive">1980</unitdate><container id="6c8c4dad3394bc56ab848e1742ab7ae2" label="documents [510424.1.318]" type="box">1</container><container id="9532b70e08d95aedff4c3598ab4b1990" parent="6c8c4dad3394bc56ab848e1742ab7ae2" type="folder">3</container></did></c><c id="af1452ac66d2474a902cfdc482f6de65" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cycle Communications Associates (CCA) -- Proposal to Establish CCA</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1980" type="inclusive">Jun 1980</unitdate><container id="bf1b6f589eac3d0dca41ef225094d653" label="documents [510424.1.318]" type="box">1</container><container id="d007669a4f9c02277cebf8c018fdd91f" parent="bf1b6f589eac3d0dca41ef225094d653" type="folder">4</container></did></c><c id="1bdacc76fe5a4f239173e4db81ca6d99" level="file"><did><unittitle>DAP Grant Recommendations to Extend Consultancy in Family Planning and Population Communications</unittitle><unitdate normal="1977/1980" type="inclusive">1977-1980</unitdate><container id="4c46bc75d9043ab378f79f094fb4865f" label="documents [510424.1.318]" type="box">1</container><container id="cedd502bb8f9f2b64a3594bb34c6d556" parent="4c46bc75d9043ab378f79f094fb4865f" type="folder">5</container></did></c><c id="1538202278604eb5aa5b4b38c5db5819" level="file"><did><unittitle>East-West Communication Institute International Conference on Making Population/Family Planning Research Useful, Honolulu, HI -- Agenda, Discussion Summaries, Papers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">Dec 3-7, 1973</unitdate><container id="1616462b56b6dfb0a0eef0eb06bfcab4" label="documents [510424.1.318]" type="box">1</container><container id="d9f8c30bb4501cdfc42f52871f22fd1b" parent="1616462b56b6dfb0a0eef0eb06bfcab4" type="folder">6</container></did></c><c id="fdaf1d8677174a02936198559c52d484" level="file"><did><unittitle>Egypt -- Memoranda Re: UNFPA and AID-Sponsored Family Planning Missions, Assessment of AID/Cairo Project</unittitle><unitdate normal="1978/1980" type="inclusive">1978-1980</unitdate><container id="187d9b7411f33faa0956765bb7b1613f" label="documents [510424.1.318]" type="box">1</container><container id="9cd0652a4c279673d5565ca110874e19" parent="187d9b7411f33faa0956765bb7b1613f" type="folder">7</container></did></c><c id="4d8dae64f4514de6819c72ce8cb0fbd5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ford Foundation Population Communications Project -- Evaluation Outline and Comments on Report</unittitle><unitdate normal="1979/1980" type="inclusive">1979-1980</unitdate><container id="e461574f6edcb46ceeaeaa2aa9879b80" label="documents [510424.1.318]" type="box">1</container><container id="affa49e3bbbbf27e2a3065d88840695d" parent="e461574f6edcb46ceeaeaa2aa9879b80" type="folder">8</container></did></c><c id="de6583fe7d4b4870ba52b1649350de41" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ford Foundation Population Communications Project -- Evaluation Report</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1980" type="inclusive">May 1980</unitdate><container id="dc00d917186e3dccc061d9b2adb38ff6" label="documents [510424.1.318]" type="box">1</container><container id="de63c4a31feac8b3ab83f8aeda954b60" parent="dc00d917186e3dccc061d9b2adb38ff6" type="folder">9</container></did></c><c id="7493b7bc6a5049e0a4249b045e66d26a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Indonesia -- Memoranda Re: Ford Jakarta Field Office Support for National Family Planning Education</unittitle><unitdate normal="1977/1980" type="inclusive">1977-1980</unitdate><container id="5561b80526b4cd79356e057d93c7d296" label="documents [510424.1.318]" type="box">1</container><container id="b3cb35e924b837b7e07ae446e0215088" parent="5561b80526b4cd79356e057d93c7d296" type="folder">10</container></did></c><c id="6bd273832c824a4a8fee4f576e1c826b" level="file"><did><unittitle>International Workshop on Communications in Family Planning Programs, Tehran, Iran -- Preliminary Report to the Ford Foundation (1 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1970" type="inclusive">Jun 6-18, 1970</unitdate><container id="34408581b04e5e0d0c24803163e150d8" label="documents [510424.2.318]" type="box">2</container><container id="7bcaf43ca2261ef3d54b92153551af28" parent="34408581b04e5e0d0c24803163e150d8" type="folder">1</container></did></c><c id="244fb06a46e34e3c83b4bac45a34cd55" level="file"><did><unittitle>International Workshop on Communications in Family Planning Programs, Tehran, Iran -- Preliminary Report to the Ford Foundation (2 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1970" type="inclusive">Jun 6-18, 1970</unitdate><container id="f58a8e50255cd5e234ee936f1c528f9e" label="documents [510424.2.318]" type="box">2</container><container id="bc202bb8195116e0996a103e1bea271f" parent="f58a8e50255cd5e234ee936f1c528f9e" type="folder">2</container></did></c><c id="5bb9560fee314e1aba637ea82f3e6dbc" level="file"><did><unittitle>International Workshop on Communications in Family Planning Programs, Tehran, Iran -- Preliminary Report to the Ford Foundation (3 of 3)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1970" type="inclusive">Jun 6-18, 1970</unitdate><container id="3f7e89fedd5a425a8589cfe7f80efab1" label="documents [510424.2.318]" type="box">2</container><container id="8a3619b3fd902026ee38ab54f41870c3" parent="3f7e89fedd5a425a8589cfe7f80efab1" type="folder">3</container></did></c><c id="bb2f375299914ea2b3dbe8cd18c05006" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kenya -- Consulting Report on Developing a Family Planning Communications Plan, Proposal to Train Population Communications Personnel</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1972" type="inclusive">1970-1972</unitdate><container id="75c598aae1da6e3b098cb3c01718127b" label="documents [510424.2.318]" type="box">2</container><container id="e4d1f1a7001b16d41b82b895eeb6a46e" parent="75c598aae1da6e3b098cb3c01718127b" type="folder">4</container></did></c><c id="329d19b59a714ad38e90e204e90f562e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Korea -- Memoranda, Correspondence, Background on Planned Parenthood Federation of Korea Mothers' Clubs, etc.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1979/1980" type="inclusive">1979-1980</unitdate><container id="716fabb5733b60be1b129690509800c3" label="documents [510424.2.318]" type="box">2</container><container id="ac4d5bbd7d3123653fc7562bd80da287" parent="716fabb5733b60be1b129690509800c3" type="folder">5</container></did></c><c id="f826e4cc09dc41119d9fafa440521e92" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memoranda -- From Sweeney to Population Office Colleagues Re: Journey from Dacca, Bangladesh to Lomé, Togo</unittitle><unitdate normal="1977/1977" type="inclusive">May 19, 1977</unitdate><container id="39bfa0e9079e3616f279d97a43180136" label="documents [510424.2.318]" type="box">2</container><container id="ba01c3f9e39d8cd159c62c21946a8ed8" parent="39bfa0e9079e3616f279d97a43180136" type="folder">6</container></did></c><c id="698e655f2d24482fa3437341e0dd65c6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Philippines -- Correspondence Re: Workshop to Draft Communications Strategy for Philippine Population Program</unittitle><unitdate normal="1978/1978" type="inclusive">Jun 20, 1978</unitdate><container id="e3fe052d558fa0c724570f2961899dbd" label="documents [510424.2.318]" type="box">2</container><container id="e539540cd96a96ceb01b3dea8444b463" parent="e3fe052d558fa0c724570f2961899dbd" type="folder">7</container></did></c><c id="d8cbcfef0d8c44c392a80dabe9909e69" level="file"><did><unittitle>Resources on Development -- Reports, Papers on U.S. Private Voluntary Organizations (PVOs) and Development Education, Videotape as a Development Tool, etc.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1980" type="inclusive">1980</unitdate><container id="63c5850f15b1aeb2991658b80a6e8654" label="documents [510424.2.318]" type="box">2</container><container id="e6a860c2cc76481b1aa6d29dc6ae04e0" parent="63c5850f15b1aeb2991658b80a6e8654" type="folder">8</container></did></c><c id="1a3fa242c55442a3ae953defee0719a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Resources on Population Communications -- Papers on Computer and Videotape Communications Technology, Population Education in Developing Countries (1 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1974/1978" type="inclusive">1974-1978</unitdate><container id="bebd700dec08dbf08e3c0d2594e40069" label="documents [510424.2.318]" type="box">2</container><container id="0e38ec547748fd9cc8b16e4042b2da85" parent="bebd700dec08dbf08e3c0d2594e40069" type="folder">9</container></did></c><c id="2b4857d294dd4b94beea11a2623c375d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Resources on Population Communications -- Papers on Computer and Videotape Communications Technology, Population Education in Developing Countries (2 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1980" type="inclusive">1980</unitdate><container id="00ef3409ba46fdb8ba7caa624d53f0f0" label="documents [510424.2.318]" type="box">2</container><container id="3ead19015a8fbe4781e60d1b81a7bda8" parent="00ef3409ba46fdb8ba7caa624d53f0f0" type="folder">10</container></did></c><c id="44759933877d497eb9010b684f0e3688" level="file"><did><unittitle>Thailand -- Memoranda and Correspondence Re: Consulting Work with UNFPA and DTCP (Development Training and Communication Planning) (1 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1979/1980" type="inclusive">1979-1980</unitdate><container id="de3b6c658e1a42e64d425b7482d862a4" label="documents [510424.3.318]" type="box">3</container><container id="a445db8a6a380cd8bd25fba28584b88f" parent="de3b6c658e1a42e64d425b7482d862a4" type="folder">1</container></did></c><c id="b6c67df54e114e98af5cf4d95454ba5b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Thailand -- Memoranda and Correspondence Re: Consulting Work with UNFPA and DTCP, Report, Terms of Agreement (2 of 2)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1980" type="inclusive">1980</unitdate><container id="73fd6cd4237e83ee5b8ade4030b7f9cd" label="documents [510424.3.318]" type="box">3</container><container id="dacbaeea98ccd1f0aa932c955985492e" parent="73fd6cd4237e83ee5b8ade4030b7f9cd" type="folder">2</container></did></c><c id="b069eda6d1954ee5b0abf32479fa3eaf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Thailand -- Memoranda Re: Orientation Program for Indochinese Refugees, Background</unittitle><unitdate normal="1979/1980" type="inclusive">1979-1980</unitdate><container id="739321aa4107ff641165fefa715f72b6" label="documents [510424.3.318]" type="box">3</container><container id="9b3c045c993d13fbcbafc2d800705271" parent="739321aa4107ff641165fefa715f72b6" type="folder">3</container></did></c><c id="3380041460d048f08a9f5e3fa418a7c2" level="file"><did><unittitle>USAID -- Memoranda Re: Grants to Private Voluntary Organizations and Matching Grants Policy</unittitle><unitdate normal="1979/1980" type="inclusive">1979-1980</unitdate><container id="713eb93f4886e3ed78f5e54d1bd1d5d1" label="documents [510424.3.318]" type="box">3</container><container id="bd03ba9db43f3297f167fbef913377af" parent="713eb93f4886e3ed78f5e54d1bd1d5d1" type="folder">4</container></did></c><c id="af5314af4d104e22a662cfa1eef4c8de" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vietnam -- Memoranda Re: Meeting with Audiovisual Center for Family Planning</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1980" type="inclusive">Jun 9, 1980</unitdate><container id="dd542ba30ea7288281a0c70dbd9eed66" label="documents [510424.3.318]" type="box">3</container><container id="652214ef234d12cb04d08b8f9c086a48" parent="dd542ba30ea7288281a0c70dbd9eed66" type="folder">5</container></did></c></c><c id="5d378439b63f4b1490d1b8312dcc18b8" level="series"><did><unittitle>Reports and Writings</unittitle><unitid>II</unitid><unitdate normal="1968/1977" type="inclusive">1968-1977</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="0e8d646fb55ff5c300cf45b930aa3af0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series holds Mr. Sweeney's reports and writings on the subject of population communications. It includes two foreign language reports, one concerning Costa Rica (Spanish language) and the about North Africa (French language).</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="7fa985ee2f6280067e60fac8762cc6d1"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged chronologically.</p></arrangement><c id="62dcff724db94748bffc7a4245a4d844" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Predictions of Attitude Change for U.S. Roman Catholics"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1968/1968" type="inclusive">Aug 19, 1968</unitdate><container id="9a2fb8a6d49dd0eebf9f622d6df79cf4" label="documents [510450.3.318]" type="box">3</container><container id="84552232a3ab2de57eee338362de2731" parent="9a2fb8a6d49dd0eebf9f622d6df79cf4" type="folder">6</container></did></c><c id="ae52309fda8d4a6a9effb47eeb79686b" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Family Planning Communications in Nigeria" (consulting report)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1969/1969" type="inclusive">Mar 1969</unitdate><container id="7d8b3f39027ea2a14319975513391526" label="documents [510450.3.318]" type="box">3</container><container id="919c949445e518017ef1609a33a13640" parent="7d8b3f39027ea2a14319975513391526" type="folder">7</container></did></c><c id="9fe52aad4013488f9f49f8b8e2a0b5b9" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Suggestions for an Education and Public Information Program for Nutrition, Maternal and Child Health, and Population in Costa Rica" (consulting report)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1969/1969" type="inclusive">Sep 1969</unitdate><container id="d12fac2627549c00053307a375c23456" label="documents [510450.3.318]" type="box">3</container><container id="a0d5bbf2af8a0256601bad8e77baabe9" parent="d12fac2627549c00053307a375c23456" type="folder">8</container></did></c><c id="c72bc98609a04807be1852aa6ab190b8" level="file"><did><unittitle>"El Salvador: A Survey of Communications, Information and Education Programs in Family Planning"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1970" type="inclusive">May 1970</unitdate><container id="dcb43c1fdb47f4aedff8a87a8aca26e1" label="documents [510450.3.318]" type="box">3</container><container id="fddf66a7fea9a393223a511663307ab6" parent="dcb43c1fdb47f4aedff8a87a8aca26e1" type="folder">9</container></did></c><c id="8ce0990433754340bf43b74d5612ead2" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Guatemala: A Survey of Communications, Information and Education Programs in Family Planning"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1970" type="inclusive">Jun 1970</unitdate><container id="3e6226f14b6e5dd5d4d477c30d29ad44" label="documents [510450.3.318]" type="box">3</container><container id="e55389133573d11bc11f2b48fb3482f7" parent="3e6226f14b6e5dd5d4d477c30d29ad44" type="folder">10</container></did></c><c id="f8a90f33fe194d11bfa626bb5f0520d8" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Kenya: Developing a Family Planning Communications Plan for 1970-1971" (consulting report)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1970" type="inclusive">Aug 1970</unitdate><container id="1dcf695a7b3a838eda118277ffa2830a" label="documents [510450.3.318]" type="box">3</container><container id="511cc1d12be13418e2e402a1760a3753" parent="1dcf695a7b3a838eda118277ffa2830a" type="folder">11</container></did></c><c id="94f6fdf804e64c7bab09cf90679c3c11" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Central America and Some Caribbean Countries: A Report on Population and Family Planning Information, Education and Communications Programs"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1970" type="inclusive">Nov 1970</unitdate><container id="d38391e642ef1723a753ab375137f5c3" label="documents [510450.3.318]" type="box">3</container><container id="f78073ba2cd9802d258bc5667a0e49dd" parent="d38391e642ef1723a753ab375137f5c3" type="folder">12</container></did></c><c id="a90a556d60cc4cc9bd4aaaf5a92e5589" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Jamaica: A Survey of Communications, Information and Education Programs in Family Planning"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1970" type="inclusive">Nov 1970</unitdate><container id="978b7eacc4d485391b442dca4100c933" label="documents [510450.3.318]" type="box">3</container><container id="c35771fa7da67cab223e77753c5d723a" parent="978b7eacc4d485391b442dca4100c933" type="folder">13</container></did></c><c id="3edce437e89047338de498d2c176908e" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Ghana: Family Planning Communications: A Program Status Report"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1971/1971" type="inclusive">May 1971</unitdate><container id="d519339ab966fbfaf0ff058d6a0c013d" label="documents [510450.3.318]" type="box">3</container><container id="530eae0355a514066f06167294e08a71" parent="d519339ab966fbfaf0ff058d6a0c013d" type="folder">14</container></did></c><c id="bbbc2a9ba2404eea869be530f5eca7a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Planning Suggestions for Communications Programs"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1971/1971" type="inclusive">May 1971</unitdate><container id="5cf9ae04d098af6fb5b27517d4b75ab8" label="documents [510450.3.318]" type="box">3</container><container id="3a6f26f25cdff890763db496ff64cedd" parent="5cf9ae04d098af6fb5b27517d4b75ab8" type="folder">15</container></did></c><c id="1b10440c25ef4d68911738946d532d47" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Role of Communications in Family Planning and Population Programs," 1st International Planned Parenthood Federation Workshop on Information and Education, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia</unittitle><unitdate normal="1971/1971" type="inclusive">Nov 27-Dec 1, 1971</unitdate><container id="ce1bb6980cefe9cc18b73ce8c7e54821" label="documents [510450.3.318]" type="box">3</container><container id="d38f917671419eb9ec86e8f2224117a9" parent="ce1bb6980cefe9cc18b73ce8c7e54821" type="folder">16</container></did></c><c id="6919df5ce80047a8ae63a0070eb486ee" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A Blueprint for Program Planning for Population Communication," Work-Planning Conference, University of Chicago Community and Family Study Center</unittitle><unitdate normal="1971/1971" type="inclusive">Dec 16-17, 1971</unitdate><container id="3141dcc019b8a27495b248c71beb9416" label="documents [510450.3.318]" type="box">3</container><container id="193456482be081e054572b18f690892f" parent="3141dcc019b8a27495b248c71beb9416" type="folder">17</container></did></c><c id="fe8ff772c5814718a8581b7e9c47d663" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Communications Program Planning Needs Which Can Be Fulfilled by Library and Information Services," 5th National Conference on Population/Family Planning Library and Information Services, Chapel Hill, NC</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">May 1972</unitdate><container id="9b671990e022ca062349e2549f3079f2" label="documents [510450.3.318]" type="box">3</container><container id="95837f1a493e0f2e32e5e42c7c458413" parent="9b671990e022ca062349e2549f3079f2" type="folder">18</container></did></c><c id="01e83eac59ab4b9abb13d34ff7a8a3b3" level="file"><did><unittitle>"The Role of Communications in Population and Family Planning Programs"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">May 1972</unitdate><container id="1365cb9da6497597133ecd3402252a34" label="documents [510450.3.318]" type="box">3</container><container id="91cf91c33be1b3cfdad7133bff63891a" parent="1365cb9da6497597133ecd3402252a34" type="folder">19</container></did></c><c id="485b9eb2fa7746a59411ac463644ec7b" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Population and Family Planning: An Approach to Communications as a Program Component"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972/1973" type="inclusive">1972-1973</unitdate><container id="89ba9cf39d7cd0516877e42554506ad1" label="documents [510450.4.318]" type="box">4</container><container id="4e8c5eb9d41bbab2846ce67b2be69d63" parent="89ba9cf39d7cd0516877e42554506ad1" type="folder">1</container></did></c><c id="49e5502a22eb4286a70a208cd8163e77" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Using Commercial Resources in Population Communications Programs"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972/1972" type="inclusive">Dec 1972</unitdate><container id="04d8da5461e39e8baab1963151940b8a" label="documents [510450.4.318]" type="box">4</container><container id="a814009f050459aa386c8ab3c3a57113" parent="04d8da5461e39e8baab1963151940b8a" type="folder">2</container></did></c><c id="67b633badf1a4bf28c5caef40eb32a8f" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Papel Que Desempeñan las Comunicaciones en los Programas de Población y Planificación Familiar," Universidad de Costa Rica Centro de Estudios Sociales y de Población [in Spanish]</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">1973</unitdate><container id="d606611b904b430f24d3c8a2013a74a1" label="documents [510450.4.318]" type="box">4</container><container id="6f72085020ca4f1b15d2164108395213" parent="d606611b904b430f24d3c8a2013a74a1" type="folder">3</container></did></c><c id="0e701c3fd13147a68380fff9dc4fb092" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A Report on a Visit to Nigeria to Consult on Communications Activities of the Family Planning Council of Nigeria"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">Mar 1973</unitdate><container id="3719984dc259a0aeec6e276110023b5d" label="documents [510450.4.318]" type="box">4</container><container id="de0c978ed8684866e5081b763876f101" parent="3719984dc259a0aeec6e276110023b5d" type="folder">4</container></did></c><c id="e0ca7360f67b4db58fe3dd9808fc92ba" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Communications and the Population Program of Pakistan"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">Aug 1973</unitdate><container id="11511608f00dffcadee9f5aab15f97b5" label="documents [510450.4.318]" type="box">4</container><container id="0dce39f39bccfa8f6ce117cbb25ed5bb" parent="11511608f00dffcadee9f5aab15f97b5" type="folder">5</container></did></c><c id="5dd637270c534fb1adf46d8a670cc2fe" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Communications and Population in the Philippines: Report of a Visit"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">Sep 1973</unitdate><container id="995ed2f300a4b726c4bd2429e1d7b531" label="documents [510450.4.318]" type="box">4</container><container id="e536595204e5890f2618038695240a6b" parent="995ed2f300a4b726c4bd2429e1d7b531" type="folder">6</container></did></c><c id="02bfecfdc9574f61a7901287daa7a7a7" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Evaluation of the East-West Communications Institute"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">Sep 1973</unitdate><container id="57cdfbd670d7624c395e2f0ed6b2e070" label="documents [510450.4.318]" type="box">4</container><container id="13a287a7defb01dde01ae0aaa42420cb" parent="57cdfbd670d7624c395e2f0ed6b2e070" type="folder">7</container></did></c><c id="1fe59ac7aec340029fad6aeac6ad647b" level="file"><did><unittitle>"A Communication en Afrique," Seminaire sur les Problemes de Population et les Mass Media en Afrique du Nord et au Moyen-Orient, Tunis, Tunisia [in French]</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">Sep 24-29, 1973</unitdate><container id="a277b36d5c71464a54e53c3b4d7a95bb" label="documents [510450.4.318]" type="box">4</container><container id="4a18ce618dbb945011f0c873c2af6978" parent="a277b36d5c71464a54e53c3b4d7a95bb" type="folder">8</container></did></c><c id="e980ba6a36734e72905b2f684857cdc8" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Methodology to Support Research Utilization Practitioners," Conference on Making Population/Family Planning Research Useful, East-West Center, Honolulu, HI</unittitle><unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive">Dec 3-7, 1973</unitdate><container id="300d364728c3d3fdd162c231bb775c61" label="documents [510450.4.318]" type="box">4</container><container id="afe48d537b2dfa073e22433e31a50d2f" parent="300d364728c3d3fdd162c231bb775c61" type="folder">9</container></did></c><c id="26c00daa350f40dd97d335609982ac58" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Audiencias para Programas de Información y Educación en Planificación Familiar," Asociación Demográfica Costarricense [in Spanish]</unittitle><unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">1974</unitdate><container id="c6fbd56fc00af1414103b032c111a341" label="documents [510450.4.318]" type="box">4</container><container id="9712f078ea33742c6877c51e252b1df8" parent="c6fbd56fc00af1414103b032c111a341" type="folder">10</container></did></c><c id="c22cef208341407493fb92bd7f7324d1" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Population Communications in the Philippines: Report of a Consultant Visit"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">Jul 1974</unitdate><container id="0922d6ede42418c27630f5ba226ada5f" label="documents [510450.4.318]" type="box">4</container><container id="fb5a0f97b2690c42de3bc5288be5f9cc" parent="0922d6ede42418c27630f5ba226ada5f" type="folder">11</container></did></c><c id="5412f6bf8e7b4cb68bf25f7bfb153d3c" level="file"><did><unittitle>"The Scope of Communications in the Development of Human Resources in the Less Industrialized Countries," <emph render="italic">Teachers College Record</emph></unittitle><unitdate normal="1974/1974" type="inclusive">Dec 1974</unitdate><container id="3db5886b02175f8253bc787681b202b9" label="documents [510450.4.318]" type="box">4</container><container id="5aa64c1893984a87d656acf60653bfe0" parent="3db5886b02175f8253bc787681b202b9" type="folder">12</container></did></c><c id="b3c7c244d3bd469e98241de0a6d69f6d" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Exchange of Information Between Nations: Help in Solving Population Problems," <emph render="italic">Bulletin of the American Society for Information Science</emph> Vol. 1, No. 8</unittitle><unitdate normal="1975/1975" type="inclusive">Mar 1975</unitdate><container id="739b29535eb8b9aedf60847c96f3b92c" label="documents [510450.4.318]" type="box">4</container><container id="32c2c4ab078e9176e1695ed4a3b300b3" parent="739b29535eb8b9aedf60847c96f3b92c" type="folder">13</container></did></c><c id="5bd39be8c51f49c7b3e5cd76eba1e4b5" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Population/Family Planning Media Communications in 25 Countries" (monograph)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1977/1977" type="inclusive">Jun 1977</unitdate><container id="aa87fcaaa7329d7d044512fdc5cead87" label="documents [510450.4.318]" type="box">4</container><container id="b7ab5ea87dfb767a6fc14efdb29d93c3" parent="aa87fcaaa7329d7d044512fdc5cead87" type="folder">14</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
