<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="under_revision" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA320.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Medical Interests, Series K</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Medical Interests, Series K
 <num>FA320</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><p><date>2009</date></p><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-01-20 00:13:13 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="series">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Medical Interests, Series K</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="ctb" source="naf">Bureau of Social Hygiene. (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="ctb" source="naf">Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison), 1839-1937</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="ctb" source="naf">Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="ctb" source="naf">Rockefeller, David</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="ctb" source="naf">Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="naf">Rockefeller, John D., Jr. (John Davison), 1874-1960</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA320</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">13.3 Cubic Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1898/1961" type="inclusive">1898-1961</unitdate>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="1ae2671852e22a64bcf1bd21c81fbff0">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access note</head>
<p>Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Material in the Rockefeller family collections that provides the names, correspondence, or activities of living members of the Rockefeller family, and/or documents the net wealth of any Rockefeller family members, is restricted. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aeddecbbec3d95e647091be57496f297">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use note</head>
<p>Reproduction/duplication of archival items is routinely provided in accordance with "fair use." If the RAC does not hold copyright for an archival collection, or items within a collection, it is the user's responsibility to contact the copyright holder, or make a fair effort to do so, prior to publication.</p>  </userestrict>
  <arrangement id="85e361ef7948345645e77f78d1385458">
    <head>Arrangement note</head>
<p>The Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records are arranged by subject matter in 27 series. Most of these series are wholly or partially open for research. The series are:</p><p>A John D. Rockefeller, Sr. C Business Interests D Civic Interests E Cultural Interests F Economic Reform Interests G Educational Interests H Friends and Services I Homes J Housing Interests K Medical Interests L Real Estate M Maps and Memorabilia N Religious Interests O Rockefeller Boards P Welfare - General Files Q World Affairs R Welfare - Youth Files S Documents T Public Relations U Public Land Law Review Commission V Greenrock W Properties X Costume Collection Y Media Z John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Personal AA Abby Aldrich Rockefeller AC Abby Rockefeller Mauzé</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="ff4410575c9d65428192af40392a508f">
    <head>Biographical/Historical note</head>
<p>The central figure in the creation and operation of the Standard Oil Company during its rise to the top of the petroleum industry, John D. Rockefeller (JDR) established for the family a leading role in business and philanthropy. From the days of his earliest employment, Rockefeller, a devout Baptist, was generous in his giving to worthy causes, especially those of a religious nature. During the 1890s he developed an orderly system of philanthropic giving through an office staff that included his close advisor, Frederick T. Gates (1853-1929) and his son, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. (1874-1960). With the advise of these and other associates, Rockefeller established the University of Chicago, The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (now The Rockefeller University), the Rockefeller Foundation, and other philanthropic organizations working nationally and internationally in the fields of education, religion, and health. Rockefeller's total donations to philanthropic endeavors are estimated to have been $540 million.</p><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr. (JDR Jr.) joined his father's office on October 1, 1897. He oversaw the expansion and diversification of the philanthropic work begun by his father. During his lifetime, the younger Rockefeller gave more than $537 million to educational, religious, cultural, medical, and other charitable projects.</p><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and his wife, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller (1874-1948), passed the Rockefeller philanthropic impulse on to their children. John D. 3rd (1906-1978), Nelson A. (1908-1979), Laurance S. (1910-2004), Winthrop (1912-1973), and David (1915-) further expanded and diversified Rockefeller influence and interests, establishing their own philanthropic organizations, most notably the Rockefeller Brothers Fund (1940), and becoming more active politically.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="7e8aa0925d301cbd88d1af0727a7f74f">
    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
<p>The Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller (OMR) materials document the increasing role assumed by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in the management of Rockefeller affairs and amply document his business and philanthropic affairs. They also chronicle the entrance of JDR Jr.'s sons, John D. 3rd, Nelson A., Laurance S., Winthrop, and David, into the world of business, philanthropy, civic leadership, and politics as they joined the office.</p><p>This material contains correspondence, reports, pamphlets, memoranda, deeds, maps, contracts, reports, minutes, charters, certificates of incorporation, clippings, diaries, notebooks, calendars, and memorabilia.</p><p>There is a microfilm card index of personal and institutional names.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <fileplan id="1e29aa05a1f66b86966191a5641b1d5e">
    <head>File Plan note</head>
<p>Former Classification: III 02</p>  </fileplan>
  <scopecontent id="60ac594e3d2a08c2f363b9c740d5f001">
    <head>Scope and Contents note</head>
<p>The 35 boxes in this series cover the years 1898-1961. The Messrs. Rockefeller, Sr. and Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Abby Rockefeller Mauze, the five brothers, and their spouses are all represented in this series. Mr. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. 3rd, and Laurance S. Rockefeller are have the most connection to thse records.</p><p>The records reflect the Rockefeller family philanthropic policy toward public and private healthcare. Major subjects within the series include birth control and "social hygiene," cancer, health agencies, mental hygiene, polio, tuberculosis, and--the largest section--hospitals.</p><p>In the specific topics, such as cancer and polio, the policy on giving was generally based on personal interest or interest generated by the presentation of new lines of research. This sometimes involved expanding existing laboratories and sometimes establishing new laboratories. In either case, established and reputable committees or research facilities were supported and acted as overseers and distribution agents. Two examples of this are the American Cancer Society and the National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis.</p><p>In the two broad categories of health agencies and hospitals, the policy was generally one of giving to umbrella organizations on the national, state and local level and letting those organizations distribute the funds. This policy was adopted, in general, to avoid dealing with the hundreds of individual requests and having to make the necessarily subjective decisions involved in each case. The family strongly also believed that the most good could be done with the available funds using this method of distribution.</p><p>Despite that established policy, the family was inundated with requests for support from individual hospitals. This part of the series is the largest. The established policy was generally followed except in cases of personal interest or when the family had a residence in the area of a specific hospital. As with specific diseases and health agencies, the hospitals given support were often those that demonstrated leadership in setting medical standards. Many hospitals did receive support by showing acute need, especially those in middle- and low-income areas.</p><p>The bulk of the material is composed of routine appeals and correspondence answering those appeals. There are many instances of an agency or hospital being put on the philanthropic program early in the century and routinely sending reports for years after. Declinations were usually based on policy but were sometimes based on a judgment of the personnel involved. In none of these situations was the discussion based on anything except analysis of what was best for the particular cause and not on personalities.</p><p>The family continually supported medical training for people of color and medical care in low-income and under-served communities.</p><p>The family's interest coincides with a significant period of medical growth and transformation. In many ways the family geared its medical philanthropy to supplement the national trend in modern scientific research that was helped by the opening of the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (later Rockefeller University). Many new lines of research were supported at a time when new methods were in embryonic stages. The most significant files are those related to the "suppression of vice" and the social hygiene movement. These records shed light on the beginnings of one of the most important social movements of the 20th century.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War I</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War II</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public relations</subject>
    <subject source="local">Philanthropy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Housing rehabilitation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Religion</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public welfare</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Government policy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Folk art</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Health insurance</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1958</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">United States</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Travel</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Urban renewal</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Urban policy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Restoration and conservation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Religious institutions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">State governments -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Rockefeller family -- Art collections</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art -- Collectors and collecting</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art, Modern</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Business</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Arts</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Capital investments</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Business enterprises, Foreign</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charitable contributions</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Family planning</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Federal government -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Economic policy</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Economics</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Economic development</subject>
    <subject source="local">Philanthropy -- New York (N.Y.)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International relations -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Juvenile delinquency</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Maternal health services</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical care</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical research</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medical sciences</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charities</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Charities -- Investments</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Child welfare</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Civic improvement</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International cooperation</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International economic relations</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International education</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">International relations</subject>
    <subject source="local">Philanthropy -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Political campaigns -- United States</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Political science</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">New York (State)</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Parks -- New York (State)</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Performing arts</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Prohibition</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public health</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public health administration</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Public policy</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c id="b0f58590fdc94b4ca6621842a0072985" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Birth Control</unittitle></did><c id="1e16f8b5e907472fa600141eaed293f6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - Birth Control Organizations</unittitle><unitdate normal="1930/1939" type="inclusive">1930-1939</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="050e71069582ab4fe44c302f141ca4b3" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044925]" type="box">1</container><container id="886647eb7a41b779e0949f1d16ec9737" parent="050e71069582ab4fe44c302f141ca4b3" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="94e2582290293fa31d8e5ad8f4a13b95"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller 3rd's interest in birth control movement; discussion of moral, medical and social implications; comments on leading figures and organizations in the field. Emphasis on population control and planned parenthood after 1940. Small contributions to various organizations by members of the family. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard, Arthur Woods, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Margaret Sanger.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="6938608dd987bfab114867146673eee7"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139</p></fileplan></c><c id="ba438da6b9a4409baa345ce6c0455e53" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - Birth Control Organizations</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1957" type="inclusive">1940-1957</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="a71e587a2be7c32b670b34ff2ba4a5cb" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044925]" type="box">1</container><container id="6e1fecb09465ff43365843d635fe80b8" parent="a71e587a2be7c32b670b34ff2ba4a5cb" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="0ba8909daf7c29c182b3b15e32459761"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller 3rd's interest in birth control movement; discussion of moral, medical and social implications; comments on leading figures and organizations in the field. Emphasis on population control and planned parenthood after 1940. Small contributions to various organizations by members of the family. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard, Arthur Woods, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Margaret Sanger.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="e1ada606ab5f685838289c74c3f7fd97"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139</p></fileplan></c><c id="cf34b53c18d94f898aea3b1d7d2693d0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - Birth Control Organizations</unittitle><unitdate normal="1948/1957" type="inclusive">1948-1957</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="0d737b9c73edc5525265959d0d4ab72a" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044925]" type="box">1</container><container id="94dee44d97a1ea45ffd936b9b65a0819" parent="0d737b9c73edc5525265959d0d4ab72a" type="folder">2A</container></did><scopecontent id="108a703b2c9e28063f6c71a12816987b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller 3rd's interest in birth control movement; discussion of moral, medical and social implications; comments on leading figures and organizations in the field. Emphasis on population control and planned parenthood after 1940. Small contributions to various organizations by members of the family. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard, Arthur Woods, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Margaret Sanger.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="d3499bffd76c077c39204fe2ef6c5a3f"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139</p></fileplan></c><c id="4b96c6cfa16040b2889f1da185312396" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - Birth Control Organizations - World Population Conferences</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1952" type="inclusive">1947-1952</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="b071ed7257de1133f7bea7e92e20b56b" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044925]" type="box">1</container><container id="7e52bdb8215a8c91775872a2e218052c" parent="b071ed7257de1133f7bea7e92e20b56b" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="db6c8ab677193eaedba90a3abb507db9"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Cheltenham, 1948; United Nations, 1954.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="3330396f780b880451cf806c5bc45a6b"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139</p></fileplan></c><c id="67d72e9f39ee44478a267221c47df65b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - Birth Control Organizations - John D. Rockefeller 3rd Contributions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1952/1952" type="inclusive">1952</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="375cd6a6207e53c3d2ed2dca3653b629" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044925]" type="box">1</container><container id="e3c65b0694b01c133b82d08d6ee979ac" parent="375cd6a6207e53c3d2ed2dca3653b629" type="folder">4</container></did><fileplan id="50204b78aa7d5e1b513d1b085da03a51"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139</p></fileplan></c><c id="ce0ddf13c6a84e14819ab2447fd1fc35" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - National Committee on Maternal Health</unittitle><unitdate normal="1924/1949" type="inclusive">1924-1927, 1932-1944, 1947-1949</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="e53624d2c6d10325585546baa4944643" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044925]" type="box">1</container><container id="9ca4c7107cc875871390226d0b7e0543" parent="e53624d2c6d10325585546baa4944643" type="folder">4A</container></did><scopecontent id="f0ef2f3ae76a53190ed449ccb34a7bb4"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Scientific research into contraception and related fields; appeals to the Bureau of Social Hygiene and the Rockefellers for contributions. Personnel arrangements; policy questions within Committee. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Raymond B. Fosdick, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="5cd0753f757d3b3c852a29ddcfbca4f6"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="4e943f66eb0d4850b106fe10b9619a92" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - National Committee on Maternal Health - By-laws</unittitle><unitdate normal="1948/1948" type="inclusive">1948</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="b6959acdac5e12bb183e8debe0aeca75" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044925]" type="box">1</container><container id="450eaa087aed788315aeb6768906d95b" parent="b6959acdac5e12bb183e8debe0aeca75" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="ab50d9c4b479bfd409f69380c097ad09"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller 3rd and Arthur W. Packard on committee to revise by-laws. Arthur W. Packard did detail work.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="7d9bd56613af92d2244abbf698182ab9"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="5478c68182af4c31b027013c3ef8a861" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - National Committee on Maternal Health - Contributions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1924/1961" type="inclusive">1924, 1933-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="be9e7c051502a16726263b1ade049ebf" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044925]" type="box">1</container><container id="72946390483226b6a9328fdbe6329c4f" parent="be9e7c051502a16726263b1ade049ebf" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="ef7f64c045798891cd4d8ecd8e98285d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contributions by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd and Bureau of Social Hygiene toward research and propagation of ideas.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="8b70147a6204742d0e0e1eadba6ac878"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="a4892bef5ee64204b3af19901881ce45" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - National Committee on Maternal Health - Contributions - John D. Rockefeller 3rd</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1950" type="inclusive">1934-1943, 1948-1950</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="d1c5b1a3179e721d0fc18973182d8668" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044926]" type="box">2</container><container id="662e00da0589bad2d7e7b04e87d8cc7f" parent="d1c5b1a3179e721d0fc18973182d8668" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="575eaf55c3ee48fe3ff4c56b2b20732a"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Several anonymous contributions.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="81dcb8854186f79a4551dde71713f3c5"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="70ae1f0c276848fea7e36963e7acf325" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - American Birth Control League - Contributions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1924/1938" type="inclusive">1924-1938</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="bc51a744c7f54483182edf9614294ddf" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044926]" type="box">2</container><container id="1a25aa72b7ba62d265ced4ce1a2147c4" parent="bc51a744c7f54483182edf9614294ddf" type="folder">8</container></did><scopecontent id="d6a092abdcda2385d0f8a8866b9f2221"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Developing plans of the League. Anonymous contribution by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in 1924; direct but anonymous Rockefeller contributions during 1930. Contributions from Bureau of Social Hygiene; small donations from Nelson A. Rockefeller and Laurance S. Rockefeller; some contributions through Planned Parenthood Committee. Correspondents include Margaret Sanger, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick, Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="96702c6984e194fee401b133f12b9543"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.2</p></fileplan></c><c id="96bacaaaa6234b0f8e7882f3ad3b4f3e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - American Birth Control League - Contributions - John D. Rockefeller 3rd</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="ddcac382437102cc73dd85311cf113d4" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044926]" type="box">2</container><container id="c226a77b767d219aef169bca8789ea2e" parent="ddcac382437102cc73dd85311cf113d4" type="folder">9</container></did><scopecontent id="a1450a85ab67b933b9c4a04f4d0f1715"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Special contribution for Massachusetts fight.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="60ccbed4db8555e912b38a5998221049"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.2</p></fileplan></c><c id="bf78472ea679488c9fb028dce1e13a0a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - Birth Control Clinical Research Bureau</unittitle><unitdate normal="1929/1939" type="inclusive">1929, 1933-1939</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="0b69d1f6eaac1ed237d495a97da02b16" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044926]" type="box">2</container><container id="5bfb292f963172e2467a5245ed8eba26" parent="0b69d1f6eaac1ed237d495a97da02b16" type="folder">10</container></did><scopecontent id="4c418a151b5dea279d3f25fd1b301521"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Margaret Sanger's splinter group which carried on for a while in competition with the older Birth Control League. John D. Rockefeller 3rd is the primary donor. Correspondents include Margaret Sanger.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="dd150e89af43c8340e1c6faa2e52ade2"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.2A</p></fileplan></c><c id="3e728087d48e41ffa2262511255099ef" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - New York Birth Control Federation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="61d2c3d39052135730eb28979f37c0fa" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044926]" type="box">2</container><container id="049b295e02ce4ebbe1583af894ad6bac" parent="61d2c3d39052135730eb28979f37c0fa" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent id="ba4ec47b09e8973491519df75e6478bc"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Reports on work; requests for aid. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="a51a956f9b274116440723666f8075c0"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.3</p></fileplan></c><c id="91fed202d80e4a22aff944ae3ec17f4f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - New York Birth Control Federation - Contributions - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="92b5346d867518ba7d7395a9a8d0f1cb" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044926]" type="box">2</container><container id="e69bd2859180f7cd8ff08531c84bc0b1" parent="92b5346d867518ba7d7395a9a8d0f1cb" type="folder">12</container></did><scopecontent id="e30fcb55f708e98aacd2d686154c8bc6"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr. annual contribution.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="0a8ca2ca543fe05e27544869d4d1d159"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.3</p></fileplan></c><c id="ae54fd9b86704d06acffb3470eb8d507" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - New York Birth Control Federation - Contributions - John D. Rockefeller 3rd</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="da35aa53c510e45022f37dab1242333f" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044926]" type="box">2</container><container id="3470d3c29dcd2c8826d3fac34096ea33" parent="da35aa53c510e45022f37dab1242333f" type="folder">13</container></did><scopecontent id="3f42c353a27a56939e398ef0690f9aeb"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Annual contribution.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="220233f32da6fdb6a25af1aebb9748e5"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.3</p></fileplan></c><c id="92a4f20e172c4f29af7779a6c7ca8cdd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - Population Association of America</unittitle><unitdate normal="1935/1940" type="inclusive">1935-1936, 1940</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="0ede5e564a7235b5e2387553641dd972" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044926]" type="box">2</container><container id="87146d0c26b35bed9e0e481782538375" parent="0ede5e564a7235b5e2387553641dd972" type="folder">14</container></did><scopecontent id="067f7680e4121cb129a95521c1409950"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>To study population trends. Contribution by John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="82aa289e8790d8546205c5f12a5fec4f"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.4</p></fileplan></c><c id="14e62e1fdfd142cdae1326e3f999ded8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - Population Association of America - Contributions - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="fd3ae22f8e09182bc62dae3d3afd01ae" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044926]" type="box">2</container><container id="3208451c542791bfbb3f1ea05f73b66d" parent="fd3ae22f8e09182bc62dae3d3afd01ae" type="folder">15</container></did><scopecontent id="6150de2b2a74654393bd3f42cee27358"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="f3c52ee10db34e4e8ccfe07a1d410420"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.4</p></fileplan></c><c id="ab502eb505244bdcbe1f0fab807abff3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - Eugenics Society</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1940" type="inclusive">1934-1940</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="ebf804addd3e56ea097a82d824561530" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044926]" type="box">2</container><container id="cc90d1dc4655f0ab01e4f169dd095c5e" parent="ebf804addd3e56ea097a82d824561530" type="folder">16</container></did><scopecontent id="9ce5d43004969caa3ec7186b0456e4c2"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>English society concerned with birth control problems. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="3d73b8df4dd580711cecbe612f49b1a4"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.5</p></fileplan></c><c id="2cf57b4f2fb34d3c8821bffc8eb5766a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - National Medical Committee on Federal and State Legislation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1935, 1939</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="6022882316f13d40edcd0810a0c2a486" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044927]" type="box">3</container><container id="9d8188b5b0a7c10b6e72f479029022aa" parent="6022882316f13d40edcd0810a0c2a486" type="folder">17</container></did><scopecontent id="bc2a8fd2a453520dc8b1c9961856c0eb"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Effort to get federal laws regarding contraceptives repealed. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution. Arthur W. Packard followed committee's activities. Correspondents include Margaret Sanger, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Raymond B. Fosdick, Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="ee66950df2248ce65b0fb9c6ee77db37"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.6</p></fileplan></c><c id="7d9283befcb142cf9496ffaaec15d206" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - National Committee on Federal Legislation for Birth Control</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1937" type="inclusive">1934-1937</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="7cc536dd145c31ee6f0699a4a3e3110a" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044927]" type="box">3</container><container id="2e3dedd70abdd8ee676464e0bd9ca5ce" parent="7cc536dd145c31ee6f0699a4a3e3110a" type="folder">18</container></did><scopecontent id="d4606a616571fc30c146df67ab755c65"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Lobby group advocating changes in birth control laws. Correspondents include Arthur w. Packard, Morris Ernst, Margaret Sanger.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="8dc17a73225933098fbd92a6c9b7eaa8"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.7</p></fileplan></c><c id="f885d9035316445fb18628565767624f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - National Committee on Federal Legislation for Birth Control - Contributions - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1937" type="inclusive">1934-1937</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="9e18181809c2f824c419711af50b0947" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044927]" type="box">3</container><container id="99f91670526bd67d0ebef53c9073c983" parent="9e18181809c2f824c419711af50b0947" type="folder">19</container></did><scopecontent id="46824f149be9fea54667dd4aa931643d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="762a479781f7165f7580f20a6551b554"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.7</p></fileplan></c><c id="91762fb023484550ac7c2b22911c9da6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - National Committee on Federal Legislation for Birth Control - Contributions - John D. Rockefeller 3rd</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="a117ef5f1efba6ff17caa9b035d3f98f" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044927]" type="box">3</container><container id="3155c25121b30d25057df19b5b8c8671" parent="a117ef5f1efba6ff17caa9b035d3f98f" type="folder">20</container></did><fileplan id="372e353dd3ace303c36e2e5a12aada29"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.7</p></fileplan></c><c id="e9f416cec26c4270931a2736a5db21fa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - National Committee for Medical Rights in Massachusetts</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1942" type="inclusive">1940-1942</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="413dfd6986ada3f323bda37c9e5340e7" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044927]" type="box">3</container><container id="e7993d27dd238fec5b4d50f00bb5df89" parent="413dfd6986ada3f323bda37c9e5340e7" type="folder">21</container></did><scopecontent id="cf19ab023d0425f876335a6d8ebc163b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Worked in Massachusetts referendum to repeal state anti-contraceptive laws. John D. Rockefeller 3rd contributed. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="af9a7713aaf0f4d0797bb372a9f8fab9"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.8</p></fileplan></c><c id="250eaf11177e4bf0b8ef083c571b411d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - Maternity Center Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1952" type="inclusive">1940, 1944-1952</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="fed6479807304bb474bc895b435370e4" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044927]" type="box">3</container><container id="d68a98a148119438f3c37f200daa3f0f" parent="fed6479807304bb474bc895b435370e4" type="folder">22</container></did><scopecontent id="412331451ddf4211b16390a8fae3937f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Reports on work in educational program for parents, obstetrical training for nurses. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="f8c4100ea90e6d1fb18ecaa771a285e1"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.9</p></fileplan></c><c id="0dc1a2cb8f5e4dcbb54d7a74747374e4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - Maternity Center Association - Contributions - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1947" type="inclusive">1940-1947</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="4f23095b12582e90ed50a498af5775a9" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044927]" type="box">3</container><container id="b016f8895e2d6aa7213d4b5bd9c63793" parent="4f23095b12582e90ed50a498af5775a9" type="folder">23</container></did><fileplan id="27c79f7f8db13d41e7a3266e9e4c53e7"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.9</p></fileplan></c><c id="414fa3ccd80a452b8a880e2b1c3cb64b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - Maternity Center Association - Contributions - Laurance S. Rockefeller and Nelson A. Rockefeller</unittitle><unitdate normal="1942/1960" type="inclusive">1942-1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="ebb479a860a3beab8706985035cc4aca" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044927]" type="box">3</container><container id="c43e06e7260a62b7569be776c9750c6e" parent="ebb479a860a3beab8706985035cc4aca" type="folder">24</container></did><fileplan id="172289837549c22bbf321e380364bab5"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.9</p></fileplan></c><c id="43e7ced906e94d5ba6cb855cf97abdf2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - Population Study - L. Outhwaite - Laurance S. Rockefeller</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1951" type="inclusive">1947-1951</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="0d89176cc50261afae2810fccdf33bba" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044927]" type="box">3</container><container id="8bd038dfab8056290798f1a0f7422822" parent="0d89176cc50261afae2810fccdf33bba" type="folder">25</container></did><scopecontent id="2aac1e56494011e9029b20209c784343"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Outhwaite hired by Laurance S. Rockefeller to prepare study of population trends. Delays; supervision. No copy of study in file. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Leonard Outhwaite, Arthur W. Packard, E. B. Young.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="a616540b41ab09f27b378ea889833210"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.10</p></fileplan></c><c id="1dbda9380e9a46b9b9df78b003ca3a1b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - Birthright, Inc. (Human Betterment Association of America)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1944/1961" type="inclusive">1944, 1947-1951, 1955-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="ba6a42b1034e3a82f3459ae87cc833f0" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044928]" type="box">4</container><container id="ef507abe5bc6f2f8b1459a7a23ddd64c" parent="ba6a42b1034e3a82f3459ae87cc833f0" type="folder">26</container></did><scopecontent id="11d10ec348dd8dad7c9a8fbee687d379"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Urged selective sterilization. Abby Rockefeller Mauzé made first family contribution, 1959; repeated in 1961. John D. Rockefeller 3rd interested in organization's goals, but did not contribute. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Abby Rockefeller Mauzé.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="6f7f05a1cf728846faee8cd9a5afd939"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.11</p></fileplan></c><c id="8fc4d9fb6eaf45db8d19aa1c19c04d7b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - American Committee on Maternal Health</unittitle><unitdate normal="1949/1949" type="inclusive">1949</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="b5164a04a1ac87fe7a2991548f9f572f" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044928]" type="box">4</container><container id="f6fb7571f875696c9e7b0b29555d60d3" parent="b5164a04a1ac87fe7a2991548f9f572f" type="folder">27</container></did><scopecontent id="3243d43988e85a4b8314d2066c02c682"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Unsuccessful attempt to interest office in work of Committee. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="deefde57aa244837d4bbb49b6a5846d0"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.12</p></fileplan></c><c id="f9de992cbbd34acea885e52fc062eb49" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - Population Reference Bureau</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1961" type="inclusive">1940, 1954-1955, 1960-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="363465e144ef9c2ad7c0884edb5f2715" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044928]" type="box">4</container><container id="347dedf5ba2b4a5bce1c1699ccdcb0b5" parent="363465e144ef9c2ad7c0884edb5f2715" type="folder">28</container></did><scopecontent id="548edacc5b371e294264838bf920f991"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Information center on population problems. Issued "Population Bulletin" and other articles on population growth. Contributions by Abby Rockefeller Mauzé. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Abby Rockefeller Mauzé.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="d7184a474a9d0c9852396aeb31b6a620"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.13</p></fileplan></c><c id="6883ae491aa748b29eedd3c4aa37e097" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - World Population Emergency Campaign</unittitle><unitdate normal="1958/1961" type="inclusive">1958-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="6f11c82201c065f46b153842f65357e1" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044928]" type="box">4</container><container id="bd7f4f39cbe01fd077da92b830d7a6b5" parent="6f11c82201c065f46b153842f65357e1" type="folder">29</container></did><scopecontent id="4f5b998108d64d542bf3dd41a2c15462"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Special fund-raising campaign. Tribute to Margaret Sanger on 45th anniversary of her first clinic. No Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, William H. Draper, Margaret Sanger.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="bcdcfc6125c30cb0f726c329ec919957"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.14</p></fileplan></c><c id="1959239627f041ac9e5c93e6eca6c6d7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - World Population Emergency Campaign</unittitle><unitdate normal="1961/1961" type="inclusive">1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="899b21216809c993ed8445aa30c3122e" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044928]" type="box">4</container><container id="64d3a03193929709a9718671afd73336" parent="899b21216809c993ed8445aa30c3122e" type="folder">29A</container></did><scopecontent id="c0033dd7ddaa34107e71adaf8814340d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Special fund-raising campaign. Tribute to Margaret Sanger on 45th anniversary of her first clinic. No Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, William H. Draper, Margaret Sanger.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="1b149fb8688a3a47f2e093b25fe6d445"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.14</p></fileplan></c><c id="619616bef9414e10a61da7ca02e4d105" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - Birth Control Federation of America</unittitle><unitdate normal="1939/1942" type="inclusive">1939-1942</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="f2c594d3c113b237bb83c8de84868759" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044928]" type="box">4</container><container id="d111db9964bb222507b3e0b0dfdfc773" parent="f2c594d3c113b237bb83c8de84868759" type="folder">30</container></did><scopecontent id="de6e12c0db4a49c125b068f6c6ed3d6d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Consolidation of American Birth Control League and Birth Control Clinic. Plans, program of Federation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard, MArgaret Sanger, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="3b7713a42cd8bce988dc7873a5c821f8"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.21</p></fileplan></c><c id="e0ecf3ff8ffa47cfae6b7261cd37b5a9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - Birth Control Federation of America - Contributions - John D. Rockefeller 3rd</unittitle><unitdate normal="1939/1941" type="inclusive">1939-1941</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="64296b642bf095c1c2bffa5a130ec7db" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044928]" type="box">4</container><container id="b703205fe7075dd5462764bb1bec266d" parent="64296b642bf095c1c2bffa5a130ec7db" type="folder">31</container></did><scopecontent id="6dca37bf75b8c76a686adae4b8c98f1c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Consolidation of American Birth Control League and Birth Control Clinic. Plans, program of Federation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard, MArgaret Sanger, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="4fca5c0721a968e4f88e76eab345e89c"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.21</p></fileplan></c><c id="70d1cc9c54204841a6768fdda011053c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - Planned Parenthood Federation of America</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="845f476d4295782fb32307e8a37e68ee"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Background information on organization; routine affairs of Federation. Problems of organization; Margaret Sanger. Arthur W. Packard represented Rockefeller interest. Contributions made by Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Mary French Rockefeller, Abby Rockefeller Mauzé, and Martha Baird Rockefeller throughout the years 1940-1961. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Margaret Sanger, Kenneth Rose, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Dana S. Creel, William Vogt.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="c037ce38f7aeb9c30e026a83910ea655"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.22</p></fileplan><c id="edb8f5f0eb044f5ca2f86fc91f8479be" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1940/1946" type="inclusive">1940-1946</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="2e2ce01d1d0685dd2a3aedefe8dcf2dd" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044928]" type="box">4</container><container id="8855745ff70033c30ec0a8803842df04" parent="2e2ce01d1d0685dd2a3aedefe8dcf2dd" type="folder">32</container></did></c><c id="56a0ad04bc9c437aa7ace74747fb13cc" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1947/1949" type="inclusive">1947-1949</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="3f8d46c96f52d756eeb89b4070e6e947" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044928]" type="box">4</container><container id="4b7badb11cea52a0141b8b6a38c5e39c" parent="3f8d46c96f52d756eeb89b4070e6e947" type="folder">33</container></did><odd id="ca43fd18bba6d17dfd42b0d29e80341d"><head>General note</head><p>DR material removed to Folder 33A.</p></odd></c><c id="db9b6603e7fb4f1281f0d78101262a30" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1947/1949" type="inclusive">1947-1949</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="0f0f6bd6ff98e880df8ac27357f0eff3" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044928]" type="box">4</container><container id="3119bfa0fa772de6a0d13774672a9444" parent="0f0f6bd6ff98e880df8ac27357f0eff3" type="folder">33A</container></did></c><c id="a3bb31d6f9d34e0ba1ee6d965f1f369f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Not Used</unittitle><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="6d47a8233550e96bf2dc12b9b06ac9c0" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044928]" type="box">4</container><container id="eff4d63c95d03842ee68d516e4c239f0" parent="6d47a8233550e96bf2dc12b9b06ac9c0" type="folder">34</container></did></c><c id="8498f3cff4bf4b0ba2af50ac4c81a2ff" level="file"><did><unittitle>Not Used</unittitle><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="d2af9945d8c48863389a006fb28c6e79" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044928]" type="box">4</container><container id="7e72e148de357d61f43453dcd584da55" parent="d2af9945d8c48863389a006fb28c6e79" type="folder">35</container></did></c><c id="709e8e6bd6dd4107aec13d70acf5544e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Not Used</unittitle><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="880ccfda15a17b1a6df62698f93f7ae7" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044928]" type="box">4</container><container id="95d49dd13888c3029a989ea902477ad1" parent="880ccfda15a17b1a6df62698f93f7ae7" type="folder">36</container></did></c><c id="19fcdc22b88d4baaabb9ec8682875880" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1950/1952" type="inclusive">1950-1952</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="ef5323910e45b720b36d7bce216bf161" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044929]" type="box">5</container><container id="007c9cc16ac06641e934d20f5a40c68e" parent="ef5323910e45b720b36d7bce216bf161" type="folder">37</container></did></c><c id="89393c654bbd40ff97a01926aed3194a" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1953/1959" type="inclusive">1953-1959</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="4c61881b55f58fe59fc15c1c40311ae4" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044929]" type="box">5</container><container id="d402232714ec02f56692af373d947c5a" parent="4c61881b55f58fe59fc15c1c40311ae4" type="folder">38</container></did></c><c id="aeb9f5543d0f4ce19752d638a7bd1d56" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1960/1961" type="inclusive">1960-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="89644501f8a4e68038db7826a5c67c54" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044929]" type="box">5</container><container id="07fc4cad7674b0cecf9c0fa25d29ec6e" parent="89644501f8a4e68038db7826a5c67c54" type="folder">39</container></did></c><c id="59938063d347426a9895c3e0f84f0002" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1958/1961" type="inclusive">1958-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="966abc5ca3e12535f55a0a4d555a50bd" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044929]" type="box">5</container><container id="7a5fa2224fa703e9e63355d0166a4aa7" parent="966abc5ca3e12535f55a0a4d555a50bd" type="folder">39A</container></did><accessrestrict id="956475ab22746d3e78e4b6d00e2c7180"><head>Conditions Governing Access note</head><p>Restricted material.</p></accessrestrict></c></c><c id="86e5fe1c06b84b7db3a2163606258582" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - International Planned Parenthood Federation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1948/1956" type="inclusive">1948, 1951-1956</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="67bb795963275fce87f57fdc15d7dedd" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044929]" type="box">5</container><container id="8d902e481b2fd63a7e7a654ea069bb2e" parent="67bb795963275fce87f57fdc15d7dedd" type="folder">40</container></did><scopecontent id="4f41166a460b82e507e84de3bebaf0e4"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Policies and program of Federation; family interest in international program. Contributions by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include Margaret Sanger, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Martha Baird Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="54c0cc4d65e5b6307870865926256f25"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.23</p></fileplan></c><c id="ca015135be814a7cb756986c9f461d88" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birth Control - International Planned Parenthood Federation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1957/1961" type="inclusive">1957-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="153b89cd7c0071f6bb0e7cf404ec22d1" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044929]" type="box">5</container><container id="7727aad0f32560a40bad6ecbde0b0ba6" parent="153b89cd7c0071f6bb0e7cf404ec22d1" type="folder">41</container></did><scopecontent id="575f8f28cd208b382475bc56af60a3af"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Policies and program of Federation; family interest in international program. Contributions by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include Margaret Sanger, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Martha Baird Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="2e957c28f093c0e714ed8e83400160e8"><head>File Plan note</head><p>139.23</p></fileplan></c></c><c id="dbc5ace5b6e749e69e340bd0a976dc02" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Cancer</unittitle></did><c id="4c59a01937e94838810e14ab084950e1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cancer - American Cancer Society - General Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1913/1929" type="inclusive">1913, 1915-1929</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="c2330d16c33ad204c481f7e24e549a4b" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044930]" type="box">6</container><container id="397e008a274d59f67a3c26f6160d41e1" parent="c2330d16c33ad204c481f7e24e549a4b" type="folder">42</container></did><scopecontent id="2356a5de61b0a9a4d69ff6a7efe73dc6"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Formerly American Society for the Control of Cancer. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $125,000 in 1926 toward endowment, plus $15,000 to complete $1,000,000 campaign. Contribution record; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made largest annual contribution by any individual. Thomas M. Debevoise a member of Society. Contributions by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, Laurance S. Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="e655fbfd8b2a65dc46df153a99032265"><head>File Plan note</head><p>136</p></fileplan></c><c id="66419b56a679493bac304ccd1ed4b62e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cancer - American Cancer Society - General Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1930/1961" type="inclusive">1930-1931, 1937-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="1e29b37ef47442d75009eec90af44b88" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044930]" type="box">6</container><container id="59904a8d8a1a100fc74999f50b2ffdca" parent="1e29b37ef47442d75009eec90af44b88" type="folder">43</container></did><scopecontent id="635bab98d1098bd50551ccf576cfdd67"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Formerly American Society for the Control of Cancer. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $125,000 in 1926 toward endowment, plus $15,000 to complete $1,000,000 campaign. Contribution record; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made largest annual contribution by any individual. Thomas M. Debevoise a member of Society. Contributions by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, Laurance S. Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="d1856c6c77c1cb9028474e32ae0e0331"><head>File Plan note</head><p>136</p></fileplan></c><c id="44c47a99b0a44ba893695d987fa7d561" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cancer - American Cancer Society - Westchester County Committee</unittitle><unitdate normal="1930/1949" type="inclusive">1930-1932, 1940-1941, 1946-1947, 1949, 1951-1953, 1957, 1959-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="c1372f350ac881ca3b37f14648bc75ee" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044930]" type="box">6</container><container id="7a642bb0e74836326aaa8747428dc759" parent="c1372f350ac881ca3b37f14648bc75ee" type="folder">44</container></did><scopecontent id="97187e95de560609d4a5beb2bceb20c4"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Small gifts.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="cac154148ccb7c526023f71a0c51029f"><head>File Plan note</head><p>136</p></fileplan></c><c id="16f40289bdca41aabde82aa9b15a20dc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cancer - New York City Cancer Committee</unittitle><unitdate normal="1930/1950" type="inclusive">1930-1935, 1940-1950</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="8431f72b8aa774bdfb61f8ee2e0ccbca" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044930]" type="box">6</container><container id="5f629733b6f8e83b2a18d3c2862114b0" parent="8431f72b8aa774bdfb61f8ee2e0ccbca" type="folder">45</container></did><scopecontent id="42454dea3ed95a77fe0554cc41e2478a"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Subject of individual family giving until 1947, after which Rockefeller Brothers Fund made regular contributions and family declined most requests. Small small gifts made; Laurance S. Rockefeller stock gift; others, 1950-1961. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Martha Baird Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="bd539649bbcec3af000710107081f56a"><head>File Plan note</head><p>136</p></fileplan></c><c id="899045b92dca4999a95dbd23c0d82a69" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cancer - New York City Cancer Committee</unittitle><unitdate normal="1951/1961" type="inclusive">1951-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="8f3d57cc6cea1c516505f0a98e8e01d3" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044930]" type="box">6</container><container id="d720eef8dc14d4a763d44b9c6ad657a4" parent="8f3d57cc6cea1c516505f0a98e8e01d3" type="folder">46</container></did><scopecontent id="7e594a1b9e002d257ca31de0d3d7ac58"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Subject of individual family giving till 1947, after which Rockefeller Brothers Fund made regular contributions and family declined most requests. Small small gifts made; Laurance S. Rockefeller stock gift; others, 1950-1961. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Martha Baird Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="154e12eca7019f17c96444c92e00a823"><head>File Plan note</head><p>136</p></fileplan></c><c id="89ef4eb88e954259a538c7d3217b015d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cancer - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1933/1949" type="inclusive">1933, 1937-1949</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="8806ea00949bbbc45b659a4007101e46" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044930]" type="box">6</container><container id="666226ecc6454b46cad89668aee82b59" parent="8806ea00949bbbc45b659a4007101e46" type="folder">47</container></did><scopecontent id="3eba3688080a3d679caf0d5397db17cc"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Suggested cancer cures, crackpot and otherwise. Requests for aid, declined.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="a45fe6ecdd326b64518a3508707adbcf"><head>File Plan note</head><p>136.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="e97974f3e1d840acb50aef8992be763f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cancer - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1959" type="inclusive">1950-1959</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="4d888e30e08ac4de92a3857ca3e3d70b" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044931]" type="box">7</container><container id="685216d144e6a9fcf62808b84f0edaad" parent="4d888e30e08ac4de92a3857ca3e3d70b" type="folder">48</container></did><scopecontent id="426154a7ff8602de1f7ffc6b547145b4"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Suggested cancer cures, crackpot and otherwise. Requests for aid, declined.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="da3fa4a3239e788d28c28e1187df8710"><head>File Plan note</head><p>136.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="93c734db4c414ec39569a3e1102a50db" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cancer - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1960/1961" type="inclusive">1960-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="908acc4918d24c2117789bef8861355d" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044931]" type="box">7</container><container id="2a524cd063cee30fefe01ecec441ecdb" parent="908acc4918d24c2117789bef8861355d" type="folder">49</container></did><scopecontent id="a9b3603d94a5a7cdcf810a2977d5fd28"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Suggested cancer cures, crackpot and otherwise. Requests for aid, declined.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="6502bb1e82d3771b6bbf5bb60ee2ca78"><head>File Plan note</head><p>136.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="4094d5ade99c4d429477c695bb773dae" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cancer - National Cancer Foundation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1946/1961" type="inclusive">1946-1949, 1956-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="ed4ee7cb24aaa8438dfe28d3d3839b54" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044931]" type="box">7</container><container id="3009d851459fe941dfe53b539c27e4c4" parent="ed4ee7cb24aaa8438dfe28d3d3839b54" type="folder">50</container></did><scopecontent id="c500ea79958edac06a1c858e420c3893"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Laurance S. Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Mrs. Frank Washburn.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="93d4d301794345016c13873a34b6bd9c"><head>File Plan note</head><p>136.2</p></fileplan></c></c><c id="55178bd88ad84b4b8a3f263fa0d911ab" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies</unittitle></did><c id="4518074e025c4ad09e6c5b6bbbb8bda1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - American Public Health Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1919/1956" type="inclusive">1919-1932, 1937, 1944, 1949, 1954-1956</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="924f5059cb8b74655132c77e89f9f1dd" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044931]" type="box">7</container><container id="94c0c97ea26e25f6bb2e2606c1b0f03a" parent="924f5059cb8b74655132c77e89f9f1dd" type="folder">51</container></did><scopecontent id="c0968bfaa56cf4c305ddee20763583ee"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>To improve medical conditions at local level. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. becomes sustaining member at $50.00 a year, 1919; increased gifts to $100 in 1925; discontinued in 1930. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. served on special committee in New York City for American Public Health Association (APHA) convention. Raymond B. Fosdick article from "American Journal of Public Health," November 1944. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s letter to Dr. Albert Gregg (recipient of Lasker Award). Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="1829187c9b36f928d1d2fd11565d5aaf"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137</p></fileplan></c><c id="69388c61313042f18538b5e1cf5d42a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Citizen's Health Committee on Neighborhood Health Development</unittitle><unitdate normal="1941/1946" type="inclusive">1941-1943, 1946</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="1a04d4850c2c30e8d198ddfac43ad712" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044931]" type="box">7</container><container id="9519d5cd52b0fd82da8f50bfc0f797b1" parent="1a04d4850c2c30e8d198ddfac43ad712" type="folder">52</container></did><scopecontent id="92145b6ec72d587b22f615f86c43a180"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>To inform public of health services. John D. Rockefeller 3rd contributions. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="bc13a46c212aa2c1d23c8a975b54b2a0"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="ac4071b64e2c444282cf97483fc1ce9e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - United States Public Health Service - Subcommittee for Civilian Cooperation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="59259f0fb54a1f9045c3b65554c5835c" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044931]" type="box">7</container><container id="71f3581c50642c1c27f98c95c73c135f" parent="59259f0fb54a1f9045c3b65554c5835c" type="folder">53</container></did><scopecontent id="ecb936620cb8406fb9cc35d2fb5237c1"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Branch of hygiene work directed to fighting venereal disease in armed forces during World War I. Based on cooperation with the federal government. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. referred matter to Rockefeller Foundation and Bureau of Social Hygiene; agreed to make small monthly gifts. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s attitude toward publicity about venereal disease fight. Major W. F. Snow's Reports. USO's 1943 objectives. Correspondents include W. H. Zinnser, Jerome D. Greene, Major W. F. Snow, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="0741fe35e8054741126048036e295bc8"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="1265206396f241f0b09b486820c72cfd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - United States Public Health Service - Council of National Defense - Major Snow</unittitle><unitdate normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="09ce6b50683c86bc5705a72bf8a0e7d4" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044931]" type="box">7</container><container id="cc8543e4675af9c9aae5c56076f6cc64" parent="09ce6b50683c86bc5705a72bf8a0e7d4" type="folder">54</container></did><fileplan id="f297088cc88fe127270fdc46d19d7cc0"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="e8be17ef755144eba33d2b57e4b62618" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - United States Public Health Service - Subcommittee for Civilian Cooperation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1920/1943" type="inclusive">1920, 1943</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="6df48365d0f915336a253f6aadb8a7c3" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044931]" type="box">7</container><container id="b23b0e021acd1df0fc3c1e97e06ae48f" parent="6df48365d0f915336a253f6aadb8a7c3" type="folder">55</container></did><scopecontent id="848affc9b04a763f9a2141c35c1870b3"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Branch of hygiene work directed to fighting venereal disease in armed forces during World War I. Based on cooperation with the federal government. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. referred matter to Rockefeller Foundation and Bureau of Social Hygiene; agreed to make small monthly gifts. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s attitude toward publicity about venereal disease fight. Major W. F. Snow's Reports. USO's 1943 objectives. Correspondents include W. H. Zinnser, Jerome D. Greene, Major W. F. Snow, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="650cdc258b70c44c268eb2ddfd777075"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="93f2e487a5e5497895af1e3558e9f6ac" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Department of Health - New York</unittitle><unitdate normal="1912/1960" type="inclusive">1912-1913, 1918, 1920-1923, 1933, 1942-1947, 1956-1957, 1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="e48da556294a294ab383e67c271cf6c9" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044931]" type="box">7</container><container id="8186d3501cc413e18ef5723ef4380cb7" parent="e48da556294a294ab383e67c271cf6c9" type="folder">56</container></did><scopecontent id="8f2ace7498dce3147ba7f4cc3bd18920"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contributions through Rockefeller Brothers Fund. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Martha Baird Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="aa5667f58b23461b8d8f54a1bbdc2422"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.3</p></fileplan></c><c id="05fbd424d5c34daabc7cc27bd16bbb0b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Department of Health - New York - American Museum of Health</unittitle><unitdate normal="1939/1950" type="inclusive">1939-1941, 1947-1950</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="2b9a038bdfdbebb0354bb2e09a805516" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044931]" type="box">7</container><container id="bf6e41ad0b588454e922983c5831f772" parent="2b9a038bdfdbebb0354bb2e09a805516" type="folder">57</container></did><scopecontent id="0a6c1e9e6410606037470276f86e12d4"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Museum at Hunter college. Mayor LaGuardia asks Rockefellers to support organization; declined.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="235b5fe9fde0bbaee1002f4657c93235"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.3</p></fileplan></c><c id="abd9c301799940a787bc0ada9d84483b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Department of Health - New York - Baby Week</unittitle><unitdate normal="1914/1914" type="inclusive">1914</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="6894719bfb45f89d683b776109ff50d5" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044931]" type="box">7</container><container id="70f536ab2c595235b018a7cc09ab4f82" parent="6894719bfb45f89d683b776109ff50d5" type="folder">58</container></did><fileplan id="7e7be0b52053e9bd6c12b42bd347c393"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.3</p></fileplan></c><c id="bc1ecb9763ea4487980f2126aa276d39" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Public Health Research Institute of New York City</unittitle><unitdate normal="1941/1952" type="inclusive">1941-1950, 1952</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="12b856557f31aca81117f2978157e471" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044932]" type="box">8</container><container id="a6554c2a3fbba47f8e634202e655ec3f" parent="12b856557f31aca81117f2978157e471" type="folder">59</container></did><scopecontent id="3b027256ffde1735f88cdc6db086854d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Research on infectious diseases; city supported. No Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="21ea4983f3a5dd03cee3efacc6cb5064"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.4</p></fileplan></c><c id="28454e146b204c5e8ddf042cb5847389" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Public Health Research Institute of New York City</unittitle><unitdate normal="1941/1952" type="inclusive">1941-1950, 1952</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="59a3019d65a9fb0cc8fa16731bfd58ca" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044932]" type="box">8</container><container id="dd6d5185c5076997cd609e44957d7992" parent="59a3019d65a9fb0cc8fa16731bfd58ca" type="folder">59A</container></did><scopecontent id="8cb5eb641c6cad033f496f925ab5a8a1"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>David Rockefeller a vice president for a short time. Correspondents include David Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="ea955b02c5b3545ab8ae0f93e516435c"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.4</p></fileplan></c><c id="f03dabc2761b4a3e9272a61eefe49d84" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Public Health Research Institute of New York City - Laurance S. Rockefeller</unittitle><unitdate normal="1960/1961" type="inclusive">1960-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="5c8ff9aa3e97ab5d63f51e6779b43f66" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044932]" type="box">8</container><container id="96ded60422eab5aaf3120c7f08806944" parent="5c8ff9aa3e97ab5d63f51e6779b43f66" type="folder">60</container></did><scopecontent id="7e62c7409437fe26313f1fd9616e8e97"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Establishment of a Department of Psychopharmacology at Institute. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, David Heyman, David F. Freeman.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="459f7795a59bc2119a9aa8899c652037"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.4</p></fileplan></c><c id="61819bd8cd114301875fa5888ece2061" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1955" type="inclusive">1947-1955</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="a21d298e1bf3a4b992bc13c867fc9325" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044932]" type="box">8</container><container id="91e5077e60b856d310694e27f8275b20" parent="a21d298e1bf3a4b992bc13c867fc9325" type="folder">61</container></did><scopecontent id="fa16a49fcf4354889ea6c00bf0a2505c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appeals to members of the family for aid in various health programs; declined. Arthur Jones' participation in attempt to outline plan for national medical care, 1950. Laurance S. Rockefeller gift to National Paraplegia Foundation.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="39f5273458fc45f24f20903cdc6d5f09"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.5</p></fileplan></c><c id="bc78d0cda5374a20bd6221ee9f522d0a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies</unittitle><unitdate normal="1956/1956" type="inclusive">1956</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="4fdaeadbc4af3aaf131801dfabf4100f" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044932]" type="box">8</container><container id="1f666dd30b0b90db3ca061fc848a9510" parent="4fdaeadbc4af3aaf131801dfabf4100f" type="folder">62</container></did><scopecontent id="1da67ac834f744c5ed1e87b4ce8a6c04"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appeals to members of the family for aid in various health programs; declined. Arthur Jones' participation in attempt to outline plan for national medical care, 1950. Laurance S. Rockefeller gift to National Paraplegia Foundation,$50,00.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="501617973a020ba28131f78d82cb7947"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.5</p></fileplan></c><c id="8f811c07d5084eee8e54d3868cdcdc2a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - National Publicity Council</unittitle><unitdate normal="1943/1955" type="inclusive">1943-1944, 1955</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="8ce60d33ef6a4d5d64760d64ad3f0bf7" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044932]" type="box">8</container><container id="b6766f328a1e66d89aac47a881064c2f" parent="8ce60d33ef6a4d5d64760d64ad3f0bf7" type="folder">63</container></did><fileplan id="9fc71c4408cd3033d55a3b9b590d8bc6"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.5</p></fileplan></c><c id="ddc7f9a139574f25a4c8e217cdfcd622" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1946/1949" type="inclusive">1946-1949</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="3799642a38778251b8bc03f127e709dc" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044932]" type="box">8</container><container id="59de89f7195e652e9da29feeebdfac27" parent="3799642a38778251b8bc03f127e709dc" type="folder">64</container></did><fileplan id="e5761bb0f36bc0461186d59331aff595"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.5</p></fileplan></c><c id="b8f0b9c61e6148789e200fc68faf7dac" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1958" type="inclusive">1950-1958</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="3e058b75457359cb33a409f05175244e" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044932]" type="box">8</container><container id="e83fd2e6c23d844f23b08d436ddfd43c" parent="3e058b75457359cb33a409f05175244e" type="folder">65</container></did><fileplan id="e274540414f064440c5946ba6af3c7e6"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.5</p></fileplan></c><c id="c5488989c1e047edaf3ecc620509a754" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1958/1961" type="inclusive">1958-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="b0a94f6fb132c6709aff46c1261c93cb" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044932]" type="box">8</container><container id="7f0db6586d9aa49ba9cb49d35ff9bb78" parent="b0a94f6fb132c6709aff46c1261c93cb" type="folder">66</container></did><fileplan id="3eb474a489170ee714fd7fda44a2ea0f"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.5</p></fileplan></c><c id="4e04228c4d5f4992949b4e1b2e2bc80f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Health Council of Greater New York</unittitle><unitdate normal="1945/1950" type="inclusive">1945-1950</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="7d33a3818c4ebf098300d13f7bd1771d" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044933]" type="box">9</container><container id="dd8b18181b4e9dc7d38f334d9f4777d5" parent="7d33a3818c4ebf098300d13f7bd1771d" type="folder">67</container></did><scopecontent id="763ce1585e87d9b2575b78bcaca8ca0c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Study of health needs in New York City; group to coordinate various health agencies. By-laws, incorporation. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="979cf976ff7e9115b581e094ea74cba5"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.6</p></fileplan></c><c id="8cc6984e37ea42608a3ca8f19f76bad2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Health Council of Greater New York - Committee on Nursing Services for Civilian Defense</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1951" type="inclusive">1950-1951</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="b58137d2ed69a72906b8d676e7faa351" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044933]" type="box">9</container><container id="9e877f32148543daecd0bbc9520c3624" parent="b58137d2ed69a72906b8d676e7faa351" type="folder">68</container></did><fileplan id="b8b4c8fbd4dec24666fa65dca159e35b"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.6</p></fileplan></c><c id="79ac9f4be2b8484496890dfcaea1d7f8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - National Health Council</unittitle><unitdate normal="1946/1958" type="inclusive">1946-1958</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="9382f76bda7290549c0690ec60622f04" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044933]" type="box">9</container><container id="c9af643e1f0890d0402a37303b71d338" parent="9382f76bda7290549c0690ec60622f04" type="folder">69</container></did><scopecontent id="89be1dd5c2f7b7bbc72a15fad6168ab9"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>National Health Fund; Alan Gregg Fund. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel, Philip E. Ryan.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="c264e40b31d0b2a0b1839c1acd359faa"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.7</p></fileplan></c><c id="82b01b1cd2414866bd77a72d0e9cf7fa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - National Arthritis Research Foundation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1946/1955" type="inclusive">1946, 1955</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="31df4a0087a77e02e394e472dce1dd27" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044933]" type="box">9</container><container id="dc72f4d4fea054243933f8127f696702" parent="31df4a0087a77e02e394e472dce1dd27" type="folder">70</container></did><scopecontent id="d4e49f9bdd64a2d1a980774b29371886"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Invitations to dinner, declined. Correspondents include Spyros P. Skouras.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="30e53ff0043686a33bd1d4bb1eb77332"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.8</p></fileplan></c><c id="38b9a9a387b2471180a3d34db2ad09d1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Medical Memorial Fund, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1942/1948" type="inclusive">1942, 1944, 1948</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="5e2aa289bcc5fd4442fe1051ce54148a" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044933]" type="box">9</container><container id="00509aa214d0eb5adec8a319de2eb43f" parent="5e2aa289bcc5fd4442fe1051ce54148a" type="folder">71</container></did><scopecontent id="c3f6deb1c45f6ff8c1e0669f07944b1c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Organization to investigate needs and support medical research. Planned to siphon off some of the money spent on funeral flowers. Not successful apparently; no Rockefeller contribution. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="8e9bc07abb49d6a062f702a88a4d5393"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.9</p></fileplan></c><c id="73cc49864a4d4b8ca0edc4d90aa5a0a8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - National League for Nursing/National Organization for Public Health Nursing</unittitle><unitdate normal="1935/1960" type="inclusive">1935-1936, 1945-1954, 1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="7995311ab76b04beca3c50d9818ef927" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044933]" type="box">9</container><container id="c3b21e1eb75151c1ea7f5bd76aaed357" parent="7995311ab76b04beca3c50d9818ef927" type="folder">72</container></did><scopecontent id="5e70a94df6e69ef3a93d440f98ef6fe9"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contributions by Mary French Rockefeller ($25 annually); Mary Clark Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="ae9aca932fdeea1a384fc17af1469ce9"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.10</p></fileplan></c><c id="16e9663f3b024e6d829246d4036167de" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Cerebral Palsy - Miscellaneous Organizations and Treatment</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1961" type="inclusive">1947-1955, 1959-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="e9416b95e4f61e791730d5608b23e8ae" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044933]" type="box">9</container><container id="6b6db21cadbcb091efc8955724396a97" parent="e9416b95e4f61e791730d5608b23e8ae" type="folder">73</container></did><scopecontent id="1b31fa1cbfea212768ec10fc5b847112"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Invitations to activities, declined. Laurance S. Rockefeller contribution. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Harold Lunn, Anita Colby.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="d227eaacd5232c733ccf92099313858e"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.11</p></fileplan></c><c id="78d9d18f63054632b392193a3b3c261c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - National Mental Health Foundation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1946/1949" type="inclusive">1946-1949</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="278702bb839914e3f7fc478f3bc2818d" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044933]" type="box">9</container><container id="c2b3cffa7236a62e9ad507b3528b9f71" parent="278702bb839914e3f7fc478f3bc2818d" type="folder">74</container></did><scopecontent id="a752c3e5566c56909fdaa22a09bc3135"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>To improve the care of the mentally ill; backed up Dr. Rufus M. Jones. Rockefeller Foundation contribution, 1947; later requests for aid declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Rufus M. Jones.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="60e5f58777446ee5575eb18b3b7cf0ec"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.12</p></fileplan></c><c id="5bdbeb3ba7b44491b1d2b06d63a485a9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - National Mental Health Foundation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1946/1949" type="inclusive">1946-1949</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="85655134c9a4708ab0e980f32011c67f" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044933]" type="box">9</container><container id="8d092be7db9e489a88120bba6afbfbcd" parent="85655134c9a4708ab0e980f32011c67f" type="folder">74A</container></did><scopecontent id="86f67a48bc9c490514678b033cb00969"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Correspondents include David Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="0e5f678568b3ad0de2d9232b02893a0b"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.12</p></fileplan></c><c id="84fe828175194adc907a675e1cb987f4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - New York Heart Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1945/1961" type="inclusive">1945-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="e238f427d82520a66304d9ba435dc6d4" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044933]" type="box">9</container><container id="9c8d1275e47e7e802084e33f413dccf5" parent="e238f427d82520a66304d9ba435dc6d4" type="folder">75</container></did><scopecontent id="fad3d650aca43b1166228e93393e04e6"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Requests to members of family for aid and support. Some contributions; annual contribution by Abby Rockefeller Mauzé, 1947-1960. Correspondents include Abby Rockefeller Mauzé, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Thomas Dewey.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="fadd5295f4ade2035418ba422c501bf2"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.13</p></fileplan></c><c id="0536fd5f01344e44b112aae3130abd20" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - New York Heart Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1945/1961" type="inclusive">1945-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="6f05b0b7056c363a38b1ab4a6d8121fb" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044933]" type="box">9</container><container id="b92bb0b79412d23faf18520b14958231" parent="6f05b0b7056c363a38b1ab4a6d8121fb" type="folder">75A</container></did><scopecontent id="f8152f854f0b2b2351d6b4cdb7de1829"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Correspondents include David Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="4519f890cf08a6136a2d65079e0fbb0b"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.13</p></fileplan></c><c id="2c78d30812614e958c19c38090132afc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - National Multiple Sclerosis Society</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1960" type="inclusive">1947-1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="20c5b0d5fa5c31d73412a8ee4036d03f" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044934]" type="box">10</container><container id="e1236b1f39d8612a8ad5483a5ab91ed9" parent="20c5b0d5fa5c31d73412a8ee4036d03f" type="folder">76</container></did><scopecontent id="29c71b041da039aab6441ff8775df7fa"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>History of society; list of family's contributions, 1948-1959. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="602625ac4d0acc7eb4c2c582b8162561"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.14</p></fileplan></c><c id="aaf200faf9c2456481e20fa9259eb606" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - National Multiple Sclerosis Society - David Rockefeller</unittitle><unitdate normal="1955/1960" type="inclusive">1955-1956, 1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="9052bc59f869da40d5e8e21eeecae449" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044934]" type="box">10</container><container id="05cfd560c3257de3e660f04b1acb66f8" parent="9052bc59f869da40d5e8e21eeecae449" type="folder">77</container></did><scopecontent id="3ed5c2937c6455b9f6be2c8b4502e87d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Invitation to become chairman of 1955 campaign; declined. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, David Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="b060b8209a216c07ddb6c35af5b252d6"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.14</p></fileplan></c><c id="c6004caa088843ac949629409afec134" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - National Multiple Sclerosis Society - John D. Rockefeller 3rd</unittitle><unitdate normal="1952/1956" type="inclusive">1952, 1955-1956</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="065981cba7f69517cc5c3b035699fb5e" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044934]" type="box">10</container><container id="8022fd0518a37c66b8d8d508e0ba6ef5" parent="065981cba7f69517cc5c3b035699fb5e" type="folder">78</container></did><scopecontent id="2bcbbc7b24510851ea1a8a3a5d37217d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Request for contribution by personal friend, Mrs. T. E. Camp. No contributions made.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="447e4585c7c8a4dbfd6bbdbc34e2665f"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.14</p></fileplan></c><c id="c7348b3299054493a2e48a78155bf063" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - National Multiple Sclerosis Society - Laurance S. Rockefeller</unittitle><unitdate normal="1946/1961" type="inclusive">1946-1949, 1952-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="e26d53db88d29a1ae94276d97c6a524e" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044934]" type="box">10</container><container id="711ab1ab9c53b39fe33275072dc2918b" parent="e26d53db88d29a1ae94276d97c6a524e" type="folder">79</container></did><scopecontent id="dcf8ddb1d7fc7cc4c287f5f5f7f03e39"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contributions made on non-recurring basis. Death of Alan Ryder Breed, classmate of Laurance S. Rockefeller at Princeton, of multiple sclerosis. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Arthur Jones, Mrs. Richard Storrs, William C. Breed, Francis L. Waitmarsh.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="18e9b23afaf359909b7bbb526165beb4"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.14</p></fileplan></c><c id="2365df195c544999a0ff365fe96ef0b4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - New York Diabetes Association, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1961" type="inclusive">1947-1948, 1951, 1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="20f0d25acd8dd0ef08c416c360057a1b" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044934]" type="box">10</container><container id="674775c0440cec866f31dd2b78951f67" parent="20f0d25acd8dd0ef08c416c360057a1b" type="folder">80</container></did><scopecontent id="377af80a10e93e006e664373fa835fe6"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>To educate public on medical care for diabetes. Asked Nelson A. Rockefeller to be honorary patron of New York Diabetes Association; declined.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="00ee424d7a9cc607c482c5533fadd363"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.15</p></fileplan></c><c id="00f547c5be574da7ab7063dd1ebedb2e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Muscular Dystrophy Association of America</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1960" type="inclusive">1950-1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="81feac5723ef5bba54b830e8b2662c3b" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044934]" type="box">10</container><container id="328743b18f9854049edf0e60d2802fdd" parent="81feac5723ef5bba54b830e8b2662c3b" type="folder">81</container></did><scopecontent id="0af116a25621a40f32804d6338aa6023"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>To inform public and promote research. Mary French Rockefeller contribution. correspondents include Dana S. Creel, Arthur Jones, Mary French Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="3dc0e89600b4f42b15f8d13c3328262a"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.17</p></fileplan></c><c id="30cc493ff20a475aa3f8754a68b85736" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Virginia Council on Health and Medical Care</unittitle><unitdate normal="1946/1961" type="inclusive">1946, 1950, 1952-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="2674d62208a95aec6dfeb71923cb356c" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044934]" type="box">10</container><container id="ecbbcda1b763bca4a1889f88d084e9c0" parent="2674d62208a95aec6dfeb71923cb356c" type="folder">82</container></did><scopecontent id="84e2f245cad280815a45cbde5fe79d23"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>$3,000 contribution by Winthrop Rockefeller. Correspondents include Arthur Jones, Edgar J. Fisher, Carlisle H. Humelsine.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="14580c419df5b23e123b9984aa20aeb7"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.18</p></fileplan></c><c id="0ce57cbfe9ca4b6d81ff91556ca10893" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - International Society for Rehabilitation of Disabled</unittitle><unitdate normal="1953/1961" type="inclusive">1953-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="55bddf875a248c561056c507fc115d02" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044934]" type="box">10</container><container id="5c6dba0a7903f245e9025504f0d3c561" parent="55bddf875a248c561056c507fc115d02" type="folder">83</container></did><scopecontent id="7bf17d3d82ea200826ceffb68f2ef16c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Formerly International Society for the Welfare of Cripples. American Korean Foundation program. David Rockefeller gifts, Mary French Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, Arthur Jones, Howard Rusk, David Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="e4c1495a138bac94e4688a1fcd92ad77"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.19</p></fileplan></c><c id="42024059b26e47deb9a848ec889d42d8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - People to People Health Foundation, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1959/1961" type="inclusive">1959-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="6307d35ec7bd35789605b7e108b8d66a" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044934]" type="box">10</container><container id="54b65fc384340ccda787eab38432c8eb" parent="6307d35ec7bd35789605b7e108b8d66a" type="folder">84</container></did><scopecontent id="57bc3ba775cc156fa27a2738ef7384e4"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>"Project Hope" Navy hospital ship in Far East. John D. Rockefeller 3rd's contribution. Correspondents include David Freeman, William Walsh, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="bc0402bb07e51a214006eac49de133a3"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.20</p></fileplan></c><c id="b9bfc057ab294142a7467e268bc72b01" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Allergy Foundation of America</unittitle><unitdate normal="1954/1958" type="inclusive">1954, 1956-1958</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="142b7e24234ab1603e66834ec26b30b8" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044934]" type="box">10</container><container id="740363bc97ce80b3750ada972d2033d1" parent="142b7e24234ab1603e66834ec26b30b8" type="folder">85</container></did><scopecontent id="445c10accc93dc70c0b35c62003038b8"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Also American Foundation for Allergic Diseases. Edwin S. Webster Jr. Memorial Fund; Laurance S. Rockefeller's interest, contributions; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Raymond B. Fosdick contribution. Correspondents include Charles D. Marple, David Freeman, Arthur Jones, Horace Baldwin, Russell Ziegler, Thomas M. Debevoise, Dana S. Creel.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="2a5d62abe0c7d24669f08078f8a57e3d"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.51</p></fileplan></c><c id="aa9744fa2261437d9a94250dd910f1f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Allergy Foundation of America</unittitle><unitdate normal="1959/1960" type="inclusive">1959-1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="66d5ab71dbc44a5a0ee17c309b133d7c" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044935]" type="box">11</container><container id="7b1f085ca028ba1a47fc9cdbed2ad6f0" parent="66d5ab71dbc44a5a0ee17c309b133d7c" type="folder">86</container></did><scopecontent id="cef5cd8ec90f1fcf4ec0a16dc8d1a153"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Also American Foundation for Allergic Diseases. Edwin S. Webster Jr. Memorial Fund; Laurance S. Rockefeller's interest, contributions; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Raymond B. Fosdick contribution. Correspondents include Charles D. Marple, David Freeman, Arthur Jones, Horace Baldwin, Russell Ziegler, Thomas M. Debevoise, Dana S. Creel.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="1dd08d49ed2924c1c337095c433d2ed3"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.51</p></fileplan></c><c id="03905467df0f4ed498cac51b2f3530aa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Arthritis and Rheumatism Foundation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1948/1960" type="inclusive">1948-1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="d83fd011012ff1538dc544abb9bee9b9" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044935]" type="box">11</container><container id="5382175e785bc13c179bda7ad4af2593" parent="d83fd011012ff1538dc544abb9bee9b9" type="folder">87</container></did><scopecontent id="74a0e9c30f36da55a2a9019841a110d8"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Research organization. Some contributions; Rockefeller Brothers Fund made grants totalling $9,000; discontinued in 1956. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Paul Holbrook, John Corley.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="902411d21f8675fa8e8b29ea8610934f"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.81</p></fileplan></c><c id="15709442cca842068fc164b9ac60e8bc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Westchester Cerebral Palsy Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1946/1959" type="inclusive">1946-1959</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="9847ffaa4ea91174bc64dc00d4de5f84" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044935]" type="box">11</container><container id="a77bee8186021f9dbc0a7b823a0755b4" parent="9847ffaa4ea91174bc64dc00d4de5f84" type="folder">88</container></did><scopecontent id="43650dc33992ab08f94e2d1961bb9473"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Association to collect funds for research and referral clinic. Later requests declined. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Willard Simpkins.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="4e190c23ddb3343c20e99db013a71c49"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.111</p></fileplan></c><c id="89a17a814a2241178890855e4bb1f227" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Westchester Cerebral Palsy Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1946/1959" type="inclusive">1946-1959</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="d991230a38c1c5213bb77aa824767311" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044935]" type="box">11</container><container id="aeeab479ce646ff707b49866f3f1092c" parent="d991230a38c1c5213bb77aa824767311" type="folder">88A</container></did><scopecontent id="06eabd9d6adfa697cc7f3492d0ba0a5d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>David Rockefeller's single contribution. Correspondents include David Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="1e64380ba996d21dad8da8fa3628440e"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.111</p></fileplan></c><c id="606dbb6660854681ba30d365d7135b4d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - United Cerebral Palsy</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1961" type="inclusive">1950-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="5086444dbe3b478a53973ce77839e3ca" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044935]" type="box">11</container><container id="d50c7c1cb5339b454fb80d0210a6067d" parent="5086444dbe3b478a53973ce77839e3ca" type="folder">89</container></did><scopecontent id="178a56267243bf050453fa6b62ee81e2"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Many requests for participation; declined. Rockefeller Brothers Fund grant. Correspondents include Roger Firestone, Dana S. Creel, Thomas S. Nichols.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="a773a4e6b4c7d5018d1d8cae8d0afc9d"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.112</p></fileplan></c><c id="83e4adbe13094faa8e2943a1aaabef1b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - United Cerebral Palsy</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1961" type="inclusive">1950-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="b0d0737d2a78b772f539ca2da228fe76" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044935]" type="box">11</container><container id="6ec0b47b51a34546661ae2649007aebc" parent="b0d0737d2a78b772f539ca2da228fe76" type="folder">89A</container></did><scopecontent id="817333da1ab2df81d99d010d9a0660ff"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contributions by David Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="5fa61687f2af3b28ccd28bb83ce43c95"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.112</p></fileplan></c><c id="1bfc300a6d0e413d9afaab3d7e527bd4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - United Cerebral Palsy Research and Educational Foundation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1955/1961" type="inclusive">1955-1956, 1959-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="e8c6608147d676fd59b21bc7617c657f" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044935]" type="box">11</container><container id="28e5a40bbfad355bd2765cd20caadf8a" parent="e8c6608147d676fd59b21bc7617c657f" type="folder">90</container></did><scopecontent id="90ce7d36088594c3de6284f9f207e417"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Roger Firestone asks for Laurance S. Rockefeller's participation; declined.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="74c94bd222bc0851ba850c9654b77e3c"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.112</p></fileplan></c><c id="d5173e2a1d7741ba9977841a66930225" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - United Cerebral Palsy - New York City</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1961" type="inclusive">1950-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="b12bef6dd5af99558efdc2298b6a6eaf" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044935]" type="box">11</container><container id="71c2d5f99153b28b6cc2be883f6aafa7" parent="b12bef6dd5af99558efdc2298b6a6eaf" type="folder">91</container></did><scopecontent id="42f3e729f3a7d5e619eb42142be8d75e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Promotion of research, provide information, etc. Laurance S. Rockefeller gift. No real interest shown. Correspondents include Arthur Jones, Peter Grimm, Percy J. Ebbott.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="91d4d66cf621f3b196a3b19f7f890550"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.113</p></fileplan></c><c id="376c529c74a949ea8ae7b865d637a2ae" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - United Cerebral Palsy - New York City</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1961" type="inclusive">1950-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="570fef667833e361054b1deaf8c8638c" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044935]" type="box">11</container><container id="956c59603ede9179d25e90eeafb6a06e" parent="570fef667833e361054b1deaf8c8638c" type="folder">91A</container></did><scopecontent id="ad9d4fd9b7cf90b0f49a1c9534980385"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>David Rockefeller's contribution.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="d8428b1be17ff40a31190241d99d9200"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.113</p></fileplan></c><c id="be83dd1ee21c485eb4d5bad3f293b634" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - National Association for Mental Health</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1961" type="inclusive">1950-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="81f8e85819167f06d6e9c62779f46ced" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044936]" type="box">12</container><container id="a6e03246dee0e6e50a1a71329844a9cf" parent="81f8e85819167f06d6e9c62779f46ced" type="folder">92</container></did><scopecontent id="3728ae9dadc41d07a308c56c61b48dd2"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contributions from family members; Rockefeller Brothers Fund contributions. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Dana S. Creel, Arthur Bunker, Orin Root, Marka DuPont.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="a1f270a8ce0388b2ba6037c6e571b7e9"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.121</p></fileplan></c><c id="7c19ef34c62e4816af8db52474dc561f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - New York Mental Health Fund</unittitle><unitdate normal="1954/1955" type="inclusive">1954-1955</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="93877f2397c5bdecf12af9b637284422" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044936]" type="box">12</container><container id="67e118a9b71f7c04c9fb07a262548e61" parent="93877f2397c5bdecf12af9b637284422" type="folder">93</container></did><scopecontent id="1b2925a1976c1e6a443461cf731958c1"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Request for aid, declined.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="79ff3500fb6e3d0831a657a42a38f5b3"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.122</p></fileplan></c><c id="d77864bdf9ff4b759e5d1932e32c8d01" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Mental Health Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1958/1961" type="inclusive">1958-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="32e76bcc389c149c7a1ef33a57afbb73" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044936]" type="box">12</container><container id="c9e6259fdca5cdb0a67bc94bb4f3e977" parent="32e76bcc389c149c7a1ef33a57afbb73" type="folder">94</container></did><scopecontent id="905eae406a8d8d8a00ef3315217899d1"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Mrs. Godfrey Rockefeller originates Research In Schizophrenia Endowment. Correspondents include Helen G. Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Mrs. Julian Street Jr., Edward L. Love.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="b28d23e893b31a04f11aca31515c6191"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.123</p></fileplan></c><c id="79a9a97f206849d19d6155dd9ad75049" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Mental Health Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1958/1961" type="inclusive">1958-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="acd9bad5af5739f5da9b9fc3fed9793c" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044936]" type="box">12</container><container id="3eeed62f6850463009c3b9e53837cbb3" parent="acd9bad5af5739f5da9b9fc3fed9793c" type="folder">94A</container></did><scopecontent id="04ee014288c68732aef088d9952febfc"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>David Rockefeller gift to Staten Island Mental Health Society.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="9a4cbf27bd287452996cc804cc042dc9"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.123</p></fileplan></c><c id="7d0b620d15a64a87be3b931f32d39544" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Tappan Zee Mental Health Center, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1955/1961" type="inclusive">1955-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="77711dff3be03d52dc0deef8ea53de68" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044936]" type="box">12</container><container id="5a226e4b8415562cd45a2aa76da21351" parent="77711dff3be03d52dc0deef8ea53de68" type="folder">95</container></did><fileplan id="c3bd686af8262d25365bdfa16854963b"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.127</p></fileplan></c><c id="4cc0803b67d4403b9b9dc940779012ee" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - American Heart Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1961" type="inclusive">1947-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="3375b0fd881be839005d611f844bc0f1" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044936]" type="box">12</container><container id="ed3cc8a2d47f2db715374193ad351cb4" parent="3375b0fd881be839005d611f844bc0f1" type="folder">96</container></did><scopecontent id="8c1e4ef0739f8c0c15426bb997091bbc"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Invitation to participate, declined. Correspondents include A. W. Robertson, Arthur Jones, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="7d9f3444c0e6e560c514807d7a7f5d00"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.131</p></fileplan></c><c id="dcc3b8a6af304140bf95c4f9667431d7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - American Heart Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1961" type="inclusive">1947-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="0c81359c4997d34d2436a34948500a06" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044936]" type="box">12</container><container id="7e2e78896dd4977b7b99b9c75d84ee5c" parent="0c81359c4997d34d2436a34948500a06" type="folder">96A</container></did><scopecontent id="c3b3d0c862f00b83d940239e073a122e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Correspondents include David Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="10b2fb63fe5a728322e03fd76b07af89"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.131</p></fileplan></c><c id="8d3ff988bc6c4ae5907ae9b1bc4e7ee1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Agencies - Westchester Heart Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1948/1961" type="inclusive">1948-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="de2a54fd3e96765968d80f90a016fcc9" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044936]" type="box">12</container><container id="e98d94a38d4cfcbda4247d25f3ea27e8" parent="de2a54fd3e96765968d80f90a016fcc9" type="folder">97</container></did><scopecontent id="f17c853acaad4feb9a3916fa5a435c46"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Requests for aid, declined.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="0cc43294105fbd7f39a1e05a4fba56a6"><head>File Plan note</head><p>137.131</p></fileplan></c><c id="b2a372f033c342989f69da3d93adf78b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Philippines - Leonard Wood Memorial for the Eradication of Leprosy</unittitle><unitdate normal="1925/1957" type="inclusive">1925-1957</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="ebfbaf95031e99467c6c5a5d3aca2c4c" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044936]" type="box">12</container><container id="4ba7e4c9d25347edee1a9fc897b1e257" parent="ebfbaf95031e99467c6c5a5d3aca2c4c" type="folder">98</container></did><scopecontent id="b113db03ac2ca43c25366a9a68ce5385"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>David McAlpin's interest in organization. 1929 campaign, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributes $100,000. Other requests declined. Correspondents include Arthur Woods, Thomas B. Appleget, David McAlpin, Perry Burgess.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="9c16b6ede91efd0a2dfc5bedaf6e1614"><head>File Plan note</head><p>160</p></fileplan></c><c id="782421b984164e3fba0a36dfc9a38292" level="file"><did><unittitle>Philippines - Leonard Wood Memorial for the Eradication of Leprosy - Pledge, June 14, 1928</unittitle><unitdate normal="1928/1928" type="inclusive">1928</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="4525becd49e1fbc814a80538c65467c8" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044936]" type="box">12</container><container id="e3c6d64f545d29f1133806805b251d13" parent="4525becd49e1fbc814a80538c65467c8" type="folder">99</container></did><scopecontent id="1251e5b88d788a69379a0d61aca95e51"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Leonard Wood Memorial contribution, $100,000.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="fba81d14a712043525fc50ad33607dda"><head>File Plan note</head><p>160</p></fileplan></c><c id="8771e0232f1744029ced26bd6df75194" level="file"><did><unittitle>Madame Curie Radium Fund - Radium Institute, Warsaw</unittitle><unitdate normal="1921/1935" type="inclusive">1921-1935</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="0b7867f6bb7de417f3aba70aaf130b9a" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044936]" type="box">12</container><container id="ec855699497f6ca1865b1324727b17e2" parent="0b7867f6bb7de417f3aba70aaf130b9a" type="folder">100</container></did><scopecontent id="e8f48b1a89c067b3c67ca893ee91a925"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr. orders "Memorial" to make gift to buy radium for Curie Paris institute. Request from Belgrade for radium for clinic there; Request from M. Curie for radium to be used at Warsaw Institute, refused. Later John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $10,000 toward gift of gram of radium for Madame Curie personally. Correspondents include Madame Curie, Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="43ab6bbe93f560a0751c436b9ee8ef1b"><head>File Plan note</head><p>134</p></fileplan></c></c><c id="f62d6ce1145145c280e487588a9a42a8" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Mental Hygiene</unittitle></did><c id="c7d9a973bc0744f6967e1aa9ae268773" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Committee on Mental Hygiene</unittitle><unitdate normal="1909/1950" type="inclusive">1909-1950</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="07b6d8eecb49c586491de65aea63319d" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044936]" type="box">12</container><container id="d08595a82f776268987efadc61d31a02" parent="07b6d8eecb49c586491de65aea63319d" type="folder">101</container></did><scopecontent id="fca23fb231b67c3cffd9d27182bc28ff"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Created in 1909 to prevent insanity and care for the insane; grew out of a book by C. W. Beers. Work of the committee. Supported by Rockefeller Foundation; individual assistance by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 25th anniversary of work. Later form requests for aid declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise, C. W. Beers, Thomas Salmon, MD.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="f739755a931467ca9d6a5fd62477429c"><head>File Plan note</head><p>69</p></fileplan></c><c id="c0dd7e8d706d4dbf80f9abea062097c9" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Committee on Mental Hygiene - C. W. Beer's Book, "A Mind That Found Itself"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1907/1911" type="inclusive">1907-1911</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="018bf0e86d045da09721235f0eddf0a2" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044937]" type="box">13</container><container id="b68ca54d97bf3dc026176139e57a4977" parent="018bf0e86d045da09721235f0eddf0a2" type="folder">102</container></did><scopecontent id="9cdd76aa4f850aea831ed0e12daca384"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Autobiography of recovered mental patient; used to start interest in Committee for Mental Hygiene; brought to F. T. Gates' attention. No action in this folder. Correspondents include Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy, C. W. Beers.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="d593bdc6cf03d91c98a3c79360616d6f"><head>File Plan note</head><p>69</p></fileplan></c><c id="7f70427c464348e291de802ff43ac9bb" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Committee on Mental Hygiene - T. W. Salmon Memorial</unittitle><unitdate normal="1929/1941" type="inclusive">1929-1941</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="49d9cf9392a99d4f23a818c2d04cbf17" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044937]" type="box">13</container><container id="8145ee849865b738671db191f06cbc26" parent="49d9cf9392a99d4f23a818c2d04cbf17" type="folder">103</container></did><scopecontent id="c87bb9151f36f320e8ab057cbc09e8f1"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributes to Memorial to Dr. Salmon. Lecture series. Declines assistance to son of doctor. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="ec7476f4bbc252414635a7fac400d0b9"><head>File Plan note</head><p>69</p></fileplan></c><c id="6ac5c8558cde41bf80e1913955fffe26" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Committee on Mental Hygiene - Jonzel Foundation, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1958/1961" type="inclusive">1958-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="6471b9c5ca8ead069d0a0cfc746bf066" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044937]" type="box">13</container><container id="c38c931b1f14eb85ae34152932f0e698" parent="6471b9c5ca8ead069d0a0cfc746bf066" type="folder">104</container></did><scopecontent id="9e2a5903247e76ac269dd5de8b3b072a"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Laurance S. Rockefeller contributions.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="612b6e7f8ded6ea4c688f08781672934"><head>File Plan note</head><p>69</p></fileplan></c></c><c id="29c56d3bd46443c1b470b90f7dca6557" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Narcotics</unittitle></did><c id="62c4cf50eb3f4b4ba3a1d19c789523ff" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narcotic Drugs</unittitle><unitdate normal="1923/1940" type="inclusive">1923-1929, 1932, 1937, 1939-1940</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="7bfd81046a913c1da0fb038eb4a1cc0e" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044937]" type="box">13</container><container id="43b5e0f3f61a6d0b6912e639cc22197f" parent="7bfd81046a913c1da0fb038eb4a1cc0e" type="folder">105</container></did><scopecontent id="094a185e511f93f0c176a06b1fb24a2c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Succession of committees and individuals devoted to ending narcotic trade and addiction. Small contributions made by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include E. S. Bishop, C. H. Brent, Mrs. Hamilton Wright, William McAdoo, Fred H. Allen.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="176cff56eef0b70f6474d794659d08d8"><head>File Plan note</head><p>9</p></fileplan></c><c id="321f27472c97497dbd3900cc99b40864" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narcotic Drugs - World Narcotic Defense Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1931/1935" type="inclusive">1931-1935</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="83c2f02f57b795799bc1fde2cf6eb468" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044937]" type="box">13</container><container id="ce66051bad9bbb8685c3ff989c8a6b4d" parent="83c2f02f57b795799bc1fde2cf6eb468" type="folder">106</container></did><scopecontent id="5dde9355b9c0e4b6537e800ec17c57d2"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Requests for contributions, refused. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Arthur Woods.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="0b50a981031f40bc4ce3657954d8800f"><head>File Plan note</head><p>9</p></fileplan></c><c id="ad8361e4410d4085994aff2a9ab3088e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narcotic Drugs - R. P. Hobson</unittitle><unitdate normal="1924/1928" type="inclusive">1924-1928</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="b1261400726830a190b16298fbeaac02" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044937]" type="box">13</container><container id="bedefc862fdc6bf0c80b3c6ef6af9f42" parent="b1261400726830a190b16298fbeaac02" type="folder">107</container></did><scopecontent id="1deab75946d09e80a52745953955111d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Requests for aid in struggle against narcotics addiction; refused because of interest and contributions in other areas of field. Correspondents include R. P. Hobson.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="60e073391711f224d42d9e1095f0f18f"><head>File Plan note</head><p>9</p></fileplan></c><c id="8232e7db401545329741ab03353be914" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narcotics</unittitle><unitdate normal="1959/1961" type="inclusive">1959-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="84fdf6544dfe831e57902a051f762043" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044937]" type="box">13</container><container id="25599bf2553e45d59752e9833a38a782" parent="84fdf6544dfe831e57902a051f762043" type="folder">108</container></did><fileplan id="15ecf64ce6c5ca839db2dba0d2e81fab"><head>File Plan note</head><p>9</p></fileplan></c><c id="b1b0440cc3714992ad499803778c9e19" level="file"><did><unittitle>Narcotic Drugs - Boys and Girls Anti-Cigarette League</unittitle><unitdate normal="1922/1931" type="inclusive">1922-1931</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="a7b09922b6c9b2b2b33aa51e7817b3a9" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044937]" type="box">13</container><container id="8b685b0524485c5f8b46b5319de18ad4" parent="a7b09922b6c9b2b2b33aa51e7817b3a9" type="folder">109</container></did><scopecontent id="f874a10fb4803cb66cc564f99db30250"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Small John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="5ea0e03bfac5759da45a2d5513cdab72"><head>File Plan note</head><p>9.1</p></fileplan></c></c><c id="0e7fb602027c4f1ea8b53b11846ef7ad" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>New York Academy of Medicine</unittitle></did><c id="213cf8c023884182bf9e2b5c911cee92" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Academy of Medicine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1909/1948" type="inclusive">1909-1948</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="6c147a9a248bcdc64700ea6b4f5d3249" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044937]" type="box">13</container><container id="18701b6e1ca8a378b3ba9e547553777b" parent="6c147a9a248bcdc64700ea6b4f5d3249" type="folder">110</container></did><scopecontent id="886228c2600ee55e7f36ef096d53aca0"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Declined request to finance building for Academy and participation in other special drives. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributed $7,500 to polio drive, 1928; $5,000, 1931; $1,000, 1931. RBF financed conference on Etiology of Mental Disease. Booklet, "Self-Forgiveness" by T. V. Smith. John D. Rockefeller 3rd gift of $95,000 to Museum of Health. Martha Baird Rockefeller's pledge toward publication of Dr. J. Marshall Hoag's book on osteopathy, 1961. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller, Martha Baird Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="aecfcf2785f36782bbcf7105c9c94c77"><head>File Plan note</head><p>143</p></fileplan></c><c id="3f3ad1038ba7497b81f659eab11a4105" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Academy of Medicine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1953/1961" type="inclusive">1953-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="25ac6ad6e7bcb28b475bb8443de5b478" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044937]" type="box">13</container><container id="e16e67ff9177a017f5ed097320779c5a" parent="25ac6ad6e7bcb28b475bb8443de5b478" type="folder">111</container></did><scopecontent id="7c2d5c3bdb9e488278e890e4d53e253a"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Declined request to finance building for Academy and participation in other special drives. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributed $7,500 to polio drive, 1928; $5,000, 1931; $1,000, 1931. Rockefeller Brothers Fund financed conference on Etiology of Mental Disease. Booklet, "Self-Forgiveness" by T. V. Smith. John D. Rockefeller 3rd gift of $95,000 to Museum of Health. Martha Baird Rockefeller's pledge toward publication of Dr. J. Marshall Hoag's book on osteopathy, 1961. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller, Martha Baird Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="8df6a8facc3ebbbf1568ddb473fdd82a"><head>File Plan note</head><p>143</p></fileplan></c><c id="8331c639bdbd45f8ba2568edd621cb4c" level="file"><did><unittitle>New York Academy of Osteopathy/Foundation for Research of the Academy</unittitle><unitdate normal="1952/1961" type="inclusive">1952-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="e48c09d6d533fac85bb59ce1936ce313" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044937]" type="box">13</container><container id="ebd0e9cb3a73c847235542805b649dea" parent="e48c09d6d533fac85bb59ce1936ce313" type="folder">112</container></did><scopecontent id="cffd38a11a5486138364ab7742aa7868"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Promote research, provide information. Laurance S. Rockefeller gift; Nelson A. Rockefeller; Abby Rockefeller Mauzé contributions. Correspondents include W. Kenneth Riland, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="b5c866f7125f16fa1ed0b073eab9ef18"><head>File Plan note</head><p>143.1</p></fileplan></c></c><c id="8351cdee5aae415180fe7ae81d35a56e" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Polio</unittitle></did><c id="6848d360b6614cb6af9e0c89608c5227" level="file"><did><unittitle>Polio - Georgia Warm Springs Foundation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1928/1954" type="inclusive">1928-1954</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="3baa851161384e25313ae7906827621f" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044938]" type="box">14</container><container id="ac6e091a52d654049667f1df1c9d6fdd" parent="3baa851161384e25313ae7906827621f" type="folder">113</container></did><scopecontent id="d12c553fc99ad6e24039c6b452cdd4e9"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contributions to Warm Springs; declination to participate in President's Birthday Ball. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Franklin D. Roosevelt, Raymond B. Fosdick.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="e8f4db94b299ea227c10ccdff7dd5483"><head>File Plan note</head><p>171</p></fileplan></c><c id="0716d45e8b3f468989b4e5b5882ffc0e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Polio - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis/National Foundation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1937/1949" type="inclusive">1937-1949</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="ca6fa998c106b0c5700fec4a9096f851" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044938]" type="box">14</container><container id="b6a4e78adcd963d7dcfc6cd07fe5752b" parent="ca6fa998c106b0c5700fec4a9096f851" type="folder">114</container></did><scopecontent id="96ade44350f658bae3aab3248b888264"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Family showed only nominal interest in National Foundation program; Foundation secrecy about finances unacceptable to Rockefeller interests. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave directly to Warm Springs, Georgia, 1928-1936. Nelson A. Rockefeller contributions to Foundation, 1959-1961. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Basil O'Conner.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="25821adab74255d8d3b672df6a0a6720"><head>File Plan note</head><p>171A</p></fileplan></c><c id="2913e32d45d440e9bbd3f23e6418d4c7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Polio - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis/National Foundation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1955" type="inclusive">1950-1955</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="ee736fef83cce8fc5e2ffbf5bd50d800" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044938]" type="box">14</container><container id="591ea604b9ffd61c3fc7c537d774658c" parent="ee736fef83cce8fc5e2ffbf5bd50d800" type="folder">115</container></did><scopecontent id="c3259b1f1a14f5b8f5abdf77534c4e3c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Family showed only nominal interest in National Foundation program; Foundation secrecy about finances unacceptable to Rockefeller interests. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave directly to Warm Springs, Georgia, 1928-1936. Nelson A. Rockefeller contributions to Foundation, 1959-1961. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Basil O'Conner.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="717900a3aa045fa0f7421459de17fcf1"><head>File Plan note</head><p>171A</p></fileplan></c><c id="72e2c29335d0463cbb66b508e20666fc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Polio - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis/National Foundation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1956/1961" type="inclusive">1956-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="39dd170f2d0881a802dc45ceca42f96e" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044938]" type="box">14</container><container id="ba42c9f4929ab053e5adc797c09b2e1b" parent="39dd170f2d0881a802dc45ceca42f96e" type="folder">116</container></did><scopecontent id="22f47bc320afc8fcf12fa59068dc4c80"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Family showed only nominal interest in National Foundation program; Foundation secrecy about finances unacceptable to Rockefeller interests. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave directly to Warm Springs, Georgia, 1928-1936. Nelson A. Rockefeller contributions to Foundation, 1959-1961. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Basil O'Conner.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="a25bc8fce326a24dde8eb5ef3dc8ea79"><head>File Plan note</head><p>171A</p></fileplan></c><c id="be86f8fc2ea04aec97c82ce05f61f3ee" level="file"><did><unittitle>Polio - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis/National Foundation - Printed Material and Clippings</unittitle><unitdate normal="1938/1961" type="inclusive">1938-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="e2b5b9230afdb14d7efebc46b56f1fc1" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044938]" type="box">14</container><container id="7d60b899152c0b73355a03f0f3996081" parent="e2b5b9230afdb14d7efebc46b56f1fc1" type="folder">117</container></did><fileplan id="1f0fecfc5dd393e4b3f7180152e8ee60"><head>File Plan note</head><p>171A</p></fileplan></c><c id="58bb324c4d0e4c8fa4ae5251f76f1ad9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Polio - Sister Kenny Foundation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1944/1960" type="inclusive">1944-1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="514159e6a78678209d2c9fc054b33637" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044939]" type="box">15</container><container id="d4a32e2f19913c788f820cbaa4022cf1" parent="514159e6a78678209d2c9fc054b33637" type="folder">118</container></did><scopecontent id="6256ec2123e3ce74b5017b3b78b1b8f8"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>To promote Kenny method of treatment. Report on organization. No family contributions.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="15caa7de3fd44eb44a9dfeddfebe5383"><head>File Plan note</head><p>171.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="8510b61180064d0b85cd39a8a829be6c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Polio - Sister Kenny Foundation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1944/1960" type="inclusive">1944-1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="6e3e11a872b9de3cf053805c050b8bcb" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044939]" type="box">15</container><container id="d4e73d627fa45b10e4031300e74a6ee7" parent="6e3e11a872b9de3cf053805c050b8bcb" type="folder">118A</container></did><scopecontent id="505ae00830cd5855e28023164b8342f6"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>To promote Kenny method of treatment. Report on organization. No family contributions.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="408bf015f9eebd6b04b6d98543fb1136"><head>File Plan note</head><p>171.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="1552efc328e54cffb29ffe864d3f1375" level="file"><did><unittitle>Polio - Physical Rehabilitation Foundation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1945/1949" type="inclusive">1945-1949</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="88a1980a88750c56c15bbcd18407c642" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044939]" type="box">15</container><container id="7f20764bbd886474ca655b98b81061b9" parent="88a1980a88750c56c15bbcd18407c642" type="folder">119</container></did><scopecontent id="534b698eab069e823d63de10d3c1c985"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Betsey Barton begins foundation dedicated to studying and teaching methods of treatment for physically handicapped. No contributions made. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard, Betsey Barton.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="7c5b157c9cef9be288a63fb1fd34dd8e"><head>File Plan note</head><p>171.2</p></fileplan></c></c><c id="ba4b65d5734c4f03867faa55b091f897" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Social Hygiene</unittitle></did><c id="f2045a6f3f654ce18166305856165214" level="file"><did><unittitle>Social Hygiene - American Social Hygiene Association - Sex Education Work - Dr. Exner</unittitle><unitdate normal="1920/1923" type="inclusive">1920, 1923</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="eb91dfd5bcea79792c6b95a91813083a" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044939]" type="box">15</container><container id="cb47303d0962c58c65aa8634eb785a41" parent="eb91dfd5bcea79792c6b95a91813083a" type="folder">120</container></did><scopecontent id="c80c0de5e1263effe64beeb320a5fa7e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Becomes American Social Health Association. Operation of Association; increasing war work; John D. Rockefeller Jr.'s support. W. F. Snow's informal report to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Tribute to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for contributions to work of association, make him Honorary Life Member. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contributions to war work. Name changed to American Social Health Association. Dr. Snow's death. Correspondents include W. F. Snow, Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., William H. Zinsser.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="0c6acaf47aa3908ab48a43ecbc09d09e"><head>File Plan note</head><p>35</p></fileplan></c><c id="433890b958d7463283537b521988047f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Social Hygiene - American Social Hygiene Association - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Contributions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1915/1940" type="inclusive">1915-1940</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="d0208eac89d5180077c2d86af1be811b" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044939]" type="box">15</container><container id="21b5f95928cbce3238f00e00512ca636" parent="d0208eac89d5180077c2d86af1be811b" type="folder">121</container></did><scopecontent id="14161e87236d0719f58ec8f54077a4d6"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Becomes American Social Health Association. John D. Rockefeller Jr.'s letters of appeals for aid to A.S.H.A. List of contributors who responded to appeals. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s assistance in finding chairman for 1937 campaign; contribution toward 1940 VD campaign. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., W. F. Snow, Raymond B. Fosdick, W. Lyman.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="d1a2e86e28ed52d2f8494501cf15e298"><head>File Plan note</head><p>35</p></fileplan></c><c id="188bdd6496314cbe84670864a4705a75" level="file"><did><unittitle>Social Hygiene - American Social Hygiene Association - Dr. Snow's Salary</unittitle><unitdate normal="1919/1939" type="inclusive">1919-1939</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="f7dd42ccaeb57cd9abaf2e7178ba6428" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044939]" type="box">15</container><container id="c5208a6ec722b30442cb894e60b783a6" parent="f7dd42ccaeb57cd9abaf2e7178ba6428" type="folder">122</container></did><scopecontent id="c5dde2336ff133dd076468d93a4ec9f1"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Becomes American Social Health Association. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. guaranteed Snow $12,000 annual income; association paid him $10,000; Jr. made up difference, 1922-1924. After 1924 Snow's income was over $12,000. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. replaced salary guarantee with $2,000 annual payment to ease retirement. Correspondents include W. F. Snow, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="602f5f19d89c581c2bf62e2d87616e6d"><head>File Plan note</head><p>35</p></fileplan></c><c id="5c56711f2fc24192af2a4d0b6b50fba7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Social Hygiene - American Social Hygiene Association - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Solicitations</unittitle><unitdate normal="1915/1922" type="inclusive">1915(?)-1922</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="cdb84ea7cda7d1df92217a3686e258f4" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044939]" type="box">15</container><container id="b5b4fd3616cac93c600b0ab3ff285431" parent="cdb84ea7cda7d1df92217a3686e258f4" type="folder">123</container></did><scopecontent id="5b48de9753b325c46ca2c8bb6c1d2164"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Becomes American Social Health Association.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="caacbdc09722f69aa51ac2949d785252"><head>File Plan note</head><p>35</p></fileplan></c><c id="c3a66f045ad047058b921575fb501ea8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Social Hygiene - American Social Hygiene Association - Bureau of Social Hygiene Pledges</unittitle><unitdate normal="1919/1928" type="inclusive">1919-1928</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="e4f30b681e8c3a21ef4ba91cf494abe9" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044939]" type="box">15</container><container id="655e902404cc3d46de38a899961f9afa" parent="e4f30b681e8c3a21ef4ba91cf494abe9" type="folder">124</container></did><scopecontent id="d88df4505bb56afc05c33c013619d5f3"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Becomes American Social Health Association. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. has Bureau of Social Hygiene (BSH) make pledge to American Social Hygiene Association (ASHA); in return the two organizations were to cooperate closely in their work. ASHA officers investigated vice conditions in New York; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. financed it, through BSH, at $5,000 per quarter until 1928, when arrangement was replaced by non-recurring gift to ASHA. (BSH simultaneously being reorganized.) Regular pledges of BSH to ASHA's general work. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick, William F. Snow, Charles O. Heydt, Lawrence B. Dunham.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="a830f1ca108ea174e7a972f1b213d3ab"><head>File Plan note</head><p>35</p></fileplan></c><c id="5623426b0d314c9c9c10438bd05ff68f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Social Hygiene - American Social Hygiene Association - 1942 Appeal to USO</unittitle><unitdate normal="1942/1942" type="inclusive">1942</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="ed278f70cf0dbea0a36489577733a8a9" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044939]" type="box">15</container><container id="c4bda10ed0a1fb63968b4a9ec53924ec" parent="ed278f70cf0dbea0a36489577733a8a9" type="folder">125</container></did><scopecontent id="e6a0a0f78fbf438c39e3f6c14925632d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Becomes American Social Health Association. Arthur W. Packard assists ASHA in preparing appeal to United Service Organization for gift toward work of ASHA; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. follows negotiations. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Thomas M. Debevoise.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="c67fd5d793de17bea5b4f5dec5d3d8c7"><head>File Plan note</head><p>35</p></fileplan></c><c id="1f8435e224424596850114efb5e2719f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Social Hygiene - American Social Health Association/American Social Hygiene Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1919/1939" type="inclusive">1919-1939</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="e225c3685da9d7ca5563d53c13264c32" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044940]" type="box">16</container><container id="eb9c465678769ee0eefd3c9779097e5c" parent="e225c3685da9d7ca5563d53c13264c32" type="folder">126</container></did><fileplan id="4e8048e0f2b8dc7c7035ad9ddc7cc509"><head>File Plan note</head><p>35</p></fileplan></c><c id="e9ca6e633e1a4b6b80bd7bfb691f7a19" level="file"><did><unittitle>Social Hygiene - American Social Health Association/American Social Hygiene Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1949" type="inclusive">1940-1949</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="25a58d56061ecdad193030f6b70d5723" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044940]" type="box">16</container><container id="9989cfe5c2829407fa8fb419e16231f0" parent="25a58d56061ecdad193030f6b70d5723" type="folder">127</container></did><fileplan id="74562f021185e3f9132dc5114c610738"><head>File Plan note</head><p>35</p></fileplan></c><c id="4fb0f24eb85b466e9a723232de6da158" level="file"><did><unittitle>Social Hygiene - American Social Health Association/American Social Hygiene Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1951" type="inclusive">1950-1951</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="228385f542929bc58725afe0ff60d5b8" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044940]" type="box">16</container><container id="21a1c83db2f90b8d3ad9c6e60d9ff413" parent="228385f542929bc58725afe0ff60d5b8" type="folder">128</container></did><fileplan id="61dc81d572d2b7e355453a6c05a7ed77"><head>File Plan note</head><p>35</p></fileplan></c><c id="d4e12e5ab7e44abf96000b6e2451d40e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Social Hygiene - International Committee for Mental Health</unittitle><unitdate normal="1948/1960" type="inclusive">1948-1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="a7a9bfac2c67bdc1ae21591d5d8cb9a8" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044940]" type="box">16</container><container id="707fc2a3d0657ed965ebbd86f56d73e1" parent="a7a9bfac2c67bdc1ae21591d5d8cb9a8" type="folder">129</container></did><scopecontent id="8901f7ce5230e7d5eebbde676080bc02"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>To hold an International Congress on Mental Health; RBF contributions. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, June Bingham.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="f15f7fad55b66aaeda9363757f3cb615"><head>File Plan note</head><p>35.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="a127df2b1b66403ea66aa379c69220f3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Social Hygiene - International Committee for Mental Health</unittitle><unitdate normal="1948/1960" type="inclusive">1948-1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="11273e321e4bfbe5ff8f1eb9a5a47636" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044940]" type="box">16</container><container id="320b287b33215fc74bfd3c817ba44bc5" parent="11273e321e4bfbe5ff8f1eb9a5a47636" type="folder">129A</container></did><scopecontent id="8d9ca0d4c65ed5db2f258b511d034364"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Correspondents include David Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="0deef5d474b89e181a1cf648d98f9736"><head>File Plan note</head><p>35.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="e1ec70001d5741d3a5c25ec971c3e35b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Social Hygiene - New York Social Hygiene Society/American Society of Sanitary and Moral Prophylaxis</unittitle><unitdate normal="1910/1925" type="inclusive">1910-1925</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="2e4a60d4b5b679e50363283e67416ecd" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044940]" type="box">16</container><container id="8a4d08aa6ee292bfeeef79f9851db4f3" parent="2e4a60d4b5b679e50363283e67416ecd" type="folder">130</container></did><scopecontent id="5a1880188d41ff38638453baac69e0f3"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Rockefeller contributions. Dr. Ekner's sex education work. Society absorbed by American Social Hygiene Association. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., J. D. Greene, W. F. Snow.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="b8b2c8b41c5a72152672bfedf19d7d67"><head>File Plan note</head><p>35.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="3b7f0c15c0534c418dde81efbc25bf1a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Social Hygiene - New York Society for the Suppression of Vice/Society to Maintain Public Decency</unittitle><unitdate normal="1899/1923" type="inclusive">1899-1923</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="c7f3e26925aa3dc1b7921c1483b2007b" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044941]" type="box">17</container><container id="0ffd9a4e8948b4baea5ba54874425ef4" parent="c7f3e26925aa3dc1b7921c1483b2007b" type="folder">131</container></did><scopecontent id="f0257f4cb187f6f82c9dd6609490aeff"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Rockefeller contributions to Society, 1894-1931, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and John D. Rockefeller, Sr. Frederick T. Gates questions efficiency of Anthony Comstock. Disapproval of changing aims of society (reflected in new name), ending of contribution. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Sr., John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Antony Comstock, J. S. Summer.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="f8aee2d18381b7dc8696d56dae4fe793"><head>File Plan note</head><p>35.3</p></fileplan></c><c id="e2a58eba1b334ca58dcc4eb291883f28" level="file"><did><unittitle>Social Hygiene - New York Society for the Suppression of Vice/Society to Maintain Public Decency</unittitle><unitdate normal="1924/1949" type="inclusive">1924-1949</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="9d638c0a3bb01af9b59d47611d109226" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044941]" type="box">17</container><container id="a44a35c479d319f74d4c209acc60be41" parent="9d638c0a3bb01af9b59d47611d109226" type="folder">132</container></did><scopecontent id="dd4c33a085bd1ef5fc4481f9b166b9c1"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Rockefeller contributions to Society, 1894-1931, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and John D. Rockefeller, Sr. Frederick T. Gates questions efficiency of Anthony Comstock. Disapproval of changing aims of society (reflected in new name), ending of contribution. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Sr., John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Antony Comstock, J. S. Summer.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="ff83b845f5bda6979767757ea311587a"><head>File Plan note</head><p>35.3</p></fileplan></c></c><c id="e3b79ba8caff4cb9992745d0f91be27d" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Tuberculosis</unittitle></did><c id="d47aac541d564cfcbf12a13644c1c811" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tuberculosis - National Tuberculosis Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1904/1957" type="inclusive">1904-1957</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="a28d7880ab4101a8113d0da00646a33e" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044941]" type="box">17</container><container id="abed12d2e5781f2a78846004b5e85dee" parent="a28d7880ab4101a8113d0da00646a33e" type="folder">133</container></did><scopecontent id="1ad81f27572fbd82d8bde9943a3a7d83"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Sr. early contributions; later request declined. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="3b0de946fffd77b38fcbfb860ac89be8"><head>File Plan note</head><p>71</p></fileplan></c><c id="19211bb0ea6d4323aaa3425fd44b104f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tuberculosis - Treatment</unittitle><unitdate normal="1921/1953" type="inclusive">1921-1953</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="958cd1b3eeaffda6f87377dfb6d82d3c" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044941]" type="box">17</container><container id="45bdcdd465ee562f39727a434cc9e72e" parent="958cd1b3eeaffda6f87377dfb6d82d3c" type="folder">134</container></did><scopecontent id="731683a8008a29e7dae33ffa4404364c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Suggested cures for tuberculosis.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="a5fca1509a76d7f588c3f6231dfc0b0f"><head>File Plan note</head><p>71.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="1d0e2c8b8ae64f8d911faff9806da570" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tuberculosis - Treatment - House of Rest</unittitle><unitdate normal="1945/1955" type="inclusive">1945-1955</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="f45029122c79e9ad6df66649fa3a4f9a" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044941]" type="box">17</container><container id="ffa500b54afbbabea65d140a983c5011" parent="f45029122c79e9ad6df66649fa3a4f9a" type="folder">135</container></did><scopecontent id="719baddb2c4eea0582b884d6bdfc8178"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution; John D. Rockefeller 3rd conditional donation of $5,000; not collected.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="20416a7da5f5f7afbb041ba86baa856c"><head>File Plan note</head><p>71.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="08f349fda10947199f56c7294571d786" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tuberculosis - Treatment - Altro Health and Rehabilitation Services</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1955" type="inclusive">1947-1955</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="9761c8f9472678c63291887a98527783" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044941]" type="box">17</container><container id="e2c749b9215df7772dedbbc56b21418f" parent="9761c8f9472678c63291887a98527783" type="folder">136</container></did><scopecontent id="e4065d5770b1640cf32f14fd8e9213f8"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Formerly Committee for the Care of the Jewish Tuberculous, Inc.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="01374c6f5825c40ef32c0969221a0826"><head>File Plan note</head><p>71.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="e4866c9d88f644949c46d22e457bc6dd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tuberculosis - Tuberculosis Prevention for Children</unittitle><unitdate normal="1911/1961" type="inclusive">1911-1913, 1957-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="fbc68e7624a232bb306085099869b13b" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044941]" type="box">17</container><container id="ef1d6d50347a3eb2d24e9abda341056f" parent="fbc68e7624a232bb306085099869b13b" type="folder">137</container></did><scopecontent id="466c1208ec8242c1f8da409ac7cd2aaf"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>New Jersey home to care for children of tubercular parents. John D. Rockefeller, Sr. contributes to building fund; John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. refuse to contribute to current funds. Mary French Rockefeller contributions, 1960-1961. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Sr., John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="2ef66161f0175f6be8d48aed4f704a39"><head>File Plan note</head><p>71.1</p></fileplan></c><c id="a30f5773db98442eb42d2fef3f3fbc49" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tuberculosis - New York Tuberculosis and Health Association, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1919/1961" type="inclusive">1919-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="21f145aa5175d1d0c3c97e73d404d647" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044941]" type="box">17</container><container id="1bf0020b34045cb7b7e49f277178b9aa" parent="21f145aa5175d1d0c3c97e73d404d647" type="folder">138</container></did><scopecontent id="faed3c10ac269f7f7852986827ddff9c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Annual Rockefeller contribution to work, purchase of Christmas seals. 1950 named as final contribution year by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="308605e42e94d1657b501fe708774bb8"><head>File Plan note</head><p>71.2</p></fileplan></c><c id="230dd180eeb74eb8bffc5be0ced4cd61" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tuberculosis - New York Tuberculosis and Health Association, Inc. - Contributions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1951/1960" type="inclusive">1951-1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="9012693df0c4eebb14d7a1054b477580" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044942]" type="box">18</container><container id="b765f8f24f0d3e9c962e505e95715006" parent="9012693df0c4eebb14d7a1054b477580" type="folder">139</container></did><scopecontent id="baebd9b5c6ee21f559685e6e4def81f4"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Small annual gifts; Laurance S. Rockefeller donates $25,000 in 1960.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="9280fab35048d7afe3f428cffa790050"><head>File Plan note</head><p>71.2</p></fileplan></c><c id="305bbd070aef41a4bfb3a1438543083d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tuberculosis - Westchester Tuberculosis and Public Health Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1916/1949" type="inclusive">1916-1949</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="d161a2ca40bc1eceaa8a712e70606d46" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044942]" type="box">18</container><container id="23c06de8328f456ea7845dd1bfbeb26c" parent="d161a2ca40bc1eceaa8a712e70606d46" type="folder">140</container></did><scopecontent id="3e3e0f3470455c2b793dfebc3a61ff67"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Annual contributions of $100 by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1920-1934, for work in Westchester. Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller gave small annual amounts. List of contributions from various members of the family. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="e0e8f522acbbcdb79678ba207c87d254"><head>File Plan note</head><p>71.3</p></fileplan></c><c id="ebb2fcbc3dac433aad5c0ade101b1be7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tuberculosis - Westchester Tuberculosis and Public Health Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1916/1949" type="inclusive">1916-1949</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="eb4843aa21f6cc8772b26e82f8f77a08" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044942]" type="box">18</container><container id="2539036eb492a1d49fed9c7c44cebe43" parent="eb4843aa21f6cc8772b26e82f8f77a08" type="folder">140A</container></did><scopecontent id="8a168ec4c59ec1d1f1a90b7a6bf5f745"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>David Rockefeller gave small annual amounts. David Rockefeller gifts.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="676f713371a40e911e12ebacddb663a3"><head>File Plan note</head><p>71.3</p></fileplan></c><c id="045090a4df114e4cb36a591c1ff477f4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tuberculosis - Westchester Tuberculosis and Public Health Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1961" type="inclusive">1950-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="408c2c9db51c7ed0d369151fdfc056a9" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044942]" type="box">18</container><container id="2a7f83c1bdc77e4038a986a570d0f9df" parent="408c2c9db51c7ed0d369151fdfc056a9" type="folder">141</container></did><scopecontent id="ba14eaf906de3d81b55f969e10acd078"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller gave small annual amounts. List of contributions from various members of the family. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="b6fd637561b600cf9363117006ee56b9"><head>File Plan note</head><p>71.3</p></fileplan></c><c id="eb0fa0258c24413e9eeb3b7e52488c68" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tuberculosis - Westchester Tuberculosis and Public Health Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1961" type="inclusive">1950-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="1aabbff86adf8559dc0a5967cd177c17" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044942]" type="box">18</container><container id="b98912001b71da0b6e05f3b368fbb828" parent="1aabbff86adf8559dc0a5967cd177c17" type="folder">141A</container></did><scopecontent id="7b40716c9374f59fa42ed16c19dad0d2"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>David Rockefeller gave small annual amounts. David Rockefeller gifts.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="71572af29b761188f13bd71b592a4c16"><head>File Plan note</head><p>71.3</p></fileplan></c><c id="e57cd49e5ab44a8484285dbd9b3d9740" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tuberculosis - Saranac Lake Study and Craft Guild</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1949" type="inclusive">1947-1949</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="2455dc14d140fa85e76c4d0553fa92e7" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044942]" type="box">18</container><container id="c2a67a6f8c0f4b86af831f9a475c5a68" parent="2455dc14d140fa85e76c4d0553fa92e7" type="folder">142</container></did><scopecontent id="cbd84bbef94143b7dabed910199a4aec"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appeals for aid to Laurance S. Rockefeller, all declined on advice of Arthur W. Packard. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="5786a606944f1e70eb018b4feeb4c65d"><head>File Plan note</head><p>71.5</p></fileplan></c></c><c id="94605d7c17e6429e85c1266ec64a69de" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Hospitals</unittitle></did><c id="32354abb5f564448bffd9a1cfc06de90" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1907/1947" type="inclusive">1907-1947</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="f8369ecad567e5088ae8239146fab59e" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044942]" type="box">18</container><container id="0873f9241ce87963b9340acb4d2a40f9" parent="f8369ecad567e5088ae8239146fab59e" type="folder">143</container></did><scopecontent id="258278396047e5f20ee8dabf247ee56c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appeals for contributions from various hospitals; denial of appeals, referral of others to Rockefeller Foundation or Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, contributions made to some. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur Woods, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p><p>Auburn City Hospital, New York, 1947 Babies' Hospital, London, 1923-1924 Baptist Hospital, Winston-Salem, 1947 Benedictine Hospital of Kingston, New York, 1945-1954 Centro Medico of Caracas (Dr. J. J. Bentata), 1946 Forest Hills Hospital Association, Cleveland, Ohio, 1945 Franklin County Memorial, Maine, 1946 Grandview Tuberculosis Hospital, Oil City, Pennsylvania, 1907 Greater Cleveland Hospital Fund Miss M. Harrais, proposed hospital, Alaska, 1951 Infants Hospital, Westminster, London, England, 1924 Lawrence Hospital, New York, 1950 Leonard Wood Memorial, proposed leprosarium, 1947 Long Island College of Medicine, Brooklyn, New York, 1939 Massachusetts General Hospital, 1947-1961 New Haven Hospital, New Haven, Connecticut, 1946 North Carolina Baptist Hospital, Post Graduate School of Pastoral Care, 1947-1954 North Country Community Hospital, Glen Cove, Long Island, New York (clippings), 1946-1948 Northwestern Anti-Tuberculosis League, Pennsylvania, 1917 Ossining Hospital, New York (clippings), 1952-1955 Pascack Valley Hospital, New Jersey, 1946-1951 *Dr. Peyton, Mercy Hospital, Pennsylvania, 1939-1940 Provident Hospital, Chicago, 1947 Provident Hospital and Free Dispensary, Baltimore, Maryland Rockland State Hospital, Orangeburg, New York, 1940 School for Nurses at Mercy Hospital, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1928 St. Francis Sanatorium for Cardiac Children, New York, 1946-1952 Saint Lo Hospital, France, 1947-1955 Strong Memorial Hospital, New York, Dr. S. L. Warren, 1940 Valdez Community Hospital, Valdez, Alaska, 1947 Westchester County Hospitals (clippings), 1947</p><p>An asterisk (*) indicates hospital received Rockefeller contribution.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="629d196cb1b448e082281a7cb05a2b98" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1948/1949" type="inclusive">1948-1949</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="9839847f8d03c9701c25379a3290bbe3" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044942]" type="box">18</container><container id="45404e6162fbb38ed554e65940baf365" parent="9839847f8d03c9701c25379a3290bbe3" type="folder">144</container></did><scopecontent id="08106fe2f8f10fa0df9cec6c2062571d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appeals for contributions from various hospitals; denial of appeals, referral of others to Rockefeller Foundation or Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, contributions made to some. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur Woods, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p><p>Bicur Cholim Hospital, Jerusalem, 1948-1949 Davis Memorial Hospital, West Virginia, 1949 Dobbs Ferry Hospital, New York (clippings mostly), 1945-1954 East Tennessee Baptist Hospital, 1948 Grace Cottage Hospital, Vermont, 1949 Hillcrest Medical Center, Oklahoma (Tri-State College), 1948-1958 Madison Rural Sanitarium &amp; Hospital, Tenessee, 1948 Massachusetts General Hospital, 1947-1961 Miami Heart Institute, Inc., Col. Mettler, 1949-1950 National Cancer Hospital of America, 1949-1950 Nebraska Methodist Hospital, 1949 New Jersey Orthopaedic Hospital, 1952 New York Society of Neurosurgery (clipping), 1948 New York Hospital Study (clipping), 1948 North Country Community Hospital, Glen Cove, Long Island, New York (clipping), 1946-1948 Ossining Hospital, New York (clipping), 1952-1955 Pascack Valey Hospital, New Jersey, 1946-1951 Paul de Kruif Project, California, 1949 Placid Memorial Hospital, New York, 1948 St. Francis Sanatorium for Cardiac Children, New York, 1946-1952 *St. Johns Hospital, Jackson Hole, Wyoming, 1952-1957 St. Michaels Hospital, New Jersey, 1953 Mr. C. E. Smock, Kentucky, 1949 United Mission Hospital in Lahore, India, 1948</p><p>An asterick (*) indicates hospital received Rockefeller contribution.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="b3ee966a74564545afcf1165b0f4f286" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1950" type="inclusive">1950</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="99d0ebc8797e388be823d6cf37c40fb7" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044943]" type="box">19</container><container id="24e7fa0e4a99fe2c28d4b0f09b0bf208" parent="99d0ebc8797e388be823d6cf37c40fb7" type="folder">145</container></did><scopecontent id="3865b0f7994c06759fbd35633a7dfb26"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appeals for contributions from various hospitals; denial of appeals, referral of others to Rockefeller Foundation or Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, contributions made to some. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur Woods, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p><p>Boston Evening Clinic &amp; Hospital, Massachusetts, 1950 Dr. E. T. Carsten, Guatemala, 1950 Christ Hospital, New Jersey, 1950 Christian Medical College &amp; Hospital, India, 1954-1955 Community Memorial Hospital Fund, Virginia, 1950 Dobbs Ferry Hospital, New York (clippings mostly), 1945-1954 Emerald-Hodgson Hospital, Tennessee, 1950 Friendship Clinic, Mississippi, 1950 General Hospital of Valley Stream, Long Island, New York, 1950 Groton Community Hospital, Massachusetts, 1950 Hiroshima Memorial Hospital (Mrs. Sproul), 1950 Miss Matilda Johns, regarding Negro hospital drive, 1950 Kent County Memorial Hospital, Rhode Island, 1950 Mrs. M. Kinzie, Cleveland, 1950 Lawrence Hospital, New York, 1950 Mr. J. J. Livingston, proposed Negro hospital, 1950 Miami Heart Institute, Inc., Col. Mettler, 1949-1950 National Cancer Hospital of America, 1949-1950 North Shore Hospital, New York, 1955 Northwestern Hospital, Mrs. Anna Rosenberg, 1950 Norwalk Hospital, Connecticut, 1950 Norwegian Hospital, New York City, 1951 Ossining Hospital, New York (clipping), 1952-1955 Patrick Henry Hospital for Chronically Ill, Virginia, 1950 North Country Community Hospital, Glen Cove, Long Island, New York (clipping), 1946-1948 *Richmond Memorial Hospital, Virginia, 1950 St. Francis Sanatorium for Cardiac Children, New York, 1946-1952 *St. Johns Hospital, Jakcson Hole, Wyoming, 1952-1957 St. John's Riverside Hospital, New York, 1950 St. Louis Children's Hospital, 1950-1952 Mrs. J. M. Sperzel, 1951 Uplands Sanatarium, Tennessee, 1950-1951 Vassar Brothers Hospital, New York, 1950 Women's Hospital, Cleveland, 1950</p><p>An asterisk (*) indicates hospital received Rockefeller contribution.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="c20d5b3cbe2443529ce113aed108c927" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1951/1952" type="inclusive">1951-1952</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="bcc238f0ae4392e491c457335471f8e3" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044943]" type="box">19</container><container id="a5e832d4b8a79e41256e23a681f58b43" parent="bcc238f0ae4392e491c457335471f8e3" type="folder">146</container></did><scopecontent id="a7256496be37dfc677f2ec224b9bc53c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appeals for contributions from various hospitals; denial of appeals, referral of others to Rockefeller Foundation or Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, contributions made to some. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur Woods, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p><p>Aitken Community Hospital, Minnesota, 1951 Alexian Brothers Hospital, Missouri, 1951 American College of Surgeons (clippings), 1953 Benjamin Rose Institute, Cleveland, 1952 Berkshire Medical Group, Massachusetts, 1951 Bertrand Chaffee Hospital, New York, 1951 Booker T. Washington Community Hospital, New Jersey, 1951 Boston State Hospital, Massachusetts, 1952 *British-American Hospital, Madrid, 1952-1954 Brooklyn Women's Hospital, New York City, 1951 Christian Medical College &amp; Hospital, India, 1954-1955 *Community Hospital at Glen Cove, New York (earlier called North Country Community Hospital), 1948-1959 Dixie Hospital, Virginia, 1955 Dobbs Ferry Hospital, New York (clippings mostly), 1945-1954 Elliott Hospital, 1952 Florida Interracial Hospital (Clipping), 1951 Greenwich Hospital, Connecticut (clipping), 1951 Mrs. W. H. Hardy, proposed Negro hospital, Mississippi, 1951 Miss M. Harrais, proposed hospital, Alaska, 1951 Hospital for the Mentally Ill of Natal, Brazil, 1952 International University Hospital, Paris, 1951 Leonardtown proposed Hospital, Mr. B. O. Callis, 1952 Long Island Jewish Hospital, 1951 Maine Medical Center, 1952 *Massachusetts General Hospital, 1947-1961 Memorial Hospital, Maryland, 1951 National Cancer Hospital of America, 1949-1950 New Jersey Orthopaedic Hospital, 1952 North Shore Hospital, New York, 1955 Norwegian Hospital, New York City, 1951 Nyack Hospital, New York, 1954 Ossining Hospital, New York (clipping), 1952-1955 Pascack Valley Hospital, New Jersey, 1946-1951 Milford Hospital, Milford, Connecticut 1951 *Richmond Memorial Hospital, Virginia, 1950 St. Francis Health Resort, New Jersey, 1951 St. Francis Sanatorium for Cardiac Children, New York, 1946-1952 *St, Johns Hospital, Jackson Hole, Wyoming, 1952-1957 St. Joseph's Memorial Hospital &amp; Home for Aged, Wisconsin, 1951 Saint Lo Hospital, France, 1947-1955 St. Louis Children's Hospital, 1950-1952 Swedish Hospital, Washington, 1952 University Sanitorium of Belgium, 1951 St. Mary Convent, Mobile, Alabama, 1951 Upper Manhattan Medical Center (clipping), 1952 Mrs. H. G. Wager, 1952 Watson Hospital for Crippled Children, Pennsylvania, 1951 White Memorial Hospital &amp; Clinic, California, 1951</p><p>An asterisk (*) indicates hospital received Rockefeller contribution.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="c6b5874d6bb945db9555e7d030b7579d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1953/1954" type="inclusive">1953-1954</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="3beae9f554e39c0f563dd39925ddbc01" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044943]" type="box">19</container><container id="0485073f5656cdef397e7920f0d49acd" parent="3beae9f554e39c0f563dd39925ddbc01" type="folder">147</container></did><scopecontent id="785800eb5c002711212247bc33d16896"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appeals for contributions from various hospitals; denial of appeals, referral of others to Rockefeller Foundation or Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, contributions made to some. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur Woods, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p><p>Addison Keyette Club, Addison, Michigan, 1954 American College of Surgeons (clippings), 1953 Benedictine Hospital of Kingston, New York, 1945-1954 Blessed Martin de Porres Hospital, Alabama (Sister M. Cornelia), 1951-1953 *Booth Memorial Hospital, New York City, 1956 *British American Hospital, Madrid, 1952-1954 Brooklyn Hospitals (clippings), 1954 *Children's Hospital of Philadelphia, 1953-1961 Chilton Memorial Hospital, New Jersey, 1954 Djabo Maternity General Hospital, Colorado, 1953 Englewood Hospital, New Jersey, 1953 Friendship Sanatorium, North Carolina, 1954 Gogebic Area Memorial Hospital Association, Michigan, 1953 Holy Cross Hospital, Florida, 1953 Home &amp; Hospital of the Daughters of Jacob, Geriatrics Insitute, Weinstein Pavilion, 1954 King Edward VII Memorial Hospital, Bermuda, 1954-1955 Dr. Z. Lihr, Finland, 1954 Memorial Hospital, New York, 1959 National Cancer Hospital of America, 1949-1950 North Carolina Baptist Hospital, Post Graduate School of Pastoral Care, 1947-1954 North Shore Hospital, New York, 1955 Nyack Hospital, New York, 1954 Perth-Amboy General Hospital, 1953 North Country Community Hospital, Glen Cove, Long Island, New York (clipping), 1946-1948 Memorial Hospital Trust Association, 1954 Pfiffer Memorial Hospital, Bolivia (Miss E. M. Elliott), 1954 Rahway Memorial Hospital, New Jersey, 1953 Rockland State Hospital Chapel Fund, New York 1940-1957 St. Agnes Hospital, New York, 1954 *St. Johns Hospital, Jackson Hole, Wyoming, 1952-1957 Saint Lo Hospital, France, 1947-1955 St. Michaels Hospital, New Jersey, 1953 Southside Comminity Hospital, Virginia 1954 Wilmington General Hospital, Delaware, 1953 Winter Park Hospital, Florida, 1954</p><p>An asterisk (*) indicates hospital received Rockefeller contribution.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="56331df259ae4273a32b952957c22e66" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1955/1955" type="inclusive">1955</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="48d006a5c218fb1e74194e101f73cdc1" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044943]" type="box">19</container><container id="ac085687391fd9d34b6e27f48d663cbc" parent="48d006a5c218fb1e74194e101f73cdc1" type="folder">148</container></did><scopecontent id="922650c7d19555f1617b7e8baad32da5"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appeals for contributions from various hospitals; denial of appeals, referral of others to Rockefeller Foundation or Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, contributions made to some. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur Woods, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p><p>Belleville Medical Center (Mr. John F. Kidde), 1955 *Booth Memorial Hospital, New York City, 1956 Butler Hospital, Rhode Island, 1956-1957 *Children's Hospital of Philaelphia, 1953-1961 Christian Medical College &amp; Hospital, India, 1954-1955 Mrs. L. A. Crandall, proposed hospital, California, 1955 Dixie Hospital, Virginia, 1955 *Hartford Hospital, Connecticut, 1955-1956 Hospital Fact-Finding Service, Connecticut, 1956 Institute of Applied Biology (clipping), 1955 King Edward VII Memorial Hospital, Bermuda, 1954-1955 Mason Memorial Hospital, Bahrain, Arabia, 1955 Massachusetts Memorial Hospitals Medical Center, 1960 Miners Hospital, Pennsylvania (clipping), 1955 Neponsit Hospital, Mrs. H. R. Tanner, New York City, 1955 Peekskill Hospital (Friendly Hospital), 1955-1958 Rockland State Hospital Chapel Fund, New York, 1940-1957 Roger Williams General hospital, Rhode Island, 1955 *St. Johns Hospital, Jackson Hole, Wyoming, 1952-1957 Saint Lo Hospital, France, 1947-1955 St. Luke's Hospital, North Carolina, 1955 St. Margaret's Hospital, Kansas, 1955 St. Mary's Hospital, Oklahoma, 1955 St. Vincent Hospital, New Mexico, 1955 Spears Chiroprractic Sanatarium, Florida, 1955-1956 Toronto East General Hospital, 1954 Sacred Heart Hospital, Chester, Pennsylvania, 1956 Salvation Army Hospital, Queens, New York, 1956 Whidden Memorial Hospital, Massachusetts, 1955 Will Rogers Hospital, New York (clipping), 1955 Woonsocket Hospital, Rhode Island, 1955</p><p>An asterisk (*) indicates hospital received Rockefeller contribution.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="f1d1dfccda804fa2915fcfd71234aff5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1956/1956" type="inclusive">1956</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="fdbe868cc9dcf121f8b3fc62adbbc8eb" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044943]" type="box">19</container><container id="f3e0c4352dd112ec82581eda5e1c5d95" parent="fdbe868cc9dcf121f8b3fc62adbbc8eb" type="folder">149</container></did><scopecontent id="87ee2ed71ff944fcf5ada6e88d8a6949"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appeals for contributions from various hospitals; denial of appeals, referral of others to Rockefeller Foundation or Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, contributions made to some. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur Woods, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p><p>Alice Hyde Memorial Hospital, New York, 1956 American Memorial Hospital, France, 1956 Andrews Memorial Hospital, Kingston, Jamaica, 1948 *Booth Memorial Hospital, New York City, 1956 Butler Hospital, Rhode Island, 1956-1957 *Children's Hospital of Philadelphia, 1953-1961 *Community Hospital at Glen Cove, New York (earlier called North Country Community Hospital), 1948-1959 *Crotched Mountain Foundation, New Hampshire, 1956-1959 Miss T. Ford, Florida, 1956 Franklin Foundation Hospital, Louisiana, 1956 *Hartford Hospital, Connecticut, 1955-1956 Jones Memorial Hospital, Pennsylvania, 1956 Manchester Memorial Hospital, Connecticut, 1956 *New England Center Hospital, New England Medical Center, 1946-1961 Presbyterian Hospital, Puerto Rico, 1956-1958 Rip Van Winkle Clinic, 1950 Rockland State Hospital Chapel Fund, New York, 1940-1957 St. Elizabeth Hospital, Nova Scotia, 1956 *St. Johns Hospital, Jackson Hole, Wyoming, 1952-1957 Saint Lo Hospital, France, 1947-1955 Spears Chiropractic Sanatarium, Florida, 1955-1956 State Hospital, North Carolina, 1956 Staten Island Hospital, 1956 Watts Hospital Course in Practical Nursing, 1956</p><p>An asterisk (*) indicates hospital received Rockefeller contribution.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="e7baa4112cae4bf5b6de0434df43b3b1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1957/1957" type="inclusive">1957</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="6b174c9d410d814a5134bc2f246ce01f" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044943]" type="box">19</container><container id="10cd1d33b4d23c47c4d8aaebd7d5d19a" parent="6b174c9d410d814a5134bc2f246ce01f" type="folder">150</container></did><scopecontent id="f0e7d502b1d8be93bf4026a2bf3b747e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appeals for contributions from various hospitals; denial of appeals, referral of others to Rockefeller Foundation or Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, contributions made to some. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur Woods, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p><p>Bishop Randall Hospital, Wyoming, 1957 City of Hope, New York City Chapter, 1956-1961 *Community Hospital at Glen Clove, New York (earlier called North Country Community Hospital, 1948-1959 Crippled Children's Hospital, Virginia, 1957-1961 *Crotched Mountain Foundation, New Hampshire 1956-1959 Deborah Sanatorium, 1957 Geauga Hospital Association, Ohio, 1957 Houston Tuberculosis Hospital, 1957 King Edward VII Memorial Hospital, Bermuda, 1954-1955 Knox County General Hospital, Maine, 1957 Mercy Hospital, Maryland, 1928-1957 Orange Memorial Hospital, Florida, 1957 Ottauquechee Health Center Peekskill Hospital (Friendly Hospital), 1955-1958 Perry County Health Center, Arkansas, 1957 Presbyterian Hospital, Puerto Rico, 1956-1958 Rip Van Winkle Clinic, 1956-1957 Rockland State Hospital Chapel Fund, New York, 1940-1957 *St. Johns Hospital, Jackson Hole, Wyoming, 1952-1957 St. John's Hospital, Missouri, 1950-1957 St. Joseph's Hospital, Texas, 1957 Sisters of Charity of Seaton Hil, 1957 Whiting Clinic, Indiana, 1957</p><p>An asterisk (*) indicates hospital received Rockefeller contribution.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="64cf63743fdc47188367652f9f677a29" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1958/1959" type="inclusive">1958-1959</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="33e8b7b839c79c3ef777afbd20c33999" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044944]" type="box">20</container><container id="eb6c4e8469337f2445f235046dfefb1b" parent="33e8b7b839c79c3ef777afbd20c33999" type="folder">151</container></did><scopecontent id="57fd4fcd33a2d1dd6eccdd80234c630f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appeals for contributions from various hospitals; denial of appeals, referral of others to Rockefeller Foundation or Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, contributions made to some. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur Woods, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p><p>Baptist Memorial Hospital, Missouri, 1958 Children's Convalescent Hospital, 1958 Children's Hospital of Philadelphia, 1953-1961 City of Hope, Los Angeles Chapter, 1958 City of Hope, New York City Chapter, 1956-1961 *Community Hospital at Glen Cove, New York (earlier called North Country Community Hospital) 1948-1959 Cottage Hospital, New Hampshire, 1958 *Crotched Mountain Foundation, New Hampshire, 1956-1959 *Friends of Pusan Children's Hospital, Korea, 1959-1961 Grace Hospital, Cleveland, 1958 Hillcrest Medical Center, Oklahoma (Tri-State College), 1948-1958 Institute for Living, Connecticut, 1958 Kingsbridge Veteran's Center, MacGregor Rehabilitation Center, Bronx, New York, 1959 Memorial Hospital, New York, 1959 Northern Dutchess Health Center, New York, 1958 Ottauquechee Health Center Peekskill Hospital (Friendly Hospital), 1955-1958 Presbyterian Hospital, Puerto Rico, 1956-1958 St. Joseph Hospital, Maine, 1959 St. Joseph's Hospital, Illinois, 1958 State Department of Mental Hygiene (clipping), 1958 *United Mission Hospital in Nepal, 1959-1960</p><p>An asterisk (*) indicates hospital received Rockefeller contribution.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="2288f25d05a649ecacd48edabaf480e3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1960/1961" type="inclusive">1960-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="2016e825e517810ccb9c5cfaf6a06dcc" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044944]" type="box">20</container><container id="9da614b93c7c5fcd829f8704402b84c2" parent="2016e825e517810ccb9c5cfaf6a06dcc" type="folder">152</container></did><scopecontent id="623398eec46d2020c32e2585708e3deb"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appeals for contributions from various hospitals; denial of appeals, referral of others to Rockefeller Foundation or Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, contributions made to some. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur Woods, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p><p>*Albany Medical Center, 1961 Battle Creek Sanitarium &amp; Hospital, Michigan, 1961 City of Hope, New York City Chapter, 1956-1961 City of St. Jude, Alabama, 1961 Crippled Children's Hospital, Virginia, 1957-1961 Dorado Hospital, Puerto Rico, 1961 Eleanor Roosevelt Cancer Foundation, 1960 Epp Memorial Hospital, Ohio, 1960 *Friends of Pusan Children's Hospital, Korea, 1959-1961 Hillcrest General Hospital, New York, 1960 Hospital Santa Monica, Brazil, 1961 Iran Medical Center, New York, New York, 1961 Mamie Dowd Eisenhower Osteopathic Hospital, Colorado, 1960 *Massachusetts General Hospital, 1947-1961 Masschusetts Memorial Hospitals Medical Center, 1960 Massachusetts Osteopathic Hospital, 1961 *New England Center Hospital, New England Medical Center, 1946-1961 Ottauquechee Health Center Presbyterian-St. Luke's Hospital, Chicago, 1960 Putnam County Hospitals merger, 1960 St. Croix Hospital, Virgin Islands, 1961 St. Jude Hospital, Tennessee, 1960-1961 *United Mission Hospital in Nepal, 1959-1960 *Veterans Administration Hospital, New York, 1960 Westerly Hospital, Rhode Island, 1960 Yale Psychiatric Institute, 1961</p><p>An asterisk (*) indicates hospital received Rockefeller contribution.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="5a2cbfd6f0d840408fa964c9c3156149" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Miscellaneous - Memorial Hospital, Phoenix, Arizona</unittitle><unitdate normal="1957/1957" type="inclusive">1957</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="5b90bc2bc7c12e93dd4fe5170b01fac6" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044944]" type="box">20</container><container id="7fd93c922ffec6ddd0fdd334d8958f0e" parent="5b90bc2bc7c12e93dd4fe5170b01fac6" type="folder">153</container></did><scopecontent id="395045967115f822a3f4c7fbc77111b6"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Laurance S. Rockefeller gift to hospital.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="5c040d147162407f9527b530de12706e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - New York City (A-L)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1927/1950" type="inclusive">1927-1950</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="295e8c4867915258d95b20c53939d9f0" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044944]" type="box">20</container><container id="6f0dac2703d2ea5b5088f4ec015f2d24" parent="295e8c4867915258d95b20c53939d9f0" type="folder">154</container></did><scopecontent id="92bb018c30443f18b538c4ffbbe8ecad"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Work of Bureau for Blood Transfusion; declination of appeal for contributions. Correspondents include Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur Woods, Thomas M. Debevoise, Kenneth Chorley, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.</p><p>Association for Improvement of Mental Hospitals, Inc., 1950 Beth Israel Hospital, 1941 Bronx Hospital, 1927</p></scopecontent></c><c id="9872e3900e5b495598af60b8d1854fa0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - New York City (M-Z)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1927/1950" type="inclusive">1927-1950</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="f730eb641b8ee52d8cc16baba1c742a4" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044944]" type="box">20</container><container id="176b95185d46f59435afabdecbd36b33" parent="f730eb641b8ee52d8cc16baba1c742a4" type="folder">155</container></did><scopecontent id="01b1a3db0793a37f591191f337fc1a77"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Work of Bureau for Blood Transfusion; declination of appeal for contributions. Correspondents include Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur Woods, Thomas M. Debevoise, Kenneth Chorley, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="dc09f722810240eca59980b0c9631469" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - New York City (A-Z)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1951/1961" type="inclusive">1951-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="b273fba1d62f61030cf067717d4ff194" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044944]" type="box">20</container><container id="b1cd54249314ef350dc60c8de4f79f7f" parent="b273fba1d62f61030cf067717d4ff194" type="folder">156</container></did><scopecontent id="94d29d9c22dab6ee603441704f5802b3"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Work of Bureau for Blood Transfusion; declination of appeal for contributions. Correspondents include Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur Woods, Thomas M. Debevoise, Kenneth Chorley, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="a5cf386bd2724f5a9c6bbf04e9188d51" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - New York City - New York Society for the Relief of the Ruptured and Crippled/Hospital for Special Surgery</unittitle><unitdate normal="1943/1961" type="inclusive">1943-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="b044d4ccdcfc33478d9c17b03a86b170" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044945]" type="box">21</container><container id="3d1ea759d4c0f44dc3930e9357002c5d" parent="b044d4ccdcfc33478d9c17b03a86b170" type="folder">157</container></did><scopecontent id="6b81eaa260e59065565d73ae868c6c6a"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Needs of the Hospital; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution to research fund to be constituted as a permanent memorial to Dr. Virgil P. Gibney; contributions to budget. Declination of appeals for contributions. Correspondents include Mary Rockefeller, Willard S. Richardson, Robert W. Gumbel, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="9543d52ae9bf468db4ab2e2cbe0075f7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - New York City - City Hospital, Welfare Island</unittitle><unitdate normal="1924/1954" type="inclusive">1924-1954</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="d89be005d6c54bc236ea862f42641a19" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044945]" type="box">21</container><container id="82d6d0e1b99a3cdc6f2eaf072aa7915d" parent="d89be005d6c54bc236ea862f42641a19" type="folder">158</container></did><scopecontent id="9cf134e5414158c9d59db6dc6f86a8e8"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Family gift of radio to Dr. Bacon for use of patients. Correspondents include Abraham Flexner, Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="b55555c00f9140bc931ce505987799e4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - American Hospital Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1928/1960" type="inclusive">1928-1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="faca11f22c4a9495c7458ddefd6e7506" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044945]" type="box">21</container><container id="f38f369c62d8e6faf30fab25473cca51" parent="faca11f22c4a9495c7458ddefd6e7506" type="folder">159</container></did><scopecontent id="322e2e5fbb3933eb12d35a5b549cc4fb"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Declination of appeals for contributions; John D. Rockefeller 3rd contributions to public relations department, 1958. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard, Thomas B. Appleget.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="1abb077673704632ae2bffe506375d9e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - American Hospital of Paris</unittitle><unitdate normal="1923/1961" type="inclusive">1923-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="248119e87b65278fdcb29eb80b32124d" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044945]" type="box">21</container><container id="2bb8ab45d31e7d39e353c2923a3c48a0" parent="248119e87b65278fdcb29eb80b32124d" type="folder">160</container></did><scopecontent id="cbfda4c6fc3f5ad10aed38e1579e21f8"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Needs of hospital. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s anonymous contribution; Abby Rockefeller Mauzé contributions. Correspondents include Arthur Woods, Willard S. Richardson.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="04d742495d004a359ca29be8aa20ed6a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - American Hospital of Paris</unittitle><unitdate normal="1923/1961" type="inclusive">1923-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="97c228b696ad000822644ce51fd874bd" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044945]" type="box">21</container><container id="e8d13f7cffb119505b1ce2e6ea9e4464" parent="97c228b696ad000822644ce51fd874bd" type="folder">160A</container></did><scopecontent id="d093e08e18d02cd36ce4cf23ec4942e0"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>David Rockefeller's contributions, election as Life Member.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="bd90df8d62e649ba825e9d3f760748f5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - American Hospital of Paris - John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. $10,000 Pledge</unittitle><unitdate normal="1915/1920" type="inclusive">1915-1920</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="fd8c17e167c3fcd6c50d29a582687fe9" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044945]" type="box">21</container><container id="9953e0998b6a233fb0bdfd8b23a35773" parent="fd8c17e167c3fcd6c50d29a582687fe9" type="folder">161</container></did><scopecontent id="576ec04491b42a7166032999c4a5f5c8"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Pledge to underwrite expenses of American Ambulance Hospital in Paris; transferral of money to American Hospital in Paris. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="b24807d4bf4c4712b0fde2140dcbf437" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Baltimore Provident Hospital and Dispensary</unittitle><unitdate normal="1927/1957" type="inclusive">1927-1932, 1957</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="d23dab405f70c8baf71bdcd5ebe3ad6f" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044945]" type="box">21</container><container id="145b707cfbbea2453610c9247ef4599d" parent="d23dab405f70c8baf71bdcd5ebe3ad6f" type="folder">162</container></did><scopecontent id="d883ec7a236cbab150799912598d69fc"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledge to hospital dedicated to training Negro interns and nurses and providing post-graduate work for Negro doctors. Correspondents include Abraham Flexner, Thomas B. Appleget, Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dr. J. M. T. Finney.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="66ea8d35ed3e410cbd7cb01b9f5ff3ee" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Baylor University, Hospital and Medical College</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1959" type="inclusive">1934-1959</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="0b3ad458d18fbb105a7e1727c3bc1956" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044945]" type="box">21</container><container id="b5eb3a2e04f30f5a9257a0628704f500" parent="0b3ad458d18fbb105a7e1727c3bc1956" type="folder">163</container></did><scopecontent id="461734a102eea9c9f29f7c279cb10898"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Needs of College and Hospital, request for contribution. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Thomas M. Debevoise, Dana S. Creel.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="d48bb96b70434210be998381a2ef8e8c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Bayonne, New Jersey Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1920/1956" type="inclusive">1920-1956</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="35c948bff6055de651eb248ee96915e8" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044945]" type="box">21</container><container id="e454fa673c45c53759167815406a1104" parent="35c948bff6055de651eb248ee96915e8" type="folder">164</container></did><scopecontent id="683fa0316b756e7c287d3ae1cfb40bf0"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Erection of new buildings of Bayonne Hospital and Dispensary; survey of city hospital conditions. Pledges by Standard Oil Co. of New Jersey, Vacuum Oil Co., and Tide Water Oil Co.; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledge. Correspondents include C. J. Hicks, Willard S. Richardson, Starr J. Murphy, Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Appleget.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="0108bb5561e74bbfb4937782533a5430" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Beekman Street Hospital, New York City</unittitle><unitdate normal="1925/1956" type="inclusive">1925-1956</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="9e0029fdcae815b461105be826b3b924" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044945]" type="box">21</container><container id="57382e17345d42565e3304975b326747" parent="9e0029fdcae815b461105be826b3b924" type="folder">165</container></did><scopecontent id="dfe7851bbce43a9fdb408502214bb5ef"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledge for enlargement and equipment and current expenses. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard, Thomas M. Appleget.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="dc410b3f3e09473fa1b5f6822113bcc3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Bellevue Hospital, New York City</unittitle><unitdate normal="1930/1961" type="inclusive">1930-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="6b63abf1733b4f80ab35f81eaba7c96a" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044946]" type="box">22</container><container id="ebff93527a8725fa995456c307063653" parent="6b63abf1733b4f80ab35f81eaba7c96a" type="folder">166</container></did><scopecontent id="15a6656b5b0bb41295e4ccce865f4ac5"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appeal for contributions to various clinics of Hospital. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. 1959 gift. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="f4a6293b485d45968bb9625edee1e4b8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Bellevue Hospital, New York City</unittitle><unitdate normal="1930/1961" type="inclusive">1930-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="3070940603402fda5442b0ce145bbaef" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044946]" type="box">22</container><container id="7ef7e5613e455f5774db28b206c756ba" parent="3070940603402fda5442b0ce145bbaef" type="folder">166A</container></did><scopecontent id="d45160ae66c10e0e9eed947b28dcc47f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appeal for contributions to various clinics of Hospital. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. 1959 gift. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="0be1f426d75e46e0baeb638208b8e7b3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Bellevue Hospital, New York City - Just One Break, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1953/1961" type="inclusive">1953-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="e4bd12502714836966b40384bbf50af1" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044946]" type="box">22</container><container id="f62f8101de458c2df9ddfa3dea3c538b" parent="e4bd12502714836966b40384bbf50af1" type="folder">167</container></did><scopecontent id="12a74a629aa45c31944fb01283829bd8"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Laurance S. Rockefeller's contributions. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Capt. Percy Lawson-Johnson.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="fd83da9710e94625b148960428ddea53" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Bellevue Hospital, New York City - Social Services Auxiliary</unittitle><unitdate normal="1941/1961" type="inclusive">1941-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="1a5906a86c523522193a454b155693b7" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044946]" type="box">22</container><container id="9bc0f36686c46b6d4fdf7806280714b9" parent="1a5906a86c523522193a454b155693b7" type="folder">168</container></did><scopecontent id="4d0995ce971e57b1deece6886c5fbbf2"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's contributions to Auxiliary. David Rockefeller's contributions; Mary French Rockefeller's contributions. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="41d6ebb59aec47b7ae657ba2c09a08db" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Bellevue Hospital, New York City - Social Services Auxiliary</unittitle><unitdate normal="1941/1961" type="inclusive">1941-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="8afef3aa0259d48976280d9bdd7b6799" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044946]" type="box">22</container><container id="2767bcb68990be977449960a4939563f" parent="8afef3aa0259d48976280d9bdd7b6799" type="folder">168A</container></did><scopecontent id="14d3cb8c48147a1e9b854d411e66d43b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's contributions to Auxiliary. David Rockefeller's contributions; Mary French Rockefeller's contributions. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="af1e7d448ffa46e79297159640644a73" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Broad Street Hospital, New York City/Downtown Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1915/1941" type="inclusive">1915-1941</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="a3c104af2dfbebb43e7cd776faec092c" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044946]" type="box">22</container><container id="ef22064c4afd604523a6176bb1fbde59" parent="a3c104af2dfbebb43e7cd776faec092c" type="folder">169</container></did><scopecontent id="ff1735b708b97d951adfadde0d3ebb0e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Work of the Hospital; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, Nelson A. Rockefeller, C. J. Hicks.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="a8f597a9d9104cff8e619ace15a6e536" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Brooklyn (A-Z)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1927/1960" type="inclusive">1927-1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="3db91ecf76ed54437f95324d4ac33e44" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044946]" type="box">22</container><container id="de1c4ecd943bc3e0f4633d2df48694c9" parent="3db91ecf76ed54437f95324d4ac33e44" type="folder">170</container></did><scopecontent id="c05c2ffe3d207ad2ae160c3fd2384089"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Building Fund campaign of St. John's Hospital; declination of appeals from other hospitals for contributions. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, Thomas M. Appleget.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="54caddf627c348bfbcd168b05f4e1a2b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Brooklyn - Swedish Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1928/1938" type="inclusive">1928-1938</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="55920f6b2b041d824e166394b33d01b3" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044946]" type="box">22</container><container id="3b9e9d1481c1a67858fbfa74ce35f366" parent="55920f6b2b041d824e166394b33d01b3" type="folder">171</container></did><scopecontent id="9752e12b47c41e9727838eba63788503"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Financial needs of Hospital; declination of appeals for contributions. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, Arthur W. Packard, Thomas M. Appleget.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="90c43bef876e479c93b68cdcfb6156ef" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Charity Hospital, Cleveland, Ohio</unittitle><unitdate normal="1904/1915" type="inclusive">1904-1915</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="83287fc596042d2cb6e50204f20109e9" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044946]" type="box">22</container><container id="1efb1741afb99484c8a8476cf2939905" parent="83287fc596042d2cb6e50204f20109e9" type="folder">172</container></did><scopecontent id="450122b3ac157e55dcdf13d76152d8da"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appeals, John D. Rockefeller, Sr. contributions. Correspondents include Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, Sr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="60d5a93b9b9b439cbd5cb0c684c9d1b1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Charles F. Kettering Memorial Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1959/1961" type="inclusive">1959-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="0583dd8af10284ded9518f61d6cb659f" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044946]" type="box">22</container><container id="66b5020ff2ad1b2eda193b4beb9b4732" parent="0583dd8af10284ded9518f61d6cb659f" type="folder">173</container></did><scopecontent id="56fe8280a6d90ccbdd2e92ef867662ad"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Laurance S. Rockefeller pledge of approximately $50,000, March 19, 1960. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Eugene W. Kettering, Alfred P. Sloan.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="334f310418c14d45978e6404d2180d15" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Children's Asthma Research Institute and Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1955/1961" type="inclusive">1955-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="b2d68efadee39d4947f90c2ae29d4157" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044946]" type="box">22</container><container id="35aca3f61d672c581579f02ebfff5695" parent="b2d68efadee39d4947f90c2ae29d4157" type="folder">174</container></did><scopecontent id="1c8c775f630d8a57486688fd820e2a81"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Appeals for contributions declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="fc12c1c26ac8448e97f5645419be9151" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Children's Asthma Research Institute and Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1955/1961" type="inclusive">1955-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="9a336d4dd094d86b6c208285ee08b9e1" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044946]" type="box">22</container><container id="9d08763226d87dd7cee9b73feaeb6be5" parent="9a336d4dd094d86b6c208285ee08b9e1" type="folder">174A</container></did><scopecontent id="6790313878e42326df8302e1b2182fbc"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Correspondents include David Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="48eb82a38eb34928b32d0e6fbec00371" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Children's Hospital Medical Center</unittitle><unitdate normal="1946/1961" type="inclusive">1946-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="6ee8034beada33129c5e3c54b40d2ea3" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044946]" type="box">22</container><container id="88899441b7b3cdd5b3ee756e563d3511" parent="6ee8034beada33129c5e3c54b40d2ea3" type="folder">175</container></did><scopecontent id="c3c2bd196863da61a1a74ea76b0ab8f3"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>1952 Jimmy Fund for children suffering from cancer. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="543088e557e44ed28227584a71c21186" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Clough Memorial Hospital, Ongole, India</unittitle><unitdate normal="1912/1928" type="inclusive">1912-1928</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="4e4bf4dcd2906ec9f5e75c46cd48bdd0" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044946]" type="box">22</container><container id="31951be00bba743a2cdcd7611433473a" parent="4e4bf4dcd2906ec9f5e75c46cd48bdd0" type="folder">176</container></did><scopecontent id="981dfce6c989010fb9b06f0cedb5f457"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Plans for Hospital as memorial to Dr. Clough. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution to Building Fund and toward x-ray equipment. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, Rev. James M. Baker.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="7446e59bf66546a0b5b1476d640d8d81" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Clough Memorial Hospital, Ongole, India - Aid for Mrs. Clough</unittitle><unitdate normal="1927/1932" type="inclusive">1927-1932</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="07d371452da264059b40cd40de537600" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044946]" type="box">22</container><container id="eebaa369cc96e775e0f8e096af163bc6" parent="07d371452da264059b40cd40de537600" type="folder">177</container></did><scopecontent id="2fde60335230f12da1301f1af135a865"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Mrs. Clough's pension from Foreign Mission Society; completion of article on Laura Spelman Rockefeller and the Ongole Mission; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution to her expenses at Kingston Sanitorium; copy of book on Dr. Clough in the Telagu dialect. Correspondents include E. R. Clough, Willard S. Richardson.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="98056269903147a8919de76069d055b6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Fifth Avenue Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1920/1922" type="inclusive">1920-1922</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="ec0de0ca994c219fbc412735cb80ae3b" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044946]" type="box">22</container><container id="722c28182db47b5f73eb57c6931b43dc" parent="ec0de0ca994c219fbc412735cb80ae3b" type="folder">178</container></did><scopecontent id="bd5ee374d196b81744c50718cbae8098"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Needs of the Hospital; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution to endow James Graham Cannon Memorial Room. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Starr J. Murphy.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="d42a96326bef4b39acd36536285e3718" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - French Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1926/1955" type="inclusive">1926-1929, 1939, 1948-1955</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="3c7898716bb5306fc2caeba762ab2d46" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044946]" type="box">22</container><container id="414169226dabc6c52dd9fcf13b3f1774" parent="3c7898716bb5306fc2caeba762ab2d46" type="folder">179</container></did><scopecontent id="f3c2f1eb121cb3e6ed2e613be93c4745"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Needs of the Hospital. Correspondents include Thomas B. Appleget.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="f647f917e49d413cbb9267d12ec426a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Cleveland Homeopathic Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1901/1910" type="inclusive">1901-1910</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="dc5e2227e7e49faabe700967661d5584" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044947]" type="box">23</container><container id="88ef512eed1bf3bd36df2aad5878b38b" parent="dc5e2227e7e49faabe700967661d5584" type="folder">180</container></did></c><c id="72065245420d467e837dc72c17358bd9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Huron St. Hospital, Cleveland, Ohio</unittitle><unitdate normal="1917/1923" type="inclusive">1917-1923</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="8df65c9d36607b77f04f93ddbcadf6a7" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044947]" type="box">23</container><container id="ed3443a0f334b0f68985e34edc85cb14" parent="8df65c9d36607b77f04f93ddbcadf6a7" type="folder">181</container></did><scopecontent id="041e7132276a37ec6828cab8b1fef4fa"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Need for hospital in East Cleveland; John D. Rockefeller Sr.'s sale of part of Forest Hill estate as hospital site, restrictions on use; gift of additional land for hospital expansion, 1938. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Sr., Starr J. Murphy, Charles O. Heydt, H. T. Sims, A. L. Boulware, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Phillip Keebler, J. A. Schlitz.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="cea8f76102e04dc7bfc2a024e86d23e5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Huron St. Hospital, Cleveland, Ohio</unittitle><unitdate normal="1924/1945" type="inclusive">1924-1945</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="8f9607611fad63e97b5a50186a99571e" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044947]" type="box">23</container><container id="57a0cab4b20b06137d34e736a1732f98" parent="8f9607611fad63e97b5a50186a99571e" type="folder">182</container></did><scopecontent id="6b2b6bc22d828cbc9747574414b7fc6d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Need for hospital in East Cleveland; John D. Rockefeller Sr.'s sale of part of Forest Hill estate as hospital site, restrictions on use; gift of additional land for hospital expansion, 1938. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Sr., Starr J. Murphy, Charles O. Heydt, H. T. Sims, A. L. Boulware, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Phillip Keebler, J. A. Schlitz.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="7f79ca7524fe4a77b1278222399a6f6a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Lenox Hill Hospital, New York City</unittitle><unitdate normal="1941/1961" type="inclusive">1941-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="b6b878a6296219a799775f727f46a101" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044947]" type="box">23</container><container id="d0ff1f0481ab7d9514a4c15a8982eabd" parent="b6b878a6296219a799775f727f46a101" type="folder">183</container></did><scopecontent id="332caf2510351f8bcea0098c749a8eca"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Laurance S. Rockefeller contributions, special gift of $42,087 in 1955; suggestion that he have a memorial room or special plaque declined. Other appeals; contributions by Abby Rockefeller Mauzé and John D. Rockefeller 3rd. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, William H. Zinsser.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="18aa9fa237bd4ae1ad9e824acd65d715" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Lenox Hill Hospital, New York City - Contributions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1943/1959" type="inclusive">1943-1959</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="fdc28c4db731ee84916ba8c96da3ace4" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044947]" type="box">23</container><container id="adeb3f31504a9e4467ca46b8529bab28" parent="fdc28c4db731ee84916ba8c96da3ace4" type="folder">184</container></did><scopecontent id="660160637d2f0d0734ee959285f03357"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Laurance S. Rockefeller contributions, special gift of $42,087 in 1955; suggestion that he have a memorial room or special plaque declined. Other appeals; contributions by Abby Rockefeller Mauzé and John D. Rockefeller 3rd. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, William H. Zinsser.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="db6150735472459ea9f79e1534f46176" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Maine Coast Memorial Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1948/1961" type="inclusive">1948-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="5d4d6ea22274e0ad10ea02ea72bc5ed6" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044947]" type="box">23</container><container id="115fd42654d0a1cae0e3641a77011a29" parent="5d4d6ea22274e0ad10ea02ea72bc5ed6" type="folder">185</container></did><scopecontent id="8b87f9693d6c974b01fc22eb25eac64e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Formerly Eastern Memorial Hospital - a modern hospital for rural community. Hospital not too successful. Name changed. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur Jones, Clarence C. Little.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="35b4e8eed98c4bcd951a2a3cf064a1f4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Mary Hitchcock Memorial Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1961" type="inclusive">1936-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="fd4bd78e9cc588846651bb0335e2ae6c" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044948]" type="box">24</container><container id="fbda9a2ac4a7d4efa9355da3f7efa815" parent="fd4bd78e9cc588846651bb0335e2ae6c" type="folder">186</container></did><scopecontent id="27ea2cfd8f603f38b8c8cf12ab54cb8f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Mary French Rockefeller's annual contributions. Correspondents include Mary French Rockefeller, David Freeman.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="59b07b71d57f4a78989ddd880e879beb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Maternity Hospital of Cleveland</unittitle><unitdate normal="1899/1915" type="inclusive">1899-1915</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="a25cdf6e0c447ed9ab2fe7a31c3de02a" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044948]" type="box">24</container><container id="b69e85dea262e87c70e6b215e5f7541d" parent="a25cdf6e0c447ed9ab2fe7a31c3de02a" type="folder">187</container></did></c><c id="e687a919231b41f084b5cf7faf4cf1c4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Manhattan Eye, Ear and Throat Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1946/1960" type="inclusive">1946-1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="9b89c83ce2695091e32183e60f577bc0" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044948]" type="box">24</container><container id="448b71dcea7ef7f143029cefd7a73a49" parent="9b89c83ce2695091e32183e60f577bc0" type="folder">188</container></did><scopecontent id="ea806ffe98c914e2e17aa57d6185f120"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s nonrecurring contribution; Nelson A. Rockefeller, Mary French Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include Stanley Resor, Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Mary French Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="d932c11f93fe463f82c76680c94f1fac" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Memorial Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1900/1930" type="inclusive">1900-1930</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="5f44bc4118f7f35eb729c0636976b5dc" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044948]" type="box">24</container><container id="d6f7e2c95c7aa6f563ce3e1be1dc3e7b" parent="5f44bc4118f7f35eb729c0636976b5dc" type="folder">189</container></did><scopecontent id="4b8b3cbf8babaf754650bca44115a5ce"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Reports of Dr. Beebe's investigations into cancer research; medical needs of Memorial Hospital for the treatment of cancer and allied diseases. John D. Rockefeller's pledge to assist; negotiations between New York Hospital and Cornell Medical Center; letters of thanks from cancer sufferers. Progress in cancer research printed materials; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s membership as Founder Member of the Society of Memorial Cancer Center; his contribution to Children's Village. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Stanley Flexner, Thomas M. Debevoise, Dr. William B. Coley, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="eebeb92b628449c68ab3fc48256b618f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Memorial Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1931/1940" type="inclusive">1931-1940</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="a80cabf06de6cedfd2f3921780a469b2" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044948]" type="box">24</container><container id="4f43a395884014aa7e5d697d30914c6f" parent="a80cabf06de6cedfd2f3921780a469b2" type="folder">190</container></did><scopecontent id="758cd993e5cdf5489d92708905454d07"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Reports of Dr. Beebe's investigations into cancer research; medical needs of Memorial Hospital for the treatment of cancer and allied diseases. John D. Rockefeller's pledge to assist; negotiations between New York Hospital and Cornell Medical Center; letters of thanks from cancer sufferers. Progress in cancer research printed materials; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s membership as Founder Member of the Society of Memorial Cancer Center; his contribution to Children's Village. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Stanley Flexner, Thomas M. Debevoise, Dr. William B. Coley, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="9dfc1050473c426b85fee21663159c3b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Memorial Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1941/1961" type="inclusive">1941-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="9c284bd76121705b5c2b85c43fac6e9f" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044948]" type="box">24</container><container id="f8982cd8a217ddb45a4f25837a00aa0e" parent="9c284bd76121705b5c2b85c43fac6e9f" type="folder">191</container></did><scopecontent id="a891b7d08b5a5b486d4a08b2b0216bd2"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Reports of Dr. Beebe's investigations into cancer research; medical needs of Memorial Hospital for the treatment of cancer and allied diseases. John D. Rockefeller's pledge to assist; negotiations between New York Hospital and Cornell Medical Center; letters of thanks from cancer sufferers. Progress in cancer research printed materials; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s membership as Founder Member of the Society of Memorial Cancer Center; his contribution to Children's Village. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Stanley Flexner, Thomas M. Debevoise, Dr. William B. Coley, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="5c1a8a9f5cf34a51a21336a6642442d5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Memorial Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1960/1961" type="inclusive">1960-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="41b1124cdd1d3d14c9d9001cefe7a67c" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044948]" type="box">24</container><container id="2539364607d8391be27d8fa36afe45cb" parent="41b1124cdd1d3d14c9d9001cefe7a67c" type="folder">191A</container></did><scopecontent id="b221524cce96f0dbfeaa7809e8c4557c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Reports of Dr. Beebe's investigations into cancer research; medical needs of Memorial Hospital for the treatment of cancer and allied diseases. John D. Rockefeller's pledge to assist; negotiations between New York Hospital and Cornell Medical Center; letters of thanks from cancer sufferers. Progress in cancer research printed materials; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s membership as Founder Member of the Society of Memorial Cancer Center; his contribution to Children's Village. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Stanley Flexner, Thomas M. Debevoise, Dr. William B. Coley, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="0b458bc2ba3746d39f94d5d5a92ea95d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - Pledges for Research</unittitle><unitdate normal="1927/1940" type="inclusive">1927-1940</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="3cdcca7c75d580bbe8ca3d9dd0efc0fc" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044948]" type="box">24</container><container id="2338475c48abd9bb868308578e99c44a" parent="3cdcca7c75d580bbe8ca3d9dd0efc0fc" type="folder">192</container></did><scopecontent id="33bea27424b87f2af0908da76c43daab"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Budgets, hospital needs; payments of pledges of March 17, 1927, June 24, 1927, June 23, 1931. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Arthur W. Packard, Dr. James Ewing, Dr. William Coley, Thomas B. Appleget.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="73ed81f57631449e8153176fce0e348a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - Ogden White Files</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1953" type="inclusive">1950-1953</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="1bbcc5f2d36b4639c0da5b6cf66d8ec1" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044949]" type="box">25</container><container id="8cdafd28c72c553baf4eacb7038a4d26" parent="1bbcc5f2d36b4639c0da5b6cf66d8ec1" type="folder">193</container></did><scopecontent id="7f959c8fd0a495dda35af64f0b8f3ce7"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Expansion plans.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="41508352b08b478ba0b94bc9dba9f409" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - New Building and Site</unittitle><unitdate normal="1927/1939" type="inclusive">1927-1939</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="88d62a510db2c5212249ec3b0c6b1702" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044949]" type="box">25</container><container id="297395f38e614450f188d1c7e9db1737" parent="88d62a510db2c5212249ec3b0c6b1702" type="folder">194</container></did><scopecontent id="72514eb582939f555ee9190251f26b4e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Letters thanking John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for gift of site and building for hospital; summary of editorials about gift, resolutions of thanks from hospital. Selection of architects for new hospital. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., S. Flexner, Trevor Arnett.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="21d063e53bcb4dafa1c97c6e7bf5477e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - Contributions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1948/1961" type="inclusive">1948-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="580ef982ab6e0a63b33644cc4dd1e03f" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044949]" type="box">25</container><container id="30bd5ac5d476139df85886b2533a2a84" parent="580ef982ab6e0a63b33644cc4dd1e03f" type="folder">195</container></did><scopecontent id="0c7deb5b2b0cea656e2f32459e118c1c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contributions by members of the family; plaque in memory of Irving Hotchkiss Pardee. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Mary Clark Rockefeller, Robert W. Gumbel.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="5cce4422054940e290cb4df642034e5a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - Abby Rockefeller Mauzé Contributions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1946/1961" type="inclusive">1946-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="5c35128efd7dbc81bcca99b71ff74730" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044949]" type="box">25</container><container id="db122acdab0faf928c739a98f1cbe382" parent="5c35128efd7dbc81bcca99b71ff74730" type="folder">196</container></did><scopecontent id="1aae8eccbd03aad2137930ea29e64cd0"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Regular donations.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="42f19dbcba7a42a3a667c4465e3a4a75" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - 1949 and 1950 Gifts</unittitle><unitdate normal="1949/1952" type="inclusive">1949-1952</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="10df72e3a2fb7792ed664125b5194aa6" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044949]" type="box">25</container><container id="fe3ce277d29696922b1ab1cbb8c332f1" parent="10df72e3a2fb7792ed664125b5194aa6" type="folder">197</container></did><scopecontent id="4c5ce7ecbc8dd1a4937de27eae17be8e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution to endowment fund, construction and teaching program; cancellation of pledge for an unconditional gift. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="d44ff3d3fef7468e98623fc539aaa89f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - January 8, 1947 Offer of Normandy Realty Company</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1949" type="inclusive">1947-1949</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="b2f54e6fd0f143af02d33d5c89d0f061" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044949]" type="box">25</container><container id="e5d1807d1f2994c90e0a12c3d613bf53" parent="b2f54e6fd0f143af02d33d5c89d0f061" type="folder">198</container></did><scopecontent id="c5ffecb62fb842b7008f700e248189ee"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Transfer of stock of Normandy Realty Corporation to the Memorial Hospital list of officers; appraisal of block between 68th and 69th streets, Second and Third Avenue. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Phillip Keebler, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="2922b0c0709c4653bc387f9c699b54a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - Normandy Realty Company - Letter of Gift</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1947" type="inclusive">1947</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="ed38f0dc31ad77fa7951f3f811917ac7" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044949]" type="box">25</container><container id="a16e2bb41ae2ed15004c9afe2d8fa130" parent="ed38f0dc31ad77fa7951f3f811917ac7" type="folder">199</container></did><scopecontent id="b56a6eb8a796bdf415bc0aa4b2ab2d53"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Gift of property for staff housing purposes. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Edward C. Delafield.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="0c63df9f1e9d465db16ad0b165d613f6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - Normandy Realty Company - Letter of Approval</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1947" type="inclusive">1947</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="7f0ab658a266ae145923d1645888ea8d" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044949]" type="box">25</container><container id="d2e7804c33ba1cea0cad58b0bc5b9d40" parent="7f0ab658a266ae145923d1645888ea8d" type="folder">200</container></did><scopecontent id="666c41d740c63ad2ce6aa08857a7e709"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Letters of appreciation for gift. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="51e4fcdc2c4e4748aa8bc86bfcf44793" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Memorial Hospital - Normandy Realty Company - James Ewing Memorial Fund</unittitle><unitdate normal="1944/1944" type="inclusive">1944</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="b87e37ec8227668cd65c9a9049383135" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044949]" type="box">25</container><container id="f16689e043ddaf3a0fa6bc57d809d8e4" parent="b87e37ec8227668cd65c9a9049383135" type="folder">201</container></did><scopecontent id="3522636fccf417a1e6c1f3d008776037"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution to Fund for memorial to Dr. Ewing. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="3c7741b597374cac9fe0b179c32202d3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Mount Desert Island Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1922/1950" type="inclusive">1922-1950</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="bb80a3c8588b9a52c2f2fc0660225fd2" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044949]" type="box">25</container><container id="96e92f07adffd5b6348d25f7092aefed" parent="bb80a3c8588b9a52c2f2fc0660225fd2" type="folder">202</container></did><scopecontent id="87c47d4db1eb46bc1039217dfe92a68e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledges to current maintenance of Hospital, to cost of new elevator and operating room, to x-ray machine, to fun to help rebuild hospital. Letters asking Edsel Ford, A. Atwater Kent and others to contribute; favorable responses. Mrs. Hubbard's gift of elevator in memory of husband; installation of memorial tablet. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s supplemental pledge to indebtedness; contributions by Nelson A. Rockefeller and Mary Clark Rockefeller, Martha Baird Rockefeller gift, 1961. Annual reports. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, Robert W. Gumbel, Dr. Charles C. Morrison, Edsel Ford, Edward K. Dunham, Mrs. Peter Jay, Mrs. E. Dyer Hubbard, Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="afcb7074e3ea4e34b25155f552c7f29b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Mount Desert Island Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1922/1950" type="inclusive">1922-1950</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="14b7c84af92870ddbbe57556b37563a9" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044949]" type="box">25</container><container id="801bece0a14df3ce50871b6e56edba01" parent="14b7c84af92870ddbbe57556b37563a9" type="folder">202A</container></did><scopecontent id="c1fcb1403d87fafb01a1823f0c58d6b7"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contributions by David Rockefeller and Margaret (Peggy) McGrath Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="638fe6aacbc549b5b393f3a4521152ed" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Mount Desert Island Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1951/1961" type="inclusive">1951-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="a26a734e92ff8a3e7bf954caf00ddaac" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044950]" type="box">26</container><container id="87459497a081de286683bb40526ebc56" parent="a26a734e92ff8a3e7bf954caf00ddaac" type="folder">203</container></did><scopecontent id="24458497d8424c5c5a91346dba83e68f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledges to current maintenance of Hospital, to cost of new elevator and operating room, to x-ray machine, to fun to help rebuild hospital. Letters asking Edsel Ford, A. Atwater Kent and others to contribute; favorable responses. Mrs. Hubbard's gift of elevator in memory of husband; installation of memorial tablet. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s supplemental pledge to indebtedness; contributions by Nelson A. Rockefeller and Mary Clark Rockefeller, Martha Baird Rockefeller gift, 1961. Annual reports. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, Robert W. Gumbel, Dr. Charles C. Morrison, Edsel Ford, Edward K. Dunham, Mrs. Peter Jay, Mrs. E. Dyer Hubbard, Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="feeab0e56d874c5381ac9ed9eeecf54c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Mount Desert Island Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1951/1961" type="inclusive">1951-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="54661ab745af85e94f7c29fbeb598a85" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044950]" type="box">26</container><container id="8a0bd518181a16d5475dde417b365480" parent="54661ab745af85e94f7c29fbeb598a85" type="folder">0203A</container></did><scopecontent id="754e3a3e4a0fadb6e296752ceed34478"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contributions by David Rockefeller and Margaret (Peggy) McGrath Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="0eb1baa2e13d40018943bdd546f0abcb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Mount Desert Island Hospital - Contributions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1961" type="inclusive">1936-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="06963d8ac1a57cfdc462a92f2b7007d8" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044950]" type="box">26</container><container id="d8957b6e02d69f6f3f14fec2fc5fc86e" parent="06963d8ac1a57cfdc462a92f2b7007d8" type="folder">204</container></did><scopecontent id="0ddd193fc2db5cc5ad12d5e89c87ed61"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contributions by members of the family to current maintenance expenses. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dana S. Creel, Arthur W. Packard, Edward K. Dunham.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="eae8dee53ff148199a646123945c45c2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Mount Desert Island Hospital - Campaign for New Wing</unittitle><unitdate normal="1937/1940" type="inclusive">1937-1940</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="7d169f00ec49ab4ecc4cd34f36fa6443" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044950]" type="box">26</container><container id="023a924ebfa3a90693ce0b1ef76317bb" parent="7d169f00ec49ab4ecc4cd34f36fa6443" type="folder">205</container></did></c><c id="b625b7f558ff44449e3ac691e800ae62" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Mount Desert Island Hospital - Edward K. Dunham Memorial Fund</unittitle><unitdate normal="1951/1953" type="inclusive">1951, 1953</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="f2f7dc3aab1fe38b9429146931bb6126" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044950]" type="box">26</container><container id="d1c9286e62682b5247d3efd4445035a7" parent="f2f7dc3aab1fe38b9429146931bb6126" type="folder">206</container></did><scopecontent id="ed089c7dbe26f8f8954110adc54886ec"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Death of Mr. Dunham, establishment of memorial; contributions by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller. Use of fund to purchase elevator. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel.</p></scopecontent><odd id="9b3ff2fb6118b5cf3489f84d2b860868"><head>General note</head><p>DR material removed to Folder 206A.</p></odd></c><c id="16806a1f0a084ad2ab2325382215e260" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Mount Desert Island Hospital - Edward K. Dunham Memorial Fund</unittitle><unitdate normal="1951/1953" type="inclusive">1951, 1953</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="5ad4f1469128ce8dbf64607e0977f792" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044950]" type="box">26</container><container id="8afa2048e621357bd60e3188ac75dc55" parent="5ad4f1469128ce8dbf64607e0977f792" type="folder">206A</container></did><scopecontent id="54f499f446d83e132df4bfcebd1041f2"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contribution by David Rockefeller. Correspondents include David Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="e5958cd0a414467f9503b5764ae68bdb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - National Hospital for Speech Disorders</unittitle><unitdate normal="1920/1960" type="inclusive">1920-1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="e9fea48a0a91fd73c34e0294fe8ee650" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044950]" type="box">26</container><container id="e6ad46e55883216c1ac03734303ee0e4" parent="e9fea48a0a91fd73c34e0294fe8ee650" type="folder">207</container></did><scopecontent id="a33cfb5a906cebf90dc0e5c12971d41e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Mr. Aldrich's praise of Mr. Paine's speech clinic; appeal for contributions. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Richard Aldrich, Albert Bigelow Paine, A. Flexner, Willard S. Richardson.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="2e1a58527fd0481092deb62b8d456040" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - National Jewish Hospital in Denver</unittitle><unitdate normal="1949/1961" type="inclusive">1949-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="56c9a5cba00454f5cd695ba9cdc05f1e" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044950]" type="box">26</container><container id="5a9a0bc36feda51461a10033170465e0" parent="56c9a5cba00454f5cd695ba9cdc05f1e" type="folder">208</container></did><scopecontent id="4cdbce7de3d604cbec8b425209556349"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Requests for donation to hospital for tuberculosis patients. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Paul Felix Warburg.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="2e142b178ce842619e5dd7b9b7be88b3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Neurological Institute</unittitle><unitdate normal="1909/1947" type="inclusive">1909-1947</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="01d35b0dd2a564614da8df01a25f5f92" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044950]" type="box">26</container><container id="73b9c1b61ac9961d16ad8c484d781872" parent="01d35b0dd2a564614da8df01a25f5f92" type="folder">209</container></did><scopecontent id="732c87e2d7d6a1a6a96b5df4fc0713d3"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Need for Hospital to care for neurological patients; work of the Hospital; appeal for contributions. Correspondents include S. Flexner, W. H. Welch, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, A. Flexner.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="3df34ccec2d443348ab81ec887c00a17" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - New Rochelle Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1946/1952" type="inclusive">1946-1952</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="f6f92caf5af1b6afc7eebb44c4255918" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044950]" type="box">26</container><container id="4f741ea28cfba8fa61a35f37deded493" parent="f6f92caf5af1b6afc7eebb44c4255918" type="folder">210</container></did><scopecontent id="fffb0edf1d8cd13a089b8c27a5c9457b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Nonrecurring gifts by Nelson A. Rockefeller and Winthrop Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent><odd id="dec5698b0d97a53b6a12c67d85f569e3"><head>General note</head><p>DR material removed to Folder 210A.</p></odd></c><c id="66af7153cc474aec8489ea7359f878a1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - New Rochelle Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1946/1952" type="inclusive">1946-1952</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="e0e7d78b5fc8f985db54b0f560573fc1" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044950]" type="box">26</container><container id="c15cf054f9d8b459b93c957281c1d079" parent="e0e7d78b5fc8f985db54b0f560573fc1" type="folder">210A</container></did><scopecontent id="2cb4d22e1666c25a6b0619676d159399"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Nonrecurring gifts by David Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="ce53d652c3b249dcb14e05cb10ebfc81" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - New York Foundling Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1953" type="inclusive">1947-1953</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="3647b6a5d198409cb65951c482370a8c" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044950]" type="box">26</container><container id="a1ee395ec1ba746f1a475498b824503e" parent="3647b6a5d198409cb65951c482370a8c" type="folder">211</container></did><scopecontent id="2f688b3cb6f1247000d604991569bed2"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Work of the Hospital; appeals for contributions; Nelson A. Rockefeller's anonymous contribution toward Christmas party. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="bc5a678cf9bb4889bb866c63705294ae" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - New York Infirmary for Women and Children</unittitle><unitdate normal="1930/1961" type="inclusive">1930-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="9da552d6544b730d2f67433547b4dcbb" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044950]" type="box">26</container><container id="8528e86711f50508a561d8d24685be7b" parent="9da552d6544b730d2f67433547b4dcbb" type="folder">212</container></did><scopecontent id="6313aeaaa3d5d2749d9c2ac11f4382ef"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Work and needs of the infirmary; requests for contribution. Laurance S. Rockefeller's contributions to building fund; John D. Rockefeller 3rd's contribution to library as tribute to Narcissa Cox Vanderlip; Abby Rockefeller Mauz's contribution to Psychiatric Clinic and to Neuropsychiatric Department in memory of Dr. Pardee. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="3a88238077794ebdb19f23948e94969d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - New York Medical College</unittitle><unitdate normal="1920/1959" type="inclusive">1920-1959</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="ace04157af860cbd40c1c6b34badd8f5" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044951]" type="box">27</container><container id="aa9ac466bfaeccaf197dd30e2f704c97" parent="ace04157af860cbd40c1c6b34badd8f5" type="folder">213</container></did><scopecontent id="999fc11e11ce818b199ebc48ac2f0070"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Needs of the New York Homeopathic College and Flower Hospital; appeals for contributions. Correspondents include A. Flexner, Thomas B. Appleget, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="3687378971554b3ca4b843df4ebacd0f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - New York Skin and Cancer Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1926/1955" type="inclusive">1926-1955</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="20fb5256056a27bd51b3fe19f88c88ae" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044951]" type="box">27</container><container id="cec4382bb8eec940a7506da146d9a561" parent="20fb5256056a27bd51b3fe19f88c88ae" type="folder">214</container></did><scopecontent id="b48ac5e0b3d8d3652709ffaee33d241b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>S. Flexner's report of hospital's work; appeals for contributions. Correspondents include S. FLexner, Thomas B. Appleget, Thomas M. Debevoise.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="f0bee9ea4f0b4b80aabbd431020bde87" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - New York Throat, Nose, and Lung Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1904/1920" type="inclusive">1904-1920</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="d55d9f0059a7cd8b5e2b7de886fe5c85" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044951]" type="box">27</container><container id="d7e4bf1be8536ec523eb14aa56f00f8a" parent="d55d9f0059a7cd8b5e2b7de886fe5c85" type="folder">215</container></did><scopecontent id="74d511aa17ba020091cf3529fc9849a5"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller's contribution; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributes to Night Camp Auxiliaries. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., E. G. Beringham.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="bda22a5a3cee48fa9c9e3e51655fc509" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Northern Westchester Hospital Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1924/1957" type="inclusive">1924, 1947, 1956-1957</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="008e1b451a5313a4722bceff58dd09c7" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044951]" type="box">27</container><container id="6cc210959aaba38f0f6557ce7cdad654" parent="008e1b451a5313a4722bceff58dd09c7" type="folder">216</container></did><scopecontent id="390aa3c1cb4798403991fd56f5fcfcc7"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Need for new hospital to replace Mt. Kisco Hospital; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s anonymous contribution. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="b550d63cd7864621a03319f54679c5a0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Northern Westchester Hospital Association</unittitle><unitdate normal="1924/1957" type="inclusive">1924, 1947, 1956-1957</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="0a72d3a160fab5444bc3452670cc4e48" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044951]" type="box">27</container><container id="4b7ec498dc0bbbce9b312f68f8e9e8d2" parent="0a72d3a160fab5444bc3452670cc4e48" type="folder">216A</container></did><scopecontent id="5cfd906dba5c460e59286ff3e35a125a"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>David Rockefeller's gift. Correspondents include David Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="7f91624280b14dbeb7f150619eebec66" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Paul Kimball Hospital, Lakewood, New Jersey</unittitle><unitdate normal="1911/1957" type="inclusive">1911-1957</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="11f4f2571a424b4de7f2de16aa908553" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044951]" type="box">27</container><container id="ed519567723e21ef05c31b5930ea99ca" parent="11f4f2571a424b4de7f2de16aa908553" type="folder">217</container></did><scopecontent id="30e80dcf7e609c70e57b4e51ff5911da"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s contribution to building fund and annual expenses; contribution to maternity ward fund. Correspondents include H. T. Sims, Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Sr., Davis.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="7483e91f1cc94b52a16fd41c84c47e62" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York</unittitle><unitdate normal="1952/1956" type="inclusive">1952-1956</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="c399b2bc5824223efd23d8128ff76377" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044951]" type="box">27</container><container id="27b0d459862f2deef2232919e6b888c7" parent="c399b2bc5824223efd23d8128ff76377" type="folder">218</container></did><scopecontent id="f6c8e4c94f824f888eb723f97965e374"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>List of Board of Directors, meetings of screening committee, budget, appeals, studies. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur Jones.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="beedc3389cb545ec9cd00f26f717c6b0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York</unittitle><unitdate normal="1957/1961" type="inclusive">1957-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="525522831e4eadc82098c05023cc86d7" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044951]" type="box">27</container><container id="78c8820a430205ca7efcce3fae9e12ee" parent="525522831e4eadc82098c05023cc86d7" type="folder">219</container></did><scopecontent id="cf6bf19e24be8dbcf64105ba2a46abd6"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>List of Board of Directors, meetings of screening committee, budget, appeals, studies. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur Jones.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="b3bd40a1ad0c484c96b3f841b6f097bc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York - By-laws</unittitle><unitdate normal="1953/1958" type="inclusive">1953, 1956, 1958</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="ab16304233f5667f61a31176238ffe1b" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044951]" type="box">27</container><container id="2b72a9b517f1c99c2c4eabd8f93cef8c" parent="ab16304233f5667f61a31176238ffe1b" type="folder">220</container></did><scopecontent id="de1f7c9ba8b71e22d7c41d401e7dcecd"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Copy of by-laws of Medical Staff and Memorial Hospital Association. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="c04a587f84da48edb498c734ac66c902" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York - Contributions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1952/1962" type="inclusive">1952-1962</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="bce3d00a76a3ca0aaedd9744bb5c61c2" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044952]" type="box">28</container><container id="5150eab76493af54c877fcab2f77fe47" parent="bce3d00a76a3ca0aaedd9744bb5c61c2" type="folder">221</container></did><scopecontent id="c0f32fbf3253dd80d6dab9f45bbd2c1f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller 3rd's contributions; his contributions to Carl Miller Memorial. Pledges by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Dana S. Creel.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="1ab14c07bc92469c8282405bd49fe500" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York - Statements</unittitle><unitdate normal="1960/1961" type="inclusive">1960-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="c1443e25d56cddbbf3090caaa18669f2" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044952]" type="box">28</container><container id="79615fcf424d20b269043f230d6bccb1" parent="c1443e25d56cddbbf3090caaa18669f2" type="folder">222</container></did><scopecontent id="8ba7697f28197b34e4638ff9e62f1ea3"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Audits. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="7b52abcf1bb54991a337d0ae4d82d2dc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York - Minutes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1961/1961" type="inclusive">1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="706b6ba07f8c88389721430d94aeca18" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044952]" type="box">28</container><container id="14a79390610fc7388bde67ce4d0e21eb" parent="706b6ba07f8c88389721430d94aeca18" type="folder">223</container></did><scopecontent id="12702df1ee39062171463885d4052761"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Minutes of meetings of Board of Directors.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="3954e26cbd5c4e7aa74fa7d1cd436914" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York - New Building</unittitle><unitdate normal="1952/1956" type="inclusive">1952-1956</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="ee4263c0a1b132db67a80f184bd8d43a" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044952]" type="box">28</container><container id="598f41284b9e21e429555cf433f746f4" parent="ee4263c0a1b132db67a80f184bd8d43a" type="folder">224</container></did><scopecontent id="3116f69f6c880bde76f555b5b4652b2f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Selection of architects for the consolidated hospital; proposed plans of operation and organization; progress of building fund campaign; lists of contributors; John D. Rockefeller 3rd's participation in cornerstone-laying ceremony; Opening Day ceremonies. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, William J. Yates, S. J. Bolassi.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="da26e8c546e045d099c4dd53e8cf827d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York - New Building - Letters of Appeal</unittitle><unitdate normal="1952/1955" type="inclusive">1952-1955</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="d94e0de4313500b92d67137de4af8908" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044952]" type="box">28</container><container id="5cbd756ecb445de9ae00ba9c92d04c96" parent="d94e0de4313500b92d67137de4af8908" type="folder">225</container></did><scopecontent id="fa79dd324b144fd0594e1ac1b6f8a264"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Progress of fund-raising activities; John D. Rockefeller 3rd's letters requesting donations. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="661cbf829d8949ab8e1ef242fb4f1abc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York - Expansion Program</unittitle><unitdate normal="1960/1961" type="inclusive">1960-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="7ed73ccfbb52d5db1fb2f2ab22dfac8d" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044953]" type="box">29</container><container id="cd31406cfb181a927a4f197b94342ea2" parent="7ed73ccfbb52d5db1fb2f2ab22dfac8d" type="folder">226</container></did><scopecontent id="0eb8487efab848bb3f3972c50280c1a8"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Program; Rockefeller contributions; other contributors. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, D. Freeman.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="16825a5e41764879a0e0b38d25aef1e4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Phelps Memorial Hospital, Tarrytown, New York - Publicity</unittitle><unitdate normal="1952/1960" type="inclusive">1952-1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="8302fb73f5eb8d084d9b11d0e14fa8c0" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044953]" type="box">29</container><container id="3d1977c11448d9b56c95d8e7d20624fb" parent="8302fb73f5eb8d084d9b11d0e14fa8c0" type="folder">227</container></did><scopecontent id="f625506932937d4e37a46e79118ec2e6"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Newspaper clippings.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="634660f476504cfb9af423e8c7ccbe13" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Presbyterian Hospital, New York</unittitle><unitdate normal="1924/1961" type="inclusive">1924, 1945-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="bb9ef706d525a26614ecea0d6c8cd686" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044953]" type="box">29</container><container id="565d69c72215a4ff96a5dc941b42870c" parent="bb9ef706d525a26614ecea0d6c8cd686" type="folder">228</container></did><scopecontent id="2617ca004c23071d6a480b58ce107a2b"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Reports, activities of the Hospital; appeals for contributions. Abby Rockefeller Mauzé gift, Laurance S. Rockefeller gift, others. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, A. Flexner.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="ea2a365e58194fdf9bf8e5a35e19887f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Psychiatric Institute, Morristown, New Jersey</unittitle><unitdate normal="1922/1930" type="inclusive">1922-1930</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="77f502d3194c1576058b2fa771d9cb3c" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044953]" type="box">29</container><container id="abbf09e907a6f7ee9474f18a5eee52fd" parent="77f502d3194c1576058b2fa771d9cb3c" type="folder">229</container></did><scopecontent id="f3422656194ed8b8dab4e65df2963728"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Inquiry about work of Dr. Allen on diabetes and Bright's disease; further needs of Institute. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, S. Flexner, Frederick M. Allen.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="061223b42dfd4f389013a8f000a4d95a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Rhode Island Hospital, Providence, Rhode Island</unittitle><unitdate normal="1925/1948" type="inclusive">1925-1926, 1945, 1948</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="dcf50e3ff4f76bfc69781a6385da392d" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044953]" type="box">29</container><container id="71d2db06f0589d554f1db882dc5fe26f" parent="dcf50e3ff4f76bfc69781a6385da392d" type="folder">230</container></did><scopecontent id="6a00fe4c4380c080aef514cc0d804764"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Report on Brown University Health Service; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, W. H. P. Faunce.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="121d8ebba22c4cb8b69c8b316b731f05" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Roosevelt Hospital, New York City</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1961" type="inclusive">1940-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="cc465da86bd79aaac737a1de21bca4ec" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044953]" type="box">29</container><container id="522c95835f70481f12937066cf092fcc" parent="cc465da86bd79aaac737a1de21bca4ec" type="folder">231</container></did><scopecontent id="188522be0baaef198b9bfc6ec38eac59"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Laying of cornerstone; progress of building campaign; some gifts. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="f76ba9bfd0da48c0801da5d2aea7e54e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Roosevelt Hospital, New York City - Contributions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1939/1961" type="inclusive">1939-1947, 1949-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="c7d85b24e6c0d47e515f9bccd2a50bd7" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044953]" type="box">29</container><container id="e269d70c8660d3ca8c7bf6577deec733" parent="c7d85b24e6c0d47e515f9bccd2a50bd7" type="folder">232</container></did><scopecontent id="1feb54ccde6ee89da55bc4c966ebdb2a"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Lists of donors; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s anonymous contribution to enlargement campaign; Abby Rockefeller Milton's contribution; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1960 pledge; 1957 conditional pledge. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="6eec88918a6547e3bc40df29b2a6e3fe" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Roosevelt Hospital, New York City - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. May 1957 - Pledge and Contribution</unittitle><unitdate normal="1957/1960" type="inclusive">1957-1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="6aaee7de0224bac3ee4ced4762280235" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044953]" type="box">29</container><container id="70990eeeff949df6f8832e3e4e0f57f0" parent="6aaee7de0224bac3ee4ced4762280235" type="folder">233</container></did></c><c id="7336db6829ac441ba6a177950122e3da" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - St. Barnabas Hospital for Chronic Disease</unittitle><unitdate normal="1927/1956" type="inclusive">1927, 1943-1956</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="2103783e639d6cf7e32ddd2f5fe0dbd6" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044953]" type="box">29</container><container id="b4f0e2433930d369d0c63899e20860fa" parent="2103783e639d6cf7e32ddd2f5fe0dbd6" type="folder">234</container></did><scopecontent id="1c5160d7b79606573b7ccd8836c9351f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Printed materials; appeals for contributions. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, Thomas M. Debevoise.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="377bb5abb1db4aa8b467b926f8d8fb68" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - St. Luke's Hospital, New York City</unittitle><unitdate normal="1932/1961" type="inclusive">1932, 1943-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="e505f12e6b058903aa4a45ae84f82cb4" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044953]" type="box">29</container><container id="5aef1a4355ed9a1abf5c4cc8ea1e4447" parent="e505f12e6b058903aa4a45ae84f82cb4" type="folder">235</container></did><scopecontent id="b5764ec8edaf58138cd04b978b517a4c"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s recommendation of Dr. Alan Gregg; appeals for contributions; Abby Rockefeller Milton's contribution; contributions by Mary French Rockefeller. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="2177e98712394be78621116a39d6395b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - St. Luke's Hospital, New York City</unittitle><unitdate normal="1932/1961" type="inclusive">1932, 1943-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="7f125db5c223d843d7157a39922b76b0" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044953]" type="box">29</container><container id="ab6cd26f79660ef2ce7bd77610f513d4" parent="7f125db5c223d843d7157a39922b76b0" type="folder">235A</container></did><scopecontent id="1dbb9cd745dcb4e83b18aa229bc93f4f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contributions by David Rockefeller. Correspondents include David Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="f621700e40304fd994b230d48ebedab8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - St. Luke's Hospital, New York City - Contributions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1945/1962" type="inclusive">1945-1962</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="ced021b91970c8e0973c9bb56ab27d0c" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044954]" type="box">30</container><container id="e4a4a69defebb1a3b8fe31a672e17e4f" parent="ced021b91970c8e0973c9bb56ab27d0c" type="folder">236</container></did><scopecontent id="e5aeb63e40061f0580fe54b20d55dd23"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>From Mary French Rockefeller, Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Abby Rockefeller Mauzé.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="9a503828b6824c55b7bfda9a342f2ab5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - St. Luke's Hospital, Tokyo, Japan</unittitle><unitdate normal="1913/1956" type="inclusive">1913-1915, 1924-1946, 1956</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="77a97f84113e7c2c09519e264e1bdbdd" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044954]" type="box">30</container><container id="de44a68b329b9e5fc272e9e9992d4f72" parent="77a97f84113e7c2c09519e264e1bdbdd" type="folder">237</container></did><scopecontent id="5ae52fe86ebbf5f4d6a2b3762eb79143"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Needs of hospital; laying of cornerstone of Medical Center; progress of construction program; appeals for contributions. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s donation to reimburse hospital for earthquake and fire damage. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Arthur W. Packard, Thomas M. Debevoise, Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas B. Appleget, George W. Wickersham.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="2107c1cf8fa140d8b90f4b33978c9749" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - St. Ann's Infant Asylum and Maternity Health Home, Cleveland, Ohio</unittitle><unitdate normal="1911/1912" type="inclusive">1911-1912</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="753b4cf7b474e1879fc52163ac3c7af5" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044954]" type="box">30</container><container id="cce92606983215b63fd526df8ee87351" parent="753b4cf7b474e1879fc52163ac3c7af5" type="folder">238</container></did><scopecontent id="62374c3f5b038e63932b6117ef9c6bc3"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s contribution. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="7abc130599cd43469f81410497195a3b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - St. Vincent's Hospital, New York City</unittitle><unitdate normal="1942/1961" type="inclusive">1942, 1951-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="c4d2b54f82e7fbe1c33649e5ce1bc116" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044954]" type="box">30</container><container id="bcf4c2a1560b1181f56f04ebf7b9ffa1" parent="c4d2b54f82e7fbe1c33649e5ce1bc116" type="folder">239</container></did><scopecontent id="b9554a3e13a415f466f9c7df78b7700d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contribution through Davison Fund; John D. Rockefeller 3rd's anonymous contribution. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Alfred E. Smith.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="54bf1e2f1e694655a24ce89f63135d33" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - General Hospital of Saranac Lake</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1953" type="inclusive">1947-1953</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="6ae0732b8a741c449913f07fde9d2606" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044954]" type="box">30</container><container id="50aa679a348566b9f7a459cad54c92e8" parent="6ae0732b8a741c449913f07fde9d2606" type="folder">240</container></did><scopecontent id="78fddf622b3cda3472989a9df6b1ed91"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Laurance S. Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="3f9e97c3190d47b181dd3445ff879f36" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Society of the New York Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1919/1961" type="inclusive">1919, 1929-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="2ca4c6f3fad5a1f5a4c47994e49b35c7" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044954]" type="box">30</container><container id="4536d33b8cd446d773ea7438bf6d06c7" parent="2ca4c6f3fad5a1f5a4c47994e49b35c7" type="folder">241</container></did><scopecontent id="7ea2fc2adb8efc5404dcc17912b34088"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contributions; Jean Mauzé elected to Board of Governors.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="25f5cde0c5344be985c72b237e4cc9c2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Society of the New York Hospital - Contributions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1962" type="inclusive">1940-1962</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="fb05fd30ef0fe4d301048ae1171eef22" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044954]" type="box">30</container><container id="0dccc56fcd6dcb94a419c158110566b9" parent="fb05fd30ef0fe4d301048ae1171eef22" type="folder">242</container></did></c><c id="966a354b4b91472597c1f0ed941df40a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Society of the New York Hospital - Contributions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1962" type="inclusive">1940-1962</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="b16e40a9d5b802d21a96e28cae08dd54" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044954]" type="box">30</container><container id="92c663ea80557f86688dea313540e66c" parent="b16e40a9d5b802d21a96e28cae08dd54" type="folder">242A</container></did><accessrestrict id="aa4a743fd91aa061566d43aa0c1a71fb"><head>Conditions Governing Access note</head><p>Restricted material.</p></accessrestrict></c><c id="36ff596b36da4b59bba5c35bf6e2aff3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Society of the New York Hospital - Abby Rockefeller Mauzé Contributions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1949" type="inclusive">1940-1949</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="41f2a3d4e0fcd91469f38b135b4e12e0" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044954]" type="box">30</container><container id="90dcce474609c3fcb126677fd2f3c78c" parent="41f2a3d4e0fcd91469f38b135b4e12e0" type="folder">243</container></did></c><c id="735a25e0116d41d9bea431d1e2c736e7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Society of the New York Hospital - Laurance S. Rockefeller Contributions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1938/1961" type="inclusive">1938-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="52a1f298041b45803cad948eb40e0d1f" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044954]" type="box">30</container><container id="2a7301bb3b0ee338bc7ede8bb8f0d54d" parent="52a1f298041b45803cad948eb40e0d1f" type="folder">244</container></did><scopecontent id="b54ccafa2d7b9626d62ed7fa88154d35"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Contributions and correspondence. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="69ed2cebcba44c0bbb458f3548c74f8b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Society of the New York Hospital - Westchester Division</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1960" type="inclusive">1947-1960</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="87c57ddf00dbb0e1679f0f9db211124d" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044955]" type="box">31</container><container id="69651f8dc669a0c11a979d0563b747ac" parent="87c57ddf00dbb0e1679f0f9db211124d" type="folder">245</container></did><scopecontent id="9f2887f2a16d12851be9650d2165e222"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s gift for out-patient department; other appeals. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., James H. Wall.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="332ec4815e0d49aaac733fa385028633" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Society of the New York Hospital - Westchester Division - Contributions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1961" type="inclusive">1947-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="de2630882810e08a3866a4c12eaaff87" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044955]" type="box">31</container><container id="62f981833ae93b36b001a67100a58ec1" parent="de2630882810e08a3866a4c12eaaff87" type="folder">246</container></did><scopecontent id="3b2e9c31004b9bdd19f7f487d986ea19"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Gifts from Abby Rockefeller Mauzé.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="d7c8dd9dc9204f52b39f54eb626112a7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Society of the New York Hospital - Westchester Division - June 1955 Gift</unittitle><unitdate normal="1954/1956" type="inclusive">1954-1956</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="82ea374830212389c4b146220f5d2593" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044955]" type="box">31</container><container id="e83d8fdf199cc7e8c7f47806a0ba6292" parent="82ea374830212389c4b146220f5d2593" type="folder">247</container></did><scopecontent id="717a1e0729c6feb59fe98d9132991fd7"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="051cfa45f4584ce48c6dc94582d1997f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Stony Wold Sanatorium</unittitle><unitdate normal="1901/1948" type="inclusive">1901-1948</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="44dbe9aa6f53f1d36ad2b47fee23dfae" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044955]" type="box">31</container><container id="43f974fe1e6bf0284ba5defabecb63c7" parent="44dbe9aa6f53f1d36ad2b47fee23dfae" type="folder">248</container></did><scopecontent id="c255b4b99ae49d3e2f37deae90385a36"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Sr. contributions. Recent appeals, declined. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="b31c54702577472599434681271e7976" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Sydenham Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1943/1957" type="inclusive">1943-1949, 1957</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="720b0043ff3e14341ab76ec3be1df8e8" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044955]" type="box">31</container><container id="5c65d2ed091ef8be4d51f8261e257d0e" parent="720b0043ff3e14341ab76ec3be1df8e8" type="folder">249</container></did><scopecontent id="6c6262dc9faab6294edc76760cc84be2"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Fund-raising campaign, budgets and financial reports, activities of the Hospital; anonymous contribution to Fund; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, Frank Totten, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="5edcd4597cbf4b6dbdf36804c4297e89" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Tarrytown Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1901/1939" type="inclusive">1901-1939</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="2d8cdb87531f6eebd9260310468eb2a3" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044955]" type="box">31</container><container id="4d28d43928051ba2aedeef696722b75b" parent="2d8cdb87531f6eebd9260310468eb2a3" type="folder">250</container></did><scopecontent id="a2cc5df17c34098cb8894464bf233daa"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Later became Phelps Memorial Hospital Association. Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s election to membership in Tarrytown Hospital Association; statistical reports; plans for acquisition of new site and new building. John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s and John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contributions to Hospital for maintenance fund, current budgets, special purposes, building fund. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="d79bc42abc844821b91c4a8d20a2d756" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Tarrytown Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1956" type="inclusive">1940-1952, 1956</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="5580925c926e47e40f487a6abd5cff80" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044956]" type="box">32</container><container id="f25c683338312c8c2eaa585f345be3a5" parent="5580925c926e47e40f487a6abd5cff80" type="folder">251</container></did><scopecontent id="636f9082bee2888cd52e92c06150087f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Later became Phelps Memorial Hospital Association. Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s election to membership in Tarrytown Hospital Association; statistical reports; plans for acquisition of new site and new building. John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s and John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contributions to Hospital for maintenance fund, current budgets, special purposes, building fund. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="8d3ba21cd7454dedbe56b2e5ded6ab48" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Tarrytown Hospital - April 29, 1950 Gift</unittitle><unitdate normal="1950/1951" type="inclusive">1950-1951</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="d7bb729395cf27be46081a95a793ac72" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044956]" type="box">32</container><container id="2c19d01a8f4679af9c5c2191033b23ce" parent="d7bb729395cf27be46081a95a793ac72" type="folder">252</container></did><scopecontent id="097d83ce99e52aa9d3a023a463670f01"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Merger of Tarrytown and Ossining hospitals; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledge, with provision that pledge be voided if merger plans unsuccessful; voiding of pledge. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="a71fb26728dc4b10bcc5c2f4e0edf919" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Tarrytown Hospital - May 1952 Gift</unittitle><unitdate normal="1952/1953" type="inclusive">1952-1953</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="fcbe214914fc4aa65af54580b3cd7320" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044956]" type="box">32</container><container id="157492b74894c2f478d072a5e4c9bfef" parent="fcbe214914fc4aa65af54580b3cd7320" type="folder">253</container></did><scopecontent id="fd9de399f28f7258363567c81d01c95f"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledge to campaign; drive for new Consolidated Tarrytown-Ossining Hospital; conditions of pledge; change of name to Phelps Memorial Hospital Association. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler, Dana S. Kreel, Yates, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="4a4af68034ee45088cdcf6d53f8bf466" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Tarrytown Hospital - Merger with Dobbs Ferry and Ossining Hospitals</unittitle><unitdate normal="1929/1948" type="inclusive">1929, 1935-1948</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="4749bb872354e7deaf67411073c70dfd" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044956]" type="box">32</container><container id="45c3cb9a8ca07dd9b058ab0fc7ecdf2d" parent="4749bb872354e7deaf67411073c70dfd" type="folder">254</container></did><scopecontent id="3b8dd6e45c3866f20a263d1f2385d9e7"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Survey of hospital facilities; John D. Rockefeller 3rd's pledge to underwrite cost; copy of report, "A Survey of the Hospitals of Dobbs Ferry, Ossining and Tarrytown," by Dr. Emerson; John D. Rockefeller 3rd's pledge to survey hospitals to determine advantages of merger. Minutes of meeting of merger subcommittee; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s feeling that name "Rockefeller" should not be used in name of new hospital. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="1366552647664a1a85d22b4f0806aecf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Tarrytown Hospital - Merger with Dobbs Ferry and Ossining Hospitals</unittitle><unitdate normal="1949/1952" type="inclusive">1949-1952</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="9952845bb493133f8a17661b862efc34" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044956]" type="box">32</container><container id="2f38cb3d173aafe8d5a52bb0eaf4ef69" parent="9952845bb493133f8a17661b862efc34" type="folder">255</container></did><scopecontent id="b6387fc2ae37065e9b8a9714b80773a4"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Survey of hospital facilities; John D. Rockefeller 3rd's pledge to underwrite cost; copy of report, "A Survey of the Hospitals of Dobbs Ferry, Ossining and Tarrytown," by Dr. Emerson; John D. Rockefeller 3rd's pledge to survey hospitals to determine advantages of merger. Minutes of meeting of merger subcommittee; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s feeling that name "Rockefeller" should not be used in name of new hospital. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="6f09c322b9b84518bf40d810f3b2b406" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Tarrytown Hospital - John D. Rockefeller 3rd</unittitle><unitdate normal="1935/1952" type="inclusive">1935-1952</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="d979594bfa6c41cb8ed818a11759f989" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044956]" type="box">32</container><container id="7c2d5a7d01f0fd104300c68d29a55c02" parent="d979594bfa6c41cb8ed818a11759f989" type="folder">256</container></did><scopecontent id="6ac45df544be69517bb2dbe0a0cf98d6"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller 3rd a director; his contributions. Planning and direction.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="c732e33b3895436da20cfc7d6b0bf4d5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Trudeau Sanatorium, Saranac, New York</unittitle><unitdate normal="1899/1930" type="inclusive">1899-1930</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="972f214c20c1269544f1af620e729266" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044957]" type="box">33</container><container id="2e78e1c74e77dd3de5c76720dc0b9893" parent="972f214c20c1269544f1af620e729266" type="folder">257</container></did><scopecontent id="51b60ea4d337c8a027dcad02df5960a8"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s donation to current operating expenses; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s donations to general fund, laboratory cottage, operating expenses, building fund for research and clinical laboratory. Death of Dr. Trudeau. Contributions by other members of the family. Correspondents include E. L. Trudeau, William H. Welch, Dr. Laurason Broun, Federick Sheffield, Starr J. Murphy, Charles O. Heydt, Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Sr., John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="0f84ce9ad767488ebc1015e52b016a77" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Trudeau Sanatorium, Saranac, New York</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1956" type="inclusive">1934-1956</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="21259b448edc271aa5d28d3a3c38e3b0" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044957]" type="box">33</container><container id="b2743fa145a7b43be06f97a415f11efb" parent="21259b448edc271aa5d28d3a3c38e3b0" type="folder">258</container></did><scopecontent id="9b86be732816e785877900b2bc152e50"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s donation to current operating expenses; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s donations to general fund, laboratory cottage, operating expenses, building fund for research and clinical laboratory. Death of Dr. Trudeau. Laurance S. Rockefeller's contribution to Friendowment Fund and operating budgets; contributions by other members of the family. Correspondents include E. L. Trudeau, William H. Welch, Dr. Laurason Broun, Federick Sheffield, Starr J. Murphy, Charles O. Heydt, Willard S. Richardson, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Sr., John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="34b63fb88bb54fcb9867ba2a43562781" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Trudeau Sanatorium, Saranac, New York</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1956" type="inclusive">1934-1956</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="d93be0156873c81e09cc2ca631c97363" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044957]" type="box">33</container><container id="6d51496b768468932fe6ba4ca4c76540" parent="d93be0156873c81e09cc2ca631c97363" type="folder">258A</container></did><scopecontent id="726dfb9358bd7feba002ae7f9cbca18d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Correspondents include David Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="16482eb131914e9cbb7f9295b8d98ed9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Tucson Medical Center</unittitle><unitdate normal="1949/1961" type="inclusive">1949-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="cdcfb50dd8ba9afcae19be07bc6da41e" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044957]" type="box">33</container><container id="a73a327d009afea249f99feb669258ac" parent="cdcfb50dd8ba9afcae19be07bc6da41e" type="folder">259</container></did><scopecontent id="c8b339a222594441a15d2b4d37e5dda4"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions. Memorial gift and plaque. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="3e107322d49147408b1cd3588781e11e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - United Hospital Fund</unittitle><unitdate normal="1897/1925" type="inclusive">1897-1925</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="bbb585cbbc184ff1bc4a2947d6257cbb" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044957]" type="box">33</container><container id="c854f90be0c3dd37fd49b23c369c4d9d" parent="bbb585cbbc184ff1bc4a2947d6257cbb" type="folder">260</container></did><scopecontent id="6a59380b3e25f5cb06bfa442556e72d4"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contributions, Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial contributions; plans for survey of hospital situation in New York; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s declination of invitation to serve as member of Campaign Committee; plans for annual campaign drives. Printed materials, auditors reports, progress of fund-raising campaigns, financial and statistical data; summary of Rockefeller Brothers Fund contributions. Correspondents include W. H. P. Faunce, Frederick Greene, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller, Sr., Arthur Woods, Arthur W. Packard, Laurance S. Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="ec5b0f5506954f9fa753bdbd5ba07c50" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - United Hospital Fund</unittitle><unitdate normal="1926/1942" type="inclusive">1926-1942</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="b06c5d263bbbe4ed3a45b4f2574dccad" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044957]" type="box">33</container><container id="f66b17e1d0f7e40b57750a1162bca38f" parent="b06c5d263bbbe4ed3a45b4f2574dccad" type="folder">261</container></did><scopecontent id="312e55b0e059f03ca157a759a4626d2e"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contributions, Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial contributions; plans for survey of hospital situation in New York; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s declination of invitation to serve as member of Campaign Committee; plans for annual campaign drives. Printed materials, auditors reports, progress of fund-raising campaigns, financial and statistical data; summary of Rockefeller Brothers Fund contributions. Correspondents include W. H. P. Faunce, Frederick Greene, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller, Sr., Arthur Woods, Arthur W. Packard, Laurance S. Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="f2783654ea224bddb006d3484a56987f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - United Hospital Fund</unittitle><unitdate normal="1945/1961" type="inclusive">1945-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="995f05a2031befb1c093e126f47cfb2b" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044957]" type="box">33</container><container id="5aad4643e08d93ea21c32ef99896b995" parent="995f05a2031befb1c093e126f47cfb2b" type="folder">262</container></did><scopecontent id="ceaf9146f94fd8516360fc77092df00d"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contributions, Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial contributions; plans for survey of hospital situation in New York; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s declination of invitation to serve as member of Campaign Committee; plans for annual campaign drives. Printed materials, auditors reports, progress of fund-raising campaigns, financial and statistical data; summary of Rockefeller Brothers Fund contributions. Correspondents include W. H. P. Faunce, Frederick Greene, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller, Sr., Arthur Woods, Arthur W. Packard, Laurance S. Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="766b7ba1bf3544b3bdd972a24669be3b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - United Hospital Fund - John D. Rockefeller 3rd</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1947" type="inclusive">1934-1947</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="b1c06f30020b8c7bab509909fdf01c72" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044958]" type="box">34</container><container id="149b3c25b09594889a2f546802ab0f13" parent="b1c06f30020b8c7bab509909fdf01c72" type="folder">263</container></did></c><c id="82c2513fc07b4984a691b9f5a131090c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - United Hospital Fund - Abby Rockefeller Mauzé</unittitle><unitdate normal="1939/1961" type="inclusive">1939-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="709774158d4847b4073803dda71605eb" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044958]" type="box">34</container><container id="1d4ebac66a48820d7ac47dbc817b025d" parent="709774158d4847b4073803dda71605eb" type="folder">264</container></did></c><c id="a9b41386a05d44eab0855e86f61f7d0f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - United Hospital Fund - Laurance S. Rockefeller</unittitle><unitdate normal="1936/1961" type="inclusive">1936-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="935e82f2a6c085bfa99aec469d9b047d" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044958]" type="box">34</container><container id="1b18cd2149455e567c6f8a9a0e64bc62" parent="935e82f2a6c085bfa99aec469d9b047d" type="folder">265</container></did><scopecontent id="44beecd082cead4655e1c9ca0d0beff5"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Request for contributions, declined. Mary French Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="04cb1b01f5484cc0b9f12d190f6d9349" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - United Hospital Fund - Contributions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1928/1936" type="inclusive">1928-1936</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="55a93dfef3bad500f9c06de859cba0c6" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044958]" type="box">34</container><container id="3591117051ebe51072212735317b56f9" parent="55a93dfef3bad500f9c06de859cba0c6" type="folder">266</container></did></c><c id="647498d2599740c6ba30f9418526eb85" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - United Hospital Fund - Contributions</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1961" type="inclusive">1940-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="f509284319c0a229ebff687c4c35df9f" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044958]" type="box">34</container><container id="95c385bbc5d4575f9ac0b6c8f068228d" parent="f509284319c0a229ebff687c4c35df9f" type="folder">267</container></did></c><c id="3ba6905a28c543339ee8ff62fc77101c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - United Hospital Fund - Hospital Building and Modernization</unittitle><unitdate normal="1957/1959" type="inclusive">1957-1959</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="6c1675b93a18a806c4479e6b4443b64b" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044958]" type="box">34</container><container id="e673b3156bf7251018a3e150c304e2d5" parent="6c1675b93a18a806c4479e6b4443b64b" type="folder">268</container></did></c><c id="87228fdd99cb4adf812414be6ef06965" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - United Hospital Fund - Clippings</unittitle><unitdate normal="1944/1959" type="inclusive">1944-1959</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="cbab31018152e862914db025f60d5bbf" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044958]" type="box">34</container><container id="e72f7103df03d1992368edd5a2851937" parent="cbab31018152e862914db025f60d5bbf" type="folder">269</container></did></c><c id="74afb53222a647319c40d7029972e93c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - White Plains Hospital</unittitle><unitdate normal="1937/1959" type="inclusive">1937-1959</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="8de2e4b8429de8a942f6b4c04db49387" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044959]" type="box">35</container><container id="911b870ddc0c7a7f032992d0cb3e66c0" parent="8de2e4b8429de8a942f6b4c04db49387" type="folder">270</container></did><scopecontent id="6af6d8584408a94be6b7b66c95a02fbe"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Request for contribution to hospital for White Plains; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declines because of his responsibility to Tarrytown hospital. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="789d3f6c0e244f16a1b9b19ab5817389" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Dr. Wilmer Foundation Hospital, Washington, DC</unittitle><unitdate normal="1923/1939" type="inclusive">1923-1939</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="88065c341ad5971fe45be9109884ecab" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044959]" type="box">35</container><container id="2398a5ac6ceaafb24835a3a9341c4e68" parent="88065c341ad5971fe45be9109884ecab" type="folder">271</container></did><scopecontent id="38faa60ea189eb3802c30fc422d92cd7"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>List of contributions and trustees of William Holland Wilmer Foundation; plans for model hospital to study diseases of the eye. Certificate of incorporation and by-laws; contribution from General Education Board; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s attempts to interest Henry Ford in making contribution. Correspondents include Henry Breckinridge, A. Flexner, Thomas B. Appleget, William H. Welch, Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.</p></scopecontent></c><c id="95f65750a4994d7299644acc88ea0dc8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hospitals - Women's and Children's Dispensary, Cleveland, Ohio</unittitle><unitdate normal="1899/1919" type="inclusive">1899-1919</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="31b15ecfcc9b84626fc21cb8b1720cc6" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044959]" type="box">35</container><container id="a5821c3ae72bc893b453472fb780bdd6" parent="31b15ecfcc9b84626fc21cb8b1720cc6" type="folder">272</container></did></c></c><c id="5a77470c0fc3494a8f3de918ee45de50" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Social Medicine</unittitle></did><c id="c3402b8e741444879e2c44dadcc97066" level="file"><did><unittitle>Social Medicine</unittitle><unitdate normal="1930/1961" type="inclusive">1930-1961</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="6261bb4edd3c85ab02dbb809569f0e91" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044959]" type="box">35</container><container id="4c5de491e1025bf25ab71744006e6b8c" parent="6261bb4edd3c85ab02dbb809569f0e91" type="folder">273</container></did><scopecontent id="58e8251aa89476e9a3cfed08960c5294"><head>Scope and Contents note</head><p>Suggested plans for financing medical care. No family interest expressed. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John Dr. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard.</p></scopecontent><fileplan id="bf103567bf3ccb154789c838484e536c"><head>File Plan note</head><p>210</p></fileplan></c></c><c id="fe2f6481159a42db880fdd780f4423b3" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Health Insurance Plan</unittitle></did><c id="f1624bd14cea4900b01700c4e64ebc82" level="file"><did><unittitle>Health Insurance Plan</unittitle><unitdate normal="1944/1958" type="inclusive">1944-1958</unitdate><container altrender="Letter Document Box" id="9da0439e7a5f4bc1bd193feaae76fef2" label="Mixed Materials [A0000000044959]" type="box">35</container><container id="9084d2bc2dfcd15825f9632dc637f659" parent="9da0439e7a5f4bc1bd193feaae76fef2" type="folder">274</container></did><fileplan id="da0a37d595564d964074ddcebbaaeacf"><head>File Plan note</head><p>210.1</p></fileplan></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
