<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xd="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/doc/xsl" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd" version="3.4">
  <identifier type="local">LI09704</identifier>
  <titleInfo>
    <title>The politics of culture :
policy perspectives for individuals, institutions, and communities</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name>
    <namePart>Bradford, Gigi</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="lcnaf">aut</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Gary, Michael</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="lcnaf">aut</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Wallach, Glenn</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" authority="lcnaf">aut</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="text">New York</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <publisher>New Press : Distributed by W.W. Norton</publisher>
    <dateIssued>2000</dateIssued>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <extent>1 Bound Volumes</extent>
  </physicalDescription>
  <note>Includes bibliographical references (p. 357-362)./ Funding: Made possible in part by a grant from the Nathan Cummings Foundation.</note>
  <abstract>Preface / James Allen Smith -- Introduction / Glenn Wallach -- Part I: Defining culture and cultural policy -- Introduction / Gigi Bradford -- Culture is ordinary / Raymond Williams -- Invoking culture: the messy side of "cultural politics" / Virginia R. Dominguez -- Social structure, institutions, and cultural goods: the case of the United States / Paul DiMaggio -- The arts and the public purpose / The American Assembly -- Creative America: a report to the President / President's Committee on the Arts and the Humanities -- Designing a cultural policy / Justin Lewis -- Policy communities and policy influence: securing a government role in cultural policy for the twenty-first century / Margaret Jane Wyszomirski -- Part II: Supporting Culture -- Introduction / Michael Gary -- Culture and the state in America / Michael Kammen -- A new mission for the NEA / Mary Schmidt Campbell -- Leverage lost: evolution in the nonprofit arts ecosystem / John Kreidler -- The age of audience / Lesley Valdes -- Pictures at an exhibition: conflicting pressures in museums and the display of art / Victoria D. Alexander -- Making change: museums and public life / Alberta Arthurs -- Coercive philanthropy / Robert Brustein -- The humanities, the universities, and public policy / William Bennett -- The artist as public intellectual / Carol Becker -- Commencement address: the gift of good work / Ellen McCulloch Lovell Part III: Culture and policy from the local to the global -- Introduction / Glen Wallach -- Judy Baca: SPARC-the Social and Public Arts Resource Center / William Cleveland -- Arts impact studies: a fashionable excess / Bruce A. Seaman -- Re-presenting the city: arts, culture, and diversity in Philadelphia / Mark J. Stern and Susan C. Seifert -- Cultural policy options in the contex of globalization / Néstor García Canclini -- The policy landscape / Susan L. Siegfried -- The new study and curation of culture / Richard Kurin.</abstract>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <geographic>United States</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Cultural policy</topic>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Rockefeller Foundation, Projects
Accession Number: 2012:073
Box: R3962
Folder: 2000 cc 151 (A12)2000 CC 151 R 3962</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <identifier type="isbn">1565845722</identifier>
  <genre>volume</genre>
  <classification>306.0973 BRA</classification>
</mods>
