<?xml version="1.0"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xd="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/doc/xsl" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd" version="3.4"><identifier type="local">LI09703</identifier><titleInfo><title>Crossroads :
art and religion in American life</title></titleInfo><name><namePart>Wallach, Glenn</namePart><role><roleTerm type="text" authority="naf">aut</roleTerm></role></name><name><namePart>Arthurs, Alberta</namePart><role><roleTerm type="text" authority="naf">aut</roleTerm></role></name><name><namePart>Center for Arts and Culture</namePart><role><roleTerm type="text" authority="naf">aut</roleTerm></role></name><name><namePart>Henry Luce Foundation</namePart><role><roleTerm type="text" authority="naf">aut</roleTerm></role></name><originInfo><place><placeTerm type="text">New York</placeTerm></place><publisher>New Press</publisher><dateIssued>2001</dateIssued></originInfo><physicalDescription><extent>1 Bound Volumes</extent></physicalDescription><note>Includes bibliographical references (p. [277-283]).</note><abstract> Abstract:	"In the first book to examine the relationship between these two sometimes complementary, sometimes competing major forces, Crossroads brings together a diverse collection of artists, religious leaders, journalists, and scholars in a series of explorations of where art and religion intersect.". "Under the auspices of the Center for Arts and Culture, the country's first arts and culture think tank, and the Henry Luce Foundation, scholars and authors including Neil Harris, Paul DiMaggio, Robert Wuthnow, and Amei Wallach explore topics ranging from art in American Protestantism and the role of spirituality in contemporary art, to the sometimes divergent missions of artistic and religious leaders, to major eruptions in Brooklyn, Philadelphia, and else-where when art and religion have refused to mix. Essays look behind the newspaper headlines and the numbers in public opinion polls to get a real glimpse at the significant place both art and religion inhabit in everyday life."--BOOK JACKET.Contents: Reluctant alliance: American art, American religion /; Neil Harris --; Arts leaders and religious leaders: mutual perceptions /; Robert Wuthnow --; Religious Americans and the arts in the 1990s /; Peter V. Marsden --; The role of religion in public conflicts over the arts in the Philadelphia area, 1965-1997 /; Paul DiMaggio, Wendy Cadge, Lynn Robinson, and Brian Steensland --; The controversy over the show Sensation at the Brooklyn museum, 1999-2000 /; David Halle --; Pictorial ambivalence and American protestantism /; Sally M. Promey.; Art, religion, and spirituality: a conversation with artists /; Amei Wallach.</abstract><subject authority="lcsh"><topic>Arts and society</topic></subject><subject authority="lcsh"><topic>Arts and religion</topic></subject><relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Rockefeller Foundation, Projects
Accession number: 2012:073
Box: R3962
Folder: 2000 cc 151 (A12)2000 CC 151 (A12) R3962</title></titleInfo></relatedItem><identifier type="isbn">1565846605</identifier><genre>volume</genre><classification>291.1 ART</classification></mods>
