<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid>FA1205.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper type="filing">Nelson A. Rockefeller gubernatorial records, Program Office, Series 26</titleproper>
        <titleproper>A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller gubernatorial records, Program Office, Series 26 <num>FA1205</num></titleproper>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline>
          <addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline>
          <addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2017-06-29 00:01:46 -0400</date>.</creation>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="series">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Nelson A. Rockefeller gubernatorial records, Program Office, Series 26</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname role="aut" source="lcnaf">New York (State). Governor (1959-1973 : Rockefeller)</corpname>
      </origination>
      <origination label="creator">
        <persname role="aut" rules="dacs">Draper, Edgar D.</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>FA1205</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6.2 Cubic Feet</extent>
        <extent altrender="carrier">14 LGL sized Hollinger boxes.</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1958/1968" type="inclusive">1958-1968</unitdate>
      <unitdate normal="1963/1967" type="bulk">bulk 1963-1967</unitdate>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="b4fbb3b039fd3c095e4d547efa4473b8">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of the RAC.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <prefercite id="0aff7d28a1411688267d98653f73c011">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>
    </prefercite>
    <scopecontent id="611bfd3519925796914cb18264cfd0aa">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>NOTE TO RESEARCHERS</p>
      <p>This series contains office files of Edgar D. Draper. They document official activities in the execution of his duties as a member of Rockefeller's staff. The actions, decisions, and exchanges of information or points of view documented here occurred in the course of proposing and implementing policies for the Rockefeller administration, political campaigns, and/or Rockefeller's personal activities. However, unless a document is specifically addressed to or from Nelson A. Rockefeller, or is referred to in a document addressed to him, it should not be assumed he saw the document or was aware of its existence or substance. Furthermore, researchers should bear in mind that staff files may contain documents or drafts addressed to Rockefeller that were never shown to him. </p>
      <p>SCOPE AND CONTENT </p>
      <p>This series documents the activities of New York State Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller's Program Office. It was created by Edgar D. Draper who served as Program Associate in Rockefeller's Executive Chamber. The contents of the series predominately concern education reform and development as well as national trends in Republican Party politics. Material formats include correspondence, memoranda, reports, press releases, pamphlets and other types of publications, newspaper clippings, copies of state and federal legislative bills, and transcripts of speeches and public addresses. In addition to Draper, chief correspondents found within the series include Secretary to the Governor Dr. William J. Ronan, Executive Officer to the Governor Alton G. Marshall, Commissioner of Education of the State of New York James E. Allen Jr., and Deputy Commissioner of Education Ewald B. Nyquist.       </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement id="f7cc9bfdbdad7c2cad88b56732ca6f2c">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>The series is arranged into 7 subseries. The subseries arrangement is as follows:</p>
      <p>1. Political files, 1964-1966</p>
      <p>2. Education files, 1959-1967</p>
      <p>3. Insterstate Compact for Education,1965-1968</p>
      <p>4. Long-Range Program Planning submisions, 1962-1966</p>
      <p>5. Program planning preparations and follow-up, 1958-1966</p>
      <p>6. Federal legislation, 1961-1966</p>
      <p>7. Conference materials, 1963-1965</p>
    </arrangement>
    <bioghist id="b84453c66449024fbd55eafd87620730">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>Nelson A. Rockefeller served as governor of New York from January 1, 1959, to December 18, 1973. He was the first person elected to four consecutive four-year terms as a state governor.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <bioghist id="55c8726af2d5b4af737a1b02c724fe40">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>Edgar D. Draper served as Program Associate in New York State Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller's Executive Chamber. He also represented the state of New York as a delegate at several meeting for the Interstate Compact for Education and its governing body, the Education Commission of the States.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <otherfindaid id="b019b3b35f37ad9a004357f4bb51921d">
      <head>Other Finding Aids</head>
      <p>Detailed finding aids for each series of this collection are available:</p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA353/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Appointments Office (FA353)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA354/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Assembly and Senate Memos (FA354)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA355/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Joseph H. Boyd (FA355)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA356/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, James Cannon (FA356)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA357/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Affirmative Action (N. Lee Cook) (FA357)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA358/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Counsel's Office (FA358)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA359/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York State Committee to Reelect the President (FA359)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA360/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Jerry A. Danzig (FA360)</extref>
        <extref href="../FA361/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Executive Chamber (FA361)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA362/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, 55th Street (FA362)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA363/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Issue Books (FA363)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA364/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Arthur Massolo (FA364)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA242/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Hugh Morrow (FA242)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA365/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York Office (FA365)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA366/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Civil Service Resolutions (Charles H. Palmer) (FA366)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA367/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Political Files (FA367)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA368/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Press Office (FA368)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA369/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Public Relations (FA369)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA370/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Departmental Reports (FA370)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA371/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, William J. Ronan (FA371)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA372/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Speeches (FA372)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA373/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Diane Van Wie (FA373)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA374/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Ann C. Whitman, Gubernatorial (FA374)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA375/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Gene Wyckoff (FA375)</extref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <extref href="../FA376/overview">Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York Republican State Fund Raising Reports (FA376)</extref>
      </p>
    </otherfindaid>
    <processinfo id="e6440c4113212d37f4e1214261ca74b6">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processing Level 3: Standard Processing</p>
    </processinfo>
    <processinfo id="a1be6973d85fa8d1c151f68e6264245d">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Darren Young June 2017.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <userestrict id="b57e51e9238103350d59d2f32e8b1fa9">
      <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
      <p>RAC users must abide by all applicable provisions of U.S. copyright law. Reproduction/duplication of archival items is routinely provided in accordance with "fair use." If the RAC does not hold copyright for an archival collection or items within a collection, it is the user's responsibility to contact the copyright holder, or make a fair effort to do so, prior to publication.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <acqinfo id="95e2cbd0103854b3d1e9fd31f4a55285">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
      <p>Donated to the Rockefeller Archive Center by Happy Rockefeller.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcsh">Adult education and state</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Civil rights</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Civil service</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Civil service -- New York (State)</subject>
      <subject source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">Education and state -- New York (State)</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Educational change</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Federal government -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Government aid to education -- New York (State)</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Government policy</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Higher education and state</subject>
      <subject source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">Interstate agreements</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Legislation -- New York (State)</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Minorities -- Education (Higher) -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Occupational training--United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Political campaigns -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Political parties</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Presidential candidates -- United States -- History -- 20th century</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Program budgeting</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Public policy</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Science -- Study and teaching</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Speeches, addresses, etc.</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">State governments -- United States</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">State universities and colleges</subject>
      <subject source="lcsh">Tuition -- Education, Higher -- United States</subject>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c id="6fefa91dbe603bea4f69051618e41cb5" level="subseries">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Political files</unittitle>
          <unitid>1</unitid>
          <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Cubic Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">About 2.5 LGL sized Hollinger Boxes</extent>
          </physdesc>
          <unitdate normal="1964/1966" type="inclusive">1964-1966</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="cb9f564cb34ee8ced7dd0ff41e4c8aff">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>The contents of the subseries primarily pertain to Nelson A. Rockefeller's political record and achievements as New York State Governor, the tensions and shifts within the Republican Party at the time of the 1964 Presidential Election, Rockefeller's meetings with New York town and county community leaders, and Rockefeller's discontinued run for the Republican Party nomination in the 1964 election. General political records include the correspondence of Program Associate Edgar D. Draper, lists of commitments made by Rockefeller in regards to the activities of various state programs, and transcripts of speeches and interviews by Rockefeller and other individuals. Many of the records discuss the relationship between the Republican Party and the African American community in connection to the Civil Rights Movement and the Republican Party's 1964 presidential candidate, Arizona Senator Barry Goldwater. The subseries includes a transcript of a public statement by Rockefeller in which he discusses the outcome of the election and calls for a constructive rebuilding of the party. Materials related to Rockefeller's various town and county visits throughout the state of New York include memoranda, schedules, lists of key community leaders, and reports providing background information and points of local interest for each meeting location. These documents are loosely organized by the town or county they concern. Records related to Rockefeller's run for Republican Party presidential nominee include correspondence, reports, statements, and pamphlets as well other miscellaneous campaign materials. Several documents originate from the campaigns of other nomination candidates as well as from the larger Republican Party platform. Lastly, the subseries contains a small amount of documents related to John V. Lindsay's campaign for New York City Mayor in 1965.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="66376d8c078f82f4fd315794e9ae46f6" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>General political records</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1964/1964">1964</unitdate>
            <container id="758c8f62dd8a10915d6160e2cd617241" label="mixed materials (A0000000079637)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="12ff6c490175edfba0f710245224d068" parent="758c8f62dd8a10915d6160e2cd617241" type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="241fb24921d6fd20720e7c6ad2bdbf31" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>General political records</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="b9d8382f91e1605ce5d6e027f145299d" label="mixed materials (A0000000079637)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="ea3d7b7cdd2373a3b6ea58b8bf044d4f" parent="b9d8382f91e1605ce5d6e027f145299d" type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="aab03c4e194646eecab5343d29d404ce" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>General political records</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="19040df499cb5b074757230296068bed" label="mixed materials (A0000000079637)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="1e0a6b361b2458902ee9e47a7eb11cd3" parent="19040df499cb5b074757230296068bed" type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="4763e1b0981b4cbd28555a4369a4410f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>John V. Lindsay New York City mayoral campaign white papers</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="a5a24351a3436e10566cd5cf7d0caf31" label="mixed materials (A0000000079637)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="46b6ae13948800cc196263632dfd4b7c" parent="a5a24351a3436e10566cd5cf7d0caf31" type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="b2f788fb326834bd81a30e0db2ce8a6e" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>NAR town meetings</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="a149bbb091dd3971ee89184054fa8694" label="mixed materials (A0000000079637)" type="box">1</container>
            <container id="07dd8dc09076560311d2602db1395d5e" parent="a149bbb091dd3971ee89184054fa8694" type="folder">5, 6, 7, 8</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="5e65ab92cc684e039227e6ac10096991">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Towns and counties represented within this file include:</p>
            <p>1) Harlem; 2) Brooklyn; 3) Queens; 4) The Bronx; 5) City of Buffalo and Niagara and Erie Counties; 6) City of Syracuse and Onondaga County; 7) City of Utica and Oneida County; 8) Jamestown and Olean; 9) Albany; 10) City of Plattsburgh and Clinton County. Other miscellaneous towns and counties are also represented within the file.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <separatedmaterial id="d1347495902ee7d05a9845f7bcbc2c29">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Materials separated from file pending relocation to flat file, reformatting, or preservation treatment:</p>
            <p>1) Fax about Syracuse public elementary schools - Folder 7
2) Fax about Utica public schools - Folder 7
3) Fax about Jamestown-Olean area - Folder 7
4) Fax about Anti-Poverty Program in Albany County - folder 8</p>
          </separatedmaterial>
        </c>
        <c id="304cf0df51c26301b1165b7c9a2f8f88" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>NAR town meetings</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1966" type="inclusive">1965-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="39cd2789f0b1809261da871684442999" label="mixed materials (A0000000079638)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="6d4ed0a77349d65eb74069985019aa34" parent="39cd2789f0b1809261da871684442999" type="folder">9, 10, 11, 12</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="9f59b0766af46816ea6111988a8b84fc">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Towns and counties represented wihtin this file include:</p>
            <p>1) Nassau and Suffolk Counties; 2) City of Binghampton and Broome County; 3) City of Buffalo and Erie County; 4) City of Rochester and Monroe County 5) Rockland and Westchester Counties. Other miscellaneous towns and counties are represented within the file.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <separatedmaterial id="e5ec8bd81c57f7f485ae4d9bc6061c54">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Materials separated from file pending relocation to flat file, reformatting, or preservation treatment:</p>
            <p>1) Fax about Rochester public elementary schools - Folder 11</p>
          </separatedmaterial>
        </c>
        <c id="eb596653c07ffc63abb021ce8d5ca152" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>NAR town meetings</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="049f213416b6219e82f71a91e3b74b43" label="mixed materials (A0000000079638)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="ded14b7edf38b0c683c8c00449917c3c" parent="049f213416b6219e82f71a91e3b74b43" type="folder">13,14,15,16</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="c9f29e95867504815ffc59b106dbdeef">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Towns and counties represented within this file include:</p>
            <p>1) St. Lawrence County; 2) Harlem; 3) Cortland and Tompkins Counties; 4) Montgomery, Fulton, and Monroe Counties; 5) Auburn, Newark, and Geneva; 6) Oswego and Jefferson Counties; 7) City of New York and Duchess and Ulster Counties; 7) Saratoga Springs and Glen Falls. Other miscellaneous towns and counties are also represented within the file.   </p>
          </scopecontent>
          <separatedmaterial id="2a22f02ae7b1688cd7f1ee920fb0f5b8">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Materials separated from file pending relocation to flat file, reformatting, or preservation treatment include:</p>
            <p>1) Fax about Poughkeepsie and Kingston - Folder 15</p>
          </separatedmaterial>
        </c>
        <c id="b50a3aa35a9216866bd92d1cac8ee1e6" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>NAR town meetings briefings</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="d3ff858aa231c94ece6b425ce319d735" label="mixed materials (A0000000079638)" type="box">2</container>
            <container id="ddd07144ad18f577e5fda17ff3a12bd0" parent="d3ff858aa231c94ece6b425ce319d735" type="folder">17, 18, 19</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="fe5732ec437ae20f8d5b61e499f4bef5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>NAR United States presidential campaign correspondence and reports</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1963/1964" type="inclusive">1963-1964</unitdate>
            <container id="4af49f81ccb510b89bdbefa749dd9f45" label="mixed materials (A0000000079639)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="86d832f158e20a12c23a2192edb7e250" parent="4af49f81ccb510b89bdbefa749dd9f45" type="folder">20</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="85236ed170b6dbd44a88fb492fcf361c">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>File contains a letter addressed from Edgar D. Draper to retired Baseball player Jackie Robinson. The letter discusses the comments of several African American participants on David Susskind's television program "Open End" about the Republican Party. Draper asks Robinson if he thinks it is advisable to arrange a meeting where they can discuss suggested Republican Party outreach to the African American community. Robinson served as one of Nelson A. Rockefeller's national campaign directors for the 1964 Presidential Election.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <separatedmaterial id="1ac10b3a4080216d91ac44e730ad2316">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Materials separated from file pending relocation to flat file, reformatting, or preservation treatment include:</p>
            <p>1) Virginian Pilot press clipping</p>
          </separatedmaterial>
        </c>
        <c id="44a5589ef98e74e2b1899373e5d9c6f3" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>NAR United States presidential campaign statements, brochures, and other promotional materials</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1964/1964">1964</unitdate>
            <container id="4eec989be4d6a0dc8d00e347e522395a" label="mixed materials (A0000000079639)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="2e4fa0e7587d2f5a31e13244f0ed8563" parent="4eec989be4d6a0dc8d00e347e522395a" type="folder">21, 22, 23, 24</container>
          </did>
          <separatedmaterial id="55b5e8b7cad0fdd5a98d70d50a02343c">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Materials separated from file pending relocation to flat file, reformatting, or preservation treatment include:</p>
            <p>1) New York Times press clippings - Folder 21</p>
          </separatedmaterial>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="78a342ac9604a5a8e9725d6f45703e6e" level="subseries">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Education files</unittitle>
          <unitid>2</unitid>
          <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.5 Cubic Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">About 3.5 LGL sized Hollinger boxes</extent>
          </physdesc>
          <unitdate normal="1959/1967" type="inclusive">1959-1967</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="dfed850fa2388e14c930c018b6d4eb9b">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This subseries documents matters related to New York State funding for education as well as to attempts at education reform and development by Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller's Executive Chamber, the New York State Education Department, and other local, state, and national organizations concerned with education policy and institutions. Much of the education reform discussed in the subseries involves expansion of education opportunities to minority and disadvantaged populations, increased medical and health professional training in response to the state's Medicaid program, and improved programs for science and technology learning. Several files concern state and national education policy in a broad sense. These files include correspondence, reports, and other materials related to legislation and performance of state education programs, background information on the proposed Pennsylvania Plan property tax law, and multistate collaboration on education policy through the activities of the Interstate Compact for Education. A large part of the subseries specifically pertains to higher education policy and development with a particular focus on funding for the City University of New York. These materials include transcripts of addresses by various education and city officials before a Joint Legislative Committee on Education on March 22, 1966, CUNY budget information, correspondence concerning Rockefeller's support for the City University Supplementary Aid and Construction Bill, and a number of draft letters Program Associate Edgar D. Draper created when preparing Rockefeller's official responses to calls for greater state aid to CUNY. This subseries also includes tabulations of monetary amounts distributed by the state for college scholarships in the academic years 1958-1959 and 1964-1965.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="929bd50dbe73972dc5c919a6c6895e54" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>General education program records</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1966" type="inclusive">1965-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="e8dabd1417f015895c149f103623d978" label="mixed materials (A0000000079639)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="da028b9038e37f0dbc5d04be42fee315" parent="e8dabd1417f015895c149f103623d978" type="folder">25</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="621dd5ceb8cfafefe11279fe4e9b7661" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>General education program records</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966-01/1966-04" type="inclusive">January 1966-April 1966</unitdate>
            <container id="5665adb4aab85b4a431997f3c6891f53" label="mixed materials (A0000000079639)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="e1db09de8a103f016364b2948f9384db" parent="5665adb4aab85b4a431997f3c6891f53" type="folder">26, 27, 28</container>
          </did>
          <separatedmaterial id="223cf1032ddb8a5b66a21fec8bebc70b">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Materials separated from file pending relocation to flat file, reformatting, or preservation treatment include:</p>
            <p>1) Faxes about nonwhite in-migrant pupils in New York City schools - Folder 27
2) Faxes about primary and secondary education and students that have migrated into the state - Folder 27</p>
          </separatedmaterial>
        </c>
        <c id="07bbb7d0b03b5ae0b7fd9864d2875949" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>General education program records</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966-05/1966-06" type="inclusive">May 1966-June 1966</unitdate>
            <container id="1e4a74ecd554d0852c71dbaa5173b9fd" label="mixed materials (A0000000079639)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="03cf4a953b4bdc7570f1a3b5276a90ef" parent="1e4a74ecd554d0852c71dbaa5173b9fd" type="folder">29</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="7a6082204f713ad7b1d348b152104cf3" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Correspondence and press releases related to adult education</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="2177f61f1c85995324d71f68a336117b" label="mixed materials (A0000000079639)" type="box">3</container>
            <container id="037879e561c1f124580c643d83f577ab" parent="2177f61f1c85995324d71f68a336117b" type="folder">30</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="3aa9cc7da6ef89b7a826aa68a110e430" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>NAR address before the New York State League of Women Voters</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="43d7edcb4f5575af2bcdb2c08c1f5df6" label="mixed materials (A0000000079640)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="a24143048f1fb82023464e1234d4ac4c" parent="43d7edcb4f5575af2bcdb2c08c1f5df6" type="folder">31</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="950697c7dbf6b9af5e26c7b2054cae85" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>NAR statements on education</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1964/1964">1964</unitdate>
            <container id="556d572520a8364749d965094c41df17" label="mixed materials (A0000000079640)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="45ad51f1e8418326fc193d70c44423a9" parent="556d572520a8364749d965094c41df17" type="folder">32, 33</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="c24550f9b3df571265a0537990568c9f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>NAR statements on education</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1964/1966" type="inclusive">1964-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="699e1ed0c6e728639effc91a9f7c8c6c" label="mixed materials (A0000000079640)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="83818e9a1c2ce2cec87b86e195877fb7" parent="699e1ed0c6e728639effc91a9f7c8c6c" type="folder">34</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="779407db8db37af4074804840c2e7105" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>New York State education and departmental white papers </unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1959/1966" type="inclusive">1959-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="5eeb7674a799415c68ab0fcecb589baa" label="mixed materials (A0000000079640)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="5a6fb608d1462b6e6beec17b7299b1a4" parent="5eeb7674a799415c68ab0fcecb589baa" type="folder">35</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="436de840515049dbf0d5693741d61484" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>New York State Joint Legislative Committee on Higher Education recommendations and statements</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="c4ebaa34e0c80c2523fb687a6b7faa77" label="mixed materials (A0000000079640)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="8356be9dd27dc31046f467b39fc95b99" parent="c4ebaa34e0c80c2523fb687a6b7faa77" type="folder">36</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="f37593d8afe446726366829d1a5b07d9" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>New York State Legislature Rules Report No. 595</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="136d5f47b71bbbb5918f38db70f68488" label="mixed materials (A0000000079640)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="d1d23b0be7dc4fbc96735b63319d13ba" parent="136d5f47b71bbbb5918f38db70f68488" type="folder">37</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="2bb8b50ae1a5831ed023d8a40732d8ad" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Appropriations and budget information related to City University of New York</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1963/1966" type="inclusive">1963-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="4c585c8d097f7c4569caa5ccb6ae2b25" label="mixed materials (A0000000079640)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="3078315c44d0c6c76e80cb7d4a4b41cd" parent="4c585c8d097f7c4569caa5ccb6ae2b25" type="folder">38, 39</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="c5e06b6e8e31a9c7a04596e53446b0f6" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Correspondence and reports related to City University of New York</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="1448e7afbc3e16554e8b30ab1023376c" label="mixed materials (A0000000079640)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="da4ce18c42e0d8461c6e627ac5bfa3ea" parent="1448e7afbc3e16554e8b30ab1023376c" type="folder">40</container>
          </did>
          <separatedmaterial id="26a25c24087a89f509af70a4719e09c2">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Materials separated from file pending relocation to flat-file, reformatting, or preservation treatment include:</p>
            <p>1) Fax about CUNY Income Fund Act</p>
          </separatedmaterial>
        </c>
        <c id="ac7c0bfef70f7bdc5ad3730b0e389356" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Draft NAR position statements and letter responses related to City University of New York</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="d746db687bbd36c8a3e835917110c6af" label="mixed materials (A0000000079640)" type="box">4</container>
            <container id="351a5800b7df355facc093d859526018" parent="d746db687bbd36c8a3e835917110c6af" type="folder">41</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="0b38272fd99b5034d69fab8fd9d7cdb6" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Recommendations and statements related to City University of New York</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="2d14f9c0fddd7422b6dc2f3d91bc3e94" label="mixed materials (A0000000079641)" type="box">5</container>
            <container id="ea3bf0275559c395524648cce935f072" parent="2d14f9c0fddd7422b6dc2f3d91bc3e94" type="folder">42, 43</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="76bb65925c5a606f81aaaad6aaee82d2" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Comparative tabulations for New York State aid for higher education</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="82c3d4f1641d1537b873f7f279c0ce4d" label="mixed materials (A0000000079641)" type="box">5</container>
            <container id="f95f30b1b64086f358ead32a4196bdcb" parent="82c3d4f1641d1537b873f7f279c0ce4d" type="folder">44, 45, 46</container>
          </did>
          <separatedmaterial id="bccb9c195b56b1a44318aa4ce3b205ad">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Materials separated from file pending relocation to flat file, reformatting, or preservation treatment include:</p>
            <p>1) List of New York State cities and villages - Folder 45
2) Draft chart of state aid tabulations - Folder 45
3) Draft tabulations - Folder 46
4) College Master File - Folder 46
5) Draft list for tabulations - Folder 46</p>
          </separatedmaterial>
        </c>
        <c id="81838d87b02f5d32a0997fbaf08b2256" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Correspondence related to tabulations for New York State aid for higher education</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="92a5cf5f1675ed270e7b00fd38d34a88" label="mixed materials (A0000000079641)" type="box">5</container>
            <container id="f0caab8f9c775a2b89b00c4cb9ec906b" parent="92a5cf5f1675ed270e7b00fd38d34a88" type="folder">47</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="88a1ed86ccd1cc7edf742cb74842f078" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>New York State Education Department correspondence and reports</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="0102d7f2da9c0c2c78330e9e7048b738" label="mixed materials (A0000000079641)" type="box">5</container>
            <container id="ea29a673c5a16dc80e694c94dc35ea82" parent="0102d7f2da9c0c2c78330e9e7048b738" type="folder">48, 49, 50</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="54e8b1d828c5c37462b2ede0cbf4feb5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Correspondence and reports related to State University of New York</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="cb29a935b0c3657482b070baa09c7d50" label="mixed materials (A0000000079642)" type="box">6</container>
            <container id="385cda070a489c26c7568f21aa6fb479" parent="cb29a935b0c3657482b070baa09c7d50" type="folder">51</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="a555fde6d5b85ffd3c5355e429d4f375" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>State University of New York Construction Fund models and sketches</unittitle>
            <unitdate certainty="inferred" normal="1966/1966">circa 1966</unitdate>
            <container id="83248f07973bd552c61e137565f9bab0" label="mixed materials (A0000000079642)" type="box">6</container>
            <container id="d359758523cfcd1fdb126e25c76e0ecb" parent="83248f07973bd552c61e137565f9bab0" type="folder">52</container>
          </did>
          <separatedmaterial id="b14bbb0830b1f5789a51278c68e5b5fd">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Materials separated from file for preservation treatment include:</p>
            <p>1) SUNY model renderings and sketches</p>
          </separatedmaterial>
          <accessrestrict id="66ba89476320325f58c15ce29435134e">
            <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
            <p>Entire file is resticted until preservation actions are carried out on items.</p>
          </accessrestrict>
        </c>
        <c id="eabc2f9d2c932da133c6f8ed532ff90b" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Records related to higher education in general</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1964/1966" type="inclusive">1964-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="9d9f2e6c955c31a81a7c8fc4497fc2a5" label="mixed materials (A0000000079642)" type="box">6</container>
            <container id="c456e107b4abfc707b12eb0ca9620358" parent="9d9f2e6c955c31a81a7c8fc4497fc2a5" type="folder">53</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="7b3b72c5f4865c0728d640304b5d0f67" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Records related to higher education in general</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966-01/1966-06" type="inclusive">January 1966-June 1966</unitdate>
            <container id="da58c8ea69a3dd70326b1014c5fd58af" label="mixed materials (A0000000079642)" type="box">6</container>
            <container id="c8ce30168777aaf4e1100bc2b369908e" parent="da58c8ea69a3dd70326b1014c5fd58af" type="folder">54</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="deedc8620c346225736bea20aff34952" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Records related to health professionals' education</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="bfd08a42a0554435a670633d75fd52ee" label="mixed materials (A0000000079642)" type="box">6</container>
            <container id="f0fe052dbb564fa894aac4e2793777df" parent="bfd08a42a0554435a670633d75fd52ee" type="folder">55</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="fbd7fa367535cb838c51125afda2e587" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Records related to medical education </unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="99b05ab129d6dbb025a86d0e89075611" label="mixed materials (A0000000079642)" type="box">6</container>
            <container id="bf2bb2f4cf32ee446b2a4a7c083292b7" parent="99b05ab129d6dbb025a86d0e89075611" type="folder">56</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ebee09d438f2f559404df53097202fa7" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Correspondence and reports related to state and national education organizations</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="328e81fb77b4e493e53e38d32a3592bb" label="mixed materials (A0000000079642)" type="box">6</container>
            <container id="1b8e54d8e795a7a78571245d642d6db9" parent="328e81fb77b4e493e53e38d32a3592bb" type="folder">57, 58</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="43641f1f7e7cc90c33be4c86e7ef0e9f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>New York State Science and Technology Foundation correspondence, reports, and press releases</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1964/1967" type="inclusive">1964-1967</unitdate>
            <container id="c3b175400fc8743efa0baa856ac61a2b" label="mixed materials (A0000000079642)" type="box">6</container>
            <container id="2db37ea4e3fdd347ef1d9da3721eebc3" parent="c3b175400fc8743efa0baa856ac61a2b" type="folder">59, 60</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="f71631b27226fabe658d1848c50e37c5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>New York State Science and Technology Foundation correspondence, reports, and press releases</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="d59730ec2d536eed4674ec1ac0bcc622" label="mixed materials (A0000000079642)" type="box">6</container>
            <container id="a5c214cab4575cebad4c585bc7f4dce7" parent="d59730ec2d536eed4674ec1ac0bcc622" type="folder">61</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="53cbcf1833074ba3f88cde309e1f3940" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Records related to elementary and secondary education, general</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="da435883a397fa79d1ea9f15da42b7f4" label="mixed materials (A0000000079642)" type="box">6</container>
            <container id="a40addeefa2e030f92769c91f501b0f8" parent="da435883a397fa79d1ea9f15da42b7f4" type="folder">62, 63</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="af792fb60050b61ad5d50eb2433dd35f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Records related to elementary and secondary education, New York City public schools</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="a64b00b81f8c38712f4d4f6acf7fa25b" label="mixed materials (A0000000079643)" type="box">7</container>
            <container id="fd2ceddc433a63d5e4fb25a250be854a" parent="a64b00b81f8c38712f4d4f6acf7fa25b" type="folder">64</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="57c1cd494670a68f8f73e5441e550ec2" level="subseries">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Interstate Compact for Education</unittitle>
          <unitid>3</unitid>
          <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.25 Cubic Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">About 3 LGL sized Hollinger boxes</extent>
          </physdesc>
          <unitdate normal="1965/1968" type="inclusive">1965-1968</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="de19117eb282a3571963b56cd26c6fe6">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This subseries documents the involvement of Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller's administration in the origins and activities of the Interstate Compact for Education and its governing body, the Education Commission of the States. Much of the content found within the subseries pertains to different planning, interim, and annual meetings of the Compact and Commission. These records primarily consist of conference programs, reports, lists of attendees, meeting minutes, agendas, transcripts of addresses, and promotional materials related to both the actual meetings and the cities that hosted the meetings.  The subseries also contains correspondence, press clippings, and transcripts of public speeches that relate to the Compact in a broader sense. The correspondence compiled by Rockefeller's Program Associate, Edgar D. Draper, chiefly concerns the list of delegates Rockefeller selected to represent the state of New York at different meetings of the Education Commission of the States. Lastly, the subseries contains several copies of the Compact for Education summary, copies of the Compact's Enabling Act, copies of New York State legislative bills related to the state joining the Compact, a copy of the Education Commission of the States Bylaws, and drafts and copies of other resolutions passed by the Compact.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="9bde42f072bfb0b85422712326b52479" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>General correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1967" type="inclusive">1965-1967</unitdate>
            <container id="50069040ca5963ade8e800ce821a1cb3" label="mixed materials (A0000000079643)" type="box">7</container>
            <container id="857d674302890526a1337909b09f1a0f" parent="50069040ca5963ade8e800ce821a1cb3" type="folder">65, 66, 67, 68</container>
          </did>
          <separatedmaterial id="bcd1125664c1751399e72a69ddfe9011">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Materials separated from file pending relocation to flat file, reformatting, or preservaiton treatment include:</p>
            <p>1) Fax of draft letter to James E. Allen Jr. - Folder 68</p>
          </separatedmaterial>
        </c>
        <c id="6506abb4e86c19bc1e3ca8c9c4c52bd0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Compact for Education Enabling Act and bills for New York State adoption</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1967" type="inclusive">1965-1967</unitdate>
            <container id="eb3e07e8cd87ff3796f9b445b4deb079" label="mixed materials (A0000000079643)" type="box">7</container>
            <container id="f544a65b74591b52c2cb2ebd50c07c35" parent="eb3e07e8cd87ff3796f9b445b4deb079" type="folder">69, 70</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="2eed325010ee821e15dffb6272187ea1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Education Commission of the States Bylaws and other Compact for Education resolutions</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="200f2a5b1765d50758e5dacf0472acbc" label="mixed materials (A0000000079643)" type="box">7</container>
            <container id="acf72b9843abdcbe3f42ae2b2ca9f494" parent="200f2a5b1765d50758e5dacf0472acbc" type="folder">71</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="1c345e92f28b8364b2b9683850eadfee" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Education Commission of the States publications and reports</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1967" type="inclusive">1966-1967</unitdate>
            <container id="f91524e77f07cc686d9171a6db74cf41" label="mixed materials (A0000000079643)" type="box">7</container>
            <container id="b76457e10d1b0f692e6b0aa9fdbda899" parent="f91524e77f07cc686d9171a6db74cf41" type="folder">72, 73</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="f0da849cda93a64d05abb9fab4f79393">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>This file contains three publications printed by the Education Commission of the States: </p>
            <p>1) "Power Play for Control of Education" - a copy of the edited proceedings of the Commission's 1967 Annual Meeting; 2) Vol.1 No.7 of "Compact" - a monthly journal publication by the Commission; 3) "Seven Critical Issues in Education: Alternatives for State Action" - a collection of papers discussing education problems. </p>
            <p>This file also includes one summary report published by the New York State Department of Education about a multistate education conference that was titled "To Strengthen State-Local Relationships in Urban Education". Other types of documents such as correspondence and newspaper clippings were originally interspersed throughout the publications. They are currently housed with the publications with which they were originally attached.   </p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c>
        <c id="ad9689fc54ae3281a0260705723bcc06" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Compact for Education Planning Conference, Kansas City, Missouri, lists and proceedings</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="95c4f0c7e429b897afa61f36e3b45466" label="mixed materials (A0000000079644)" type="box">8</container>
            <container id="514efd7bc3459106ba7c369e72353412" parent="95c4f0c7e429b897afa61f36e3b45466" type="folder">74</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="fd17b1f4f1c81ff1917c1c14630d0e22" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Compact for Education Planning Conference, Kansas City, Missouri, programs and promotion</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="3c4e7d3bdc7034564cd1ad1e55a71247" label="mixed materials (A0000000079644)" type="box">8</container>
            <container id="546856e758e843c155095c3d74f454fe" parent="3c4e7d3bdc7034564cd1ad1e55a71247" type="folder">75</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="58a18bbc123104d2b0051c6d7c30f7fb" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Compact for Education Planning Conference, Kansas City, Missouri, duplicates: Lists, agendas, and reports</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="e9b49683d727a1564600e14df48ee309" label="mixed materials (A0000000079644)" type="box">8</container>
            <container id="3191b512106bfba9cff90ab7eee3a330" parent="e9b49683d727a1564600e14df48ee309" type="folder">76</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="e71ef3e0fa27c7540881c366d47e9e80" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Compact for Education Planning Conference, Kansas City, Missouri, duplicates: Reports and addresses</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="bbe8beb5d46c19cd10f75a6d656ede72" label="mixed materials (A0000000079644)" type="box">8</container>
            <container id="45ac150b19ea689cf30d352abc39ef63" parent="bbe8beb5d46c19cd10f75a6d656ede72" type="folder">77</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="d333476f477703434e08f5200c39210d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Compact for Education Interim Planning Meeting, Santa Fe, New Mexico</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="aa9b87a396900dfe04402267eb05b9bf" label="mixed materials (A0000000079644)" type="box">8</container>
            <container id="2f0a87e56ba6619a7b998317d2b32690" parent="aa9b87a396900dfe04402267eb05b9bf" type="folder">78</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="7189a9aa206085c535911cbb85564cec" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Education Commission of the States First Annual Meeting, Chicago, Illinois</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="d14c170de3cf0b12c77278b39f4fe35e" label="mixed materials (A0000000079644)" type="box">8</container>
            <container id="d8c236bd3edda1cf9eea5e96f66ad046" parent="d14c170de3cf0b12c77278b39f4fe35e" type="folder">79</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="a403a288db0dfd6323c10398f4e4e86d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Education Commission of the States First Annual Meeting, Chicago, Illinois, duplicates: Lists and addresses</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="e6c3dcb820d81668d2032a4a6675c023" label="mixed materials (A0000000079644)" type="box">8</container>
            <container id="5d8edeed8c152370b2d68ee187c22b7d" parent="e6c3dcb820d81668d2032a4a6675c023" type="folder">80</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="6f74abc6392b4fe6c6512996e60e724e" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Education Commission of the States First Annual Meeting, Chicago, Illinois, duplicates: Minutes, resolutions, and recommended studies</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="41c63d231b7115df7a3790bf0472ea20" label="mixed materials (A0000000079644)" type="box">8</container>
            <container id="3793307947337ddcd38c57235ea66003" parent="41c63d231b7115df7a3790bf0472ea20" type="folder">81, 82</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="31f495bf697c2e3a8a51d9523edae319" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Education Commission of the States Second Annual Meeting, Denver, Colorado</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1967/1967">1967</unitdate>
            <container id="409cb794d6205d933295952e5d0168a1" label="mixed materials (A0000000079645)" type="box">9</container>
            <container id="077626e7c92d6ef78e868f3ac75b386d" parent="409cb794d6205d933295952e5d0168a1" type="folder">83, 84</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="c50a4ea3a497287ed7f7cd744bb75688" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Education Commission of the States Steering Committee Meeting, Hilton Head, South Carolina</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1967/1967">1967</unitdate>
            <container id="f526ff12b31313b23ccc714719eb36fb" label="mixed materials (A0000000079645)" type="box">9</container>
            <container id="b59758f5886d5142bdf6c9841a42b48d" parent="f526ff12b31313b23ccc714719eb36fb" type="folder">85, 86</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="07b685845e874ab7df5785caaa0d1d58" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Education Commission of the States Third Annual Meeting, Denver, Colorado</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1968/1968">1968</unitdate>
            <container id="a476ed99f690f5cf235139a3bee0db57" label="mixed materials (A0000000079645)" type="box">9</container>
            <container id="cbcb54d4e074c50334dce597818fabac" parent="a476ed99f690f5cf235139a3bee0db57" type="folder">87, 88</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="73f594eac8d97193f20924b8fce606bc" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Addresses and speeches related to Compact for Education</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="243953b838b8404446fdcc7ca7e30845" label="mixed materials (A0000000079645)" type="box">9</container>
            <container id="de22a033b851b3a152da2b22bf8a2bfb" parent="243953b838b8404446fdcc7ca7e30845" type="folder">89</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="f3c09dbf832b22c2a2d8ae5299ac8c8d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Press clippings related to Compact for Education</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1966" type="inclusive">1965-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="c6c70c1a324069fbb5622652e72888b9" label="mixed materials (A0000000079645)" type="box">9</container>
            <container id="5814bef9eb8c5880a182002327baaea2" parent="c6c70c1a324069fbb5622652e72888b9" type="folder">90</container>
          </did>
          <separatedmaterial id="85530368b0024ac6eeadcaf7d28cd90e">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Materials separated from this file pending relocation to flat file, reformatting, or preservation treatment include:</p>
            <p>1) Kansas City Times press clippings</p>
          </separatedmaterial>
        </c>
        <c id="8c512921f3da131664692a51c9437eee" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous and duplicates</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1966" type="inclusive">1965-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="d749c088070700f3256ce70ac4e32f2b" label="mixed materials (A0000000079645)" type="box">9</container>
            <container id="de284619e1ccb3c4243757481ce97927" parent="d749c088070700f3256ce70ac4e32f2b" type="folder">91, 92</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="2d48a004fb00ae0f53909cdd58d06c96">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>File contains duplicates of items primarily found within the file "Compact for Education Enabling Act and bills for New York State adoption" as well as miscellaneous documents not found within the rest of the subseries. These documents chiefly relate to the operations of the Compact.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="3b67a1b1c0b64f7d87f3c7318bb0719a" level="subseries">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Long-Range Program Planning submissions</unittitle>
          <unitid>4</unitid>
          <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.75 Cubic Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">About 2 LGL sized Hollinger boxes</extent>
          </physdesc>
          <unitdate normal="1962/1966" type="inclusive">1962-1966</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="8ef57be819862a249640743168676958">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>This subseries contains a small group of Long-Range Program Plans submitted by the New York State Commission for Human Rights, the New York State Education Department, and the New York State Division for Youth. According to the Guidelines and Instructions for Preparation of Long-Range Program Planning Submissions, agencies were required to compile this data in order to assist the New York State Division of the Budget in determining annual budget needs and in identifying the long-term impact of State programs. The Guidelines identify the expansion of state government and the developments in federal assistance programs as reasons for the need of a more systematic approach by the State in coordinating the program plans of individual agencies. A copy of these Guidelines, prepared by the Division of the Budget, is included with the subseries. Not all plans appear to be complete, but their individual components have been grouped together in the files in order to represent their contextual relationship.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="4632146d61dc5afc45cbb2bf0d5c7c91" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Division of the Budget guidelines for Long-Range Program Planning submissions</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="ea658fd8391a3a49c3876698fd9bf9cd" label="mixed materials (A0000000079646)" type="box">10</container>
            <container id="08a2e89bfe52d8f97779e82d7b544df0" parent="ea658fd8391a3a49c3876698fd9bf9cd" type="folder">93</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="0e398896f106d6ee61a2f4db68aeed0b" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Commission for Human Rights</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1962/1965" type="inclusive">1962-1965</unitdate>
            <container id="dafdceb70558fb566de8f358964acbcc" label="mixed materials (A0000000079646)" type="box">10</container>
            <container id="d713753a1b39c4c26f186f78e92ee92a" parent="dafdceb70558fb566de8f358964acbcc" type="folder">94</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="f817eb46ada5568dc53ac3ffd1382187">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>In addition to the Long-Range Program Planning submission by the Commission for Human Rights, this file also contains a small pamphlet about New York State programs and legislation for advancing civil rights.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c>
        <c id="235ecad2da60a79b823aa44328a85cdd" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Education Department</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="d6a4f4eddeda3722ae54db799f7134e4" label="mixed materials (A0000000079646)" type="box">10</container>
            <container id="b9c7d943a9caa6faafff139e5d3b5cec" parent="d6a4f4eddeda3722ae54db799f7134e4" type="folder">95, 96, 97, 98, 99</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="f964e4ee9e624cfd10e3b1379e92e4ce">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>File contains all Long-Range Programming Plans compiled for the year 1965</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c>
        <c id="c354af7acb68fbd0455a033e7ab9e704" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Education Department</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="4f2f00b8113753a4dedd4401d506bcbf" label="mixed materials (A0000000079647)" type="box">11</container>
            <container id="d3ba64cdaee21b489ecc097e483ac95d" parent="4f2f00b8113753a4dedd4401d506bcbf" type="folder">100, 101, 102, 103, 104</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="8da828d2bf056358d52b5dc59d01ae1e">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>File includes Long-Range Programming Plans for: </p>
            <p>1) Center on Innovation in Education; 2) Vocational Rehabilitation; 3) Elementary, Secondary, and Continuing Education; 4) Research and Evaluation; 5) Cultural Education and Special Services; 6) Regents Examination and Scholarships Center; 7) Educational Finance and Management Services.  </p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c>
        <c id="d9cc3673b87c6b716ab43781702d2c92" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Division for Youth</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="1e61c605dd32f785c02ab6eb65b40908" label="mixed materials (A0000000079647)" type="box">11</container>
            <container id="c8a49c455305b7967c399535f6b85fde" parent="1e61c605dd32f785c02ab6eb65b40908" type="folder">105, 106</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="542f95acfe5d42b63a0c1688a20b171c">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>File contains Long-Range Programming Plans for: </p>
            <p>1) Municipal Delinquency Prevention; 2) Facilities Program; 3) Research; 4) Administration; 5) Exhibits; 6) Departmental Summary</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c>
        <c id="3bdd592821b73ca070364cd419964981" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Division for Youth</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="6bba39d632f06ef2d2aa8826e0c6ffd4" label="mixed materials (A0000000079648)" type="box">12</container>
            <container id="2738c8eba9a0dbfa68b2fc940e229517" parent="6bba39d632f06ef2d2aa8826e0c6ffd4" type="folder">107, 108</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="8c68fcf4460349636164d99f922f4f75">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>File includes Long-Range Programming Plans for: </p>
            <p>1) Administration and Research; 2) Facilitites Program; 3) Local Assistance Program.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="44e0c8ebd8b328b3174bb5263b656b86" level="subseries">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Program planning preparations and follow-up</unittitle>
          <unitid>5</unitid>
          <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.25 Cubic Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">About .5 LGL sized Hollinger box</extent>
          </physdesc>
          <unitdate normal="1958/1966" type="inclusive">1958-1966</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="1bcd4044437aabcd770dc0e82e79cdbe">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Records within this subseries chiefly pertain to the development of New York State government long-term program planning, the planning processes of different State agencies, and the program planning follow-up documentation and measures prepared by Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller's Program Associate Edgar D. Draper and other State staff members. Draper's copy of a program planning follow-up log is included. Handwritten notes have been added to this copy as well as correspondence concerning a follow-up program related to public educational television and the hearings for the 1965 Long-Range Program Planning submissions of the New York State Division for Youth, the New York State Education Department, and the New York State Commission for Human Rights. Other follow-up correspondence and reports included within the subseries pertains to a follow-up program about recruitment and training for professional State jobs.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="11440675ec90aa11f21ab17de0ccc076" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Materials related to Long-Range Program Planning preparations</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1958/1964" type="inclusive">1958-1964</unitdate>
            <container id="a8240c836ee9e4b4a7df2a08c6ee9463" label="mixed materials (A0000000079648)" type="box">12</container>
            <container id="e67d8467bb4ed1d8a62381ccecdfe6c6" parent="a8240c836ee9e4b4a7df2a08c6ee9463" type="folder">109</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="eeb1150b76b7d880b47a11958601d277" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Program Planning Follow-up log</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="b76f3cb7a5745135dc8cfe1bec133a84" label="mixed materials (A0000000079648)" type="box">12</container>
            <container id="43086a30203da8ff752e323b345cf413" parent="b76f3cb7a5745135dc8cfe1bec133a84" type="folder">110</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="30b2506dc7036d8e93ccea326dbb8020" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Program Planning Follow-up correspondence and reports</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="389a2cc033a79d23696cdacface218dd" label="mixed materials (A0000000079648)" type="box">12</container>
            <container id="b2af183144138cdd73cbbcda9605c61c" parent="389a2cc033a79d23696cdacface218dd" type="folder">111, 112</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="ffc52a0ac98327675a315789ee036b4a" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Program Planning Follow-up correspondence and reports</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate>
            <container id="a6b78a8a66df1283122770aebc46b18a" label="mixed materials (A0000000079648)" type="box">12</container>
            <container id="338124946d01fccb0d24085df2e8b471" parent="a6b78a8a66df1283122770aebc46b18a" type="folder">113</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="dab2ffbd8ca59906c924974d9bd6bd53" level="subseries">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Federal legislation</unittitle>
          <unitid>6</unitid>
          <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.25 Cubic Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">About .5 LGL sized Hollinger box</extent>
          </physdesc>
          <unitdate normal="1961/1966" type="inclusive">1961-1966</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="1a309e767f36bfb4027d6dd2e58825e8">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Subseries contains copies of federal legislative bills. These bills concern such subjects as education, school prayer, youth employment and delinquency, voting rights and other civil rights matters, hospital insurance, physical and mental health, manpower development, area redevelopment, poverty, Appalachia, and library services. Handwritten notes have been added to several of the bills.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="9f20c71a29ca7a33980a1541ae1f3cd6" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bills</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1961/1966" type="inclusive">1961-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="f030f2f5d0769cc4f9f2c22a327759ce" label="mixed materials (A0000000079648)" type="box">12</container>
            <container id="261c1b7cbe2034cf97cf8c4712cc6392" parent="f030f2f5d0769cc4f9f2c22a327759ce" type="folder">114, 115</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="9018072665f9316930c6cdaec755650c" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bills</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1963/1964" type="inclusive">1963-1964</unitdate>
            <container id="cdd30e4dad1964988ab4b95cdcebff7e" label="mixed materials (A0000000079648)" type="box">12</container>
            <container id="e3c9b50c949533855bb57af92181099d" parent="cdd30e4dad1964988ab4b95cdcebff7e" type="folder">116</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="3a84baaa8332cadfa72338e14c15694a" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bills</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1963/1966" type="inclusive">1963-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="7d14d7d001b50f42e6d8797c655adad2" label="mixed materials (A0000000079649)" type="box">13</container>
            <container id="26919da34c14a1fa1ab7146b541ddf8e" parent="7d14d7d001b50f42e6d8797c655adad2" type="folder">117</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="33c4d7aeb1d4ad8d086adfaf0d2094ba" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bills</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1963/1966" type="inclusive">1963-1966</unitdate>
            <container id="9cc1ffb45092f8e90451fb4507e6bd71" label="mixed materials (A0000000079649)" type="box">13</container>
            <container id="acfd9536a5c97415c3622269b430ef2a" parent="9cc1ffb45092f8e90451fb4507e6bd71" type="folder">118</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c id="d610ca41a5e989af489baf1f18e94c35" level="subseries">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Conference materials</unittitle>
          <unitid>7</unitid>
          <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.75 Cubic Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">About 1.5 LGL sized Hollinger boxes</extent>
          </physdesc>
          <unitdate normal="1963/1965" type="inclusive">1963-1965</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="8a6da8b8e45b7f2274b25b50db782107">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Materials found within this subseries pertain to a number of regional, state, and national conferences as well as to the different social, education, economic, and political subjects those conferences concerned. In the course of his duties as Program Associate for Nelson A. Rockefeller's Executive Chamber, Edgar D. Draper attended several of the conferences documented in the subseries. He also worked with other State government staff to prepare background information for Rockefeller's participation at other conferences and to help organize conferences set up by the State and Rockefeller's administration. Files in the subseries primarily pertain to individual conferences, but there are a few that group together documents concerning a number of different conferences on a particular theme such as industry. Common material formats found within the subseries include correspondence, invitations, schedules, programs, press clippings, and reports.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c id="6c6c22b1de95728d918d78d72d3003c8" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Governor's Conference on Aging</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate>
            <container id="09d986df52565664477f4996b0f1427e" label="mixed materials (A0000000079649)" type="box">13</container>
            <container id="1eb82f487a318c817b20e71db284ca87" parent="09d986df52565664477f4996b0f1427e" type="folder">119</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="4a2654a631e61ab79e4d518ca742028f" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Governors' Conference</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1964/1964">1964</unitdate>
            <container id="f0a8d3b53a5506467452d54b436a100b" label="mixed materials (A0000000079649)" type="box">13</container>
            <container id="8fdba7bdbf9d42207f960decddab9523" parent="f0a8d3b53a5506467452d54b436a100b" type="folder">120</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="57111fd36b453babaed80872120ae5d1" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Governors' Conference</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="35ce1ca31002b6760aaee47502ac3845" label="mixed materials (A0000000079649)" type="box">13</container>
            <container id="5283752f4e0d794a87a2b2f7ca50f201" parent="35ce1ca31002b6760aaee47502ac3845" type="folder">121, 122</container>
          </did>
          <separatedmaterial id="e95a3d1c4c49f3e114582514ebb6d844">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Materials separated from this file pending relocation to flat file, reformatting, or preservation treatment include:</p>
            <p>1) Fax about the role of the States in education - Folder 122</p>
          </separatedmaterial>
        </c>
        <c id="22273263de0be5a8374ce23f85bd76d6" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>National Negro Republican Assembly</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="5a3f270a5bd445c875afd68140465984" label="mixed materials (A0000000079649)" type="box">13</container>
            <container id="ba0af8a34dc429fefe3cab1390fd4f9e" parent="5a3f270a5bd445c875afd68140465984" type="folder">123</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="d40a11dd8edea2f4b366704ef2469be0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>New York State Citizens Committee for the Public Schools 13th Annual Conference</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1963/1965" type="inclusive">1963-1965</unitdate>
            <container id="889e811d64aaf5928afc45c3a02883f8" label="mixed materials (A0000000079649)" type="box">13</container>
            <container id="9650a82b6de4083eab275522e975fb70" parent="889e811d64aaf5928afc45c3a02883f8" type="folder">124, 125</container>
          </did>
          <separatedmaterial id="5ce0377495897e3847b41f97efe60334">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Materials separated from file pending relocation to flat file, reformatting, or preservation treatment include:</p>
            <p>1) Buffalo press clippings about school funding - Folder 124
2) Newsday's Back to School Report - Folder 125</p>
          </separatedmaterial>
        </c>
        <c id="c28d69f1664bc615fdd7d4c1589f076d" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>New York State Citizens Committee for the Public Schools 14th Annual Conference</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="28a6274bc1fa91073a05ddffc45672a9" label="mixed materials (A0000000079650)" type="box">14</container>
            <container id="af61d44416da8a1eaeac39bf136f1ca9" parent="28a6274bc1fa91073a05ddffc45672a9" type="folder">126</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="f1ae30c94ffec00f72aa629291899549" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>New York State conferences on CUNY College Discovery Program and community colleges</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1964/1964">1964</unitdate>
            <langmaterial id="b6583b1516d3da51a574ea5aeb6984f0">Most materials in English. Some documents have Spanish translations. </langmaterial>
            <container id="7527b23e830f693a1b1e2ddabd7e8093" label="mixed materials (A0000000079650)" type="box">14</container>
            <container id="f8c9e22bb30a3344388ff4c4bf17bb87" parent="7527b23e830f693a1b1e2ddabd7e8093" type="folder">127</container>
          </did>
          <separatedmaterial id="8f3b601a17552be479bc5d81ed6d298e">
            <head>Separated Materials</head>
            <p>Materials separated from file pending relocation to flat file, reformatting, or preservation treatment include:</p>
            <p>1) December 1964 issue of the "Communicator" 
2) April 1964 issue of the "Communicator"</p>
          </separatedmaterial>
        </c>
        <c id="898e411741ec8ff170a37947d753e0c6" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>New York State conferences on education</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1963/1965" type="inclusive">1963-1965</unitdate>
            <container id="f50ce1f47539f12721a3fbfed8101c05" label="mixed materials (A0000000079650)" type="box">14</container>
            <container id="b670e36bea44c0c36281f8deaf9459c0" parent="f50ce1f47539f12721a3fbfed8101c05" type="folder">128</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="b053352ac078d005d585bf86d3443ba6">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>In addition to documents concerning conferences on education, this file also contains materials related to an invitation for a Playboy Club Key application.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c>
        <c id="f5f1b864b94ca30f227ac2dab1470d0e" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>New York State conferences on industrial growth</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate>
            <container id="342531b8d4dd9958d373fbaf9a726fbd" label="mixed materials (A0000000079650)" type="box">14</container>
            <container id="ee0f8da402337aafc02157960c32dcbd" parent="342531b8d4dd9958d373fbaf9a726fbd" type="folder">129, 130</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="f078b61be2b01f928feb9d1a14b23875" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Western New York Invitational Conference on Asia</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1964/1964">1964</unitdate>
            <container id="76ea948f7b6b883648862782a9f44af4" label="mixed materials (A0000000079650)" type="box">14</container>
            <container id="cf25eca96863ec0221da30375f99c6b0" parent="76ea948f7b6b883648862782a9f44af4" type="folder">131</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c id="4c5805a92329f034d0b49117c52946ff" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>White House Conference on Education</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate>
            <container id="606b7c4e7116c474c65a6ddf9c24f47c" label="mixed materials (A0000000079650)" type="box">14</container>
            <container id="30bc027869445a8bbdc81437509b46e5" parent="606b7c4e7116c474c65a6ddf9c24f47c" type="folder">132</container>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
