<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid>FA667.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society, Office Files of Urvashi Vaid</titleproper><titleproper>A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society, Office Files of Urvashi Vaid
 <num>FA667</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Rockefeller Archive Center</publisher><address><addressline>15 Dayton Avenue</addressline><addressline>Sleepy Hollow 10591</addressline><addressline>archive@rockarch.org</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.rockarch.org" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-03-29 00:43:14 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Rockefeller Archive Center</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society, Office Files of Urvashi Vaid</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="aut" source="naf">Vaid, Urvashi</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname role="aut" rules="dacs" source="nad">Ford Foundation</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>FA667</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.62 Cubic Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1992/2005" type="inclusive">1992-2005</unitdate>
    <abstract id="e03c4a689c64ac29131d20fb78dd2e0a">The Office Files of Urvashi Vaid, Deputy Director of the Ford Foundation's Governance and Civil Society (GCS) unit from 2001-2005, document her oversight of grants to support citizens' groups working for social and economic justice, to strengthen civil society organizations and to improve government performance. The bulk of the records pertain to the Collaborations that Count Initiative. The collection spans the years 1992-2005 and consists of correspondence, memoranda, reports, grant proposals, meeting materials and publications. There are substantial records that document grant work prior to Vaid's tenure, including files created by former GCS staff members Michael Lipsky and June Zeitlin, and GCS Director Michael Edwards. The files were transferred to the Ford Foundation Archives in August 2005. The arrangement of the collection follows the original order maintained by Vaid, though a few unfoldered and stray items have been interfiled by the processing archivist.</abstract>
  </did>
  <prefercite id="4d8b5617851bce98a9cb0d4d13042896">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Information regarding the Rockefeller Archive Center's preferred elements and forms of citation can be found at <extref href="http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php">http://www.rockarch.org/research/citations.php</extref></p>  </prefercite>
  <userestrict id="1b86f6c59ac9776195bce33296f7615b">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Completion of a use agreement is required prior to providing scholarly access. See RAC Head of Reference (or applicable designee) for details. </p><p>Ford Foundation holds title, copyright and literary rights in the collection, in so far as it holds them. The Rockefeller Archive Center has authority to grant permission to cite and publish material from the collection for scholarly purposes. Permission to publish extensive excerpts, or material in its entirety, will be referred to the Ford Foundation.</p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="4e67fa7d04d6c2587e0e5832fa63c4c2">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="2e1bb0cefe015a0480a054cc3fb8c007">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged in the following series and subseries:</p><p>Series I. Collaborations That Count, 1998-2005</p><p>Subseries A. State Collaborations, 1998-2005
Grant proposals, grantee reports, correspondence, memoranda, publications and other materials documenting activities funded by the Ford Foundation in the eleven states targeted by the initiative. Files are arranged alphabetically by state name.</p><p>Subseries B. Ancillary Organizations, 1998-2003
In addition to providing direct funding for eleven state-based collaborations, the 
Ford Foundation gave over $5.2 million to organizations that provided technical assistance, research, training and other services to the project. Files pertaining to these grants contain memoranda, correspondence and reports and are arranged alphabetically by organization name.</p><p>Subseries C. Administration and Evaluation, 1998-2004
Subseries includes project planning memos and reports, requests for proposals, regional meeting agendas and materials, publicity material, evaluation planning proposals and a copy of the final project evaluation, "Power, Participation and State-based Politics" (2004). Files are arranged alphabetically by subject.</p><p>Series II. Subjects, 1992-2005 
Records concerning a variety of Ford Foundation activities, including grant initiatives, conferences, program officer meetings and Trustee trips. There is a substantial file containing memos and correspondence pertaining to the State Fiscal Analysis Initiative. Several folders document meetings of program officers from the Civil Society unit with staff from other program areas to discuss shared strategies and themes for grantmaking (Box 2, Folders 18, 19, 22). There are also briefing books and related materials pertaining to trips to Alabama and China by Ford Foundation Trustees who served on the Peace and Social Justice Committee. The files are arranged alphabetically by subject.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="e2e31713951fc61a7723ec866cef2e75">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Office Files of Urvashi Vaid document grant-making by the Ford Foundation's Governance and Civil Society and Governance and Public Policy programs during the period 1992-2005. The collection measures two linear feet and is contained in two record cartons. The bulk of the records relate to the Collaborations that Count project, 1998-2004. The files contain correspondence, memoranda, reports, grant proposals and meeting materials. There are substantial records that document grant work prior to Vaid's tenure, including files created by former GCS staff members Michael Lipsky and June Zeitlin, and GCS Director Michael Edwards.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist id="3ff69f75a80481ea2867530516ce3124">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Social activist, attorney and foundation executive Urvashi Vaid was born in India in 1958 and moved to the United States when she was eight years old. She became politically active at age eleven by participating in marches protesting the U.S. war against Vietnam. Vaid attended Vassar College on an academic scholarship and graduated in 1979 with a bachelor's degree in English and political science. She then spent three months as a volunteer intern with the Women's Prison Project and worked as a legal secretary and administrative assistant for a Boston law firm. During the early 1980s, Vaid helped found the Boston Lesbian/Gay Political Alliance and the Allston-Brighton Greenlight Safehouse Network, an anti-violence neighborhood project. Vaid attended the Northeastern University School of Law, and received a J.D. degree in 1983. From 1983-1986, Vaid worked for the American Civil Liberties Union's National Prisons Project, where she conducted class action lawsuits to improve conditions in American prisons. She then joined the staff of the National Gay and Lesbian Task Force, serving as Media Director (1986-1989), Executive Director (1989-1992), and Policy Institute Director (1997-2000).</p><p>Vaid joined the Ford Foundation in 2000 as a Program Officer, and in January 2001 was appointed Deputy Director of the Governance and Civil Society program. A major emphasis of her work was the Collaborations that Count initiative, which was launched in 1998 to support cooperation among state-level organizations working for social and economic justice. Vaid also played a role in the State Fiscal Analysis Initiative, and oversaw grants to support gay, lesbian, bisexual and transgender rights organizations. Vaid left the Ford Foundation in 2005 to head the Arcus Foundation.</p><p>Vaid is author of Virtual Equality: The Mainstreaming of Gay &amp; Lesbian Liberation (Anchor, 1996), and is co-editor, with John D'Emilio and William Turner, of Creating Change: Public Policy, Sexuality and Civil Rights (St. Martin's Press, 2000).  </p><p>
The Governance and Civil Society unit was established as part of a significant reorganization of the Ford Foundation during 1996-1997. The program incorporated much of the work and staff of the former Governance and Public Policy unit, and at its inception aimed "to improve governmental performance and accountability, stimulate new approaches to designing and implementing public policies, and enhance the role of civic organizations, particularly philanthropies, in promoting democratic values." (Ford Foundation Annual Report, 1996) </p><p>Collaborations that Count, originally known as the "Devolution Initiative," was launched by GCS in 1998. During the mid-1990s federal funds and decision-making power for many U.S. government social programs were transferred to the state and local level. To succeed in this new political environment, state-based public policy and civil society groups needed to develop new leadership skills, broaden membership, enhance organizational infrastructures and work together more effectively. Towards these ends, Collaborations that Count provided over $18 million in funds to support cooperative projects in Alabama, Idaho, Kentucky, Mississippi, Nevada, North Carolina, Oregon, South Carolina, Tennessee, Texas and Washington. Public policy and social issue groups in these states formed new coalitions that organized conferences and workshops, developed staff training programs, improved technology access, commissioned research and reached out to the public. Specific issues addressed by collaborators included welfare and tax reform, immigrant rights, healthcare access, affordable housing and racial justice. Significant policy outcomes linked to the work of Collaborations that Count-supported groups included minimum wage and labor contract reforms (Idaho), food stamp reform (Oregon) and increased funding for education (Mississippi).</p><p>In her role as Deputy Director for Ford Foundation GCS work, Urvashi Vaid coordinated  Collaborations that Count during 2001-2004.</p>  </bioghist>
  <relatedmaterial id="8e6feee85db2953c7a7e75715dbeb343">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>FA592 Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society, Deputy Director, Office Files of Urvashi Vaid, 1982-2005.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <accessrestrict id="8943f09ae7f698d38e2a3c366267c7c6">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <dsc><c id="e814bd2a0ad34a68aec3225bf29bcfc2" level="series"><did><unittitle>Collaborations that Count</unittitle><unitid>I</unitid><unitdate normal="1998/2005" type="inclusive">1998-2005</unitdate></did><arrangement id="71112d59559d1ddd9491e1da13bb62ba"><head>Arrangement</head><p>This series is arranged into 3 subseries.</p></arrangement><c id="5afbb66b9a7e42759b211c5bb3a0bb1e" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>State Collaborations</unittitle><unitid>A</unitid><unitdate normal="1998/2005" type="inclusive">1998-2005</unitdate></did><arrangement id="c5413123d8784da2435570b37c466f5b"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Files are arranged alphabetically by state name.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="4572b6f61366faf7203b48670ca6c540"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Grant proposals, grantee reports, correspondence, memoranda, publications and other materials documenting activities funded by the Ford Foundation in the eleven states targeted by the initiative.</p></scopecontent><c id="f39a4d264893496ab1f8a70e40b97237" level="file"><did><unittitle>Alabama: Alabama Organizing Project</unittitle><unitdate normal="1999/2001" type="inclusive">1999 - 2001</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="6d895c0989cb78ce83196e3f799ec77a" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="957fdcd99f0dd562de0b782f5484966b" parent="6d895c0989cb78ce83196e3f799ec77a" type="folder">1</container></did></c><c id="374b6c3eccb04238a46bb14b424ea689" level="file"><did><unittitle>Idaho: The Idaho Collaborative</unittitle><unitdate normal="1998/2002" type="inclusive">1998 - 2002</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="5af0e393d9a9376d1691acf24f016760" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="2b5d00d651b3ee2b78f88930d77b5c97" parent="5af0e393d9a9376d1691acf24f016760" type="folder">2</container></did></c><c id="3f790b08f42d4b76966859a66a6fcd69" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kentucky: Kentucky Economic Justice Alliance</unittitle><unitdate normal="1998/2004" type="inclusive">1998 - 2004</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="87869ee163c097c83bda5cd7e8aa1cc8" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="78ea9725a0752ff89c845b149aad0e17" parent="87869ee163c097c83bda5cd7e8aa1cc8" type="folder">3</container></did></c><c id="97a63e4263ae48f8b0591ed53d5da919" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mississippi: Mississippi Education Working Group – Southern Echo, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1998/2003" type="inclusive">1998 - 2003</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="f7089a8c3a563bdecae7e51ce00e7d1b" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="675580d40a001c0e354c572d60d66829" parent="f7089a8c3a563bdecae7e51ce00e7d1b" type="folder">4</container></did></c><c id="308bc27f080a4dbbbcb78f8d4f02190d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nevada: Progressive Leadership Alliance of Nevada</unittitle><unitdate normal="1998/2005" type="inclusive">1998 - 2005</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="5124cb014aa7f2f5689758bb186e0200" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="e3c9525a912ea31883a53c4b851d4e47" parent="5124cb014aa7f2f5689758bb186e0200" type="folder">5</container></did></c><c id="3a146ff32e22471f973cceb9a08952c1" level="file"><did><unittitle>North Carolina: North Carolina Alliance for Economic Justice</unittitle><unitdate normal="1998/2002" type="inclusive">1998 - 2002</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="3d73ca92fe5fb14eafc487acbd4e7f51" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="8f4594f3fda99c66c098b7d95c2849d4" parent="3d73ca92fe5fb14eafc487acbd4e7f51" type="folder">6</container></did></c><c id="d0c213aa2dd74fb3b8e6a74878223314" level="file"><did><unittitle>Oregon: The Oregon Collaborative – Rural Organizing Project</unittitle><unitdate normal="1998/2002" type="inclusive">1998 - 2002</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="4f89003bf343b81012b0dd681b8a727f" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="5291ea9c4ecdb89af41fc32a1694cfbf" parent="4f89003bf343b81012b0dd681b8a727f" type="folder">7</container></did></c><c id="b6653e45967a44bcbb9a8e65798dea56" level="file"><did><unittitle>South Carolina: South Carolina Policy and Organizing Project – Carolina Alliance for Fair Employment (CAFE)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1998/2003" type="inclusive">1998 - 2003</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="1060e0deaadbc98e2ff239f3752752b4" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="f56c3192289fc97496007a5c16c00ada" parent="1060e0deaadbc98e2ff239f3752752b4" type="folder">8</container></did></c><c id="92aeef515e1e4df48f7896f0e0d7f5fd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tennessee: Tennessee Partnership on Organizing and Public Policy – Save Our Cumberland Mountains</unittitle><unitdate normal="1998/2002" type="inclusive">1998 - 2002</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="17285ccc1cfad77db1060855f5e87594" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="cea18f311d409f013a618b63601cde5b" parent="17285ccc1cfad77db1060855f5e87594" type="folder">9</container></did></c><c id="357dda0ca4df49079e3fffd53b9d58f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Texas: ProTex: Network for a Progressive Texas</unittitle><unitdate normal="1998/2002" type="inclusive">1998 - 2002</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="eb00b77f54ba95c77b1d351bff28342d" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="b3cd0a81915c1e2632c120b250f0fd96" parent="eb00b77f54ba95c77b1d351bff28342d" type="folder">10</container></did></c><c id="76dae8e46bb9403d9b2e031b4d51be88" level="file"><did><unittitle>Washington: Washington Living Wage Movement – Washington Association of Churches</unittitle><unitdate normal="1998/2005" type="inclusive">1998 - 2005</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="e74f923208cf7ec00c0c9eabb4815df5" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="039bc4afb0c290d7de09e5cb9593d803" parent="e74f923208cf7ec00c0c9eabb4815df5" type="folder">11</container></did></c></c><c id="9861bd9b3b7042d6be9d06813a4fc366" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Ancillary Organizations</unittitle><unitid>B</unitid><unitdate normal="1998/2003" type="inclusive">1998-2003</unitdate></did><arrangement id="29f9b724ee0158642d25aa804f61a31c"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically by organization name.</p></arrangement><scopecontent id="22356cfc7e7b1ce290c4cfba5d79b8bd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>In addition to providing direct funding for eleven state-based collaborations, the Ford Foundation gave over $5.2 million to organizations that provided technical assistance, research, training and other services to the project. Files pertaining to these grants contain memoranda, correspondence and reports.</p></scopecontent><c id="824de353e1104dc4893c585a82e46483" level="file"><did><unittitle>Alliance for Justice</unittitle><unitdate normal="1998/2002" type="inclusive">1998 - 2002</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="f60c0743e4348bb1e1d3b3445f1ab1e4" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="5fe8a708e8dacc3be9a392c995d1ea80" parent="f60c0743e4348bb1e1d3b3445f1ab1e4" type="folder">12</container></did></c><c id="c08fb8461665400dbc8ac1a815114ace" level="file"><did><unittitle>Community Resource Exchange</unittitle><unitdate normal="2001/2002" type="inclusive">2001 - 2002</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="e06f37781be0e259a5013275d688226b" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="00202bbc0ff2cd784e61f1322377d88e" parent="e06f37781be0e259a5013275d688226b" type="folder">13</container></did></c><c id="67ea495162c740248e996267cee11835" level="file"><did><unittitle>Creative Communications</unittitle><unitdate normal="1998/2000" type="inclusive">1998 - 2000</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="9e4be55fe13aaa43ead28b5b43bf78a0" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="84b4eb3ecb0c062ac4ac1cdde4b115e5" parent="9e4be55fe13aaa43ead28b5b43bf78a0" type="folder">14</container></did></c><c id="c3b21b784fbf4313a9a7c7b9c97adfe1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Education Resources Group</unittitle><unitdate normal="1999/2000" type="inclusive">1999 - 2000</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="786b3bbd0927a727a9f6fa9de8cc5794" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="797e79b5c09af0b06d00aec79000383d" parent="786b3bbd0927a727a9f6fa9de8cc5794" type="folder">15</container></did></c><c id="9b49163fefab4ff2bd1aafe26b53ab9c" level="file"><did><unittitle>John J. Koprowski &amp; Associates, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1999/1999" type="inclusive">1999</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="4896dcf4e14958bcc513434de2d8a8e9" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="01655784bc8e8fff287ca3abe3f125bc" parent="4896dcf4e14958bcc513434de2d8a8e9" type="folder">16</container></did></c><c id="2ba01ec700644da39b8e4d66d0813999" level="file"><did><unittitle>Northwest Federation of Community Organizations</unittitle><unitdate normal="2002/2003" type="inclusive">2002 - 2003</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="4bb1b59f9d576831ad3a892139ff9030" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="78e174dc19e00b6ccaf9bc7a20118beb" parent="4bb1b59f9d576831ad3a892139ff9030" type="folder">17</container></did></c><c id="4c55013ea03642489de8d3d3612790b4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Progressive Technology Project</unittitle><unitdate normal="1999/2000" type="inclusive">1999 - 2000</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="ce126196264eae6d534d8a6cf2335c72" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="fb17e11543f4e159c7e93b1cf41a165d" parent="ce126196264eae6d534d8a6cf2335c72" type="folder">18</container></did></c><c id="ffcbd7702c914e8fa37acc2040701cdc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Southern Partners Fund</unittitle><unitdate normal="2000/2001" type="inclusive">2000 - 2001</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="a76afdb30c6bc6c1a3a67d0239f703ac" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="7711b38873e7890ec56ec5992b2fea26" parent="a76afdb30c6bc6c1a3a67d0239f703ac" type="folder">19</container></did></c><c id="fe3f715838904d4082aa161b72cac849" level="file"><did><unittitle>Western States Center</unittitle><unitdate normal="1999/2001" type="inclusive">1999-2001</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="54be0289b4deb8ad1b3d96ea76e6ff80" label="mixed materials [A0000000089675]" type="box">1</container><container id="a986f73c2930d06b6b30902e5c13819c" parent="54be0289b4deb8ad1b3d96ea76e6ff80" type="folder">20</container></did></c></c><c id="c46aa18c37d94d3ead53e3527a113579" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Administration and Evaluation</unittitle><unitid>C</unitid><unitdate normal="1998/2004" type="inclusive">1998-2004</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="8bcb0859a9290e1ebafdfa1026390b5c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Subseries includes project planning memos and reports, requests for proposals, regional meeting agendas and materials, publicity material, evaluation planning proposals and a copy of the final project evaluation, "Power, Participation and State-based Politics" (2004).</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="a2a0d77ba141b8f0b42b1a72a57c978e"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Files are arranged alphabetically by subject.</p></arrangement><c id="12236907dc0e4f7caa283eea2db8a9fa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Devolution Initiative</unittitle><unitdate normal="1998/1999" type="inclusive">1998 - 1999</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="98cab983e2bb9036100d252cdce0414f" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="8cea14db2663acf04d59bf623e982818" parent="98cab983e2bb9036100d252cdce0414f" type="folder">1</container></did></c><c id="08ea4b0bc049414c834b495443731187" level="file"><did><unittitle>Devolution Team Binder</unittitle><unitdate normal="1998/1998" type="inclusive">1998</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="7f8f866a6e5292bc2b7f90c4f238c92a" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="b40a1948e483a1c798d06b47b07f7da0" parent="7f8f866a6e5292bc2b7f90c4f238c92a" type="folder">2</container></did></c><c id="02b3a49ff78c459a9893b7e2e82eb303" level="file"><did><unittitle>Evaluation briefing</unittitle><unitdate normal="2004/2004" type="inclusive">2004</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="7805196b601b8eedc2b70163319341a6" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="c396e52edbef7a470cbb086f54fd5693" parent="7805196b601b8eedc2b70163319341a6" type="folder">3</container></did></c><c id="6dd0ef2ce35e4c6c8bea0cc2ba5a9c52" level="file"><did><unittitle>Evaluation report – Applied Research Center. "Power, Participation and State-based Politics"</unittitle><unitdate normal="2004/2004" type="inclusive">2004</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="a0fb09fd27663d1d3d4b95b0dba95692" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="92e250aaaf0c639c0aaa33ce759bb6c3" parent="a0fb09fd27663d1d3d4b95b0dba95692" type="folder">4</container></did></c><c id="efbed7e3efa9450e88134944a3292056" level="file"><did><unittitle>Evaluation proposals</unittitle><unitdate normal="2001/2004" type="inclusive">2001 - 2004</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="09cb51642bb470361545f3a94cc911ea" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="aec2277642c516b90c9670a02364a5dc" parent="09cb51642bb470361545f3a94cc911ea" type="folder">5</container></did></c><c id="59ca6193e0854315acfeb6dcc4c11749" level="file"><did><unittitle>Foundation Administered Project (FAP) grant</unittitle><unitdate normal="2001/2001" type="inclusive">2001</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="dd73b126c10e5afe03ecd4b450c4e9a3" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="e9dd392d12db325c0d3a4b5d762b2e7f" parent="dd73b126c10e5afe03ecd4b450c4e9a3" type="folder">6</container></did></c><c id="cef0bd7df2524e41b9819b8792b0f219" level="file"><did><unittitle>Initiative Statement</unittitle><unitdate normal="2002/2002" type="inclusive">2002</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="fa2fa86f0af84a1cc7eb85e0f95b8263" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="db98eb32a444a48d17d1ac88a9987fa6" parent="fa2fa86f0af84a1cc7eb85e0f95b8263" type="folder">7</container></did></c><c id="2cdcb01bb6bc414b82f1b7155eaab242" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Meeting</unittitle><unitdate normal="1998/2001" type="inclusive">1998, 2001</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="0bae6c425bcf51608f2a0b989d4a462c" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="9424c397d458129585d9a812431054ac" parent="0bae6c425bcf51608f2a0b989d4a462c" type="folder">8-9</container></did></c><c id="7f38d0a76b1b460bac57fa53cb7401bc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Northwest Regional Meeting</unittitle><unitdate normal="2000/2001" type="inclusive">2000 - 2001</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="900bb887200b309a08cee30125740630" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="e496423a8944d1a5689ad4857740eb81" parent="900bb887200b309a08cee30125740630" type="folder">10</container></did></c><c id="b08b5d596d7e49818d290df528060834" level="file"><did><unittitle>Publicity material</unittitle><unitdate normal="1998/2000" type="inclusive">1998 - 2000</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="68467651c330ae2218e51d063994664c" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="75f92b2ce21db46af5cff871938c4c31" parent="68467651c330ae2218e51d063994664c" type="folder">11</container></did></c><c id="5275656186d94e44a35012bc95381cac" level="file"><did><unittitle>Request for proposals</unittitle><unitdate normal="2001/2001" type="inclusive">2001</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="d15aa5fbdd525223fd50a3a965779bb7" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="bcba5b72867d689c878a9fdc00c225bd" parent="d15aa5fbdd525223fd50a3a965779bb7" type="folder">12</container></did></c><c id="ed22cd1affa24e588c45cb11037058ee" level="file"><did><unittitle>Southern Regional Meeting</unittitle><unitdate normal="2001/2002" type="inclusive">2001 - 2002</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="c61498d8807bbd5a23151251a9b072bf" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="c9756d1d9739dfdd468f9880c364a021" parent="c61498d8807bbd5a23151251a9b072bf" type="folder">13-14</container></did></c><c id="9f846897189a42f081e832a1403a7e73" level="file"><did><unittitle>Web site</unittitle><unitdate normal="2000/2000" type="inclusive">2000</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="66c6294ddc564a247e55711ded3a48f9" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="4d11cc5ab442bd1385a741b23872e561" parent="66c6294ddc564a247e55711ded3a48f9" type="folder">15</container></did></c><c id="5f32daa9b01b4228953db685f411d4b1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Work plans</unittitle><unitdate normal="2000/2001" type="inclusive">2000 - 2001</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="8aa1dd2a26a574b9d512ae30d4124b7b" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="182282bb5126b2c3b7b90ca2aafabc4d" parent="8aa1dd2a26a574b9d512ae30d4124b7b" type="folder">16</container></did></c></c></c><c id="52cb73f4331f4fcc833687ac4ccb4a4c" level="series"><did><unittitle>Subjects</unittitle><unitid>II</unitid><unitdate normal="1992/2005" type="inclusive">1992-2005</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="b5805f4d494e923b7fd0f45d0bca0f13"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Records concerning a variety of Ford Foundation activities, including grant initiatives, conferences, program officer meetings and Trustee trips. There is a substantial file containing memos and correspondence pertaining to the State Fiscal Analysis Initiative. Several folders document meetings of program officers from the Civil Society unit with staff from other program areas to discuss shared strategies and themes for grantmaking (Box 2, Folders 18, 19, 22). There are also briefing books and related materials pertaining to trips to Alabama and China by Ford Foundation Trustees who served on the Peace and Social Justice Committee.</p></scopecontent><arrangement id="507d31ae19ed0d52b179c3d9f65811a3"><head>Arrangement</head><p>Arranged alphabetically by subject.</p></arrangement><c id="ae4b9e1f483641c3a90fab3d6a00af5f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Campus Compact National Student Summit</unittitle><unitdate normal="2002/2002" type="inclusive">2002</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="18ff18d197c7f5b8683c3bb00b6638be" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="ba42fe488073d66d4ca58025a3b0f3f6" parent="18ff18d197c7f5b8683c3bb00b6638be" type="folder">17</container></did></c><c id="20ec8fe12c3946b3bc7b44beda77f98e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Civil Society and Community Development meeting</unittitle><unitdate normal="2002/2002" type="inclusive">2002</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="89cc9697059da7b60594cdbc617e639c" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="cc4284aa4c3dbb5f37d753580a410b4a" parent="89cc9697059da7b60594cdbc617e639c" type="folder">18</container></did></c><c id="ecbd38c8060d480881d6977982ad5f46" level="file"><did><unittitle>Civil Society and Social Justice meeting</unittitle><unitdate normal="2001/2001" type="inclusive">2001</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="f92e5472223b0d97cb369a7dc6c6172a" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="725644c54d671e5e892676b59b000ea2" parent="f92e5472223b0d97cb369a7dc6c6172a" type="folder">19</container></did></c><c id="96f9d57495a447978965bc0d8f61b197" level="file"><did><unittitle>Conference on Diversity and Coexistence in Asia</unittitle><unitdate normal="2003/2003" type="inclusive">2003</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="90de4e9c02632bb46ade06d877935f77" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="277d13a09c143d99e842675ef04b6742" parent="90de4e9c02632bb46ade06d877935f77" type="folder">20</container></did></c><c id="0befb1e1b490415b84124777ba1a08b4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Convening on GLBT Rights and Issues and Religious Traditions in the US: Framing Difficult Dialogues and Seeking New Partnerships</unittitle><unitdate normal="2004/2004" type="inclusive">2004</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="bfe8b9166499bd9b15c5d2b4663442e5" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="9612ebae36819a8a0ba04a0efb2859f1" parent="bfe8b9166499bd9b15c5d2b4663442e5" type="folder">21</container></did></c><c id="1e004dc49f754cbb8c9ebe10e99cf25f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Governance and Civil Society meeting</unittitle><unitdate normal="2002/2002" type="inclusive">2002</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="fc090aee20eec22fa4d8bccb1b47494f" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="ff1df7010a3086d27746a98dadbe3dde" parent="fc090aee20eec22fa4d8bccb1b47494f" type="folder">22</container></did></c><c id="20e0f3fad72d41ccad4933de99cac008" level="file"><did><unittitle>Non-profit Infrastructure Funders Group</unittitle><unitdate normal="2002/2005" type="inclusive">2002 - 2005</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="2b46d61edc71ffd9a0dc28003883a7b5" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="69ea8e03dc469052354a0dbea68df0b2" parent="2b46d61edc71ffd9a0dc28003883a7b5" type="folder">23</container></did></c><c id="653dc3499aaf446f8009303bfb351fee" level="file"><did><unittitle>Peace and Social Justice accomplishments</unittitle><unitdate normal="2002/2002" type="inclusive">2002</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="031e3e1dd5fb5cc67257082b48c7eb46" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="124c789a17c479d1d4e801e14fce2918" parent="031e3e1dd5fb5cc67257082b48c7eb46" type="folder">24</container></did></c><c id="abf49581bd514183ba8ed10ff5efad94" level="file"><did><unittitle>Peace and Social Justice Trustee Committee Spring Trip to Alabama</unittitle><unitdate normal="2002/2002" type="inclusive">2002</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="c9eeb8853fc2d7a708658f46f6f81e64" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="e1dee2c86b00627fea8c9c62844f3c3a" parent="c9eeb8853fc2d7a708658f46f6f81e64" type="folder">25</container></did></c><c id="386b42cd0e9c4cffbd878090402db2f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Peace and Social Justice Trustee Committee Spring Trip to China</unittitle><unitdate normal="2004/2004" type="inclusive">2004</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="87fdd3675c66a80afeae74a72b8c15d7" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="ff55387829ef9597909aee0a30111162" parent="87fdd3675c66a80afeae74a72b8c15d7" type="folder">26</container></did></c><c id="7a228fa54d4f4a76a8b7340bae218ee6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Post 9/11 September 11, 2001 grants</unittitle><unitdate normal="2001/2003" type="inclusive">2001 - 2003</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="3ef1e5a19d93ce92fd9808cc142175a1" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="12c2873dbe9e2e3cf0068b65937eb89f" parent="3ef1e5a19d93ce92fd9808cc142175a1" type="folder">27</container></did></c><c id="1ae3aa0b203f40d2995689fe78b97749" level="file"><did><unittitle>Program Division Joint Worldwide Meting</unittitle><unitdate normal="2002/2002" type="inclusive">2002</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="141419096231853a6ec03f5dbd925284" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="378468792affc45fa79a7d2e4ca1f4c6" parent="141419096231853a6ec03f5dbd925284" type="folder">28</container></did></c><c id="964ed85d63254e21a9b3ce469e167815" level="file"><did><unittitle>Replenishing Democracy Initiative</unittitle><unitdate normal="2003/2003" type="inclusive">2003</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="6beb94a3a612b778a25bc110fad50b22" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="9e3e9836a4cee82b1dc97e8ffe35bd51" parent="6beb94a3a612b778a25bc110fad50b22" type="folder">29</container></did></c><c id="4451f7d950d94b74a73d97917ebd4113" level="file"><did><unittitle>Social movements</unittitle><unitdate normal="2002/2002" type="inclusive">2002</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="d325334af8c5e98ee717065c16410996" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="5998114617a8a32bf6731fff6b40a3cd" parent="d325334af8c5e98ee717065c16410996" type="folder">30</container></did></c><c id="9a2eacd82d30423b811f3fb2adfa6df9" level="file"><did><unittitle>State Fiscal Analysis Initiative</unittitle><unitdate normal="1992/2004" type="inclusive">1992 - 2004</unitdate><container altrender="Record Storage Box (Paige)" id="6a1861993116057f9eed04e8fa9b12e9" label="mixed materials [A0000000089676]" type="box">2</container><container id="672f12d009231a684bb6e87722cf622d" parent="6a1861993116057f9eed04e8fa9b12e9" type="folder">31</container></did></c></c></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
